Heart, heart, heart...
just one more heart.
You might as well
be showing us
your hand, Neelix.
This is a game of
strategy, deception.
Never let the opponents
know your hand.
Right.
( snorts in disgust )
Ten.
I see your ten and raise you 20.
Neelix?
I'm thinking...
20... another 20.
( laughs )
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say we're being hustled.
Ensign...
Oh, I'm not buying
the innocent Talaxian routine.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I've-I've... This is
the first time I've played...
What is it called?
ALL:
Poker.
Look, why don't
we make things
a little more
interesting?
Forget the chips.
Let's bet on tomorrow's
work detail, all right?
Whoever wins this hand
gets the morning off.
I'm in.
Sounds good to me.
What have you got?
Two pair.
Does... does that beat a flush?
I knew you were bluffing.
That beats me. Tom?
Battle stations!
( poker chips
clatter to floor)
And I had a full house.
I can't shake 'em.
Return fire.
Why didn't our sensors
detect them?
It looks like they used
a dispersal field
to mask their approach.
Warp drive?
No luck. Too much damage
to the plasma injectors.
Harry, get down there
and see what you can do.
Shields down 18 percent.
Harry, status?
I need time
to clear the injectors.
Sir, the cube's power output
is fluctuating.
Then we're still in the game.
Bring us about.
Target their propulsion matrix.
We've lost phasers.
Arm photon torpedoes.
Fire when ready.
We knocked out
their main propulsion system.
Good.
Now get us out
of here, Tom.
They've got us
in a tractor beam.
Harry,
we need warp power now.
We lost two more relays.
I can't!
( screams )
Harry?
Harry?!
Engines are off-line.
We are the Borg.
Your biological
and technological
distinctiveness
will be added to our own.
Resistance is futile.
CHAKOTAY ( distorted):
Neelix.
Neelix!
Commander?
It's all right.
You were unconscious,
but I don't think
you're injured.
I was dreaming you'd
been assimilated.
Your subconscious
was jumping the gun,
but not by much.
From the look
of this room,
I'd say we're
in an assimilation chamber.
Where's Harry?
He's not here.
Well, we've got to find him.
We need to get
our bearings first,
figure out
what's going on.
We're in a Borg cube,
and Harry's missing.
That's what's going on.
Sir...
Nobody we know.
Some kind of botched
assimilation?
From the looks of it.
( sighs ):
What are they
waiting for?
They've got three more
potential drones here!
Stay calm.
Calm?
We're in the
chamber of horrors,
or haven't you noticed?
We're not drones yet.
If we keep our heads,
maybe we can find a way out.
There's a force field
around this room.
Let's try to disable it.
Their ion trail ends
directly ahead.
I'm detecting another vessel,
bearing 30 mark 112.
It's a Borg cube.
Red Alert.
Alter course to intercept.
Adjust shields
to rotating frequencies.
Have they detected us?
TUVOK:
Unclear. The vessel's
holding position.
As soon as we're
within sensor range,
start scanning
for the away team.
On screen.
SEVEN:
Their propulsion system
is off-line.
The damage is not that severe.
The drones should've
repaired it by now.
Lucky for us they didn't,
or we'd never have
caught up with them.
Any sign of our people?
Not yet.
They are targeting
our warp core.
Shields are holding.
Return fire.
Aim for their weapons array.
Now they're going
after our impulse engines.
That one was meant
for our sensors.
They can't seem to make up
their minds.
Their attack strategy
is erratic, inefficient.
TUVOK:
And finished.
We've disabled their weapons.
That was too easy.
Maybe they're in worse shape
than we thought.
I'm picking up
non-Borg life signs.
One of them is
definitely Talaxian.
It looks as though they haven't
been assimilated yet.
Try to get a transporter lock.
Their shields
are interfering.
Target their shield generator
and fire.
SEVEN:
Captain, I believe I can explain
the unusual behavior
of these Borg.
There should be thousands
of drones manning the vessel,
but I'm picking up
only five signatures.
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
It doesn't sound like
they've lost their confidence.
Their shield generators
are too deep inside the vessel.
Our weapons can't reach them.
Open a channel.
Borg vessel, this is
the Starship Voyager.
You're holding our crewmen.
We're willing to cease firing
if you return them.
Negotiation is irrelevant.
You will be assimilated.
Not today and not by you.
Agree, or I'll resume firing.
They are scanning us.
We will return your crew members
in exchange
for specific technology.
Talk about unusual behavior.
The Borg negotiating?
What technology?
Your navigational deflector.
Disengage it
from your secondary hull.
JANEWAY:
Mute audio.
If we surrender our deflector,
we'll be dead in space.
We won't be able
to go to warp.
What would they want with it?
SEVEN:
When their communications
array was damaged,
it severed their link
to the collective.
They intend to adapt
our deflector to regain it.
And call for reinforcements?
That's the last thing we need.
We'll have to stall them
until we can find
another way out of this.
I'll consider the exchange,
but first I want to be certain
my crewmen are unharmed
and alive.
You have scanned our vessel.
Our scans were inconclusive.
We want to see them
for ourselves.
You may transport
one individual.
Seven.
BORG:
Proceed to Grid 63,
Subjunction 01.
State your designation.
Seven of Nine.
These drones
have not fully matured.
Where are the others?
There are no others.
The drones
aboard this vessel were...
deactivated.
We are the Borg.
Seven of Nine--
a Borg designation.
She's like us.
Not like us.
She's damaged.
Her infrastructure
has been removed.
We could fix her.
You will add to
our perfection.
You are neonatal drones.
You should still be
in maturation chambers.
We've matured
long enough.
Doubtful. Your thoracic nodes
haven't formed yet.
You're incomplete.
You'll continue
to malfunction.
You must return
to your maturation chambers.
Comply.
Don't listen to her.
We tried to
go back in.
The chambers
were off-line.
What happened
to the adult drones?
We don't know.
Irrelevant.
Don't tell her anything.
This vessel has been
severely damaged.
You won't be able
to repair it alone.
I can help you,
but first you must
release the hostages.
That wasn't the agreement.
I've modified
the agreement.
I didn't realize I'd be
dealing with children.
Your behavior
is erratic. I can't
be certain that you...
No modifications.
We show you the hostages;
you give us the deflector.
Comply.
Take me to them.
If she tries
to resist...
assimilate her.
Do you have
a designation?
Second.
You were the second
to emerge from
the chambers.
No, the first.
I could not
establish order.
I became second...
and he became first.
So you've established
a chain of command--
a hierarchy.
We're a collective.
A collective of
five on a vessel
normally run
by 5,000.
What makes you think
you'll survive?
When we reestablish
our link with the Borg,
they will come for us.
( footsteps approaching )
Commander, we've
got company.
I wish to see
if they're injured.
Seven?
Don't let their appearance
fool you.
They are in control
of this vessel
and all of its armaments.
Are you injured?
Nothing serious.
The previous tenant.
We were trying to perfect
our assimilation techniques.
You failed.
One of these captives
was attempting
to disconnect
the security field.
Actually, I was
just trying to...
( yells )
That was unnecessary.
He is not
permanently damaged.
He learned his lesson.
The Borg are prepared
to negotiate for your release.
I will return for you.
Give my regards to Harry.
The deflector array.
I'm not authorized
to give you technology.
I must report back
to Captain Janeway.
Agreed.
I also need to take
an adult drone
and a datanode back
to Voyager for analysis.
Why?
Something happened
on this vessel
that none of us understand.
If it happens again,
it could endanger all of you.
No sign of Harry yet,
but there are parts
of the cube that
we still can't scan.
Could the drones
be holding him
in another location?
Unlikely. Seven said
they didn't seem
to be aware
of his presence.
If he ejected
in an escape pod,
we would have detected
his beacon by now.
Try to activate
his combadge.
Match the carrier wave to
a Borg interlink frequency.
They shouldn't
detect it.
Aye, Captain.
What have we learned
from our friend here?
The bigger they come,
the harder they fall.
Behold the David
that slew our Goliath.
A pathogen?
A spaceborne virus
that adapted
to Borg physiology.
It's inert now, but in
its virulent state,
it attacked the drones
and killed them.
Why weren't
the juveniles infected?
The maturation chamber
is designed to protect
developing drones.
Malfunctions caused
by the deaths
of the adults
lead several of the chambers
to open prematurely.
Does this pathogen
only target the Borg?
The Borg and other
cybernetic organisms
it encounters.
You're not thinking
of using it as
a biological weapon.
If we can revive
the pathogen
and reintroduce it,
we could neutralize the drones
without harming
the away team.
Neutralize? You mean
"murder," don't you?
Captain, they're
children.
Need I remind you
that these "children"
have committed
murder themselves
in their futile attempts
to assimilate others.
Seven...
tell me something.
You saw them,
talked to them.
Do you think
they'll kill the hostages
if we don't give them
what they want?
Yes.
I want that pathogen
as an option, Doctor,
but I won't consider
using it until I've seen
these drones for myself.
Think you can arrange that?
Then you're with me.
( combadge chirping )
( groaning )
( alarm bleeping )
Computer, identify the source
of this com signal.
Starship Voyager.
( sighs ):
I need to respond
on the same carrier wave.
That procedure will require
significant modifications.
Well, don't worry.
I'm way ahead of you.
Why are you here?
I wanted to make
a new proposal.
We've already negotiated.
You've seen
the hostages.
Now give us the
deflector as agreed.
Maybe it's hard
for you to accept,
but you don't have
to rejoin the hive.
Our Doctor can remove
your implants,
you can come with us.
You were individuals
yourselves not long ago--
children with families.
You were abducted
and assimilated.
I recognize your species.
You're Brunali.
And you're Norcadian.
Do you remember
your world?
A Theta-Class planetoid.
Population: 260 million.
Binary suns.
And what did it look like
when those suns set each night?
Can you remember that?
Irrelevant!
The deflector, now.
We need more time.
That deflector array
is essential to our...
No.
( gasps )
Give it to us.
Or what? You'll
assimilate me?
That won't solve
your problem.
I can't give you
Voyager's  deflector,
but maybe we can repair
your technology.
Clarify.
Seven knows a good deal
about Borg systems.
You have two hours.
I don't know
the extent of the damage.
It could take longer.
Two hours...
or your hostages die.
Don't come back
here, Captain.
I bought us another two hours.
The pathogen?
It should be
ready by then.
Did you see the away team?
I'm afraid not.
But Seven assured me
our people haven't been harmed.
I can't believe
we're negotiating
with adolescent drones.
They're not exactly drones.
Mature Borg are predictable.
They'll ignore you
or assimilate you,
but these... juveniles,
they're unstable.
They are contemptuous
of authority,
convinced
that they are superior--
typical adolescent behavior
for any species.
( console beeping )
It's a transmission...
from the cube.
Seven?
No.
It's Harry.
I'm clearing it up now.
Delta Flyer  to  Voyager.
Respond.
We're receiving you, Ensign.
Where are you?
Still in the Flyer.
It's locked up
in some kind of hangar bay
along with two alien ships.
I've isolated his coordinates.
How close is he
to their shield generator?
Roughly 800 meters.
Harry, are there
any plasma charges
aboard the Flyer?
Yes, ma'am.
In that case,
how do you feel
about going for
a little walk?
I could use the exercise.
Tuvok will guide you
to the shield generator.
If you destroy it, you won't
have to make the trip back.
Understood.
I have the technology
you've requested.
Thank you.
You were a drone
for 18 years.
Correct.
I accessed your datafile.
Why?
I thought
it might be relevant.
( sighs )
What else did you learn?
You were assimilated
as a juvenile, like us.
My parents
were scientists
studying the Borg.
They took me with them.
My childhood was short.
Childhood?
The years between birth
and physical maturity,
when humanoids adapt
to their roles
as individuals.
Perhaps you have memory
of yours.
I don't know.
What about your parents?
Do you remember them?
No.
No memories.
Your subvocal processor
is malfunctioning.
I can repair it for you.
It's a slight adjustment.
It won't be painful.
The first told me
my malfunction
could not be repaired,
until we reconnected
with the collective.
This color...
My mother's hair...
was this color.
FIRST:
I thought
we agreed--
no irrelevant discussions.
What is the punishment
for disobeying the protocols?
Deactivation.
I engaged him in
this discussion.
Return to your station.
I found some
unsettling information.
I examined their
communication records.
The collective did
receive the drones'
initial distress call.
How long before they arrive?
A vessel was
not dispatched.
The collective declared
the neonatal drones
irrelevant
and severed their link
to the hive permanently.
They see them as damaged,
unworthy of reassimilation.
Precisely.
Are the drones aware of this?
No. They don't
have the ability
to decrypt the message.
Once they learn they've
been rejected by the hive,
they won't need our deflector.
They might be willing
to release the hostages.
Normally when drones
learn they're irrelevant,
they deactivate themselves.
But these neonatal drones
are unpredictable.
They may not adhere
to Borg protocols.
There is another option.
We could invite them
to Voyager.
When they realize they have
no place else to go...
If you're suggesting
transforming them
into individuals,
that would be
extremely difficult.
You turned out
pretty well, Seven.
That's because I was prepared
before you encountered me.
What do you mean?
When I was first captured
by the Borg,
I was young and frightened.
I watched my parents
assimilated.
Then I was placed
in a maturation chamber,
and the hive mind began
to restructure
my synaptic pathways,
purge my individuality.
When I emerged five years later,
the turmoil
of my forced assimilation
had been replaced with order.
You may not be aware
of this, Captain,
but that order continues to be
a source of strength for me.
I could not have regained
my humanity without it.
I appreciate
your insights.
But just because they
didn't have the benefit
of your Borg upbringing,
doesn't mean we're going
to turn our backs on them.
There has to be another way.
Not all drones
can be saved, Captain.
Continue the repairs
aboard the Borg cube.
We'll hold onto this
information for now.
Yes, Captain.
They do have one thing
going for them.
You.
If there's anyone
who can reach them,
it's you.
KIM:
Three of hearts
on a transwarp conduit.
Ensign?
King of clubs...
on a power coupling.
I'm marking my route
with playing cards in case I
have to come back this same way.
TUVOK:
You shouldn't distract yourself,
Mr. Kim.
I need a little distraction.
This hike is bringing up
some bad memories.
An earlier visit to a Borg cube?
Nope, haunted house
my parents took me to
when I was six.
Borg vessels may be forbidding,
but they are not haunted.
( sighs ):
Tuvok?
Turn left, Ensign.
Nine of diamonds on a data node.
The resonance field
collapsed.
It'll take an hour
to reinitialize.
These delays
are intentional.
I'm working
as efficiently as I can.
Examine my work for yourself
if you have doubts.
This data's flawed.
More likely it's
your understanding
of quadric field
theory that's flawed.
Ignore her.
She's trying to divide us.
They rely on you.
Yet you lack
the skills necessary to ensure
their survival.
We've managed so far.
We're Borg.
You've forgotten
what that means.
The unity of the collective...
common goals...
the quest for perfection...
I have not forgotten.
But you don't need
to remain drones
to experience those things.
Come back with me to Voyager.
38 minutes.
You're wasting time.
( alarm blaring )
Another maturation chamber
is malfunctioning.
SEVEN:
Its autonomic nervous
system is failing.
It's Borg.
It will adapt.
It's not adapting.
Let Seven help.
We can modulate the stasis field
to stabilize its functions,
at least temporarily.
Assist me.
The field is degrading.
We need to transport it
into an incubation pod--
quickly.
( baby wheezing )
Why is it doing that?
It's respiratory
system is impaired.
And this incubation pod
is malfunctioning.
We must transport this
infant to Voyager.
No. The drone is part
of our collective.
Not if it dies.
( baby panting )
Tetryon levels are rising.
I'm getting closer.
TUVOK:
The shield generator
should be directly ahead.
I see it.
The first charge is in place.
( com static )
Tuvok?
( banging )
( gasps )
( sighs )
Hello?
You left these.
( sighs )
I like her.
She looks like Seven of Nine.
Is Seven your friend?
You know, she's my friend, too.
Maybe someday...
Your weapon won't work here.
Dampening field.
How long has it been
since you lost contact?
Four or five minutes.
His bio-signs?
Doctor to the Captain.
Please report
to Sick Bay immediately.
On my way.
Keep looking
for him.
What's the emergency?
I thought you should see
for yourself.
Somebody left a bundle
on our doorstep.
I turned around
and there she was,
lying on a bio-bed.
Seven must have
beamed her here.
A good thing, too.
A few more minutes
and I wouldn't have been able
to do anything for her.
It's hard to believe
she could grow up
to be a drone.
( baby crying )
Hold her for a moment
while I take some readings.
( baby stops crying )
Oh. I guess she just
wanted to be held.
Oh.
The pathogen.
I finished synthesizing it.
Start working with Tuvok
on a way to deploy
the virus.
Captain, you don't
seriously plan to use it.
If I have to.
Let's just hope your
brothers and sisters
don't force my hand.
You complain of delays,
then you interrupt my work.
Can you identify this?
It's a plasma charge.
You tried to deceive us.
FIRST:
Nanoprobes were injected
into his bloodstream.
He won't survive
without medical attention.
Call your Captain.
Tell her to give us
the deflector.
That won't be necessary.
I only need a few more
minutes to repair...
No more delays.
No more deceptions.
The deflector.
Resistance is futile.
FIRST:
Comply.
Return Harry Kim;
then we'll talk.
We've talked enough.
Your requests are irrelevant.
Comply, or we'll assimilate
the others.
It'll take us at least an hour
to dismantle the deflector
and transfer
the components...
Now.
I can't give it to you now.
It's complex technology
that's part of our ship.
We can't simply remove it,
and no amount
of threats from you
is going to change that.
They've locked a tractor beam
onto the deflector.
TORRES:
They're trying
to tear it off.
Hull stress is increasing.
Breaches on Decks 10 and 11.
Increase shield strength
and randomize the harmonics.
They're adapting.
Even with Voyager's
deflector,
your efforts to
return to the hive
will fail.
They'll come for us.
No, they won't.
The Borg received
your message,
but chose
to ignore it.
They consider
you irrelevant.
Irrelevant?
We are damaged.
They don't want us.
Ignore her.
It's another lie.
Their reply is
in data grid 426.
Use decryption
protocol theta-3.
Return to your station.
It's another deception.
She's manipulating us.
The transmission
is authentic.
It's a mistake.
The collective does not
tolerate imperfection.
Then we'll assimilate
more species...
prove we're worthy.
Hull stress is reaching
critical levels.
Reroute all emergency power
to structural integrity.
That'll buy us
another minute at most.
Captain, I found a fluctuation
in their shield grid
near a plasma duct.
It's too intermittent
to beam out the hostages,
but we could use it
to deploy the pathogen.
Captain...
Not yet.
There is
no alternative.
There's always
an alternative.
We just need to find it.
Their tractor
beam draws power
from the same grid
as their shield matrix.
If we use the deflector
to send a feedback pulse
along the beam,
it could disrupt
their shields. Do it.
Rerouting more plasma.
If this doesn't work,
it'll do more damage
to us than the cube.
It'll work.
Prepare to fire.
You have no future
with the Borg...
but you do
with Voyager--
a chance to reclaim
your real lives.
What do you know
about real lives?
Does he speak
for all of you?
You should make your
decisions yourself,
as individuals.
They are sending
a feedback pulse
through our tractor beam.
It's overloading
our shield matrix.
Adapt!
Their tractor beam
is fluctuating.
Their shields
are dropping.
I've got a partial lock
on the away team.
Boosting the confinement beam.
I've got three of them.
Confirmed.
Chakotay, Paris and Neelix
are in Transporter Room 2.
What about Seven and Harry?
They must be in a section
that's still shielded.
Amplify the feedback pulse.
The other captives are gone.
The shields around this chamber
are failing.
Instructions.
Lower your shields.
Lower the shields!
No!
( grunts )
Leave her alone.
Get back to your station.
Do what I say.
What you say?
I thought we were
a collective.
One mind, one voice.
I protected you...
gave you order.
Your order.
Your rules.
Their feedback pulse
is overloading
the induction grids.
This vessel will be destroyed.
We must evacuate.
No!
Assist me!
( groans )
You're damaged.
Lie still.
We have to resist.
The collective will come for us.
His cortical implants
are depolarizing.
I can't help him.
We'll find a new home.
You'll see.
W-we are Borg.
Yes.
We are Borg.
Lower the shields.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Harry is recovering
in Sick Bay,
and the rest
of the away team
is safe and sound.
As for the drones,
the Doctor's removed
most of their implants,
leaving us with four
very troubled children.
We've sent out calls
to any Brunali
and Norcadian ships
that might be
in the vicinity,
but we haven't gotten
any responses so far,
and we're still
trying to figure out
where the other
two came from.
It may take a while.
They could use the time.
They have a great deal
to learn.
It might help if they
had someone around
who knew what
they're up against.
I've never been responsible
for children.
Mr. Neelix would be
a wiser choice.
From what I've seen,
you're the one they've
established a bond with.
They'll be looking to you
for guidance.
Perhaps I could...
help them avoid
some of the obstacles
I've encountered.
Do we have to regenerate now?
Yes.
But first...
I was able to salvage
your assimilation
profiles.
They include your names
and some limited
biographical data.
Icheb.
My name was Icheb.
Your name
is Icheb.
I remember now.
It was my father's second name.
My designation is Mezoti.
It-it's a pretty name.
Yes, it is...
and it's all yours.
Azan and Rebi...
I'll tell you more
about them tomorrow.
Computer, decrease
ambient lighting by 60 percent.
Good night.
Sweet dreams.