( engine rumbling,
horn honking )
Get out of the way!
( horn honking )
Oh.
Whoa. Easy, now.
Whoo.
( horn honking )
( sheep bleating )
Hey, watch out!
Come on. Come on.
Sorry.
Tommy, me boy...
Did you hurt yourself,
Tommy-Boy?
( grunts )
I think I zigged when
I should have zagged.
Well, maybe you ought
to stick to a horse
and carriage.
Still, she's a beauty.
The world must
be treating you well
to afford such a thing.
( chuckles )
Just dipping into
my inheritance.
Oh, come into some money,
did you?
So who's passed on?
Um, my grandfather
on my mother's side.
An aristocrat,
God rest his soul.
Sounds like he was a fine man.
I'd drink a toast to him,
if I had a shilling
to me name.
( laughs )
Here. It's on me.
It'll take three pints
to do a proper job, Tommy-Boy.
And this isn't
even enough for two.
There. That's
all I've got.
You're a generous man.
Care to join me
at Sullivan's?
Ah, I wish I could,
but I'm on my way
to Castle O'Dell.
Night's coming.
And they say
when the sun goes down,
the queen of the faerie folk
reclaims the castle.
Ah.
I'll give her
your regards.
Don't say
I didn't warn ya.
Computer,
replace
damaged tire.
Saints preserve us.
I thought I would die
from the shock of it.
Now, Seamus, you're
not a great one
for telling things
the way they were.
I'll admit I've been known
to add a little color
to stories from time to time
to liven things up,
but with God as my witness
I saw Tom Paris using
unnatural powers
to fix that
wheel of his.
Tommy-Boy practicing
unholy magic?
Next thing you'll
be telling me is
you want to pay
for your own drinks.
Make fun if you like,
but he was heading
up to Castle O'Dell
only an hour before dark.
Oh, leave it
alone, Seamus.
Can't one day go by
without you making
an ass of yourself?
Mm.
But that Tom Paris
is an odd one.
Coming and going
through town as if
he built the place.
That's right,
and where does he go?
Oh, he's a shifty one,
and for that matter,
so are his friends.
If you're talking
about Katie O'Clare,
you better watch your mouth.
Oh. Well, you know what
they say, Sullivan--
birds of a feather...
They also say superstition
is the religion of fools.
Kilmanin, 1846.
What?
Old Patsy
down in County Meath
spoke of a band
of spirit folk
who came
to Kilmanin in '46.
Kilmanin?
Did you ever hear
of it, Doc?
No, this is the first.
Ah, but you won't
find it on any map.
Not anymore.
It was a town
not much different
than Fair Haven.
That is, until this group
of strangers arrived.
The townsfolk welcomed them
with open arms.
After all, a stranger
is just a friend
you haven't met yet.
But they regretted their
hospitality soon enough.
The cows stopped
giving milk.
The potatoes grew
rotten in the ground.
Then people started
to go missing.
Oh, go on.
It's true.
What happened
to them?
They were taken...
( whispers ):
to the otherworld.
SEAMUS:
When winter came
and the nights grew longer,
the entire town vanished,
every post,
every nail--
poof-- into thin air,
never to be seen again.
Are you suggesting
that Fair Haven's going
to go the way of Kilmanin
just because we have
a few new folks in town?
I'm suggesting you keep an eye
on Tom Paris and his cohorts.
Not to mention
that lady friend of yours.
So Katie's some kind of
goblin now, is that it?
She's certainly cast
a spell on you.
Well, if you ask me...
( throat clearing
and shushing)
Katie!
Am I interrupting?
Aw, just some nonsense.
Seamus is up
to his old tricks again.
Good day to you, Katie.
Oh, it's good to see you.
What'll it be?
The usual, please.
Well, one cup of tea
coming right up.
Did you snatch
any children
on the way
into town, Katie?
JANEWAY:
What?
Never mind.
I missed your smile.
What have you been
doing with yourself?
Nothing terribly exciting.
Just helping my aunt
and uncle out on the farm.
They're not as spry
as they used to be.
Although, they've got
a goat that could argue
Mossie Donegan's talking pig
under the table.
You'll have to
bring him into the bar
the next time you're up.
We'll arrange a debate.
I'll see that I do.
I hear they opened
a nickelodeon in Dooleen.
I thought it might be nice
to go to a show.
I've got to
tend the bar.
I wish you'd let me
know you were coming.
I would've made
arrangements.
That's all right.
We can go
some other time.
No, I mean, you've
already made the trip.
It'd be a shame if
you have to leave.
Well, I could be
convinced to stay
if you'd be up
for a game of... rings.
( laughs )
Let's go.
Computer, one dozen
Broadway lilies.
Something tells me
that's not lunch.
Already ate.
Ah. Who are they for?
A friend.
Oh, and this friend
wouldn't happen to be
a lovely Irish lass,
now, would she?
Aren't you due
on the Bridge?
Ah, you better watch
yourself, Harry.
These country girls aren't
as simple as you think.
Maggie O'Halloran
could be a little more
than you can handle.
I heard about your
little traffic accident.
( chuckles ):
That was a clutch
malfunction.
It wasn't my fault.
If you ask me,
that whole program
is an accident
waiting to happen.
You have been running
Fair Haven around the clock.
Just yesterday,
I had to replace
three holo-emitters.
I ran a full diagnostic
this morning.
Everything is fine.
Whatever you say.
But when your quaint,
little seaside town
starts to depolarize,
don't come running to me.
If you'll excuse me,
I'm late for a moonlight stroll.
Are you sure you
don't need a chaperon?
( laughs )
Not with your driving record.
( chuckles )
I think I know just
what'll make his date
just a little
more interesting.
Just don't blow out
any more holo-emitters.
What are we doing
out here, Seamus,
skulking about in the
dark, spying on folks?
What's the
matter, Milo?
You got a case
of the willies?
Well, what if
you're right?
What if this Tom Paris
is some kind of demon?
If we're caught, he'll
cast a spell on us.
Then stop your squawking
or he'll catch us for sure.
Come on, man.
He's getting away.
Ah.
A captain is only as good
as his crew.
It must be lonely
out there on the sea
with only the
stars to guide you.
Sometimes,
during the night watch,
with the timbers creaking,
and the dark water
stretching out as far
as the eye can see,
you can believe you're
the only man in the world.
Maybe you should think
about settling
down on dry land.
Well, believe me, I do.
As often
as I think of you.
MAGGIE:
Can I ask you
something, Harry?
KIM:
Of course.
Would you like
to hold my hand?
If you promise
to hold mine back.
( groans )
Look. He's got some sort
of contraption in his hand.
Ooh, maybe we're going
about this the wrong way.
We should go down
to St. Mary's
and tell Father Mulligan
the whole story.
He's not going to listen
to talk of the supernatural.
Aw, if you fill
his collection box,
he'll listen
to anything.
That's true.
I thought you were
promised to Ray Ewan.
Not anymore.
Ah.
Can I ask you
something else, Harry?
Please.
Would you like
to kiss me?
Is that a trick question?
( gasps )
( moos )
Holy Mother of God!
( laughs )
Tom!
( Tom laughing )
KIM:
Don't you have
anything better to do?
PARIS:
Oh, boy.
She really turned on you.
KIM:
Ha-ha, very funny.
I could have
been trampled.
Relax. The holodeck
safeties are on.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Poor Maggie.
All right, all right.
You've had your fun.
Now change her back.
Chakotay to Paris and Kim.
Report to the Bridge.
On our way.
( laughs )
What about Maggie?
She'll be fine.
Let her graze.
Did you hear that?
Ah!
CONGREGATION:
Amen.
DOCTOR:
Please be seated.
I recently heard a tale
of two farmers,
who shall remain nameless
for the sake of this sermon.
It seems one broke
the other's plow
and refused to replace it.
His comeuppance was served
to him not by the hand of God
but by the other farmer,
in the form
of a clogged irrigation ditch.
Now, do you think
their disagreement
stopped there?
Of course not.
They go on...
just as the heathen did of old.
After all, one spiteful act
deserves another, right?
( murmuring agreement )
Wrong!
What these sinners
have forgotten
is that they are neighbors.
He's in love with the sound
of his own voice.
DOCTOR:
Whether we are man or woman,
parent or child...
flesh and blood
or photons and force fields...
( murmuring )
It has been said...
On the other hand,
perhaps he's been nipping
at the sacramental wine.
And, as such,
our community is everything.
It is our world,
and we are a part of it
just as a branch
is part of a tree.
Do you see... branches
tearing leaves off one another?
No!
Do you see
roots hoarding water
from the trunk?
No!
Do you see...?
( cow moos )
SEAMUS:
Easy, Maggie.
Whoa.
( murmuring )
Oh. Easy now.
( moos, bell clanking )
Did you make a wrong turn
on your way
to the milking shed?
Oh, nothing like that
at all, Father.
Something terrible's
happened.
DOCTOR:
What now?
This was
Maggie O'Halloran.
The spirits
have turned her
into a cow.
Maggie O'Halloran's
been eaten by a cow?
Did you see these spirits?
That we did--
Tom Paris
and Harry Kim.
( sighs, cow moos )
I hate to disappoint you,
but it sounds as though
you've been the victim
of a practical joke.
Tom Paris is a known prankster.
( voice shaking ):
Oh... it was unholy magic,
I tell you.
Aye, aye.
We saw it
with our own eyes.
When did this alleged
transformation take place?
Last night.
Well, then,
that settles it.
This couldn't possibly be
Maggie O'Halloran.
I saw Maggie this morning
on my way into church.
She was at her cart
tending her flowers.
She's probably there now.
( cow moos loudly )
Well, I... I think
that's enough excitement
for one morning.
This mass is over.
Go in peace.
Um... leave the cow.
Oh...
All right, Father.
Excuse us, Maggie.
Take care,
Maggie.
Whoa.
Maggie...
Well, good morning, boys.
Is everything all right?
Y-you're looking a little
out of sorts this morning.
Yes. Well, I must admit
I'm not quite myself today.
Oh?
Well, this is going
to sound very odd,
but I feel like I just woke up
from the strangest dream,
and I don't remember going
to sleep.
You're right, that
does sound odd.
Do you remember anything
about last night?
Well, I was out
with Harry Kim.
He chatted me up
at The Ox and Lamb,
and we were off on a
walk before I knew it.
What did you do on your walk?
We talked.
What kind of a girl
do you think I am?
Now, Maggie,
we weren't implying anything.
No!
Do you recall
anything else
about the evening?
Ah, did anything out of the, um,
ordinary happen?
Anything at all?
I don't remember.
Well, tell us
about the dream, then.
Oh, it was
most unpleasant.
I was walking
around town
with nothing but a
bell around my neck.
Well, somehow, I
wound up in church.
Everyone was staring
at me.
You were there,
Seamus...
And you,
too, Milo.
The next thing I knew,
I was tending my flowers
just as you
boys walked up.
Well, that's
quite a story, Maggie.
Can we get a quick one?
Maybe just a wee taste.
So, I said to young Harry,
"I'm not one for rainy days
and gray skies."
As soon as the words were
out of my mouth,
he called up the spirits
to do his bidding.
A second later,
there wasn't a cloud in the sky.
I was up near Ballahick farm
with little Mary.
She was playing
near the well.
Somehow, she lost her footing
and fell in.
I was so frightened.
I didn't know what to do.
So, I ran to the Colbys'
to get some help...
but... when
we returned,
there was Mary
in the meadow,
talking with
Katie O'Clare.
There wasn't a
scratch on her.
Katie said
I must've been mistaken
when I saw her fall.
There was
no mistake.
WOMAN:
I saw something
strange, too.
Well, I hesitated
to say anything
for fear
you'd think me mad.
But after listening
to your stories today,
I feel you've a right
to know.
Well? Speak up.
Last Sunday,
after his sermon,
I saw Father Mulligan
vanish into thin air.
( sighs ):
He's one of them,
right enough.
Father Mulligan, Tommy-Boy,
Katie and the rest--
they're spirit folk.
What about that Neelix fellow
who runs The Ox and Lamb?
Well, if he doesn't
look like a leprechaun,
I don't know who does.
They're all probably
up at Castle O'Dell,
conspiring against us.
Now...
that's enough.
I can't deny there's been
some unusual goings-on.
But what are you proposing--
that we run Katie
and her friends out of town?
Or maybe we should line them up
in front of a firing squad--
is that what
you want?
These people
have been
our neighbors.
We've become friends.
Let's not forget that.
Well, we can't just
sit here and do nothing
while they take
over Fair Haven.
I'm not saying we do nothing...
but let's go about this
like civilized people.
What do you suggest--
we sit them down
and discuss it over tea?
You're looking lovelier
than ever, Katie.
Thank you.
Open it.
"The Faerie Queene
by Edmund Spenser."
Thank you, Michael.
It's the longest poem
in the English language,
and the first to use
a nine-line stanza.
I'll start
reading it tonight.
I love epic poetry.
Really?
I didn't know that.
( sighs )
It seems as if there's
a lot of things
I don't know about you.
I thought you'd
want to know
there's been some talk
about you and your friends.
Strange things have been
happening around town.
Folk are saying you're to blame.
What kind of strange things?
People using unholy magic...
vanishing into thin air...
changing the weather.
By any chance,
would all of this
have anything to do
with your reading suggestion?
As a matter of fact.
Don't tell me.
They say
I'm the "Faerie Queene."
Frankly, they could tell me
you're the devil himself,
and I wouldn't care.
( chuckles ):
I'll try not to
take that personally.
The sad truth of
the matter is...
I don't know
who you are.
What do you mean?
You've been lying to me, Katie.
I've been doing
some checking
with friends of mine
in County Clare.
Seems nobody's heard
of you there.
It's a big county.
And I've got a lot of friends.
You've been evasive
from the day we met.
I was a fool not to see it.
Where do you go
when you leave here?
There've been times I wanted
to talk to you--
tell you about my day,
about a book I'd read...
just to say
hello...
but I can't,
because I don't know
where to find you.
What are you hiding, Katie?
I'll admit I have misled you
about some things,
but never
about anything important.
And I wasn't lying
when I said I care about you.
I wish I could believe that.
You can.
I didn't want to deceive you...
but under the circumstances,
I had no choice.
What circumstances?
Michael...
there are things about me
you may not be able
to understand.
Try me.
Who are you, Katie?
Where are you
really from?
The truth.
Computer, end program.
How did he know?
Those are questions
no holodeck character
should be asking.
What exactly did you
do to that program?
Well, I, I just added a few
bells and whistles
to make the characters
more realistic.
Nothing too fancy.
Well, something's
gone wrong. The people
of Fair Haven
aren't simple country
folk anymore. Report.
It looks like we've
worn out our welcome.
It's the first time
we've tried running
a holodeck program
nonstop.
We're lucky it lasted
this long.
There are damaged
subroutines
in all of the
character files.
So much for my
open door policy.
Shut it down and repair
the damaged systems.
As I recall,
everything was fine
until someone started
turning people into cows.
( chuckles )
Computer, display Fair Haven
character Michael Sullivan.
Tom.
Where am I?
Where's Katie?
He shouldn't be aware
that he's in the lab.
I've isolated
the damaged subroutines.
I said where the hell am I?!
I-it's all right, Michael.
Take it easy.
What is this place?
Try to relax.
If someone doesn't tell me
where I am, I'm going
to start busting heads.
His perceptual filters
are malfunctioning.
What are you saying?
What's a perceptual filter?
I-it's o... it's okay.
We're trying to help you.
There.
Look at these.
Those are the algorithms
designed to keep
him oblivious
to anything outside
the program's parameters.
They're off-line.
Give me a minute.
That should do it.
How are you
feeling, Michael?
Never better.
Harry, Liam's been looking
for you.
You're the only man
in four counties
to beat him at
arm wrestling.
He wants a rematch.
Tell him he's got one.
I'll do that.
( chuckles )
That was easy enough.
Yeah. Unfortunately,
it looks like all
the other characters
have the same malfunction.
Don't tell me we're going
to have to go through
every one of them?
If we reactivate
the program,
use the primary
control port
in Sullivan's pub,
we could reset all
the perceptual filters
with a single
command sequence.
Ah. I guess we'll be
seeing you later.
Looking forward to it.
Computer, resume
Fair Haven program
in Holodeck 1,
and transfer
Michael Sullivan
back to his bar.
Danny!
Danny, come here.
Fetch Doc Fitzgerald.
Tell him to meet me
in the church.
Go on, hurry, lad.
We thought we'd reset
his perceptual filters,
until we took a closer look
at his subroutines.
Turns out he was just
playing along.
Ha. Never underestimate
an Irish hologram.
We'll have to
reprogram Michael
when we do the others.
Let's just hope he
didn't share the experience
with too many others.
Got it. These
resequenced algorithms
should do the trick.
Good luck.
What the hell
was I thinking?
A minor malfunction.
Well, that's the problem.
I've got a boyfriend
who malfunctions.
Tom and Harry'll fix him.
And if they can't?
One piece of advice
you've always given me--
tell the truth.
Hate to break the news
to you, Michael,
but I'm a starship Captain,
and you're a 300 deciwatt
holodeck program.
I couldn't do it.
In that case...
you'll have to get creative.
I'm not a
superstitious man, Doc,
but I've been seeing things
I can't explain.
You're not the only one.
At first I thought we had
an epidemic on our hands.
But this is no fever.
No, it's not.
Last night, I was
talking to Katie,
and the next thing I knew,
I was being spirited away
to God knows where.
They took you? Where?
Maybe it was the otherworld.
I don't know.
Tom Paris was there.
Young Harry, too.
What did they
want with you?
I'm not sure.
They were talking about me
like I wasn't there.
Saying things
about Fair Haven--
that we knew too much
about them.
Oh, Lord.
And that's not all.
They were saying something
about coming to the pub tonight
to change the town somehow.
What does that mean?
I'm damned if I know.
How did you get away?
With all the talk
about us knowing
too much about them,
I figured that if I pretended
nothing was out of the ordinary,
they might let me go.
And sure enough, that's
exactly what they did.
I wonder if this is how
things started in Kilmanin
back in '46.
I'm not sure what
they have in mind.
But we'd better
be prepared.
We're in luck.
Nobody's home.
SEAMUS:
If we're going to fight them,
we've got to use
the right ammunition.
Biddy Ramsey gave me this
before she passed on.
She knew a thing or two
about fairy magic
and how to fight it.
Everything she learned,
she learned from this book.
I doubt if it says anything
about using rifles.
You'd be surprised
how many things
a bullet will stop.
I don't like this one bit.
Guns, Seamus.
Under normal circumstances,
I'd agree with you, Michael...
but these aren't
normal circumstances.
Maybe you'd still like us
to be acting civilized.
Where did that
get you before?
A ticket to the
otherworld, that's what.
Now, we don't know
what the spirit folk
have in store for us.
That's just it.
We don't know much
about anything, do we?
And we've got Milo here
acting like a holy war
has been declared.
Relax, Sullivan.
The rifles are only
a last resort.
Besides,
we've got incantations,
which are more lethal
to spirit folk than any
weapons forged by man.
That's how we're going
to force them back
into their realm.
And we've got red twine
to stop them from
changing shape.
And don't forget about
the ash berries.
Ash berries, right.
That's how you keep them
from using their powers
against you.
They've been walking
amongst us for weeks now,
pretending to be
our friends.
Lying to us, making mischief.
What's next?
Yeah!
What is next, Seamus?
I for one am not going
to stand by
and let them run roughshod
over our town.
( shouting agreement )
We can't rest
until we've driven
every one of them out.
( all agreeing )
They're here!
Tom Paris and Harry Kim--
they're in Sullivan's right now!
Who's with me?
Come on.
( door opens )
( shouting )
There they are!
Seamus, let us explain.
You're making
a mistake.
The only mistake
we made
was letting you
into Fair Haven.
What's that?
Shoot it.
No, wait, wait. That's
a delicate piece of...
...technology.
Warning. Holodeck controls
and safety protocols are
off-line.
A voice from
the otherworld.
Emergency overrides
are malfunctioning.
Computer, freeze program!
62 percent compliance.
They're getting away!
After them!
( angry shouting )
PARIS:
Computer, exit.
Gunfire?
Two shots directly
at the primary controls.
We can't deactivate
the program or get
the safeties back on line.
Where are Tom
and Harry now?
St. Mary's.
Looks like some
of your parishioners
are holding them captive.
We can't blame them
for being frightened.
They must think we're
some kind of sorcerers.
Well, we could use
a little magic right now,
because that's about
the only way we're going
to get our people back.
Transporters?
Too many stray photons.
We can't get a lock.
We should enter
the holodeck
with a security team
and take them by force.
Need I remind you
that the holo-characters
have weapons as well.
We'd be risking armed conflict.
Well, then let's
just pull the plug.
Cut power to
the holo-grid.
That would purge the
program from our database.
Exactly.
But we'd lose
Fair Haven
and all its people.
They're not people.
They're holograms.
And they weren't
programmed to
be violent.
I don't believe
they'd harm anyone.
You can't be certain.
Well, I am certain.
And I'd like to find
a less drastic solution.
With all due
respect, Captain,
Michael can be
reprogrammed--
Tom and Harry can't.
One problem at a time,
B'Elanna.
The people of Fair Haven
may not be real,
but our feelings
toward them are.
I won't destroy
these relationships
if we can find
another way.
Now, if we could attach
transport enhancers
onto Tom and Harry,
would that be enough
to cut through
the interference?
I believe so.
Good.
Then, we just need to get
someone close to them.
Doctor.
A few words of inspiration
should get me within reach.
I suggest you use
your mobile emitter.
It'll isolate you
from the malfunctions.
Good idea.
Stand by to cut power
to the holo-grid,
in case things
get out of hand.
TORRES:
Aye, Captain.
In the meantime,
I believe your flock
needs tending.
SEAMUS:
Ex labis caelstium sanctorum
super ad aures atorum
larvarum mentientium.
From the lips
of the heavenly saints above
to the ears of the dark
and lying spirits--
may your spectral forms
be cast back to the otherworld!
Back to the otherworld!
( sighs )
There must be some trick
to these incantations.
What do you make
of this, Seamus?
We should just
tell them the truth.
Oh, good idea, Harry.
Do you want to tell them
they're only holograms,
or should I?
I see you left your box
of charms at Sullivan's.
I believe this is
the talisman
you used
on Maggie.
Maybe we should turn
them into cows.
No, no, there's been
a misunderstanding.
We are not spirit folk.
( chuckles ):
I think we've heard enough
of your lies, Tommy-Boy.
I say we tie them up
to the lamppost in the square
and show them how spirit folk
were dealt with
in the olden days.
( crowd agrees )
Leave them alone.
It's bad enough
you've got them trussed up
like Christmas turkeys.
There's no need
for foolish threats!
You'd better watch
whose side you're on.
You're not above
suspicion yourself.
Oh, so we're going to start
turning on one another
now, is that it?
We are if you're choosing
them over your own people.
Sinners!
Sinners, all of you.
You have the audacity
to turn a house of worship
into a prison?
This is where we gather
to pledge our love
for our fellow man--
not condemnation.
You should all be
ashamed of yourselves.
Quite a rousing
sermon, Father,
but I'm afraid you're
not going to find
too many takers tonight.
Not after your
little vanishing act.
It seems Grace Declan
saw you disappear
into thin air
on Sunday.
Aye. I'd say that sounds
a wee bit unholy.
You're in league
with them, aren't you?
Tie him up
with the others.
Listen to yourselves.
You're letting confusion
and fear get the best of you.
Doctor to Janeway.
What's this?
Fire and brimstone
don't seem to be working.
Look here, Seamus!
Another talisman.
Quick, get it
off of him!
Beam him out of there.
His program's been
disengaged from
the mobile emitter.
And what were you planning
on doing with these?
Those are the devices
that will allow us to leave.
Just put them on our coats
and we'll be on our way.
You'd like us to believe
that, wouldn't you?
Something
tells me these are
spirit charms.
We pin them on you
and God knows what
powers you'll have.
This is no charm.
It's some kind of a machine.
Oh, it doesn't matter.
They won't be telling us
the truth about any of it.
Oh, they'll tell us
the truth, all right.
There's more than one way
to pluck the wings
off a pixie.
We'll induce a trance.
Give me Billy
Ramsey's spoon.
Keep your eyes
on the silverware, Father.
( sighs )
I hope you know
this is blasphemous.
Oh, this is ridiculous.
I can't be hypnotized.
( sighs )
I can't isolate
the Doctor's program.
He's been integrated
into the Fair Haven matrix.
He's vulnerable.
Tell us the words.
How do we banish the spirit folk
to the otherworld?
There is no otherworld.
Only Voyager.
"Voyager"?
Federation Starship,
Intrepid-class,
registry number
NCC-74656.
You're from some sort of vessel?
Mm-hmm.
He's talking gibberish.
Maybe he's not.
This ship of yours--
is that where you took me?
Look here.
It says if you
can get a spirit
to reveal
his true name,
you'll render yourself
impervious to his charms.
What is your true name?
I haven't decided on one yet.
Katie's on that ship,
isn't she?
Tell me where to find
her so I can get to
the bottom of this.
I'm sorry, Michael.
I can't do that.
Then I guess I'm asking
the wrong person.
Tell me how to get
to Voyager.
WOMAN: No, Michael.
What are you doing, Sullivan?
No man who's gone
to the otherworld
has ever come back.
I have.
( crowd murmuring )
How do I get there?
TUVOK:
Captain, the mobile emitter
has been activated.
Lock on to the signal.
( whoosh of
active transport)
I had a cousin, went to America.
He saw some strange things...
but nothing like this.
You're not in America.
This is a starship.
It's called...
Voyager.
I know.
Should I transfer him
back to the holodeck?
No.
My name
isn't Katie O'Clare.
It's Kathryn Janeway.
Captain Kathryn Janeway.
It's going to be difficult
to explain.
Maybe it's best
if I just show you.
You've seen my world.
It seems fair
that I should have
a chance to see yours.
Captain?
So this really
is a starship.
But how can that
be possible?
Have you ever read
The Time Machine
by H. G. Wells?
Are you telling me you've
traveled back through time?
In a manner
of speaking.
That's Patrick Gibson
and his cousin, Frank.
They work on the wharf.
They're in my pub
every Saturday night
for the rings
tournament.
You'll find a lot of
familiar faces on Voyager.
We've been visiting
your town for months.
Why?
We're explorers.
I-I'm not letting you
off the hook that easy,
Kathryn Janeway.
There must be more
interesting places
to explore
than Fair Haven.
Can you think of any
place you'd rather be?
I guess that leaves
but one question.
How long are you
planning on staying?
Well, that depends...
if we're still
welcome.
My door
is always open.
But you're the Captain
of a starship.
I'm a barkeep.
Just because we're
from different worlds
doesn't mean we can't
care for each other.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Go ahead.
The situation has escalated.
The townspeople have started
to pile kindling
at the base of three lampposts
in the village square.
Stand by.
Take them outside now!
( door opening )
Stay back!
What are you doing?
That might not be
Michael Sullivan.
A demon could have
taken his shape!
It's me, Milo.
I've been to the place
they call Voyager,
and I've brought
Katie back with me.
I've come in hopes
that we can resolve
our differences peacefully.
Peacefully?
I'm sure
that's what you told
the people of Kilmanin.
They had nothing to do
with what happened
in Kilmanin,
if it happened at all.
We're truly sorry
for what's happened here.
We never meant
to frighten anyone.
Seamus, you were right
about one thing.
They are quite
different from us.
But not in so many ways
that we can't be friends.
And we're not
spirit folk.
Some of our technology
may seem like magic,
but I assure you it's not.
Katie showed
me things
that are beyond
our comprehension.
They have machines that
I can't begin to describe,
but not once have they
used them against us.
Quite the opposite,
in fact.
Milo, you said you
didn't like the rain.
And young Harry Kim
made it go away.
Edith Mulcahey herself
said that Katie O'Clare
pulled her daughter
from the well and
out of harm's way.
These are not the deeds
of spirits and
mischief-makers.
But they turned Maggie
into a cow!
Uh, that'll never happen again.
I swear.
MICHAEL:
There, you see--
we have his word.
And if we can't trust
a man's word in Fair Haven,
what can we trust?
If you want...
we'll leave
and never bother you again.
But we'd prefer to find some way
to keep our friendship alive.
( device beeps )
Captain?
I, for one, would like
to keep playing rings
with Harry and Tom.
Keep having Neelix's
steamed cabbage
at The Ox and Lamb,
keep taking walks
with Katie.
Let's not turn our backs
on these good people.
If we do,
we're only punishing ourselves.
Just because we're
from different worlds,
doesn't mean we can't
care for each other.
TORRES:
If we're going to
retain the program,
we can't keep running
it around the clock.
Not until we've repaired
these damaged systems.
Not ever!
We've pushed the limits
of holo-technology
and they've pushed back.
If we try it again,
we're just asking
for trouble.
I'm afraid we're
going to have to close
your open door policy.
Yes, ma'am.
What about
the characters?
Should I purge
their memories of
the last few days?
No. Leave them.
They think we're space men
from the future.
It won't exactly
be like old times.
We learn to accept alien species
with new technologies.
Let's hope
the people of Fair Haven
will learn to accept us.
But before we shut down
the program and begin repairs,
what do you say
to one more round at Sullivan's?
My treat.
( laughter )
You may be from the moon,
Tommy-Boy,
but I've got three shillings
that says I can still
whip you at rings.
Ho! You're on.
Hello, Harry.
I'll catch up
with you later.
SEAMUS:
Tommy-Boy!
I've been told there's a pot
of gold somewhere in Glen Abbey.
Would you be able to find it
with one of those fancy
machines of yours?
Just follow
the rainbow, Seamus.
Rainbow, eh?
KIM:
I didn't think you'd ever
speak to me again.
Well, I suppose I can
forgive and forget.
It's not that often
you meet a handsome
young man
from outer space.
( chuckles )
What's this,
Christmas come early?
It has for you.
Open it.
A Connecticut Yankee
in King Arthur's Court
by Mark Twain.
I've read some of his books,
but not this one.
It's about two people
from different times
who fall in love,
among other things.
Sounds familiar.
Maybe I have read it.
( chuckles )
Thank you, Katie.
Or Kathryn now, is it?
Oh!
They say if you know
a spirit's true name,
that it renders
you impervious
against her charms.
Do you think there's
any truth in that?
Not a word.
I'm glad to hear it.