( alarm blaring )
Tam'vitte...
Rel mestal!
Mestal te'iote senve.
Siote ven'suil.
Bekta!
Tam'vitte,
me'iote sendaya Voyager.
Federation Starship Voyager,
if you can hear me,
please respond.
FEMALE:
If you can hear me,
please respond.
Voyager, please respond.
Come on, Voyager.
I know you're there.
Hello?
Voyager?
Are you receiving
this transmission?
My designation is Mezoti.
You sound a little young
to be working the com.
I'm eight.
I see.
Are there any grownups
I could speak to?
My species is 689,
Norcadian.
What species are you?
That's a complicated question.
Explain.
I don't know how long
I can keep this channel open.
I need you to patch me through
to Captain Janeway.
I'll try, but my height
may be insufficient.
( console beeping )
( static )
Hello?
Voyager?
Mezoti, you are
not authorized
to be in here.
Are you going to report me
to the Captain?
Considering this is
your first offense,
a warning will suffice.
What were my
instructions?
To wait in the Cargo Bay
until you returned.
Why didn't
you comply?
You left the children
unsupervised.
Lieutenant Torres
required
my assistance
in Engineering.
I was gone for less
than ten minutes.
ICHEB:
We told her
not to deviate
from your
instructions.
She wouldn't listen.
When the Captain asked you
to take charge
of these children,
you assured her that
you could maintain order.
Controlling them is
proving more difficult
than I anticipated.
They're highly
unpredictable.
Meditation helps
Vulcan children
to control their emotions.
You might consider...
Mezoti!
I'm trying to talk
to the woman.
What woman?
The one transmitting
from Spatial Grid 2369.
She's made contact
with a small ship,
approximately
three light-years from here.
Alien vessel, this is
the Starship Voyager.
Respond.
FEMALE:
Tuvok? That's you, isn't it?
This is Lieutenant
Commander Tuvok.
Sounds like
someone got promoted.
I want to hear all about it,
but first
I need to speak
to Captain Janeway.
You're a sight for sore eyes,
Captain.
You, too, Harry.
I'm sorry, but do we know you?
I'm Ensign Lyndsay Ballard.
I was a member of your crew.
Of course, I'm not surprised
you don't recognize me.
I don't know who you are,
but I'm not amused.
Ensign Ballard died almost...
It was on stardate 51563.
I can't blame you
for being skeptical, Captain.
But if you'd let me come aboard,
I can explain everything.
We'll beam you to Sick Bay.
I'm sure you'll want me
behind a level-10 force field.
No offense.
None taken.
I'm just glad to be home.
Captain?
What do you think?
She seems to have
intimate knowledge
of this ship and its crew.
I think we should
find out who she is.
Captain,
I'd like to come with you.
I was very close
to Lyndsay,
and if somehow it's her...
I'll know.
Harry and I were on our way
to a Class-M planet
in the Vyntadi expanse,
to recover dilithium ore
we'd detected
a few days earlier.
When we landed, we
realized it was a trap
set by a Hirogen
hunting party.
They'd reconfigured
a power cell
to give off false
dilithium readings.
That's exactly what happened.
Go on.
Harry and I headed
back to the shuttle.
We were ten feet away, when I
was hit with a neural disrupter.
Harry said
my injury wasn't that bad.
He always was a terrible liar.
I tried to get Lyndsay back
to Voyager, but...
she was already dead.
We buried her in space.
Go on with your story.
I woke up
on a ship,
in a stasis chamber
surrounded by aliens.
They told me they'd used their
technology to reanimate me.
I didn't believe them
when they said I'd died,
but they showed me visual scans
of my own corpse
lying in the torpedo casing
I'd been buried in.
The Kobali said
I'd been drifting for weeks.
"Kobali"?
If you ever met them,
you'd remember.
They look just like this.
After the reanimation process,
they spent months altering
my DNA.
They were constantly
scanning me, injecting me...
Just to make you look
like one of them?
That's how they procreate.
They salvage the dead
of other races.
I was given a Kobali name
and placed with a family
to help me acclimate.
You were a prisoner.
At first.
I wanted to contact you
to tell you I was safe,
but the Kobali wouldn't let me.
They said you were part
of my kyn'steya...
my...
my past life, and that I
needed to forget you...
all of you.
So I spent two years
letting my new family
think I'd accepted them.
When I finally earned
their trust,
I stole a shuttle and started
looking for Voyager.
That was six months ago.
They've been chasing me
ever since.
In spite
of her appearance,
I'm detecting traces
of human DNA.
I've compared them
with the genetic samples
from Ensign Ballard's file.
They match.
It's certainly
a convincing story.
But your Starfleet training
is telling you
to consider
all the possibilities.
Maybe I'm some sort
of hybrid clone
or a telepath who accessed
Ensign Ballard's memory somehow.
Believe me, I was suspicious
myself at first,
but I am Lyndsay Ballard.
Until we find evidence
to the contrary...
welcome home.
Captain, could you
give us a minute?
Doctor.
So it's really you.
In the flesh...
so to speak.
I've missed you, too.
I know you're all
as eager as I am
to welcome
Ensign Ballard back.
She's a fine officer
who's shown a lot
of courage and determination
over the past few years,
and we're lucky to have
her with us again.
So let's do everything we can
to make her feel at home.
Tom and I have already
taken the liberty
of removing Lyndsay's
personal effects from storage.
And whenever
you're ready,
your old shift
is waiting for you
in Engineering.
Thanks, Lieutenant.
Before we get ahead of
ourselves, let's not forget
the Kobali are still out there.
It seems they want her back
as much as we want to keep her.
We'll need to take precautions
in case they track her
to Voyager.
I've run preliminary scans
on the Kobali shuttle.
I believe I can adapt
our systems to counter
a possible attack.
Very good. Well, if there's
no further business...
Thank you for saying
those nice things about me.
You seem surprised.
To be honest, I never
thought you noticed me.
My mistake.
So, you still playing
the clarinet?
Actually, I've taken up
the saxophone.
Ambitious.
I bet you're
good at it.
You always were
my biggest fan.
Please, no past tense.
Sorry. This is a little
strange for me.
Really?
It's been a perfectly
normal day for me.
Deck 2.
It just so happens
that hearing you
play music again
is #26 on my list.
List?
Something I made up
to pass the time
while I was away.
I tried to think of
everything I would do
if I got
back to Voyager--
including some things
I wasn't able to
accomplish the first
time I was here.
Like showing up
for duty shifts on time?
That's #27.
They're here.
Ah.
Why don't you and I
have a cup of tea while
the children play?
Thank you, but they require
my supervision.
I like your braid.
I could show you
how to do it.
SEVEN:
Mezoti.
Something wrong?
I've allotted one hour
for recreational activity.
There's no time
for irrelevant conversation.
It's not irrelevant.
Adhering to our schedule
will allow us to use our time
more efficiently.
We'll be able
to participate in a wider...
...Wider variety
of activities.
Fun will now commence.
Green.
Grid 313.
Counter. Grid 10.
They're cheating.
How?
Azan is using
his neural interface
to share
information.
Is this true?
You will exercise
Punishment Protocol 9-Alpha.
If they cannot participate,
neither will I.
You are encouraging
disorder.
And you never let us do
what we want.
You will exercise
Punishment Protocol 9-Alpha.
No... I won't.
There you go.
I can't believe
you saved all this.
Tuvok thought I should
recycle everything,
but I just couldn't
bring myself to do it.
My skates and I
thank you
from the bottom
of our hearts.
Do you know how long
it took me to fold those?
( chuckles ):
Same old Harry.
What's that supposed
to mean?
You're still sort
of obsessive.
I'm tidy.
Is that why you used to request
baryon sweeps of your dorm room?
When you live
across the hall
from a slob...
Hey.
Show some respect for the dead.
Did I say something wrong?
It's nothing.
Just because I've been gone
for three years
doesn't mean I can't still
read you like a book.
I gave the eulogy
at your funeral.
Oh?
What'd you say?
Come on.
It's everyone's fantasy
to hear their own eulogy.
Absolutely not.
It's probably
for the best.
You always were
a terrible public speaker.
Just hope you didn't
stutter too much.
( long sigh )
I told them you had
a favorite saying...
something you got
from an old Klingon
battle cry.
"Own the Day."
I said that you
always believed in...
attacking each day...
possessing it...
and that that was what
made you so much fun
to be around.
Is that when everybody
burst into tears?
I said that, if
you'd been there,
you would've told them
to own that day,
to attack it,
make it their own
and plan to do the
same thing tomorrow.
Pretty strong stuff.
You were a strong person.
Not always.
These last six months
haven't been easy.
There were plenty of times
when I could have given up.
But you didn't.
You know why?
You.
I wanted to see you again.
Hmm. Guess I won't be
needing this anymore.
DOCTOR:
Sick Bay to Ensign Ballard.
I've finished analyzing
your bio-scans.
I'm on my way.
My scans identified
a genetic pathogen
in your bloodstream.
It appears to have converted
most of your human DNA
into a Kobali
protein structure.
Is there any way
to reverse it?
The biochemical changes
have affected every system
in your body.
I'm afraid there isn't
enough of your original DNA left
to make you
human again.
But I believe I can effect
some cosmetic changes.
Are you saying
you could make me
look like me again?
Yes. The alternations would
literally be skin-deep,
and it may take
several treatments,
but I've devised
an inaprovaline compound
which should do the trick.
Physiologically,
you'd still be Kobali,
with a multispheric brain,
a binary cardiovascular
system...
But I'd look human.
Oh, yes.
I've lived with this face
for long enough.
Let's do it.
Have a seat.
You may experience
some dizziness.
I'll hang on to
Harry for support,
if he doesn't mind.
That's what
I'm here for.
What?
Something wrong?
See for yourself.
Here we are...
one Jiballian Berry salad.
I have been looking
forward to this
for a very long time.
It was #6 on her list.
There isn't much variety
in the Kobali diet.
We ate the same gray
paste for three years.
It doesn't taste
the way I remember it.
What's wrong? Too sweet?
No offense, but it's got
sort of a metallic flavor.
Seems fine to me.
I guess my taste buds
are still Kobali.
Can I get you something else?
Thanks.
But I need to take
care of #16:
Dazzle Lieutenant Torres.
One minute early.
( sighs ):
There's a first time
for everything.
An alignment error
has been cropping up
in the dilithium matrix.
We can't seem to figure
out what's causing it.
I-I know that you're
still settling in,
so I'll give you
a couple of days to...
It's a vyk'tiote.
Excuse me?
Oh, a Kobali word to describe
a certain kind
of wave phenomenon.
It's hard to translate.
Try me.
Literally, it means
"crumpled dance."
All I need to do is vyq'tal
the qen'dioqe matrices,
stabilize the per'cheya,
tez'tel se nenna...
Cham'bioque!
What?
You were speaking Kobali.
I didn't realize.
I'm sorry.
Well, whatever
you did,
the alignment
error is gone.
Nice job.
Thanks.
I think there might be
a few... "crumpled dances"
in the warp core, too.
Feel like taking a look?
Any sign of the Kobali?
None.
The latest tactical reports
from Tuvok.
Commander...
I no longer wish
to serve as guardian
to the Borg children.
What's the problem?
Their behavior
is chaotic.
My attempts to
apply discipline
only result in
further disorder.
Well, kids and disorder
usually go hand-in-hand.
Neelix issued
a similar warning
prior to my taking
this assignment,
which is why I devised
an activities schedule
to promote focus and unity.
0700 hours, the children
emerge from their alcoves.
Nutrients are ingested
in the Mess Hall
prior to proceeding
to the Science Lab
to begin classes.
At 1300 hours, nutrients
are consumed a second time
before reporting
to the holodeck,
where they're studying
comparative alien physiology.
Doesn't sound like
there's much time for fun.
On the contrary.
I've scheduled
recreational activities.
You can't always
schedule fun, Seven.
Sometimes it needs
to be spontaneous.
According to my research,
children require structure.
I agree,
but not to this extreme.
You're treating them like
they're still on a Borg cube.
You're comparing me
to the collective?
You have all four children
functioning as one.
They do the same things together
at the same time.
So that each child has
the same opportunities to learn.
They're individuals.
Maybe they're rebelling
because you don't let them
express themselves.
Then grant my request.
Choose a more suitable
crew member to instruct them.
Sorry, Seven.
Permission denied.
Well, I see
you're finally
going to try
my hockey program.
Actually, I'm taking
Lyndsay skating.
Oh. Mm. You two sure
have been spending
a lot of time
together lately.
Don't start.
Oh, now, let's see...
for those of us
keeping score,
Harry Kim has fallen
for a hologram,
a Borg, the wrong twin,
and now, the
dearly departed.
We're friends.
Ah.
Just like before.
Uh, all right,
maybe there was a time
when I thought
of pursuing Lyndsay,
but I closed
the door on that
when we both got assigned
to Voyager.
Mm. Don't look now,
but that door
is creaking open.
( sighs )
What do you think?
Uh... you look great.
Doctor thought I should stick
to my original color,
but this seemed more exciting.
Hair is one of
my specialties,
despite evidence
to the contrary.
It's just too bad
that beneath this
beautiful red hair
still lies the six-lobed
brain of a Kobali.
Well, are you feeling human
enough for a little skating?
I'd love to, but I
already have a date.
Who with?
The Captain.
She's invited me
to her quarters for dinner.
In six years, I have
never been invited
to the Captain's
quarters for dinner.
Well, I'll give her
your regards.
Oh, damn!
( door chimes )
Come in.
Formal dress
wasn't required, Ensign.
Well, I just... I figured
dinner with the Captain...
I'd hardly call this dinner.
My replicator decided
to liquefy the pot roast.
It looks fine to me.
Stop trying
to get on my good side
and grab a slice of bread.
Peanut butter
and jelly sandwiches.
I hope you don't mind.
Not at all.
I lived on them
at the Academy.
So, how was your first day
back on the job?
Pretty good, I think.
Lieutenant Torres called
my work "competent."
Trust me, that's high praise
coming from B'Elanna.
Commander Tuvok finished
his analysis of your shuttle
and presented me
with 37 different ways
of repelling a Kobali attack.
Did he include
your pot roast?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean...
I can't believe
I just said that.
Why? It was funny.
We're not on the Bridge,
Lyndsay.
You have permission
to speak freely.
Do you really mean that?
I wouldn't
have said it otherwise.
Then... there's something
I've wanted to ask you
for a long time.
Why me?
I'm sorry?
Why did you choose me
for that away mission?
Well, I suppose I thought you
were best suited for the job.
No, I wasn't.
Dilithium extraction was always
Lieutenant Torres' specialty.
And Tuvok had
far more experience
conducting away missions,
but you didn't send
either one of them.
Was it because
they were closer to you?
You blame me.
No. No, that's not what I meant.
It's okay, Lyndsay.
No, it's not.
I'm not offended.
No, you don't understand.
"Never harbor anger toward those
who brought you death,
for they gave you the chance
to live again."
In letting me
die, Captain,
you gave me life.
I'm sorry.
Lyndsay...
I shouldn't have come.
You're late.
We expected you hours ago.
For what?
Your farewell party.
You weren't supposed
to come back.
You don't belong
here anymore.
Harry, what's going on?
"Lyndsay Ballard,
beloved friend
and crewman"--
does that sound right?
What?
For your eulogy...
does that
sound okay?
Harry, I'm not dead.
Denial: one of
the final stages.
It was illogical for you
to return.
Please, I don't want to go.
I couldn't save
you before, Lyndsay.
What makes you think
I can save you now?
Jen'to ka'siote...
Jhet'leya.
( door chiming )
Come in.
What's wrong?
Bad day, I guess.
B'Elanna told me
you did great in Engineering.
I solved
a simple problem.
Didn't sound
so simple to me.
Any Kobali can discern
simple wave distortions.
Even if B'Elanna
was impressed,
the others were
staring at me.
I'm sure it was
just your imagination.
And then, to make
matters worse,
I started babbling
in front of the Captain.
Oh. I used to get pretty
nervous around her, too.
Yeah, don't worry.
I'm sure she didn't
take it personally.
Hey...
I know this isn't easy...
but I'll help you
through this.
You have always been
far too nice to me.
Why is that?
You really don't have
any idea, do you?
Think about it.
I rearranged my schedule
at the Academy
just so we'd be
in the same classes.
I let you teach me how to skate,
even though I hate the cold.
I'm crazy about you.
I have been
since the day we met.
Why didn't
you ever tell me?
I was never good
at public speaking, remember?
But I figure
how often do you get
a second chance.
Which is why I'd very much
like to kiss you now.
"Own the Day."
Sorry.
You are creating disorder.
Seven will be angry.
I don't care.
They're cubes.
I can see that.
Precisely 1/1,000 the
size of a Borg vessel.
Well done.
A 26-sided polyhedron,
composed of hexagons,
octagons and squares.
Impressive.
What's this?
Can't you tell?
It's you.
I don't see the resemblance.
Look. Here's your
ocular implant,
your nose,
your mouth...
You were instructed to create
a geometric shape.
I reminded
her of that.
She wouldn't comply.
This was more fun.
Don't you like it?
It is crude.
However, it does demonstrate
ingenuity and individuality.
She deviated
from your instructions.
Aren't you going to implement
a punishment protocol?
No.
Resume your disorder.
Lyndsay?
They're coming.
Red Alert.
Raise shields.
We are being hailed.
On screen.
I've come for Jhet'leya.
If you're referring
to Ensign Ballard,
she's made it clear that she
doesn't want to go with you.
She's my daughter.
Please... I've come a long way.
I only want to speak with her.
You don't have
to see him, you know.
They can't make you.
I want to, Harry.
It's time
to stop running.
I appreciate this, Captain.
I'm willing
to oblige
as long as
you understand
that this
meeting is over
as soon as Ensign
Ballard says it is.
What have they
done to you?
Given me my life back.
You were so beautiful.
It's good to see
you, Jhet'leya.
My name is Lyndsay.
Why did you leave us?
I wanted to be
with my people again.
These people?
The same ones who set you
adrift in space?
We jettisoned her body
in accordance with our customs.
You abandoned her.
You had no right to
tamper with her remains.
We were acting in accordance
with our customs.
You mutilated her.
Ensign...
The reanimation
process
usually results in
extensive memory loss,
which makes the
transition less painful.
Unfortunately,
some remember
their former lives
more than others.
Jhet'leya, for example.
I told you to call me...
Lyndsay Ballard.
She's dead.
She has been
for three years.
Forgive me for being so blunt,
but when we found her,
she was a lifeless corpse.
We salvaged that raw material
to create a new person--
my daughter-- whom I love.
I'm not your daughter.
You may have altered
your appearance,
but do you still think
like these people?
Even now, the first words
that come into your head,
are they in their language
or mine?
I realize this place
is familiar to you,
but it's not where you belong.
Your sister misses you.
Tynsia.
She keeps asking
when you're coming home.
What should I tell her?
Tell her that her sister's dead.
I'll escort you
to the transporter room.
I won't give her up, Captain.
She made her wishes clear.
She's confused.
Thanks to what
you did to her.
I don't want to fight you.
Your ship is no match
for Voyager.
Every life is precious
to my people, Captain.
I won't be coming back alone.
Midnight snack?
Kobali cuisine
at its finest.
So I was giving
some thought to #32--
"Make Tuvok laugh."
He has this holo-program,
"The Temple of T'Panit."
I thought we might tweak it,
so that instead
of Vulcan prayers,
the monks recite
Ferengi limericks.
You're not laughing.
Sorry.
I can't stop thinking
about Q'ret.
I can't believe he had the nerve
to call himself your father.
I'll bet Professor Ballard
would have had something
to say about that.
Who?
Your... dad.
Doesn't he teach
at some university?
I don't remember.
I don't remember
anything about him.
Let's get down to the holodeck.
We've got some monks to tweak.
Sure.
( gasps )
What's wrong?
Why did she start to
revert all of a sudden?
Our old friend,
the pathogen.
It's adapting
to counteract my treatments.
It's possible she'll suffer
occasional relapses
for the rest of her life.
You said you could
maintain my appearance.
I can, but it looks like
I'll need to increase
the frequency
of your treatments.
You'll have to see me
at least twice a day.
How am I supposed to do my job
if I'm in here all the time?
How am I supposed
to do anything?
Please try to underst...
Stoi'gia!
Net'staika
pen'daeli shevaob!
I'm sorry.
( hatch opens, closes )
Wow.
This place sure is lived-in.
If you're here to lecture
me about cleanliness...
I'm here to ask you
to stop the treatments.
You know what
happens if I do.
You'll look Kobali again?
So what?
I thought you were cute bald.
I don't care if you're human,
Kobali or Bolian.
I just want you to be happy.
I wouldn't fit in.
Are you saying Tuvok
and Neelix don't fit in?
That's different.
They got to grow up
in their own cultures.
They know where they
come from, who they are.
Wherever they come from,
they're part of this crew now,
just like you.
Lyndsay was part
of this crew.
If I stop the treatments,
I won't be Lyndsay anymore.
( sighs ):
You don't honestly believe that.
Since the day I got back here,
I haven't felt right.
First I thought
it was Voyager.
Things had changed so much,
I thought if I just
gave myself more time
I'd get used to it.
But it's me.
I've changed.
And the more I try to deny it,
the more I feel like a ghost.
I'm sorry, Harry...
but I can't
keep fighting anymore.
What about us?
The girl you were in love with
died three years ago.
Shields down to 48 percent.
Target the lead ship's
weapons array.
Life support's
failing on Decks
6 through 10.
Reroute power
to compensate.
Shields at 20 percent.
Hail them. Tell them
you'll surrender me.
Don't listen to her, Captain.
I appreciate
the gesture, Lyndsay,
but I'm not giving you up.
It's not a gesture.
I want to go.
I don't belong here.
She's not well.
She doesn't know
what she's saying.
I know exactly what I'm saying.
Shields at 13 percent.
I'm detecting power fluctuations
in the lead vessel's warp drive.
A polaron burst
could overload the core.
That would destroy
the ship.
They're not leaving
us much choice.
Whatever we do,
we have to do it fast.
You're sure
this is what you want.
Captain,
I can fire that
polaron burst myself.
Stand down, Ensign.
We can't just let
them take her!
Even if you stop them,
I can't stay
on Voyager.
I don't want to lose you.
You already did, but
at least this time,
we've been given the
chance to say good-bye.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 53679.4.
The Doctor has stopped
Ensign Ballard's treatments,
and her Kobali physiology
is already beginning
to reassert itself.
All but one of us
have said our good-byes.
Vien'ke debala,
Jhet'leya.
I taught myself
to say a few words in Kobali.
That's very sweet of you,
but you just told me
the comets are tiresome.
Guess I better work
on my pronunciation.
I'm sorry
you didn't get to finish
everything on your list.
I think I took care of
what really mattered.
That's pretty.
It belonged
to a friend of mine.
Would you like it?
Your friend wouldn't mind?
I think she'd be happy
knowing I gave it to someone
with such pretty hair.
Seven's letting us go
to the holodeck by ourselves.
She says we can run
any program we want.
Do you want to come?
Have you ever heard
of "The Temple of T'Panit"?
It's a Vulcan program.
Sounds boring.
Don't worry.
We'll make a few tweaks.