JANEWAY:
Why potatoes?
SEVEN:
Their first idea
was to clone Naomi,
but I suggested they start
with something smaller.
Quite a feat of engineering.
It's a Teirenian ant colony.
I infused the soil
with a blue ion dye,
so it'd be easier
to see the insects.
They're luminescent.
The drones produce
a fluorescent enzyme
that's activated
by the queen.
Drones and queens?
I thought we were trying
to get these children away
from the Borg.
The project
was Mezoti's idea.
I didn't want to discourage
her individuality.
I like bugs.
Well done.
Let me know before
you take up beekeeping.
What have we got here?
It's Kataris.
Your father's planet.
I've been learning all about it.
Naomi programmed the geophysical
and atmospheric conditions.
There's quite a storm
in those mountains.
The Arpasian range is known
for high winds and hail.
I'll remember to bring my coat.
Now, this looks
impressive.
It's a high-resolution
gravimetric sensor array.
Ambitious.
It'll augment
our ability to scan
for the neutrino flux
associated with wormholes.
It could help Voyager
find a faster way home.
The engineering principles
are sound.
I expected these projects
to be interesting,
but this is truly exceptional.
Thank you, Captain.
I am very interested
in astrophysics.
Well, you've obviously got
a knack for it.
Well done.
How did you think of scanning
for neutrino fluctuations?
I've been studying
Starfleet records.
He's a remarkable young man.
He hopes to earn
a permanent posting
in Astrometrics one day.
I'm afraid that
won't be possible.
Captain, the boy has
a unique talent.
It's not a question
of merit.
We've made contact
with his parents,
and I've set a course
for their planet.
( Icheb speaking
indistinctly)
My scanner is calibrated
to pick up changes
in neutrino
trajectories.
That's good news.
You've exceeded your scheduled
time here by one hour.
I am almost finished.
Your work
will have to wait.
There's something
we need to discuss.
Look at this.
( sighs )
It's a star forming
in the Orpisay nebula.
The Orpisay nebula
is out of range
of our sensors.
I increased the resolution
of the long-range scanners.
Impressive.
When I was on the cube,
I never thought
about what was outside--
pulsars,
quasars,
nebulas--
but here in this lab,
I feel like I can see
the entire galaxy.
What did you want
to talk to me about?
You said there
was something
we needed to discuss.
Yes. That's correct.
It's time for you
to regenerate.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'd like the data
you've collected
on Icheb's species
so I can prepare him
for reassimilation.
Maybe we could refer to it
as "getting reacquainted
with his family."
If you prefer.
I'll transfer the files
to Astrometrics.
Thank you.
How'd he take
the news?
You haven't told him.
No.
Why not?
It won't be easy for him
to accept.
He's adapted to life
on Voyager.
And you've adapted
to having him here.
My feelings are irrelevant.
Are they?
Would you like me
to tell him?
It's my responsibility...
but I am uncertain
how to proceed.
Well, you've already
helped him make
one difficult transition.
How did you do that?
By giving him the benefit
of my own experiences,
encouraging him to be resilient
in the face of obstacles.
Sounds like a good strategy.
Is your alcove
malfunctioning?
I'm calculating
neutrino trajectories.
You need to regenerate.
Very well.
Wait.
We've located your parents.
Voyager is due
to arrive at their
planet tomorrow.
Do I have to stay with them?
They're your parents.
I don't remember them.
After my parents
were assimilated,
I never saw them again.
You're fortunate
to have this chance.
What about the others?
We haven't been able
to locate their
families yet.
That's not what I mean.
What will happen to them
if I leave?
They depend on me.
They'll adapt.
I'll never see you again?
I've been studying
Brunali culture.
It's very different
from what you've
become accustomed to
on Voyager.
In what way?
They're an
agrarian society.
Their technological
resources are limited.
Are they capable
of space travel?
Yes, but most
of their vessels
were destroyed
by the Borg.
How will I continue my studies?
I don't know.
Icheb...
I'm detecting
scattered enclaves
on the northern
continent--
all with populations
of fewer than 10,000.
Judging from the residual
gamma radiation,
it appears they've suffered
numerous Borg attacks
over the past decade.
That's not surprising.
There's a Borg transwarp conduit
less than a light-year away.
Not exactly prime real estate.
Tuvok, run continuous scans
for Borg activity.
Tom, put us into
synchronous orbit.
Yes, ma'am.
Seven, you'd better get Icheb.
According to these scans,
you're in perfect health.
Then why does my stomach
feel so strange?
Hmm.
Oh, I should have known.
You've got butterflies
in there.
I never assimilated
butterflies.
It's an expression used
to describe anxiety
or apprehension,
both of which are
perfectly natural reactions
for someone about to meet
his long-lost parents.
If it's any comfort,
I'm sure they're just
as nervous about meeting you.
Parents are irrelevant.
Really?
Do you think Naomi's mother
is irrelevant to her?
I have Seven of Nine to
assist me in my education.
I have you to care
for my medical needs.
Your parents can nurture you
in ways this crew can't.
They can explain
the Brunali culture,
share their experiences
with you.
You didn't have parents.
No, but...
You adapted to serve
a vital function
aboard this vessel,
forged relationships
with its crew--
all without the
benefit of parents.
I had my programming
to fall back on.
And how would your
programming respond
if you were asked to
live with strangers?
Are you damaged?
He's fine.
I was just giving him
a last-minute checkup.
It's time.
The "butterflies" will go away.
JANEWAY:
Hello.
I'm Captain Janeway.
Icheb.
You've... grown.
He spent several months
in a Borg maturation chamber.
This is Seven of Nine.
That's a Borg designation,
isn't it?
Like your son, I was liberated
from the collective.
Seven has been instrumental
in helping Icheb
make his transition.
Then we're very
grateful to you.
I'm Leucon,
Icheb's father.
This is his
mother, Yifay.
How are you?
Fine.
Do these hurt you?
No.
We're very happy to
have you back with us.
Mala, Remi,
Yivel.
Welcome home, Icheb.
I would like
to return to
Voyager now.
Thank you for coming.
Where's Icheb?
I thought it might be
better if we talked
ourselves first.
What exactly is
there to discuss?
How to make this transition
easier for your son.
Please, sit down.
It won't be easy for him
to give up the luxuries
of your ship.
It's more than a
question of luxuries.
Icheb has special medical needs.
We have a physician
in our settlement.
We should arrange for him
to consult with our Doctor.
He also requires
daily regeneration.
I'm sure you can adapt
some of our technology
to make that possible.
What about his
educational needs?
Our children go to school.
Will he be able to continue
his studies in astrometrics
and spatial harmonics?
If Icheb has an
aptitude for science,
I'm sure he'll find that
we have a great deal
to teach him.
For example?
We've developed
sophisticated techniques
in agricultural genetics,
which allow us to grow crops
in an inhospitable environment.
Icheb has expressed no interest
in agriculture.
I'm sure, once he's been exposed
to the subject,
he'll find it quite challenging.
There's still the issue
of his safety.
We're perfectly capable
of protecting our son.
Your proximity to a Borg conduit
makes you extremely vulnerable.
I'm curious if you've
ever considered relocating.
Seven.
LEUCON: No.
It's all right, Captain.
This planet is our home.
We will never leave it.
We will defend it
against the Borg,
or anyone else who threatens us.
Your courage is admirable
but unrealistic.
Wait for me
in my ready room.
Captain...
Now.
I apologize
for her behavior.
She and Icheb have
grown very close,
but that's no excuse
for rudeness.
We'd like to see
our son now.
Please be patient.
If we rush things,
your next encounter with him
may not go any better
than the last.
Stay aboard Voyager
for a while.
It'll give Icheb a chance
to get to know you
in an environment
that's familiar to him.
I'll have Neelix
do everything he can
to make you comfortable
while you're here.
Your attitude is making
a difficult situation worse.
I was simply
attempting to ensure
Icheb's well-being.
By insulting his parents?
Those issues needed
to be discussed.
You could've done it
with a little more tact.
Perhaps. But that
doesn't alter the fact
that those individuals may
not be suitable guardians.
Those individuals are
his mother and father.
Which is no guarantee
that they'll be able
to care for him.
He's far more
likely to flourish
if he remains
on Voyager.
That's not an option, Seven.
Are you ordering him
off the ship...
That's not what I said.
...so that he can be
assimilated again?
What makes you so sure
that's going to happen?
They shouldn't remain
on that planet.
It's their home.
It's not worth protecting.
Who are you to decide that?
Anyone who values
their own goals
over the safety of their
children is irresponsible.
Are we talking
about Icheb's parents or yours?
Both.
It's not like you to admit
to something like that.
It would be naive for me to
claim objectivity in this case,
but I'm not prepared
to return Icheb to parents
who may be as careless
as my own.
I know what it's like
to feel protective
towards someone you've helped
through a difficult period.
But Icheb is
an individual now.
You have to give
him a chance
to form
his own opinions.
If I do...
and he decides to
remain on Voyager...
Then it'll be my problem.
Is your mother pretty?
What are
they like?
I'm busy.
I never met my father.
I don't
remember ours.
Neither do I.
Are you going to stay
with them?
If you leave,
who is going to help us
with our science projects?
If you don't stop
asking questions,
I'm going to put all of you
in a cargo container
and transport you back
to the Borg.
Come with me.
Where?
To dinner
with your parents.
I'm working.
You can continue
your work after the meal.
I don't have anything
to talk about with them.
Then it will be
a very quiet evening.
I'm not going.
Your attendance is not optional.
Enjoy your meal.
Come, sit down.
I prefer to stand.
Mr. Neelix let me
use his galley
to prepare some poma.
I'm not hungry.
It was your favorite food
when you were little.
I'm not little anymore.
No.
No, you're not.
Your mother worked hard
on that meal.
Couldn't you at least try it?
Good.
Isn't it?
Nice to see the family
back together again,
isn't it?
When you were little,
you would only eat...
The Borg didn't leave us
much to work with,
but we didn't need much,
just a little ingenuity.
Everything you see,
we built with our own hands--
our homes,
cultivation bays...
What's this?
A genetic resequencer.
We use it to alter the
DNA of certain plants
to conform with
environmental conditions.
You built this as well.
We adapted parts
from damaged vessels.
Nothing's been wasted.
Efficient.
Efficiency's one attribute
we share with the Borg.
In our case,
it's a necessity.
I know our settlement
seems primitive...
compared to Voyager,
but I promise you,
that will change.
What about space travel?
Someday...
we'll have ships
that rival Voyager,
but we need the dedication
of young people like you
to help us.
Icheb!
How are you?
Well! Thank you!
Maybe later you can join us
up on the field
for a game of pala!
I don't remember
how to play!
( chuckles ):
It will come back to you!
You used to be
quite an athlete.
You can make
a difference here, Icheb.
I don't know anything
about agriculture...
or genetics.
It won't take you long to learn,
not with a mind like yours.
It's time to return
to Voyager.
I am staying here tonight.
They don't have
a regeneration unit.
We're going to have
to install one eventually.
Might as well do it now.
As far as I'm aware,
he hasn't decided
to remain here yet.
But he has asked to stay
tonight.
Return with me to the ship.
We'll prepare
a regeneration unit.
I've adapted
this neural transceiver
to interface
with the portable regenerator.
It has enough power
to complete one full cycle.
We'll have to devise
a way of recharging it.
If Icheb decides to stay.
My wife and I appreciate
everything you've
done for our son.
It's obvious you
care about him.
He's a unique individual.
Yes, he is.
To get him back is... well...
a miracle.
How was he taken?
Since the Borg
first attacked us,
we've taken great pains
to hide whatever new technology
we develop.
So that passing cubes won't be
attracted to your planet.
Unfortunately, we haven't
always been successful.
One morning, about
four years ago...
Icheb heard me talking
about a new
fertilization array
we'd constructed
in the lower field.
He wanted to see it.
I told him I'd take
him the next day.
( sighs )
But he was impatient,
the way boys can be.
I never even realized
he'd wandered off
when the alarm
sounded.
It turns out the Borg
were just as interested
in our new technology
as Icheb was.
They took him...
assimilated everyone
in the area.
Oh. If only I'd kept
a closer eye on him.
Icheb has a mind of his own.
But still...
it's hard not to blame myself.
Your parents must've felt
the same way when they lost you.
My parents were with me
when the Borg attacked.
I can't imagine what that
must've been like for them,
watching their daughter
being assimilated...
helpless to
defend her?
It's important
that Icheb regenerate
for six uninterrupted hours.
I understand.
He may resist.
He doesn't like to waste time.
I have had to contend with
his lack of patience as well.
LEUCON:
Over there is a star
called Kelsin III,
and to the west is
the Orlitus Cluster.
There, just above it,
when you connect
those six stars,
they form what we call
the Great Horn.
I see it.
You inherited your
love of the stars
from your father.
Being on that starship,
you learned much more
about astronomy than I have.
Our little window
can't compare
to Voyager's
Astrometrics Lab.
No.
But it's nice.
You see?
We have everything
we need right here--
a warm fire, good food
that we grow ourselves,
and people who love us.
Icheb has people on Voyager
who love him, too.
You've grown attached
to the crew on that ship,
haven't you?
They've provided for me,
given me opportunities.
LEUCON:
They're good people--
people who've experienced
hardship themselves.
Seven of Nine told me
about your science project.
She said it might prove
very useful.
It's designed
to detect wormholes.
How will that benefit them?
It may help them find
a way back to Earth.
Why is that so important
to them?
It's their home.
Interesting, isn't it?
What?
With all their technology,
their opportunity
to explore the galaxy,
the thing they want most
is to get home.
Good morning.
Did you regenerate
successfully?
Yes, and I slept...
under the stars.
You should try it.
You weren't in
class this morning.
The others missed you.
I was helping my father.
There is something
we need to discuss.
What is it?
You've decided
to stay with them.
Yes.
You're certain?
This is my home.
I have a responsibility
to help them rebuild it.
I'll inform the Captain.
Thank you.
I'm sure you'll
want to say good-bye
to the other children.
Inside, you'll find pads
containing data on
a variety of subjects
that will allow you to
continue your studies.
I've also included a
high-resolution telescope.
It's a poor substitute
for astrometric sensors.
I will use it every day.
Good-bye, Icheb, and good luck.
Thank you, Captain.
I hope you find a way home.
( sighs )
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Regeneration cycle incomplete.
What is it?
I can't regenerate.
Warning.
Explain.
Regeneration cycle incomplete.
I miss Icheb.
So do I...
but we'll adapt.
Now return to your alcove.
If you find my parents,
will I have to go with them?
We'll discuss that
when and if the time comes.
I hope you don't find them.
Regenerate.
Seven?
Yes?
What if the Borg try to
assimilate Icheb again?
His people lack resources.
The Borg have little reason
to return to their planet.
What if Icheb's on a ship?
Unlikely.
He was on a ship last time.
You're mistaken.
He was on the surface
when he was assimilated.
No. He wasn't.
A class-1 transport
was detected
in Grid 649...
one life-form...
species: Brunali.
This better
be important.
It is.
Sorry, I don't read Borg.
You'll have to translate.
This is tactical data
from the cube where we
found the children.
It says that Icheb was alone
aboard an unarmed
transport vessel
when the Borg took him.
Oh, why are you
telling me this
at 0300 hours?
Icheb's father told me
the boy was assimilated
on the planet's surface.
Is it possible
you misunderstood?
No. He was very specific.
That cube was disabled
by a deadly pathogen.
It suffered extensive damage.
Isn't it possible
these records were corrupted?
Perhaps, but I found
another inconsistency
in Leucon's story.
He told me Icheb was assimilated
four years ago,
but further analysis indicates
the Borg attacked three times
during the last decade--
nine years ago,
six years ago
and again last year.
All right.
Let's assume your information
is accurate.
What does it prove?
His father was lying.
Why would he do that?
I'm not certain, but
we have an obligation
to find out.
What are you proposing?
That we return
to the planet,
demand an explanation.
( sighs ):
Those people
have been through enough.
Do we really need
to interrogate them?
We have a
responsibility
to ensure
Icheb's safety.
He chose to stay
with his parents.
Maybe he didn't have
all the information.
Just because they weren't
completely candid with you
doesn't mean
they're unfit parents.
At some point...
you have to let go.
I know what you're thinking--
that I'm having
emotional difficulty
accepting my separation
from Icheb.
And you're correct,
but if there's a possibility
he's in danger,
even a remote one,
I have to do whatever I can
to protect him.
If I don't, I'll be no better
than my own parents.
Couldn't we at least
wait a few days?
What would that accomplish?
He's just
getting settled.
The longer we wait,
the harder it'll be
for everyone.
You know that.
Why do it at all?
There's nothing compelling us
to go through with it.
It's what he was born for.
Hasn't he been through enough?
Why not give him a chance
at an ordinary life?
He's not an ordinary child.
No, but he can help us
in other ways.
He's bright.
He-he's hardworking...
Leucon...
his return was a gift.
We can't waste it.
I don't want to lose him
a second time.
To survive, we all have
to make sacrifices.
You taught me that.
We won three
games in a row.
Sit down, Icheb.
We need to talk.
You know that
you're very important to us.
Yes.
What you don't know is why.
What do you mean?
What is that?
If you relax, it won't hurt you.
Father...
You'd better hold him.
( grunts ):
What are you doing to me?
No!
Prepare the launch.
Hail them.
We didn't expect
to see you again, Captain.
We'd like to ask you
a few questions,
if you don't mind.
Questions?
Regarding Icheb
and the circumstances
of his assimilation.
We've already
discussed that.
The story you told me
was inconsistent with our data.
We don't owe you
any explanations.
In that case,
I'd like to talk to Icheb.
LEUCON:
He's not here.
Where is he?
That's not
your concern.
Scan for his bio-signs.
He is not in the settlement.
I'm detecting
a Brunali transport vessel.
Distance:
nine million kilometers.
It's heading for the coordinates
of the transwarp conduit.
CHAKOTAY:
According to these readings,
that ship is traveling
at warp 9.8.
It only looks that way.
It's been designed to emit
a false warp signature--
strong enough to
penetrate subspace.
They're using it as bait
to attract the Borg.
Icheb's on that vessel,
isn't he?
He's fighting
for his people.
Alone, on an unarmed transport.
We don't have
particle weapons
or powerful starships
at our disposal.
We're forced to use
the only resource we have.
Your children?
YIFAY:
No.
Our genetic expertise.
Icheb's not bait.
He's a weapon.
The first cube that captured him
was infected
by a pathogen.
Icheb was the carrier,
wasn't he?
Every time we try to rebuild,
begin to make progress,
the Borg come
and take it away from us.
Tom, set a course
for that transport vessel,
full impulse.
PARIS:
Aye, Captain.
LEUCON:
You have no right to interfere.
We're trying to save
our civilization.
By taking away Icheb's future.
If we don't
stop the Borg,
the Brunali
have no future.
LEUCON:
Captain, a Borg ship
will emerge from that conduit
at any moment.
You'll be destroyed.
We'll take our chances.
End transmission.
Red Alert. Battle stations.
PARIS:
We're coming within range,
Captain.
KIM: I'm picking up
Icheb's life-signs.
Bio-scans indicate
he's unconscious.
Transport him
to Sick Bay.
I can't. There's some kind
of interference.
By my estimate,
It's the conduit.
a Borg vessel will emerge
in less than 40 seconds.
Transfer auxiliary power
to the transporters.
I still can't establish a lock,
not at this distance.
30 seconds.
Tom, get us closer
to that ship.
Yes, ma'am.
The conduit's opening.
20 seconds.
Seven?
Still out of range.
You heard her, Tom.
When that Borg ship
comes through,
I'm going to have a hell
of a time getting away from it.
One problem at a time.
TUVOK:
Ten seconds...
nine... eight...
I've got a lock.
Transport in progress.
...five... four...
He's in Sick Bay.
Get us out of here, maximum...
Target their tractor beam
generator.
Phasers targeted.
Fire.
No effect.
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
Perhaps not.
There is a way to get a weapon
through their shields.
I'm listening.
Transport a photon torpedo
to the Brunali vessel.
Set it to detonate as soon
as it's inside the sphere.
TUVOK:
That will occur
in approximately 20 seconds.
However, Voyager will be
inside less than
three seconds later.
Tom, full reverse thrusters.
It might buy us
a couple more seconds.
Do it.
Transport complete.
Detonation in
ten, nine...
...five... four...
Tom, go to warp on my mark.
Three, two...
All hands, brace for impact.
Now, Mr. Paris!
The Borg vessel has taken
heavy damage.
They are not pursuing.
( sighs )
Are you saying
his parents reinfected him?
No. They merely
sedated him.
I don't understand.
He was genetically
engineered
to produce the
pathogen... from birth.
Bred to kill Borg.
Is he in danger?
I can suppress
the pathogen.
He'll be fine...
physically.
He's going to need help
coming to terms with
what's happened.
Captain, I...
Use your maternal
instincts.
They worked before.
I thought you
were studying
spatial harmonics.
My parents suggested
I might have an aptitude
for genetics as well.
I see.
What have you learned?
This is the genome
of a typical Brunali male...
and this is my DNA.
They're nearly identical,
but do you notice
the differences
in the third, 13th
and 17th chromosomes?
Yes.
My parents made
microgenetic alterations
so I would produce
the pathogen.
Quite ingenious.
It's also barbaric.
They were trying
to defend themselves...
their way of life...
preserve their species.
I know how
difficult it is
to acknowledge
your parents' faults,
but what they did
was wrong.
You don't have
to forgive them.
Do you think
they will ever forgive me?
For what?
I could have destroyed
that sphere.
I failed them.
You would have been
reassimilated.
I know, but...
But what?
Maybe it was my destiny.
Maybe.
In the future, you may choose
to fight the Borg,
but you'll do it
in your own way.
You're an individual,
and you have the right
to determine your own destiny.
It's time to regenerate.
And if I prefer
to continue studying?
It's your decision.