You're late.
There was a problem
with the pulse drills
on level four.
They're going to be
here any moment.
I want to make
a good impression.
You're certain
we should be doing this?
Orek will be pleased that
we took the initiative.
I hope you're right.
Welcome to Telsius.
Thank you.
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway.
This is Commander Tuvok.
We're from the Federation
Starship Voyager.
"JANEWAY":
We have several mines
like this on Earth.
MINER:
I'm not familiar
with Earth.
That's because it's 30,000
light years from here.
30,342.4,
to be exact.
You're a long
way from home.
It's difficult sometimes.
Then I close my eyes
and think
of the farm in Indiana
where I grew up.
For a moment,
I'm home again.
Should we get down
to business?
Yes. We've had
a shortage of dilithium
for the last two months.
If we can't
replenish our supply,
we may be forced
to suspend work.
Our chief of mining
operations has gone
to the Grenna system...
But, um,
we are authorized
to conduct trades
in his absence.
What are you
prepared to trade?
I'm afraid
the only commodity
we have is,
uh, bolomite.
We really don't have
much use for that.
On the contrary,
Captain.
Bolomite is used in
omega radiation therapy.
The orphans on...
Orphans?
The settlers
on the Narva Colony
were exposed to toxic
levels of omega radiation.
The entire adult
population was killed.
We're doing all we can
for the children.
All right.
20 kilotons of dilithium
for an equivalent amount
of bolomite.
We only have ten kilotons left.
Then ten it is.
Captain,
I must point out
that dilithium is worth
nearly twice as much
as bolomite.
Tuvok, these people
need our help.
I'm not going to quibble
over a few tons of ore.
Perhaps we should celebrate.
I wish we could, but there's
a neutronic storm
approaching our ship.
We should be
leaving orbit.
Give us an hour to
finalize the arrangements.
We'll be waiting
to hear from you.
Before we leave,
would it be possible
to tour your facility?
It's our duty
as Starfleet officers to...
Unfortunately,
the storm won't wait.
Maybe on our next visit.
Live long and prosper.
This hair
is so uncomfortable.
I find it
aesthetically pleasing.
The negotiations?
It would've been perfect
if "Tuvok" hadn't decided
to improvise.
I was portraying my character
as truthfully as possible.
Once we finish a
transaction, we leave.
Is that clear?
Indeed.
Incoming transmission
for Captain Janeway.
Ready.
This is Captain Janeway.
The bolomite is
ready for transport.
We thank you for
your generosity.
Directive 927
of the Starfleet
General Order:
"Always help
those in need."
Transport complete.
We've enjoyed
meeting you, gentlemen.
Uh, Captain, uh, we haven't
received the dilithium yet.
Oh, the neutronic storm
seems to be interfering
with our transporters.
If we don't
leave orbit immediately,
we will sustain heavy damage.
What about
our dilithium?
We'll be back
to deliver it as soon
as the storm clears.
Well, how long
will that be?
Captain Janeway out.
Let's go.
( laughing )
Computer, activate
the sonic shower.
( humming )
( humming gets louder )
Oh...
adjust the frequency.
( loud humming continues )
Whew! Computer, deactivate
the sonic shower!
Report.
We've got systems failures
on eight decks, Captain.
That explains why
my sonic shower
was a little
louder than usual.
Make that nine decks.
I've run every
diagnostic I know,
and I can't seem to
isolate the problem.
Gremlins.
Excuse me?
In the early days
of aviation, engineers blamed
imaginary little creatures
called gremlins
for malfunctions
they could not explain.
( beeping )
Well, one of
your gremlins
just paid a visit to
the replicator system.
Tuvok, we saved you a seat.
What's wrong?
Someone has altered
one of my holodeck programs...
again.
Are you sure it isn't
just one of these
malfunctions?
Everything on the
ship's been affected,
including the holodecks.
The Oracle of K'Tal
isn't programmed
to wear pajamas.
Well, maybe he overslept.
I am not amused by your
practical jokes, Mr. Paris.
Why do you
always think it's me?
Mr. Kim?
I'd like to
claim credit,
but I'm innocent.
The next time
I visit the holodeck,
I expect to find
my program restored
to its original parameters.
I'm telling you, Tuvok,
we didn't do it.
I wonder how the oracle
would look in a sombrero.
( laughing )
Everybody,
stop eating.
Captain, what's wrong?
If I could have everyone's
attention for a moment.
We found a contaminant
in the replicator system.
It's nothing serious,
but if any of you
start to feel a little queasy,
report to Sick Bay immediately.
In the meantime,
the galley is closed.
I wish I hadn't
had seconds.
Here.
Well, that explains it.
Don't tell me
a simple heating
coil in the stove
is responsible for
everything that's gone
wrong this morning.
Any component connected
to the integrated circuitry
can spread
a contaminant.
This isn't
Starfleet issue.
Where did it come from?
I obtained it
during a trade.
With whom?
Sister Dala.
"Sister"?
One of the clerics
on Selnia Prime.
Tom and I met her during
our away mission.
She was the one
trying to help all
those poor orphans.
It's all in our report.
Did you run a diagnostic
before you installed it?
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
I'm a little busy now.
Can it wait?
I'm afraid not.
I'll be right back.
One excuse after another.
You're stalling,
and I don't have time for it.
Captain, this is Mr. Orek.
He's chief of
mining operations
on Telsius Prime.
A problem, Mr. Orek?
Not if you deliver
our dilithium.
Dilithium?
It's all clearly documented.
Ten kilotons of bolomite ore
in exchange
for ten kilotons of dilithium.
I think there's been
some sort of misunderstanding.
One way or another, I intend
to collect what you owe me.
We've enjoyed meeting you,
gentlemen.
MINER 1:
Captain, we haven't
received the dilithium yet.
Oh, the neutronic storm
seems to be interfering
with our transporters.
If we don't leave orbit
immediately, we will
sustain heavy damage.
MINER 2:
What about our dilithium?
We'll be back to deliver it
as soon as the storm clears.
( sighs ):
Do you still deny you
made the trade?
That woman isn't me.
Who is she, then?
Well, she's obviously
an impostor.
I have transmission logs,
transport records,
scans of your shuttle craft.
I have never been to
your planet, Mr. Orek,
aboard Voyager
or any other vessel.
Our ship's logs will confirm
what the Captain's
been telling you.
How do I know
they're authentic records?
How do we know
your records
are authentic?
You think I falsified data?
Why would I do that?
Perhaps to extort
dilithium from us.
I'm not the thief here.
We are not questioning
your integrity, Mr. Orek.
It does appear
you've been cheated,
but not by me
or anyone on my crew.
How naive do you think I am?
First, you prey upon
the sympathy of my miners
by telling them stories
about poor, orphaned children.
Now you try to convince me
you're the victims here.
Did you say
"orphaned children"?
A despicable tactic.
Will you excuse me
for a minute, please?
We are not finished!
Neelix.
Captain, we're
making real progress.
Never mind that.
Tell me more
about this cleric
who gave you
the heating coil.
Sister Dala?
What do you want to know?
Everything.
Well, Tom and I met her
during our away mission.
We were on a small planetoid
in the Wyanti system
searching for a spore
the doctor wanted
to grow anti-viral
proteins with.
I tell you, Neelix,
when I first joined Starfleet,
I knew it was going
to be one glamorous
adventure after another.
But I never dreamed that
I'd have the opportunity
to go on
a mold-hunting expedition.
I'm detecting
traces of glamour
in this direction.
Please, go no further.
This is our sanctuary.
Our scans didn't detect
anyone down here.
Our sect is
a solitary one.
We dampen
our life signs
to protect
the privacy of
our meditations.
We're terribly sorry
if we've disturbed you.
Begin the cleansing.
Olat mal pri,
mal pra, mal prolat.
Olate kal mi,
kal ma, kal molat.
I hope we haven't
committed a serious
transgression.
The transgression was ours.
We should have
guarded the sanctuary
more carefully.
The deities will be angry.
Come on, Neelix.
We better get
out of the way.
Of... Of course.
Our sincere apologies.
If there's anything
that we can do...
Forgive me, but
you look familiar.
I don't think that
we've ever met before.
Do you see it?
Yes.
You bear
a striking resemblance
to our Redeemer of Light.
I'm flattered.
Each spring, we make
a pilgrimage to Narva
in his honor
to help the orphans.
Well, that's a very
worthy cause.
It is.
Unfortunately, we have no food
to bring them this year.
Why not?
A blight infected
our hydroponic pods.
The crop
was destroyed.
Maybe we could replicate
some food for you.
We bestow
charity on others.
The deities forbid us
from accepting
it ourselves.
How about a trade?
Yeah. Good idea.
You must have something
that we can use.
That way, you wouldn't
be accepting charity
and the deities
would have nothing
to get angry about.
Your heart is as kind
as your face.
May the deities
bless you.
JANEWAY:
That's when they gave
you the heating coil?
It was going to take a while
to replicate the supplies
they needed,
so we invited them
back to the Flyer.
That's when they
must have gotten
access to our systems.
Captain?
Did you leave
either of them
alone at any point?
I don't think so.
After we ate,
Tom took Brother Mobar
to see the cockpit,
but I stayed
in the aft section
with Sister Dala, talking.
About what?
Well, me, mostly.
She wanted to know all
about my role on Voyager.
Ambassador,
Morale Officer, Head Chef.
It sounds as though
you're invaluable.
I do what I can.
Where is
your Voyager now?
About three
light-years from here.
Your crew is alone
in this region?
We are the only
Federation starship
within 30,000
light-years.
That must be difficult.
Sometimes it is,
but we manage.
We've single-handedly
taken on the Borg,
the Hirogen, Species 8472...
I'm impressed.
Captain Janeway deserves
most of the credit.
She's an extraordinary woman.
Your captain is a woman?
The finest one I've ever known.
Tell me about her.
Well, uh...
she's commanded Voyager
for almost six years now.
Before that, she was
a science officer
on the Al-Batani.
Where does she come from?
Earth.
It's in the
Alpha Quadrant.
She grew up on
a little farm in
a place called Indiana.
You'd like her.
I'm sure I would.
Sister Dala...
Yes, Brother Mobar.
It's late. We must return
to the sanctuary.
So soon?
It's time for
the evening meditation.
We can't thank you enough
for all you've done.
We're just glad
that we could help.
The blessing.
Certainly.
May the deities
bless these travelers.
Tala ot val.
Tala ot relina.
Sen tala.
Sen relina.
Val golina.
Su ketran.
Tala otval.
Tala ot relina.
Then we transported them
back to their sanctuary.
How long did this
blessing last?
No more than
a minute or two.
That's probably
all they needed.
For what?
Just what I thought.
The entire database
was downloaded
18 days ago.
Brother Mobar.
The talisman.
It was obviously
some sort of scanner.
What would a couple
of religious clerics
want with our database?
It might help if they wanted
to pose as federation officers.
Gentlemen,
I believe you've been had.
The way I see it,
we're both victims.
Your bolomite
was stolen,
and our reputation
has been damaged.
What are you proposing?
You said you had
scans of the vessel
that visited
your mining colony.
If you allow us
to analyze them,
we might be able to
derive the impostors'
warp signature.
We could find them
and recover your property
before they cheat
someone else.
This is all difficult
for me to believe.
Two of your crewmen
deceived by clerics?
Hmm! Could they really
have been so naive?
A legitimate question.
It's obvious we're dealing
with clever adversaries--
they fooled both of us.
But I'm confident
we can stop them.
Perhaps I should
contact Telsian Security.
They have persuasive methods
for determining the truth.
In the meantime,
the real thieves
could be halfway
across the sector
with your bolomite
in their cargo hold.
And finally,
our bridge.
Is this a typical
Federation vessel?
Well, the Delta Flyer
may look a little worn,
but that's only because
she's been through
so much.
This ship
has helped fend off
the Borg, the Hirogen,
Species 8472.
Most of your technology
is outdated.
Show him the mothership,
Mr. Chakotay.
The USS Voyager...
Intrepid Class.
15 decks of the most
advanced technology
you'll find anywhere.
Dilithium-powered
warp engines,
integrated
bio-neural circuitry,
holodecks...
Is this a typical
Federation vessel?
Every ship in the fleet is built
to exacting standards.
But I'd be lying if I told you
I didn't think Voyager
was exceptional.
As her captain,
I'm not entirely objective.
I'm sure you feel the same way
about your ship.
It is my home.
I'm glad to hear you
say that, Mr. Varn...
because that's exactly
what the Federation is--
A home for an extended family
who share resources
and come to one another's aid
in time of need.
So, if my ship joins
your Federation,
Voyager will help
me fight my enemies?
The primary goal of the
Federation is exploration.
Military objectives...
There's no need
to bore our guest with
Starfleet protocol, Tuvok.
My enemies have
sophisticated
weaponry.
As do we.
Photon torpedoes...
optronically
targeted phasers...
multi-spectrum shielding.
All of which
we would not hesitate to share
with a fellow member
of the Federation.
What will I have
to do to join?
In order to be considered,
a candidate must make
formal application.
An extensive review is conducted
by a committee composed of...
The process is complicated,
but Captain Janeway
has influence
with the Federation council.
And you would use that
influence on my behalf?
I'd be foolish not to.
You are just the type of
candidate we're looking for.
I'll have to discuss
this with my shipmates.
Joining the Federation
is a serious commitment.
Take all the time you need.
Captain, our latest orders
from Starfleet Command:
we won't be back here
for at least six months.
Well, perhaps we can discuss
your application then.
If we were
to apply now,
could you assure us
we'd be accepted?
You realize you'll have to
commit considerable resources.
I'll do whatever is necessary.
Well, let me be
the first to say...
welcome
to the Federation.
You look like you could
use a cup of coffee.
I've been
flying concentric
search patterns
for the last 12 hours.
Any sign
of the impostors?
Neelix, what has happened to us?
I know exactly what you mean.
I've been over it
a thousand times.
Why didn't we see this coming?
Orphans!
It's the oldest gambit
in the book.
I mean, if it'd been Harry,
I could understand it.
He trusts everybody,
but you and me?
We've dealt with our share
of shady characters.
I think maybe...
maybe we've lost our edge.
Hand me one of those
terra nuts.
What are you doing?
Proving you wrong.
Ah, the old shell game.
All we need
now is a mark.
I think I see one coming.
You go ahead.
I'll follow your lead.
Now watch carefully.
I place the terra nut
under the cup.
Then I shuffle them.
Round and round they go.
Keep your eye
on the nut.
But be careful, the hand
is faster than the eye.
Now, for three hours
of holodeck time,
can you tell me
where is the terra nut?
Uh...
There.
No, no.
No, that one.
Oh... I really thought
I had you this time.
Oh, keep trying,
Neelix.
You'll fool me
one of these days.
This looks like
an interesting game.
May I have a turn?
Oh, be my guest.
But, uh, you'll have
to wager something.
If I win, you take three
duty shifts in Sick Bay.
And if I win, you take
three shifts in the kitchen.
Done.
Ready?
Now, watch carefully.
Round and round they go.
Follow the terra nut
if you can.
But be careful--
the hand is faster
than the eye.
Careful, Doc,
try not to blink.
Don't you worry, Mr. Paris.
You have to get up
pretty early in the morning
to fool my optical
subroutines.
Where is it, then?
In your left palm.
How did you...?
Superior visual acuity.
See you in Sick Bay.
I'm detecting a vessel
on long-range scans.
The warp signature matches
the impostor's ship.
Harry, tell Tom
his coffee break is over.
Set a pursuit course.
Yes, ma'am.
The photon torpedoes
you gave me are worthless.
No better than plasma flares.
Perhaps you
didn't arm them properly.
And in the middle
of the battle,
the Polonians warned me
to cease hostilities
or face destruction at the hands
of your Federation.
You allowed my enemies
to join.
Evidently, the Federation
Council decided that...
Your Federation is a fraud!
I demand reparations.
You'll have to submit
a formal report
to Starfleet.
Enough! If you
will not reimburse me,
I'll seize your ship.
Disable the beam!
I can't.
We have an
additional problem.
Voyager.
There's another ship
alongside the impostors.
It's got them
in a tractor beam.
Hail both vessels.
No response from either one.
Well, let's try to
get their attention.
Mr. Tuvok...
Voyager's charging weapons.
Perhaps we should
surrender to them.
The Federation has an
extremely humane policy
regarding the treatment
of prisoners.
Hail Varn again!
Do it!
Look on your
scanners, Varn.
Our mothership's
arrived.
She's armed and
ready to defend us.
Tell them to stand down.
Release us or Voyager
will destroy you.
The other ship is hailing.
On screen.
Stand down, Voyager.
I have no argument with you.
However, the vessel
you're tractoring...
I paid for my
Federation membership.
The Delta Flyer
belongs to me now.
Sir, I think
you've been misled.
Yes, I have.
Three direct hits.
Shields down to 60%.
Target his tractor beam.
Nobody is taking possession
of the Delta Flyer
today except us.
Lock onto them.
CHAKOTAY:
Yes, ma'am.
Now our tractor generator's
off-line.
Shields down to 41%.
The impostor's ship
is powering engines.
Seven, transport everyone
on that vessel directly
to the brig.
Establishing a lock
on three life signs.
That impact damaged
the transporters.
I'm losing annular confinement.
Harry, reroute
additional power!
They're gone.
JANEWAY:
Seven?
I only got one of them.
Get us out of here,
Mr. Paris.
Aye, Captain.
Nice hair.
It's not really my taste.
Posing as a Starfleet captain,
selling memberships
to the Federation...
Too bad we didn't
think of it, Tuvok.
Imagine the resources
we could have acquired
over the past six years.
Indeed.
I have to admit
I'm impressed.
I wish I could say the same.
The great Captain Janeway.
Somehow, I expected you
to be... taller.
I make a better you than you.
Oh, I don't know.
I'd say we're
very much alike--
resourceful, intelligent,
ambitious--
but with just one
tiny difference.
And what is that?
I'm not a liar and a thief.
You're going
to give me
a detailed account
of everyone you cheated
and exactly what you did
with their property.
Why would I do that?
Because if you don't,
I'm turning you over
to Telsian security.
Oh, is that supposed
to frighten me?
How much do you know
about the Telsians?
Just that they're a more
gullible species than most.
Tell her about your
research, Mr. Tuvok.
I beg your pardon,
Captain?
On Telsian law.
I think it's only fair
that we let our guest
know what to expect.
The Telsian criminal
justice system
is rather barbaric.
Tell her about
the prisons.
Barely habitable.
Inmates often die
of malnutrition
before they are
brought to trial.
Torture is commonplace,
as is disease,
including several
incurable forms
of psoriasis.
I think she gets
the general idea.
Suppose I do tell you.
How do I know you won't turn me
over to the Telsians anyway?
If you make full restitution
to your victims,
I'll give you safe passage
out of this area.
Is that a promise, Captain?
I know it's hard
for you to believe,
but occasionally,
some of us tell the truth.
Give me the Delta Flyer
and three days
to get as far away
from here as I can,
and then I'll send you
the information you want.
How naive do you think I am?
As far as the victims
are concerned,
you're the one
who cheated them.
Without my help, you'll be
the one who has a problem
leaving this sector.
Tuvok, contact
Telsian security.
Tell them we have
a prisoner to turn over.
Psoriasis?
Improvisation is not
foremost among my talents.
Considering I caught you
off guard,
I thought your performance
was exemplary.
Thank you, Captain.
Was your order
to call the Telsians
part of the deception,
or did you actually
want me to contact them?
Not yet. Let's give Dala
some time to think
about those
barbaric prisons.
Do you believe
she'll relent?
I'm not sure.
Something tells me
she's just as stubborn
as I am.
Then, am I
to assume you have
an alternative plan?
I'm like you, Tuvok--
making it up as I go along.
The Captain said
bread and water,
but I didn't see any harm.
I'm not hungry.
I'll just leave it here...
in case you change your mind.
May I ask you something?
You want to know
if you really resemble
the Redeemer of Light?
I'm not that gullible.
Then what?
Do you ever feel guilty...
taking advantage of people
who actually think that
you care about them?
You seem like a good person.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
Actually, I think you're
just sorry you got caught.
Probably.
There.
Now you're being honest.
I knew it was possible.
If you don't mind my asking,
why do you do what you do?
My father taught me most people
will exploit you if they can.
So, it's best
to exploit them first.
You know, I used
to be a lot like you.
Living by my wits.
Never trusting anyone.
Always trying to end up
on the more profitable side
of a transaction.
But now you don't hesitate
to help starving orphans.
I changed--
when Captain Janeway
made me part of the crew.
I suppose you
suddenly reformed.
No, no.
Not right away.
At first, I was just
exploiting an opportunity
to get a warm bed,
food, protection.
I kept waiting to
find out what the Captain
wanted in return.
But she never asked
for a thing.
On the contrary.
She expected
a great deal from me.
Honesty, loyalty,
hard work.
I should've guessed.
But I discovered that
those were commodities
I had in abundance,
and it was much more
profitable to share them
than it was to be self-serving
and cynical all the time.
I'm happier than
I've ever been.
I suppose that you think
I could change, too.
Stranger things
have happened.
Do you really think
that she'll give me
safe passage
if I make
restitution?
If that's what
she promised you.
Then what?
I have never done
anything else.
Captain Janeway
let Seven of Nine
remain on board,
and she was Borg.
Are you saying she'd do
the same thing for me?
I'd be willing to talk to her.
I cheated you.
Why are you being so kind to me?
Like my great-grandmother
used to say,
"It's nice to be nice."
Is that tea still warm?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so clumsy.
Security to the brig.
She's gone.
It's not right
to abandon her.
Going back is
too dangerous.
She's our captain.
No, she's not.
And even if she were,
we wouldn't be able
to rescue her.
We'd be captured ourselves.
Without Captain Janeway,
it will be difficult to
continue our activities.
It's too late for that.
There must be
a logical way...
What's logical is to get
as far away as we can.
(  beeping  )
There's a vessel
approaching.
It's the
Delta Flyer.
Activate the shields.
They're hailing.
It's Captain Janeway.
Our Janeway or theirs?
Which one did you expect?
I'm pleased
to see you, Captain.
Lower the shields
so I can transport aboard.
How were you able to escape?
I'll tell you once I'm aboard.
It's difficult to believe
you weren't detected.
Are you accusing me
of something?
ZAR:
...being cautious.
How do we know
this isn't a deception?
DALA:
Why would I try
to deceive you?
ZAR:  You could be helping
Voyager capture us...
Are we in position?
DALA:
I don't have time for this.
Ready?
Captain on
the Bridge.
As you were.
Now, what about
the bolomite
and the rest
of our earnings?
They're exactly
where we left them.
Well, it's time to collect them
and leave the region.
Set a course before
Voyager finds us.
You're not in command here.
I just spent
the last 24 hours in
Voyager's brig.
I have no intention
of going back.
I'm picking up life signs
on the Delta Flyer.
That can't be.
I was right.
You brought them here.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Whoever it is must've
stowed away.
They're hailing.
On screen.
This is Tom Paris
of the Starship Voyager.
Prepare to be boarded.
He's charging weapons.
Evasive maneuvers.
Let's get everything
on board as quickly
as we can.
How many transport
enhancers do you
recommend, Captain?
Do I have to think
of everything?
We'll need
at least ten
if we're going to beam
all that bolomite
through
the geostrata.
Maybe we should take 12.
"We"?
Is there a problem?
In six years
I've never known you
to dirty your hands
with menial labor.
Well, there's a first time
for everything.
You don't trust us.
Who knows what
the two of you planned
while I was
in Voyager's brig?
As Chief of Security
I would never...
It's all right.
We'll all go together.
After you.
DALA:
The next populated sector
is 13 days from here.
When we arrive, we'll
trade the Delta Flyer  for a
new ship.
Voyager will
never find us.
Are all the transport
enhancers in place?
That's the last of them.
We can go now...
if that's acceptable
to you, Captain.
I'm afraid there's been
a change of plans.
I've found the stolen items,
Captain,
you can lock
onto my coordinates.
I told you
she couldn't be trusted.
How could you bring yourself
to deceive your fellow officers?
Voyager, I repeat,
I am in position.
Can you get a lock?
Negative. The geostratum
is too dense.
Keep trying.
Tuvok.
Voyager, now would be
an excellent time
to initiate transport.
You're not
transporting anything.
Captain?
Voyager, please respond.
You're a sight for sore eyes.
Commander... Tuvok?
The one and only.
Logic would indicate
that neither of us
has the advantage.
Your logic is flawed.
Stay where you are.
What did they promise you
for betraying us?
I believe you've
mistaken me
for someone else.
Where's Dala?
I'm afraid she's
indisposed at the moment.
( groaning )
I wouldn't get up
too fast if I
were you, Captain.
It's going to take
another few minutes
for the ambizine
to wear off.
Captain's log,
Stardate 53849.2.
The stolen property
has been returned
to the Telsian miners,
as well as vessels from
seven different worlds.
I'm hoping
that the reputation
of the real Federation
will survive the events
of the last several days.
Round and round they go.
Follow the terra nut
if you can. But remember,
the hand is sharper
than your visual acuity.
I thought we'd already
disproved that theory.
You tell me.
(  sighs  )
The terra nut
is firmly entrenched
up your right sleeve.
Sorry.
That's impossible.
The old handoff.
Ooh.
That's cheating.
We've still got it.