MALES ( in unison ):
Captain's Log, Stardate 53896.
B'Elanna Torres
has requested permission
to take the Delta Flyer
and search for dilithium.
Shining Voyager,
far from home,
far from the gleaming cities
of Earth.
Headstrong B'Elanna Torres
and young Harry Kim
speed away from Voyager
on the Delta Flyer
in search of
their treasures.
"KIM":
I've trimmed
the sails,
but the sea is rough.
Maybe we should return.
I know what I'm doing.
MALES:
A wave as high as a mountain
struck the Delta Flyer.
Get into the
escape pod.
We die together.
No one is going to die.
Go.
MALES:
Young Harry Kim left her side
and B'Elanna Torres
was thrown against the rocks,
the rocks of our very shore.
Which is where I,
Kelis the Poet,
found her...
broken...
dying.
She told me her story...
...and now I've told you.
An excellent conceit, that
you discovered her yourself.
Thank you.
Well, now that
B'Elanna Torres
has come to our shore,
what will happen?
Does Captain Janeway
come searching for her,
or does she give
her up for lost?
Who can say?
Well, I would hope
that you can.
I want to see more of these
Voyager Eternals.
Inspiration...
can't be forced.
One week.
Or three weeks.
Uh, maybe two.
One week.
The story will continue.
Have you noticed
how thin
my performers have gotten?
( clears throat )
Let them eat this.
Ladies and gentlemen--
our patron
salutes you.
Finally!
( performers gasp )
We're doing another
Voyager play...
as soon as I
can write it.
Shall we celebrate,
the two of us?
I have very little time.
Celebrating
will have to wait.
( grunts )
Who are you?!
Kelis... Kelis,
the Poet.
Your servant.
My servant.
All right.
Then let me go.
I... can't.
Why not?
You'll fly from me...
the way inspiration
always does.
You're trying to kill me.
I'm releasing the heat
from your veins.
What are you talking about?
You've been in a fever
since I found you.
Bleeding is the best way
to treat it.
Oh, I can see I'm in good hands.
Something tells me
you have your doubts.
There's a medkit over there.
A box.
Made out of metal?
There's a small
cylinder inside.
Bring it here.
Give it to me.
( electronic whirring )
Don't be afraid.
It won't hurt you.
Here.
Pass it over
where you cut me.
( whirring )
You're an Eternal.
I suppose such things
are to be expected.
What other things do you
expect from an Eternal?
The power to make the ground
open up and the sky to fall.
All the strange events
sung by the ancient poets.
Fortunately for me,
no poet has ever sung
about your clan.
I'm the first.
My clan?
The Eternals on Voyager.
"Shining Voyager,
far from home."
How do you know about that?
TORRES:
Delta Flyer Log,
Stardate 53918.
Harry and I are continuing
toward the fourth planet.
Sensors have picked up
natural dilithium deposits
on nearly every land mass.
CHAKOTAY ( staticky):
Acknowledged.
Has your warp core been damaged?
TORRES:
Yes. We're running on thrusters.
Can you track our position?
How long have I been here?
Eight days.
I was walking through
these mountains.
I saw a light burn
across the sky,
and I heard a
terrible sound.
When I arrived, I found you.
I treated your wounds.
And you tied me to this chair.
When a gift falls
from the heavens,
only a fool would let her go.
You've already given me
one play.
The story told by those voices.
I pieced them together,
tried to fill in the gaps.
You made a play out of our logs?
The Away Mission
of B'Elanna Torres.
My patron was impressed.
Well, he has great taste.
Now, take that knife
of yours and cut me free.
That... would be unwise.
Why?
My patron is intrigued
by the Voyager Eternals.
He wants another play.
To compose that, I need more...
details.
And you expect
to get them from me?
I did save your life.
I need to get back
to Voyager.
I need another play.
What exactly
do you want to know?
Everything.
It's not possible.
We "Eternals" have our rules.
We can't just...
give everything away.
How did you get lost?
Cut me free and I'll tell you.
You won't leave me?
Cut me free.
You're the one
who's leaving.
Don't come back.
Computer, bring the subspace
transmitter on line.
Unable to comply.
Why not?
Insufficient power.
Great. Now there's no power.
KELIS:
Are you hungry?
I told you not to come back.
You haven't eaten in days.
We have to support each other,
we poets.
I'm an Engineer.
I fix things.
From the looks of it,
you're not
doing so well.
Are you a poet
or a critic?
Tell me about Earth.
I have to sing
for my supper, huh?
We all do...
...in one way
or another.
Earth.
It's, uh...
an island...
a beautiful island,
blue and green.
And Voyager?
A-a great ship?
In a long line of great ships.
How did Voyager get lost?
The Caretaker.
An Eternal.
Yes, you could say that.
He...
caused a storm,
which blew us off course.
Tom Paris.
Are you in love with him?
Supper is over.
Come with me.
( grunting with effort )
( electronic whirring )
This is where we put
all the names and dates
when our heads
won't hold anymore.
A memory.
Exactly.
Tell me...
have you ever seen this before?
Winter's tears.
Can you get me some?
This is... dilithium,
isn't it?
What you were
looking for.
Where can I find it?
The only deposit
I know of
is on the hunting
grounds of my patron.
He'd execute me
for trespassing,
and you, well, he'd love
to capture an Eternal.
M-maybe I'm more powerful
than he is.
Perhaps, but, if he caught you,
he'd force you to fight
against his enemies.
They're constantly
at each other's throats,
bickering over territory,
raiding each other's
land, starting wars
whenever they can be
guaranteed of good weather
and we suffer
the consequences.
You don't want
to get involved with them.
Which is why you're going
to get the dilithium.
I told you,
I'd be executed if I'm caught.
The dilithium...
or I don't say
another word about...
"shining Voyager,
far from home."
( thunder rumbling )
Did you...?
Don't get caught.
( thunder rumbling )
Well?
Beautiful.
I've got an idea
for your next play.
I've been visited
by inspiration herself.
How does this sound?
The Rescue
of B'Elanna Torres--
right here, in one week.
MALE:
One week?!
Let's get to work.
Dismissed.
That's it?
Mr. Paris, try to stay calm.
No, that's not going to happen.
Isn't there anything else
we can do?
Not until something
shows up on sensors.
I'll take
a shuttle out myself.
I'll run
a planet-by-planet search.
An inefficient plan.
CHAKOTAY:
And too dangerous.
You could be hit
by the same spatial eddies that
sent the Flyer off course.
We need to concentrate
our efforts from here, Tom.
All right?
Dismissed.
( sighs heavily )
Steady-armed Paris,
bound by a sleep
that brings no rest...
The door opens and
the shadow of a woman
falls on the helmsman.
His eyes open...
Seven of Nine,
did you find B'Elanna Torres?
I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
Closer.
Unpleasant news,
delivered by the most
pleasing of messengers.
KELIS:
No, no, no, no.
Seven of Nine is a Borg,
the scourge
of the Eternals.
I...
You're portraying her
like a shy bride
on her wedding night.
Once more.
Seven of Nine,
did you find
B'Elanna Torres?
I am sorry
to disappoint you.
I can't blame
my performers.
These Eternals on Voyager
are difficult to understand.
Will you stop walking around?
You're going to break something.
This Tuvok, for example.
He's not like anybody
I've ever met.
No emotions?
How's that possible?
It just is.
( whirring )
It worked?
It worked.
( console beeping )
Okay.
Computer, bring subspace
transmitter on line.
What happened?!
I don't know.
The transmitter must have
been weakened in the crash.
It couldn't take
the energy surge.
( grunting with effort )
These Vulcans...
Enough!
( exasperated sigh )
What kind of
metallurgic
technology
do you
people have?
Alloys...
which ones can you make?
Steel? Bronze?
Bronze.
Bronze, all right.
I need a plate of metal
this big, as thin as it can be--
three parts tin
to five parts bronze,
one side coated with gold.
Gold is expensive;
I can't afford it.
Then you're going into debt.
Then tell me about the Vulcans.
Get me the plate,
and then I'll tell you.
Everyone's asleep.
I'll do it in the morning.
The Vulcans?
Maybe I've miscounted, but...
I don't think you've slept
in ten days?
Your count is accurate.
Don't you think
you should go to bed?
( sighs ):
As a Vulcan,
I can function
without sleep
for more than
two weeks.
But there's a point
of diminishing returns
when your mind starts
to play tricks on you.
My mind, Mr. Neelix,
does not play tricks.
The ship is lonely
without them, isn't it?
If you would allow me
to continue my sensor analysis,
I might be able to locate them.
If there's anything else
you need...
a stronger tea, perhaps.
When a friend is lost,
the mind is split in half,
divided between memory
of the past
and fear of the future.
Harry Kim, Ensign.
Only a boy
when fate took you
from the arms
of blue-green Earth.
B'Elanna Torres,
half-Klingon, half-human.
I am honored to call you...
What are you doing?
Is that a tear?
Yes.
Logical Tuvok doesn't cry.
That's why they call him
logical.
Everybody cries.
The land of Vulcan
has no laughter,
and it has no tears.
It is a very quiet place--
calm, just like Tuvok.
I can't believe that.
You don't have to;
just don't cry.
The audience
won't believe it either.
They'll either think Tuvok
is an unfeeling monster
or that I am a bad performer.
They'll realize that beneath
your unfeeling exterior
is a heart
that's breaking, silently,
and in more pain than any of us
can possibly understand,
because that's what it is
to be Vulcan.
Try it again.
Kelis!
KELIS:
What's wrong?
Our patron has been insulted
by his enemy to the north.
The armories are opened.
( murmuring )
Has a battlefield
been chosen?
Not yet.
Then we have a chance.
I need your help.
I've given you
enough help.
Where's that
piece of metal?
Not bad.
My patron's been angered
by the leader
of a neighboring state.
He'll want to take revenge.
It could lead to war.
We Eternals aren't supposed
to take sides.
I'm not asking you to fight.
I need a way to change his mind.
I don't have
that kind of magical power.
Yes, you do.
I believe
the right kind of play
can turn the mind
from violent thoughts.
The perfect play
might even stop a war.
( tricorder beeping )
I can't fix the transmitter
with this.
It has too many impurities.
It'll never carry
a plasma charge.
If the fighting starts,
scouting parties will start
moving through
these mountains.
You'll be discovered.
But my play...
it could stop it
from happening.
You have to help me.
There's nothing I can do.
Then come with me.
I'll show you
what I've done so far.
It's our only chance.
She's a fellow poet
from across the eastern sea,
an expert
on the Voyager Eternals.
She's devoted
her life to them.
She's here to help.
The Rescue
of B'Elanna Torres.
We begin with Harry Kim,
reaching Voyager
in the escape pod.
He tells Captain Janeway
that B'Elanna Torres
is lost.
We continue to the point
where they discover
a piece of
the Delta Flyer.
After that...
It's simple. They search
for B'Elanna Torres.
B'Elanna Torres is found...
Or not found.
The end.
Sounds pretty
straightforward to me.
That's exactly
the problem.
Where is the
mistaken identity?
The discovery?
The sudden reversal?
Mistaken identity--
a character who is someone else.
Discovery--
the moment when that identity
is revealed.
Reversal-- a situation
that turns from good to bad
in a blink of an eye.
Find the truth
of your story,
and you won't need
all those tricks.
I don't know how things are done
across the Eastern Sea,
but here,
poets have become lazy.
They rely on
manipulation
to move
their audience.
It wasn't always that way.
Welcome.
Thank you.
The truth of my story.
It's an
old-fashioned idea.
Today audiences want
excitement... passion.
Let me show you
what I've done
with Captain Janeway
and Commander Chakotay.
Let's make
a good impression
on our visitor.
Chakotay,
why must I be denied
what every other female officer
on this ship can have?
Captain?
The privilege...
of your touch.
( door chimes )
Come in.
If that was good news,
you'd be smiling.
I was just contacted
by an alien
transport vessel.
They picked up
the Delta Flyer's
distress call.
TORRES:
The primary controls
are off-line.
I've ordered Harry to eject.
I still have thrusters.
I'm setting a course
for an L-Class planet.
I'll try to maintain contact.
They couldn't get a
fix on her position.
That was ten days ago.
B'Elanna ordered Harry
into an escape pod.
What's the longest
he could survive?
Less than ten days.
An L-Class planet.
I've already narrowed
the search parameters.
If B'Elanna made it there,
it's possible Harry did, too.
Good night, Commander.
Captain.
( gasps )
We'll have a final rehearsal
in the morning.
The last Tuvok scene
doesn't make sense to me,
and we still don't
have an ending.
I've got the rest of
the night to work on it.
Maybe you can get
some sleep.
What did you think?
Captain Janeway kissing
Commander Chakotay?
Tom Paris kissing Seven of Nine?
I don't see the point.
Anger is like fire.
Love can be the rain
that extinguishes it.
My patron is filled
with hatred for his rival.
So our play should be
filled with love.
You can't change
somebody's way of life
with a few lines of dialogue.
Yes, you can.
It's been done before.
Do you know what
this place used to be...
a hundred years ago?
A temple.
And this was
the altar stone.
Every year a victim
would be sacrificed on it
in honor of winter,
and then one year--
nobody remembers
exactly when or why--
a play took the place
of the ritual,
and no one had to die
here again.
Why can't my play
take the place of a war?
Well, you're going to have to do
a lot better than Harry Kim
kissing the Delaney sisters.
Why?
Because...
when you think that
you are surrounded by enemies,
when you're up against the Borg,
or... or Species 8472,
the last thing on your mind
is romance.
You're an Eternal.
You have to help me.
I'm sorry, Kelis.
The Borg...
tell me more
about them.
They are soldiers,
part of a vast army.
They all think
the same thoughts
and they travel on ships
that look like hives.
Like insect colonies.
They even have a queen.
That sounds
terrifying.
Captain Janeway
hasn't been able
to destroy them.
She is a Starfleet officer,
trained to avoid violence
whenever possible.
She would make peace
with the Borg, if she could.
This is what I need...
an enemy,
someone to stand
in the way
of Voyager
finding B'Elanna Torres. It...
Captain Janeway,
driven by vengeance,
must seek out
the Queen of the Borg.
The audience thinks she plans
to destroy them all, but...
Go on.
The sudden reversal!
Eh, Captain Janeway, holding
her spear at the queen's throat,
throws her weapon aside,
and she argues
passionately
to put an end
to their conflict...
in words...
...no one will fail
to understand.
Including your patron?
( sighs )
That's much better
than all that kissing.
Stay and help me.
I still need an ending.
You'll figure something out.
B'Elanna Torres
dies tragically.
You wouldn't dare.
I followed you here
expecting to find
a love nest.
It's quite a nest.
You're no poet
from across the sea.
You're an Eternal.
Maybe even B'Elanna Torres
herself.
Don't be ridiculous.
Mm.
You know
all he thinks about is you?
We're collaborators,
that's all.
If you come to the performance
tomorrow night,
I'll expose you to the Autarch.
Just leave us alone.
( voice breaking ):
You fix your ship and go.
Please.
Friend of yours?
Harry?
( laughs )
Give me a hand.
Here.
Oh, how?
( laughs )
I ran into some turbulence
in the escape pod,
decided to turn around
and follow your ion trail,
landed about 200 kilometers
from here.
You walked?
At night.
I tracked your position
with a tricorder
and tried to stay hidden
during the day.
( sighs )
Uh...
I've got
some emergency rations left,
a phaser, and the escape
pod's transmitter,
which I didn't have enough
power left to run, but...
Harry Kim saves the day.
Just the ending
I was looking for.
Huh?
The final moment.
The last scene.
More important than anything
that's gone before.
But what is it?
Where is she?
Your collaborator's
probably halfway across
the Eastern Sea by now.
She'll be here.
You said we'd have an ending
by mid-morning.
We won't have time
to learn it.
It'll come to me.
Don't worry.
KIM:
Want to give it a try?
Why not?
( grunts )
The 38th time
might be the charm.
( sighs )
( electronic whirring )
( console beeping )
It's working!
COMPUTER:
The subspace transmitter
is on line.
Why don't you
do the honors?
Voyager...
this is the Delta Flyer.
Our patron has arrived.
He's not in a
very good mood.
He will be.
Not if this is
any indication.
Yes. Kelis, this is
no way to end a play.
It doesn't make sense.
It'll have to.
Go, go.
( audience applauding )
PERFORMER ( on stage ):
Who are the enemies
of Voyager?
PERFORMER 2:
The Borg...
PERFORMER 3:
Species 8472...
You know where the ridge ends
just below the peak?
Run there
as fast as you can.
You'll find a vessel
wrecked against the rocks.
Go inside and give this
to our friend.
Don't be frightened. Go.
( snoring )
( snoring continues )
Tuvok.
( snoring )
( louder ):
Tuvok.
As you were.
Bridge to Chakotay.
CHAKOTAY:
Go ahead.
Request permission
to be relieved.
Understood.
I'll be right there.
( console beeping )
We're picking up
a subspace transmission--
Starfleet frequency.
It's a little rough.
Hang on.
TORRES ( staticky ):
...Delta Flyer.
Harry and I are all right.
We're on an L-Class planet.
Propulsion is down...
( static )
Origin?
5.2 light-years.
F-type star.
Looks like the fourth planet.
Lay in a course...
maximum warp.
Seven of Nine.
Captain.
The Delta Flyer
has been found...
in pieces on
a rocky shore.
And B'Elanna Torres?
No sign of her.
Seven of Nine, you are
my eyes and my ears.
If anyone can find
her, it is you.
Her eyes and her ears...
and the viper in her nest.
I, Seven of Nine,
have no intention
of finding B'Elanna Torres.
I, Seven of Nine,
am Queen of the Borg.
Surprised? No one will be
more surprised than Janeway
when I take my revenge
on Voyager.
Say nothing or you, too,
will be assimilated.
Captain...
I will comply.
My enemies are everywhere...
without and within.
Seven of Nine is
Queen of the Borg.
Surprised?
So was I.
Tell her nothing,
or I will lose my advantage...
and my ship as well.
PARIS:
Are you okay?
Yes.
We're fine.
PARIS:
Good to hear it.
We'll see you soon.
( metal creaking )
Don't be afraid.
What is it?
"Without inspiration...
B'Elanna Torres will perish."
He's threatening
to kill off B'Elanna.
As the climax to his play.
Let him.
That means...
that he still can't
figure out the ending.
Uh, who cares?
I do.
You're serious.
Harry...
...have you ever
inspired anybody?
That's kind of a
strange question.
Well, it's been a strange
couple of weeks.
He needs me, or he's the one
who's going to die
on that stage.
What are you talking about?
COMPUTER:
The transporter is on line.
Tell the Captain
I'll be a little late.
B'Elanna...?
Wait for my signal.
My death is irrelevant.
You will never see
the gleaming cities of Earth.
You will be assimilated.
And if I let you live?
Also irrelevant.
You don't believe that.
The battle is over.
Go home.
How foolish of you
to let me go...
free to attack you again.
And again and again,
until all your drones and
all my crew are destroyed--
until everything
we value is gone
and there is nothing left...
but our hatred.
This final scene
will ruin everything
that we've done out there.
We'll have to improvise.
It's too late.
TORRES:
No, it's not.
I knew you'd come.
And I told you not to.
Wait!
Let's go.
Finally, Voyager
has reached our shores.
TORRES:
And not a moment
too soon.
Kelis the Poet
must say good-bye
as B'Elanna Torres
returns to
the Eternals
in a dazzling
blaze of light.
On a faraway,
snow-covered peak...
TORRES:
No!
Right here,
before your eyes.
Wait. She's not
from across the Eastern Sea.
She's an Eternal.
I'm telling you she's
B'Elanna Torres.
The real
B'Elanna Torres!
I saw her ship!
The lead actress,
in a fit of jealousy
brands her rival
an Eternal.
Our patron rises
to his feet
to stop the play.
Nicely done.
( audience murmuring )
I almost believed you.
( chuckles )
Continue.
Stay.
Voyager needs me.
So do I.
No, you don't.
You have all that you need
right here.
I'll be inspired...
...every time I think of you.
One to beam...
...to ascend...
to the heavens.
And so ends
the rescue of
B'Elanna Torres,
half-Klingon,
half-human,
B'Elanna Torres,
Chief Engineer.
These stories will continue...
for as long as we have
the breath to tell them...
...and as long
as our patrons...
remain wise
and compassionate.
And Voyager
will continue
on her journey
to the gleaming cities
of Earth...
where peace reigns...
and hatred has no home.