( door chimes )
Come in.
You wished to see me.
We've known each
other for how long?
Approximately 20 years.
We've served on three
starships together.
I was present at your
daughter's Kolinahr.
I consider you one
of my closest friends.
And I regard you
with the same esteem.
I've always been
honest with you,
but you've been keeping
something from me.
I don't know
what you mean.
Don't you?
It took exhaustive research,
sifting through
teraquads of data,
separating fact from rumor...
but eventually,
I arrived at the truth.
Captain...
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
So, it's not long
before you hit the big
three digits, hmm?
Indeed.
Have you informed
anyone else of
your discovery?
Don't worry, Tuvok,
my lips are sealed.
Well, you're supposed
to blow out the candle.
That is not a Vulcan custom.
Humor me.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
Well?
It was a fire hazard.
We're receiving
a distress call--
a small vessel on
an intercept course.
Life signs?
KIM: One.
It's Ocampan.
We're being hailed.
Kes?
KES:
Captain Janeway...
I need your help.
( sighs )
Will you please give me
permission to come aboard?
Of course. What's happened?
Please, let me come aboard.
Prepare the docking port.
Tell the Doctor to stand by.
Her ship is accelerating.
It's on a collision course.
Janeway to Kes.
Cut your engines.
You're coming in too fast.
Five seconds
till impact.
Lock on a tractor beam.
Evasive maneuvers.
Hull breach on Deck 9!
Emergency force fields.
Captain, a transporter
was activated
just before impact.
She's beamed aboard.
( explosions )
KIM:
I'm reading
bulkhead ruptures--
Deck 11, Section 17...
18... 19.
Cause?
Unknown.
I have located Kes.
She's moving through
those sections.
She's giving off high levels
of neurogenic energy.
Janeway to Kes.
Kes, respond.
( rumbling )
Hull breach, Section 20.
Force fields.
Security to Deck 11.
Force fields are not holding.
She's approaching
Main Engineering.
Bridge to Engineering.
Intruder alert.
Stop where you are.
( grunting )
( groaning )
Kes?
( quiet sigh )
State your intentions.
Evacuate
Engineering.
( loud pulsating whir )
Warp power is fluctuating.
Torres to Bridge.
Kes is in direct contact
with the warp core.
She's drawing power
from it somehow.
Shut it down.
Warp power is
returning to normal.
B'Elanna, report.
SEVEN:
Lieutenant Torres is dead.
Kes has vanished.
TORRES:
And send Mulcahy.
He's in deflector
control.
We'll need more power
to Junction 12-J,
and tell Harry I
want to talk to him
about building
a new energy grid.
Lost?
No, just looking.
Captain Janeway suggested
that I get more familiar
with the ship.
Well, if you have any
questions, let me know.
Thanks.
We're about to
run a diagnostic
on the warp
core assembly.
You can watch
if you want.
Thanks, but I really should
be getting back to Sick Bay.
Computer, how long
has Voyager  been
in the Delta Quadrant?
56 days, 17 hours.
Back so soon?
I thought you went
to the Airponics Bay
to collect herbs.
I forgot something.
Ah.
Pyong Ko.
Excuse me?
You encouraged me
to choose a name,
remember?
Pyong Ko was a 21st-century
surgeon who discovered
the genetic sequence for
inhibiting cancer cells.
It heralded a new chapter
in Earth's medical history.
That's a perfect
name, Doctor.
Hmm.
Then again, I'm also
considering Schweitzer,
Jarvik, Pasteur.
There are so
many options,
each with
its own merits.
Why don't you give it
some more thought?
You don't have
to decide right away.
Of course, it's not
that I require one
for reasons of vanity.
I'm just a hologram,
after all,
but if I had a name
other than "Doctor"
or "Hey, you,"
it might encourage the crew
to treat me
with a little more respect.
Kes?
( door opens )
Hello?
Neelix?
( sighs )
You know, Neelix, if you want
to put your own stamp on it,
maybe you should give it
your own name,
like "the Greasy Neelix,"
or the, uh,
"Double Talaxian with Cheese."
Ah. It has
a nice ring to it.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
I'll keep that in mind.
Sweeting, what'll
it be? The usual?
I'm not hungry.
I thought that I'd bring
Captain Janeway some coffee.
That's very thoughtful.
I'm looking forward
to tonight.
Actually, I have
a lot of work to do
in Sick Bay.
But I already reserved
the holodeck.
I thought we could take
a moonlit stroll
through the marshlands
of Oshionian Prime.
Another time.
I promise.
Something wrong?
Bad morning.
Anything I can do?
I'll be fine.
I'm not having
a great day, either.
Nobody seems to like
today's menu.
I tried blaming it
on a replicator malfunction,
but no one
believed me.
Wait. I... I think
I see something.
Neelix to Security.
Kes's frown is losing
its structural integrity.
Red Alert.
I'm detecting a smile.
That's my Kes.
The coffee?
That last attack
nearly cost us
our impulse drives.
Fortunately,
B'Elanna found a way
to reroute power
from the deflector.
A good choice
for Chief Engineer,
if I do say so myself.
Getting to know
your enemy.
JANEWAY:
I feel like I already do.
Remember the old story?
A man goes to Risa,
where he meets a beautiful woman
who invites him
for an evening of passion.
He wakes up in the morning
feeling wonderful,
until he discovers
he's missing a kidney.
Every cadet about to go
on his first shore leave
hears that cautionary tale.
Doesn't seem so outrageous
anymore, does it?
No, but the Vidiians are more
than just
your garden-variety monsters.
I've been studying
their culture.
They were a lot like us
before the phage.
Do I detect a note of sympathy?
Makes you wonder what we'd do
under the same circumstances.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Oh, you read my mind.
Vidiians?
I'm afraid so.
We've picked up two more ships
on long-range sensors.
I've gone to full
tactical alert. We're
taking every precaution.
I'm sure you'll get us
through it safely.
Thanks for
the vote of confidence.
Tuvok thinks he's found a way
to penetrate their shields.
The next time they attack us,
it won't be so easy.
That's good to hear.
TUVOK:
Captain to the Bridge.
On my way. Oops.
I... I'm so clumsy.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
This desk has seen
its share of coffee spills,
believe me.
Ensign Wildman has
an intriguing proposal.
We've been analyzing
the Vidiian bio-readings
from the last attack.
Their immune systems
have been compromised
by the phage.
We could synthesize
a neural agent
that would incapacitate
them without affecting us.
Might come in handy
if we're ever boarded.
Exactly.
Work with the Doctor.
When you've got something,
find a way to deploy it
through
the environmental systems.
WILDMAN:
Aye, Captain.
( sighs )
The ships we detected
earlier have disappeared
from our sensors.
Maybe we outran them.
They wouldn't give
up that easily.
Why would they? Voyager's
the only organ bank
within half a parsec.
We fought off
their first attacks.
Now they seem content
to show up on sensors
just long enough
for us to change course.
It's like
we're being herded somewhere.
If we maintain
our present course,
we're gonna enter a region
filled with subspace vacuoles.
We'd have to drop
to impulse to get through.
Sounds like a good place
for an ambush.
The Maquis used to lure
the Cardassians
into the Badlands.
Those Galor-class cruisers
had nowhere to run.
Neither will we, unless...
Tom, how dense
are those vacuoles?
They cover about 70
percent of the region.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Tom, what's the first thing
they teach you
about maneuvering
at warp?
"Faster than light,
no left or right."
When possible,
maintain a linear trajectory.
Course corrections
could fracture the hull.
Exactly. We'd have
to drop to impulse
every time we made
a course change,
but what if we let
Voyager do the driving?
Ma'am?
We could preprogram
every kilometer.
That way we'd only spend
a second or two at impulse
every time the computer
executed a turn.
Auto-navigation
the entire way?
No offense,
but the neural gel packs
can calculate vectors
a little faster than you can.
B'Elanna?
We'd need a more accurate
scan of the region.
If we even graze
one of those vacuoles...
We could send
a shuttle ahead.
The Delta Flyer.
Its sensors
are more advanced.
The Delta what?
Forgive me.
I... must have been thinking
of another starship.
Prepare a shuttle.
I want all
of Voyager's systems
operating at peak efficiency
by the time Tom gets back.
If we're going
to pull this off,
there's no margin
for error. Dismissed.
Computer, display an image
of the Ocampan homeworld.
Plot a course from
Voyager's current position.
Homesick?
Lieutenant.
Tom.
It's okay. A lot
of people on board
feel the same way.
I spent my entire life trying
to get away from Ocampa.
Why would I want
to go back?
Because it's home.
Home for me means
a penal colony.
Out here, I get to fly
a state-of-the-art ship,
and there's no admirals
in sight.
What are you doing?
Getting ready for
a scouting mission.
You planning on going somewhere?
Uh, no, of course not.
I was just studying
the helm configurations.
I didn't know
you could pilot a shuttle.
( chuckles ):
I can't...
but I'd like to learn.
Well, then,
why not learn from the best?
I could start you off
on the holodeck
on an old class-1.
That's the kind of shuttle
my father used to take me up in.
That would be very nice,
Lieutenant.
Tom.
Identify yourself.
It's me, Tuvok.
Naomi Wildman.
MAN:
May I help
you, sir?
Lieutenant, is
something wrong?
( soft music playing )
NEELIX:
Hello, sweeting.
I took the liberty
of preparing one of your
favorite meals.
It's under replicator program
"Neelix 1."
Call me
if you'd like some company.
Miss you.
Computer, end music.
Open an encrypted channel.
Direct the signal
to the following coordinates.
( sighs )
COMPUTER:
Channel open.
My name is Kes. I'm aboard
the Starship Voyager.
Respond.
I know you're receiving
this transmission,
and I also know that
your attempt to capture
this ship will fail.
If you want
to harvest Voyager's crew,
I suggest you answer me now.
Explain.
Captain Janeway is aware
of your ambush.
She's found a way
to evade your vessels,
but I can help you.
I'm listening.
I can send you tactical data
on their shields, weapons--
everything you need
to take this ship.
This is a deception.
Do you want this crew or not?
In return?
Safe passage to Ocampa
for myself and one other.
Why would you sentence
your own crew to death?
They're not my crew.
They abandoned me
a long time ago.
( whirring )
Computer, access Voyager's
tactical database.
Command authorization required.
Access granted.
Naomi Wildman?
She appeared to be
half Ktarian.
Ensign Wildman's
husband is Ktarian.
I met him once on
Deep Space 9.
There's more. I followed her
to Cargo Bay 2,
where I saw a woman
and two children,
all with cybernetic implants.
Borg?
I can't explain it,
Captain.
I've had hallucinations
before, but only while
in a state of
deep meditation.
These were specific,
and they evoked a sense
of anticipation.
It almost sounds like you're
describing a premonition.
Indeed.
I didn't think
Vulcans had premonitions.
They don't.
That's what concerns me.
Computer, maintain
a continuous proximity scan
of Lieutenant Tuvok,
ten meter radius,
all sensor parameters.
In case you have
any more "visions."
A logical plan.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
We're approaching the vacuoles.
On my way.
Last chance to take
the long way around.
It does feel like
we're sneaking through
a graveyard at midnight.
Any sign of the Vidiians?
Not yet, but it's a safe
bet they're in there.
Tom?
Trajectories
laid in.
Our trip will take three hours,
12 minutes, 11 seconds,
with 216 course changes.
Well, let's get started.
Engaging at warp 8.
Sit back and enjoy the ride.
( rumbling, beeping )
One of the vacuoles
shifted position.
The computer's
adjusting our vector.
PARIS:
Dropping
to impulse.
2.3 degree turn starboard.
Jumping to warp 6.
One down, 215 to go.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
PARIS:
Dropping
to impulse.
New heading:
O-31 mark 2.
( console beeping )
There's a ship approaching.
It's on
a collision course.
I'm not reading any ship.
Lieutenant?
Permission to be relieved, sir.
I am not well.
Of course.
DOCTOR:
The molecular structures
appear to be stable. Good.
Report.
We've devised
a neural agent
that should inhibit the
Vidiians' motor functions
without causing any
permanent damage.
Good. I don't want to add
to their health problems.
I just want to keep them
from adding to ours.
I'll get to work.
Doctor, when was the
last time you examined
Ensign Wildman?
I performed her annual physical
six weeks ago.
Did you find
anything unusual?
She's in
perfect health.
This may seem
like a strange question,
but I need to know
if she's pregnant.
I'm not at liberty to
disclose that information.
Doctor-patient
confidentiality.
What about
"Captain's orders?"
Sorry. Medical
protocol supersede
your authority
in these matters.
The security of this ship
could be at stake.
She planned on
telling you herself.
Boy or girl?
Female...
half Ktarian,
as a matter of fact,
which should nearly
double the infant's
gestation period.
How did you know?
And they say I'm rude.
CHAKOTAY:
We're receiving
a distress call.
JANEWAY:
Life signs?
KIM:
It's Ocampan.
JANEWAY:
Kes?
KES:
Let me come on board.
TUVOK:
Her ship is accelerating.
It's on a collision course.
KIM:
Hull breach on Deck 9!
JANEWAY:
Emergency force fields.
TUVOK:
She's approaching
Main Engineering.
SEVEN:
State your intentions.
KES:
Let me come on board.
TUVOK:
It's on a collision course.
CHAKOTAY:  We're receiving
a distress call.
( overlapping chatter )
Problem?
( grunting )
( groaning )
Hey.
Torres to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency.
20 milligrams lectrazine.
Cortical stimulator.
( groaning )
We'll start at 20 millijoules.
Ready.
Now!
( beeping )
He's gone into
synaptic shock.
I don't understand.
Can I speak with him?
I think it's
best to keep him
sedated for now.
When did this begin?
Earlier this afternoon
in Engineering.
Time... I need
the exact time.
Lieutenant Torres called
Sick Bay at 1422 hours.
Computer, display proximity scan
of Lieutenant Tuvok
at 1422 hours.
Oh...
Captain?
Tachyons.
I beg your
pardon?
There was a surge
of tachyon particles
just before Tuvok collapsed.
That could have
triggered this,
but where did
they come from?
They're normally caused
by temporal distortions.
Time travel?
Let me know
if his condition changes.
Kes...
you have telepathic
abilities.
Have you experienced
anything unusual
during the past
couple of days?
Hallucinations,
premonitions?
No, nothing.
If you do, you'll
let me know?
Of course, Captain.
We're low
on neuro-stabilizers.
I'll go replicate some more.
Hurry back.
Where's the tactical data
you promised us?
I'm downloading it now.
I'll transmit it to you
once you've arrived.
I need it now!
Janeway's already suspicious.
If I transmit it now,
I'll be discovered.
That's your problem.
Apparently it's yours, too.
Gentlemen, scan for
tachyon particles deck by deck.
Tachyons?
Do it.
Looking for
something specific?
I'm not sure.
( loud rumbling )
Report!
We're under attack.
A Vidiian ship is closing
on our position.
Battle stations.
We've lost warp drive
and weapons.
They're cutting
through our shields.
Remodulate.
KIM: I'm trying.
They keep matching
the frequencies.
We've still got impulse.
They've taken
out navigation.
I can't plot a course.
They're cutting an access route
through the hull.
Evacuate Deck 3
and seal it off.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Are you ready with
that neural agent?
DOCTOR:
Aye, Captain.
Stand by to release it
on Deck 3.
Acknowledged.
50 milliliters
should suffice.
( alarm blaring )
Doctor!
Doctor to the Bridge.
Environmental controls
aren't responding!
Harry, what's going on?
We've been locked out
of that system.
What do you mean,
"locked out?"
The command relays
have been fused.
They knew
where to find us.
They knew our
shield frequencies,
which systems
to target...
We're being boarded!
CHAKOTAY:
I'm reading
an EM fluctuation.
It could be a transmission.
Location?
Airponics Bay.
Who's down there?
I'm picking up
two bio-readings.
The sensors must
be malfunctioning.
They're both reading as Kes.
Security to Airponics Bay.
Shut down control functions
to that section.
I'm going down there.
Something tells me
we've got more
than one battle
on our hands.
Computer, initiate
site-to-site transport.
Program Kes beta-6.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Control functions
have been disabled.
( sighs )
( groans )
Shh! Shh!
Shh. I'm taking you home.
We've got weapons back.
Can you target those hooks?
Not at this range.
We'd breach
the upper hull.
It's better than
being dissected.
Reverse the hull polarity.
Maybe we can
shake them loose.
Now, one of you
doesn't belong here,
and I'm guessing
it's you.
Tuvok's premonitions
were real.
You're from
the future.
A future I'm about to change.
You're helping
the Vidiians, Kes. Why?
( groaning )
MAN:
...Security
to Deck 11...
( panting )
Tell me why you're doing this.
I won't let you hurt her again.
I haven't done anything
to harm her.
You took her from Ocampa--
her home.
She's a prisoner on this ship.
No one's a prisoner here, Kes.
I was a child.
You corrupted me
with your ideas.
What ideas?
Exploration, discovery.
I believed you!
( loud explosive rumbling )
Hull polarity
loosened their hold,
but not by much.
It's a start.
Reroute the deflector.
Have it discharge
antigraviton pulses
along the hull.
Engage the inertial dampers.
Get a controlled pitch going.
In three years,
I'm going to
leave Voyager
in search of higher things,
because you encouraged me
to do it.
You encouraged me
to develop my
mental abilities.
I wasn't ready.
But what I found...
I couldn't control it.
It scared me.
I had nowhere to go.
I thought
of returning
home to Ocampa,
but I had changed too much.
I knew
they'd be frightened of me.
I knew they wouldn't accept me,
but they'll accept her.
You don't have
to destroy this ship, Kes.
We can help you.
No. I trusted you.
Kes...
No!
( groaning )
We're breaking free!
They're trying to lock on us
with a tractor beam.
Reverse thrusters.
Full power.
That could tear
the hull apart.
Then tear it apart!
Photon torpedoes--
full spread.
Ready!
Fire!
( groaning )
It's set to kill, Kes.
( groans )
Janeway to Bridge.
Status?
CHAKOTAY:
The Vidiians are in retreat.
Everything all right down there?
For now.
She was here...
in my last premonition.
She appeared older.
Her face was tired.
What was she doing?
She had her hands
on the casing,
as if she was drawing
energy from it.
The tachyons
are concentrated here.
It's possible
she needed the core
to travel back in time.
If that's true, then
she'll need it again.
But we don't know
when that'll be.
We have to be ready.
Doctor to the Captain.
Go ahead.
Kes has regained consciousness.
TUVOK:
What do you remember?
I was in Airponics,
and then I felt dizzy,
and then I was
watching myself.
Yourself?
Computer,
deactivate EMH.
What I'm about
to tell you
stays between
the three of us.
Understood?
Yes, Captain.
Something terrible
has happened...
or more precisely,
will  happen.
We're going to need your help
to prevent it
from happening again.
It took exhaustive research,
sifting through
teraquads of data,
separating fact
from rumor...
but eventually,
I arrived at the truth.
Captain...
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
So, it's not long
before you hit the
big three digits, huh?
Indeed. Have you informed
anyone else of your discovery?
Don't worry, Tuvok,
my lips are sealed.
Well, you're supposed
to blow out the candle.
That is not a Vulcan custom.
Humor me.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
On my way.
Well?
It was a fire hazard.
We're receiving
a distress call--
a small vessel on
an intercept course.
Life signs?
One.
It's Ocampan.
I'd almost forgotten.
We're being hailed.
Red Alert.
Raise shields.
Captain?
All hands, this is the Bridge.
Begin emergency
evacuation of Deck 11.
Repeat:
All hands evacuate Deck 11.
You heard her.
Get moving!
Now!
Open a channel.
Kes.
Captain Janeway...
I need your help.
Will you please give me
permission to come aboard?
Of course. What's happened?
Please, let me come aboard.
Her ship is accelerating.
It's on a collision course.
Five seconds to impact.
Tuvok.
Lock on a tractor beam.
Evasive maneuvers.
Shields are holding.
Her ship is intact.
Captain, a transporter was
activated just before impact.
She's beamed aboard.
I'm reading bulkhead ruptures
on Deck 11,
Section 17... 18, 19.
How did you know?
Ready?
Shut down the warp core.
You have the Bridge.
( alarm blaring )
( warp core powering down )
KES:
Remember me?
The innocent child
you're here to save?
You blame
Captain Janeway,
but the choice
was yours.
You made the decision
to leave Ocampa,
and you made the decision
to leave Voyager.
If you're watching me now,
you've come back to take revenge
on the people
who cared about you.
That's not who you are,
and that's not who I am.
Don't do this.
Find another way home.
Captain Janeway will help you
if you give her a chance.
Try to remember
who you were.
Try to remember me.
Don't you remember?
You made that holo-recording,
because you didn't want
this to happen again.
Three years ago,
you traveled back in time.
Kes, you wanted to take
that woman with you,
and you were willing
to hand the rest of us over
to the Vidiians to do it.
It didn't work.
You forced me
to kill you, Kes.
If you go back now,
it'll all happen again.
Just before this
terrible thing happened,
you told me
you had nowhere to go.
That's not true.
Stay here with us.
I can't.
I don't belong here.
I need to be with
my own people.
You told me you had
the ability to get home,
but you were afraid the Ocampans
wouldn't accept you. Why?
( sighs )
I remember...
What? What do
you remember?
The holo-recording--
I remember making it.
You asked me to help you,
to help myself.
( laughs )
You wanted me to
remember who I was.
( sighs )
These years were so
filled with confusion...
and anger. I...
I buried the memory.
I'd almost forgotten.
Does it really matter
which Kes goes home?
A few snacks
for the journey home.
You do still
like leola root?
Thank you.
What?
Just looking.
See anyone you know?
Only you.
Good-bye, Kes.
Captain.
What should we
tell the others?
A friend got lost.
We helped her find her way.