Computer,
deactivate Mess Hall lights.
( gasping ):
Oh! You scared me.
That wasn't my intention.
No, of course not.
I-I-I guess I'm-I'm just
a little jumpy--
especially after
what happened the last time.
That's why I'm here.
Oh?
We'll be shutting
down main power soon.
The children's
regeneration cycle
will be interrupted.
They'll require
supervision.
Well, I'm happy to help.
To tell you the truth,
I'd be grateful
for the distraction.
The procedure could
take several hours.
How much do they know
about what's happening?
Nothing.
The children have
overactive imaginations.
I don't want to alarm
them unnecessarily.
What if they start
asking questions?
I can't just lie to them.
You have considerable
child-care experience.
I'm sure you'll manage.
That's close enough.
Let our momentum
carry us in.
( sighs ):
Cutting engines.
Now, there's
a creepy image.
Reminds me of something
out of Edgar Allan Poe.
Looks like a vampire bat.
You can make out the wings,
even the ears.
What do you see, Tuvok?
Two Starfleet officers
with juvenile imaginations.
Come on, Tuvok.
Haven't you ever looked
up at the clouds
and seen an animal?
I will never understand
the human need
to find imagery
in something as innocuous
as a cloud.
Harry, are we ready?
Yes, ma'am.
Then let's do it.
All hands... initiate
shutdown sequence.
Computer, deactivate EMH.
NEELIX:
Everything's all right.
We've just had to shut down
main power temporarily.
Nothing to be concerned about.
Three, two, one--
mark.
All decks report shutdown
complete, Captain.
Janeway to Seven of Nine.
We're ready.
Acknowledged.
Why did they shut down
main power?
It's simply a precaution.
We've entered a class-J nebula,
and the Captain wants
to make sure
that we don't attract any, uh,
residual EM radiation.
Our shields provide
sufficient protection
against nebula discharge.
Is that so?
( chuckles )
Well, I'm afraid
that gaseous anomalies
were never really my specialty.
Come on, gather 'round.
I brought toys
and stories and games,
and I thought that later
we might even have
a little sing-along.
I should go
to Astrometrics.
Seven may need my help.
I'm afraid that Astrometrics
is shut down, too.
If we're not
analyzing the nebula,
why did we enter it?
Oh, that is
a long and dull story
and not nearly as interesting
as "Flotter Meets
the Invincible Invertebrates."
Is Voyager
in danger?
Mezoti, there's really no need
to leap
to those kinds of conclusions.
Maybe if you explained
what's happening in more detail,
we wouldn't have to guess.
This has something
to do with Deck 12,
doesn't it?
Well, what makes you say that?
Deck 12, Section 42
is off limits
to everyone
but senior officers
with a level-6
security clearance.
That's because it's
haunted, isn't it?
Who told you that?
Naomi.
She was just trying
to frighten you.
I'll have to have
a talk with that girl.
Is it true?
Does a ghost live there?
You're really too old
to believe in such silly things.
If it's not a ghost,
what is it?
We deserve
an explanation.
I don't think that Seven
would be too happy
if you all started waking up
with nightmares.
Tell us.
Please?
All right.
Gather 'round.
But I'm warning you--
this is not a tale
for the faint of heart.
We're not faint of heart.
Our cardiopulmonary
systems are reinforced.
So don't leave anything out.
All right, but remember,
I warned you.
It all began several months ago,
before you joined Voyager.
We were exploring
a dark nebula,
just gathering deuterium.
We had no idea
what was in store for us,
but when the turbulence
started getting rough,
we should have seen that
as an omen.
How goes the particle
collecting, Commander?
We've gotten
enough deuterium
to power the warp engines
for another thousand
light-years.
Excellent.
Something wrong?
Uh, now that you mention it,
there is something
that I feel compelled
to share with you
in my capacity
as Morale Officer.
The crew seem
a little on edge.
Oh?
They don't appear
particularly
anxious to me.
Well, they're very good
at hiding their fears.
Starfleet training.
Um, I was wondering
how soon we might
be leaving this nebula.
Knowing could help
reassure them.
Well, it's
difficult to say.
The Bussard collectors
are running at maximum,
but it's a slow process.
We could be here for
several more days.
Days.
Mr. Neelix, are you certain
it's not you who is on edge?
You know me too well,
Mr. Vulcan.
I can assure you, a J-class
nebula is no cause for alarm.
I know it's illogical,
but staring
into this murky cloud
for hours on end
can be a little unsettling.
When I was a child,
an immense plasma drift passed
through the Talaxian system.
The stars and the moons
were blotted out for months.
From horizon to horizon,
all you could see
was this... this enormous,
menacing cloud.
Ever since then, I've
found it a little disturbing
to be in nebulas.
Perhaps the Captain
might give you permission
to install curtains.
That's an excellent idea,
and I have
just the right material.
Report.
KIM:
The nebula's beginning
to destabilize.
Cause.
I'm not sure.
It could have something to do
with the nadion emissions
being produced
by the Bussard collectors.
You're not remembering
correctly.
I beg your pardon?
The Bussard collectors
don't produce
nadion emissions.
Well, the technical details
don't matter.
What's important is
that Voyager's presence
was destabilizing the nebula,
and the crew
wasn't interested
in taking any chances.
We've got 80 percent
of the deuterium we wanted.
Maybe we shouldn't
push our luck.
Agreed. Bridge to Engineering.
TORRES: Go ahead.
We're suspending
the dilithium intake.
Acknowledged.
Tom, take us out.
Aye.
NEELIX:
But at that exact moment,
in the fraction of a second
before Tom could
engage the engines, zap!
We were hit.
What was it?
The ghost?
Shh. Let him finish.
Whatever it was,
it shook the ship hard.
An EM discharge
penetrated the hull--
Deck 7,
Section 10.
Increasing power
to structural integrity.
We're clear.
Damage.
Power outages on three decks.
Auxiliary subprocessors
are off-line.
No injuries reported.
Assign repair teams.
Resume course.
NEELIX:
We'd taken some
minor damage,
but for the most part,
everything was fine...
or so we thought.
What none of us knew
was that a mysterious stowaway
had come aboard Voyager.
What kind of stowaway?
It was obviously
a space-dwelling
life-form.
Yes, but we didn't know that,
not at that point.
Was it non-corporeal?
In a manner of speaking.
Hostile?
Well, I'm getting to that.
Species 5973?
Who are they?
The Borg encountered them
in Galactic Cluster 8.
They're multispectrum
particle life-forms.
No, that's not what this was.
Maybe it was
an interphasic species.
We can either debate
comparative xenobiology,
or I can continue
with the story.
Now, it's up to you.
Continue the story.
Somehow I thought
you'd say that.
Now, where was I?
Oh, uh, yes...
Life aboard Voyager
would have been more
or less back to normal,
if it weren't for a few
strange malfunctions.
( door chimes )
JANEWAY:
Come in.
I've got reports
from repair teams.
It looks like
that EM discharge
did more damage
than we thought.
Transporter Room 1
is out of commission;
half the sonic showers
are off-line,
and we temporarily lost
artificial gravity on Deck5.
Any injuries?
Ensign Mulcahy
bumped his head
on the ceiling.
Ouch.
This is terrible.
Computer, another cup
of coffee, black.
You can add
replicators
to your list.
We're getting started
on the wrong foot
today, my friend.
Captain?
I'm sorry.
I was talking
to Voyager.
It's nothing
to be embarrassed about.
I used to have
long conversations
with my Maquis ship.
Really? What did you two
talk about?
Oh, I can't tell you that.
Captain-Starship
confidentiality.
Of course.
If the Doctor heard us,
he'd probably recommend
counseling.
I won't tell if you won't.
Deal.
Commander,
do you see that?
It's a meteorite cluster.
I doubt it's anything
to worry about.
I'd tend to agree...
if it weren't the same one
we passed an hour ago.
Ensign.
Yes, ma'am.
Are you conducting
a survey of
meteoroids, Tom?
Ma'am?
Check your sensors.
We're traveling
in circles.
Not according
to my readings.
Tuvok, run a level-4 diagnostic
on the navigational array.
There is a malfunction
in the subprocessors.
It appears we're heading
back the way we came.
All stop.
Reinitialize your sensors.
I'm telling you,
we rely too much
on 24th-century
technology, Captain.
You give me a window
and a sextant,
and I guarantee I'll get you
where you want to go.
We've jumped
to warp 6.
Tom?
Don't look at me.
Shut down
the warp engines.
I can't.
Manual override.
No response.
Bridge to Engineering.
I'm reading all stop.
Lieutenant Torres,
respond.
Computer, locate
B'Elanna Torres.
Lieutenant Torres
is in Engineering.
Ensign Trumari
is on Deck 4, Section 30.
Commander Tuvok
is on the Bridge...
Find out what's going on.
Harry, pull the speech
processors if you have to,
but shut that thing off.
Ensign Boreck is in Engineering,
Level 2.
NEELIX: Meanwhile,
Commander Chakotay
was headed
for Engineering...
or so he thought.
( sighs )
Engineering.
Bet you wouldn't try
to pull this on the Captain.
Have it your way.
I'll walk.
NEELIX:
The turbolift started
to fall faster
and faster...
Anybody hungry?
Neelix!
You haven't touched
your snacks.
Snacks are irrelevant.
Continue the story.
What happened to
Commander Chakotay?
The turbolift plunged
11 decks at high speed.
The g-forces pinned
Commander Chakotay
to the ceiling.
He knew
that at any minute,
he was going to come
crashing down to the bottom
of the turbolift,
and there was nothing
that he could do about it,
but then...
the descent stabilizers
reactivated.
The way
B'Elanna tells it,
Commander Chakotay
was not very happy
when he showed up in
Engineering that morning.
If I didn't
know any better,
I'd say this ship is
trying to kill me.
Do you have any idea
what's going on?
I've traced the problem
to a series of gel-packs
on Deck 13.
It looks like
they were burned out
by am EM discharge
from the nebula.
And those gel-packs
interface
with all the
affected systems.
I'm on my way
to repair it right now.
Feel like giving
me a hand?
Only if we stay
out of the turbolifts.
I'll tell you
about it on the way.
NEELIX:
While Chakotay and B'Elanna
headed for Deck 13,
new problems
were cropping up
all over the ship.
Crewman Celes, step away
from the control panel.
Did I do
something wrong?
You caused a power
failure in Astrometrics.
I did? How?
That's what
I'm attempting
to find out.
I don't see how I could have
done anything...
I've located
the problem.
It appears you
inadvertently overloaded
a series of EPS conduits
while performing
your diagnostic.
But I haven't even started
the diagnostic.
Then what were you doing?
Nothing. I just got here.
I know that wasn't my fault.
These gel-packs
aren't burned out.
There's no trace
of any EM discharge.
Could it have dissipated
this quickly?
No, it moved.
Moved?
The discharge seems
to be traveling
through
the bio-neural circuitry...
jumping from system to system.
Can you isolate it?
It's in a series of gel-packs
that interface
with the environmental controls
outside Cargo Bay 2.
Let's try to get there
before it jumps again.
NEELIX:
By then, Seven of Nine
was in Cargo Bay 2
to run diagnostics,
but, because the com system
was down,
they couldn't warn her,
and she had no idea
that something was
in the room with her.
Here?
In this cargo bay?
Then what happened?
The creature was clinging
to the circuits
and bulkheads,
using them to move
about the room.
It was getting
closer and closer.
Seven of Nine to the Bridge.
Bridge, acknowledge.
NEELIX:
But, of course,
there was no answer.
Why didn't she remodulate
her neural transceiver,
send a message that way?
Uh, that's
an interesting question.
You'll have to ask her.
Stop interrupting.
Seven tried to get out,
but she was trapped.
( beeping denial )
( coughing )
What happened to Seven?
The entity must
have infiltrated her
cybernetic systems
and turned her against
the rest of the crew.
It most certainly did not.
You're letting your imagination
run away with you.
What happened?
Why did the light go out?
It's all right. I just have
to replace the power cell.
It'll only take a moment.
Nothing to be frightened about.
I'm not frightened,
but Azan is.
I am not.
There.
( both gasp )
Sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
Now, where was I?
Oh, yes.
Seven was trapped
by the force fields,
but fortunately for her,
help was on the way.
Computer, deactivate
this force field.
We'll have to cut power
to the field generators.
The computer's
not accepting
my command codes.
Stand back.
The force field's down.
Let's get her to Sick Bay.
NEELIX:
Now, most of us were just
going about our business,
oblivious
to what was happening,
but that was
about to change.
Kim to Engineering.
Neelix to the Bridge.
I want everyone to report
to their stations
until we figure out
what's going on.
Aye, sir.
Uh, Ensign, uh, maybe
I should come with you.
The Captain might need me.
This is your post.
You may be needed here.
Oh, of course.
If you need anything,
anything at all,
you know where to find me.
So there I was.
The only thing I could do
was wait...
alone...
in the dark.
Oh... uh...
Voyager was dead in space.
System after system
was failing,
including
the environmental controls.
Ensign Paris told me
it was hotter
than the Tarkanian desert
on the Bridge.
Don't you ever sweat?
Not unless the temperature
reaches 350 degrees Kelvin,
with a humidity factor
at approximately...
Forget I asked.
Very well.
I'll make you
a deal, Voyager.
The next M-Class planetoid
we find, we'll set down,
and I'll give you
a nice maintenance overhaul.
What do you say?
Tom, check the conn.
( system powers up )
( chuckles )
I don't know
what you did, Captain,
but I've got
helm control back.
( sighs ):
Thanks, my friend.
I'm going to try
to get thrusters
and impulse engines
back on line.
Tom, I'm reading an EM
surge in your console.
Get away from there.
( screaming )
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency!
Can we transport him?
Transporters are off-line.
Why am I not surprised?
( console bleeps )
Now what?
Warning.
Oxygen depletion in progress.
Breathable air is being sucked
out of the Bridge.
Reroute emergency
power to environmental
control.
( coughing )
No effect.
Everyone out of here now!
( coughing )
NEELIX:
In Sick Bay, the Doctor
had his hands full, too.
You're fortunate.
Another few moments and
you'd have been asphyxiated.
Where do you think
you're going?
Lieutenant Torres needs
help with the repairs.
Doctor!
( groaning and gasping )
What happened?
An EM surge--
Seven had a similar experience.
The environmental system
converted Cargo Bay 2
into a micronebula.
When Gibson and
McMinn tried to vent
the gas from Deck 7,
they were struck
by a discharge, too.
Are we thinking
the same thing?
It could be
an intelligence
at work here.
Some kind of an
electromagnetic
life-form
that's using the
environmental controls
to make the ship more
hospitable for itself.
And attacking anyone
who tries to stop it.
My matrix is
destabilizing.
Transfer his program
to the mobile emitter.
Quickly.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Power failure.
Let's get the
injured out of here.
NEELIX:
Deck by deck,
section by section,
the crew was losing
control of Voyager.
People were scattered
throughout the ship
with no idea
what was happening.
( grunts )
What did you do that for?
Ensign, I'm so sorry.
I-I thought... I thought
you were a Hirogen,
or-or a Borg.
And what gave you that idea?
It's dark. Your shadow.
Trust me, there are
no aliens roaming
the corridors.
You mean we haven't
been boarded?
It's just a power failure.
Isn't that what
they sometimes do?
Cut the power?
What who sometimes does?
Hostile aliens.
They might be trying
to infiltrate the ship.
How long has it been
since you've run
into anyone else?
I don't know,
four or five hours.
I-I tried Sick Bay,
but it was deserted.
Decks 3 and 4 are empty.
I-I was on my way
to the Bridge.
You're the first person
I've seen.
Well, there's no one
on the Bridge either.
You see? Then maybe I was right?
Maybe the reason
we can't find anyone
is because they've
all been assimilated.
Slow down.
There was an environmental
failure on the Bridge.
That's why it's been evacuated.
I don't know what happened
in Sick Bay or on Decks 3 and 4,
but I'm sure there's a perfectly
reasonable explanation.
Uh-uh. No one's
been assimilated.
Then where are they?
They've probably set up
a temporary command post--
most likely in Engineering.
That's where I'm going.
Can I come with you?
Of course.
Ensign?
What?
Do you think we
could stop by
a weapons locker
on the way?
NEELIX:
I still had no idea
what was going on.
I'd been waiting
in the Mess Hall
for more than four hours
in the dark,
cut off from the rest
of the crew.
( door opens, closes )
Is somebody there?
Hello?
Is somebody out there?
Tom, if that's you,
this isn't funny.
( screaming ):
Stay away!
Calm yourself, Mr. Neelix.
Y-you really shouldn't sneak up
on people like that.
I could have shot you.
Your restraint
is commendable.
Is there a problem
with the air supply?
An alien life-form
has seized control
of Voyager's
primary systems.
It's flooded
numerous sections
with poisonous gas.
Are you saying
that this alien life-form
is trying to kill us?
Its intentions
aren't clear.
However, we
should evacuate.
Where to?
The Captain
has established
a secure command
post in Engineering.
Were you scared?
Well, considering that
Engineering was eight decks down
and the only way
to get there was
to crawl through pitch-black
Jefferies tubes...
it's fair to say
that I was never more frightened
in my life.
You shouldn't have allowed
yourself to be afraid.
Is that so?
Fear distracts people
from accomplishing their goals.
Well, that's true, I suppose.
On the other hand,
fear can sometimes
be very healthy.
Explain.
Well, it keeps you alert.
Keeps you from putting yourself
in unnecessary danger.
I was afraid once.
You've been afraid
many times.
Icheb.
Do you want to tell
us about it?
It was when we were
first disconnected
from the hive mind,
before Seven rescued us.
I couldn't hear anyone
else's thoughts anymore.
I felt alone.
I can understand
why that was frightening.
When you're scared,
it helps to have someone
to talk to, doesn't it?
Yes.
Of course, in my case,
the only one person I had
to talk to was Commander Tuvok.
I tried passing the time
with a little conversation,
but, as you've
probably noticed,
he's not exactly
what you'd call chatty.
I'll bet Starfleet has
specific, uh, procedures
to deal with these kinds
of situations.
You know, something like,
uh, Protocol 1005.
In the event your
starship is invaded
by a hostile electromagnetic
life-form...
What do you suppose
that, uh, that protocol
would be, exactly?
Rest assured, this crew
is doing everything possible
to regain control
of the ship.
You're right.
I'm just being silly.
I concur.
Of course, the crew
of the Salvoxia
probably thought
they were going
to regain control
of their ship, too.
Did I ever tell you
about the Salvoxia?
If I say yes,
will it prevent you
from telling the story?
It was a Talaxian
freighter.
Horrible tragedy.
Happened nearly
a century ago.
After suffering
a cascade failure,
it began to lose
life-support generators
one by one.
Pretty soon, there
wasn't enough air left
to sustain
the entire crew,
so they began
to draw lots.
Can you imagine?
Draw the short straw
and you suffocate?
Anyway, the air
continued to diminish,
and they kept
drawing lots.
The crew got
smaller and smaller
as they waited for
someone to rescue them.
But no one ever came.
The Salvoxia
drifted through space
for the next 80 years,
until somebody
finally found her.
Makes me short of breath
just thinking about it.
Perhaps you should
occupy your mind
with pleasant thoughts,
before you hyperventilate.
Right.
Pleasant thoughts.
What did the bodies
look like?
I beg your pardon?
After 80 years--
were they decomposed?
They may have been preserved
by the vacuum of space.
Oh. I shouldn't have
told you that story.
It's too gruesome.
I wonder what the crew
of the Salvoxia
did for food after
their emergency
rations were gone.
Maybe they ate each other.
All right, uh, that's enough.
Now, where was I?
We'd made it more
than halfway to Engineering,
when we ran into
an obstacle.
Commander!
( pants )
What do we do now?
If I can access
environmental controls,
I may be able
to vent the gas.
Is there another
way around?
It would take several hours
to reach Engineering
by an alternate route.
There is no guarantee
we'd find a clear path.
Pleasant thoughts.
Pleasant thoughts. Ah.
While we were
in the Jefferies tubes,
a good number of the crew
had gathered in Engineering.
97 crewmen have been
accounted for.
They're in secure locations
throughout the ship.
Neelix?
No one's seen him.
I shouldn't have ordered him
to stay in the Mess Hall.
You were
following procedure.
TORRES:
Captain.
Bad news.
The life-form's infiltrated
the main computer matrix.
As long as it remained
in the gel-pack,
there was a chance
to contain it.
But we can't purge it
from the main computer
without crashing the few
systems we have left.
Things were looking grim,
but the Captain was about
to make a breakthrough
that would change everything.
COMPUTER:
Captain Janeway.
Captain Janeway
is in Main Engineering.
Sorry, Captain.
I know it's irritating.
I'll try to shut it down.
Hold on a minute.
This is Captain Janeway.
Respond.
Authorization code required.
Janeway-pi-alpha.
Captain?
It's only a hunch...
but I think this life-form
may be trying to communicate.
Sounds like a com system
malfunction to me.
I'm not so sure.
The life-form's been moving
from system to system.
If it's intelligent
it may be learning
how to use those systems
in some rudimentary way.
Are you attempting
to communicate?
Unable to comply.
Even if it understands
what you're saying,
it may not know
how to respond.
B'Elanna, can you call up
the com system's
syntax subroutines?
I'll try.
We're attempting
to make it easier
for you to speak to us.
Try to access
the database
at Engineering
Station 3-1.
Database accessed.
Why have you come
aboard our ship?
Captain Janeway,
report to Astrometrics.
Why do you want me
to go there?
Captain Janeway,
report to Astrometrics.
I guess I'll find out
soon enough.
Captain, Astrometrics is
flooded with nebular gas.
Astrometrics life support
has been restored.
It could be some
kind of trap.
This life-form,
whatever it is,
has already injured
at least 11 crewmen.
I can try to establish
a dialogue,
or I can let it
take over my ship.
Seven, you're with me.
Yes, Captain.
While Captain Janeway
and Seven of Nine
headed to Astrometrics,
Tuvok was trying
to ease my fears
by guiding me
through a meditation.
Concentrate on the rhythm
of your breathing.
Envision your lungs
filled with light.
Follow it back in time
to a moment
when you felt no fear...
a moment of happiness...
serenity.
My birthday dinner.
Describe it.
I was surrounded
by all my friends.
They'd gotten together
to cook me dinner.
They prepared
all my favorites--
steamed chadre kab,
terra nut soufflé...
I felt loved...
appreciated...
safe.
( screams )
Captain Janeway
served you nebular gas?
No, of course not.
It was just my imagination
playing tricks on me
during the meditation.
My head was too full
of scary images for me to relax.
The Captain, on the other hand,
seemed to be getting things
under control.
( panting )
Review of navigational logs
in progress.
Are you searching
for something?
Affirmative.
The nebula...
Manual helm control enabled.
You're returning
control of the ship.
Affirmative.
You want me to take you
back to the nebula.
Affirmative.
Well, why didn't
you just say so
in the first place?
Returning to the nebula
is too dangerous.
We'd risk invasion
by other life-forms.
I'm beginning to think
this was all an accident--
not an invasion.
Captain?
Think about it.
The EM surge didn't hit us
until our Bussard collectors
destabilized the nebula,
and then what happened?
The ship began experiencing
random malfunctions.
I'm not so sure
they were random.
Navigational sensors
were fooling us
into heading back
toward the nebula,
and then, when Tom tried
to resume course,
he was attacked.
This life-form isn't
trying to hurt us.
It's trying to get home.
Can you give us access
to the Bridge?
Life support on the Bridge
has been restored.
Level-10 authorization required.
Level-10.
Captain's eyes only.
It wants me to go alone.
The Captain
and the life-form had begun
to establish a rapport,
but the relationship
was fragile.
Is the viewscreen
functioning normally?
Affirmative.
I'm sorry to tell you this...
but your nebula is gone.
Clarify.
The gasses must have continued
to dissipate after we left.
Warning. Life support failure
on all decks.
Abandon ship.
Abandon...
Ship.
Abandon ship.
The creature
was that angry?
Its home had
been destroyed.
The life-form wanted
Voyager for itself,
and it was going to kill
anyone who remained on board.
Captain Janeway's
only chance of saving her crew
was to try to reason
with the creature.
Listen to me.
I can still help you.
Abandon ship.
There are
other class-J nebulas.
I'll find you one.
Unable to comply.
I'd be able to "comply"
if you gave me access
to Astrometrics.
Warning.
Oxygen depletion in progress.
Give me back helm control!
Warning.
Helm circuits are overloading.
Abandon ship.
At least give me
access to the com
so I can warn my crew!
Unable to comply.
NEELIX:
As the Captain was facing
one of her worst fears,
losing her ship,
I was with Tuvok
and about to face
one of mine.
( grunts )
Tuvok!
Lie still.
I'll try to...
( gas hissing )
Mr. Neelix...
proceed without me.
I'm not leaving you here.
I am injured.
Logic dictates
that you take the mask
and proceed
to Engineering.
I don't care
what "logic dictates."
This isn't the Salvoxia.
We're not drawing lots.
I am giving you an order.
And I'm disobeying it.
You're coming with me
if I have to drag you by
your pointy little ears.
I had no choice.
I had to control my fear.
( gases roar )
Pleasant thoughts.
While we made our way
to Engineering,
Captain Janeway tried to
make the creature reconsider
what it was doing.
You're going to kill everyone
on this ship.
Do you understand
what that means?
To deprive of life...
extinguish.
Yes... and if you extinguish us,
you'll be
extinguishing yourself.
You need this crew.
Clarify.
The technology you're using
needs to be maintained.
Who do you think is going
to do that when we are gone?
Voyager's secondary systems
have already begun to fail.
In a few weeks, primary systems
will start to go off-line.
Unable to confirm.
Access the internal sensors.
Run a shipwide diagnostic.
See for yourself.
Abandon ship.
( sighs )
NEELIX:
The Captain's rapport
with the creature
seemed to be
breaking down,
and she couldn't afford
to wait any longer.
I need everyone's attention.
We're abandoning ship.
Get to the escape pods.
We may not be able
to eject the pods.
We'll push them out
if we have to.
He needs medical
attention!
It'll have to wait.
We're abandoning ship.
The entire crew
had to evacuate.
The Delta Flyer and
the shuttles were launched,
followed by all but one
of the escape pods.
That's everybody
but the Captain and
the First Officer.
After you.
I did what you asked--
we're abandoning ship.
What more do you want?
Diagnostic complete.
Secondary systems off-line.
Primary systems at 32 percent.
Estimated time to failure--
six days, 13 hours.
That sounds about right.
Captain Janeway,
report to Engineering.
Like hell, I will.
I won't be your prisoner.
You'll have to kill me.
Acknowledged.
( gas hissing )
Captain Janeway,
report to Engineering.
Not until you restore
life support...
and give me back control
of my ship.
Unable to comply.
Then we'll die here together.
I'm guessing...
( coughing )
I've got
about two more minutes...
and then you're on your own.
Captain Janeway,
report to Engineering.
I told you...
( coughing )
...the only way I'm helping
is if you return control
of my... ship!
( coughing )
It looked like
the creature was calling
the Captain's bluff.
She was down
to her final breath.
But at the last moment...
( coughing )
( wheezing )
Access to all systems
has been restored.
It took almost two days
for the crew
to return to the ship.
Eventually,
an artificial environment
was created
in an isolated section
of Deck 12.
The creature's been
living there ever since.
I told you there was
a monster on Deck 12.
Haven't you
been listening?
It's not a monster.
It's an alien
life-form.
( rattling )
What was that?
Maybe it's an alien life-form
coming to get us.
Haven't you learned anything
about letting your imagination
get the best of you?
There.
That little jolt
was probably nothing more than
our friend leaving the ship
to go to a new home
that the Captain found for him.
Time to regenerate.
What if the life-form
didn't leave?
What if it
wants revenge?
Well...
w-what if I told you
I made up the whole thing?
Naomi told me you
always exaggerate.
I knew the story
wasn't true
the moment you said
the Bussard collectors
produced nadion emissions.
I should've known better
than to try fooling
the four of you.
All right, in you go.
Pleasant dreams.
How are the
children?
Tucked in their alcoves,
safe and sound.
I hope
they weren't frightened.
Oh... why would they
be frightened, Captain?
They were in the dark
for three hours.
Oh, no, not to worry.
I told them a story
to pass the time.
Let me guess-- "Mother Goose."
Certainly not.
Some of those fairy tales
can be frightening--
ogres
and child-eating monsters.
Speaking of which,
is everything... okay?
We're just taking
some final readings
before we resume course.
Show him, Harry.
Well...
I hope it lives
happily ever after.