Four of Twelve,
Subjunction of Unimatrix 525.
You have a disease.
You're one of many
with this sickness.
We want to cure you.
But we need a better way
to identify those
with the mutation.
Our testing method is too slow.
It could take centuries
to identify everyone.
Help me find
the interlink frequency
that binds
all of you together.
Then we can put an end
to this,
quickly, efficiently.
Comply.
( gasping wheeze )
I've disconnected you
from the hive mind.
You're alone.
I know how
uncomfortable
that can be.
Tell me what
I want to know,
then you can
rejoin us.
I... don't... know.
You must
remember something.
I don't... remember.
The frequency.
I don't remember!
Deactivate him.
Wait.
Dismantle him.
Bring me his
cortical array.
( birds chirping )
( inhales )
( laughter )
That reminds
me of the time
my mother caught me
feeding lerraberries
to my younger brother.
MALE:
What's a lerraberry?
We'll save that
for next time.
Until then.
MALE:
Annika.
( gasps )
Another
milestone.
You've had your
first dream.
I felt awake.
Dreams can often
seem quite real.
Tell me more
about this forest.
( sighs )
It was... familiar.
Perhaps your
unconscious mind
was drawing on a
childhood memory.
I spoke to someone.
He called me
by my human name.
Did you recognize him?
He seemed... familiar.
This could give us a
fascinating glimpse
into your
unconscious mind.
Any one of those images
might have a
symbolic meaning.
The mysterious stranger,
for example--
is he a father figure,
or does he represent
a repressed desire
for male companionship?
I don't wish
to dream again.
Please repair
my cortical array.
This isn't
a malfunction, Seven.
It's a natural step
in your human development.
It might seem unsettling now,
but you'll get used to it.
Before you know it,
you'll look forward to climbing
into your alcove each night.
This will keep a record
of your REM cycles.
You're late,
Mr. Paris.
Ma'am?
According to the ship's
chronometer,
by 22 seconds.
I'll make it up
at the end of my shift.
See that you do.
Take your station.
Open it.
That's an order.
Not only late
but improperly dressed.
That belongs
on your collar, Mr. Paris.
JANEWAY:
Allow me.
As ship's Captain,
I hereby reinstate you
to the rank of Lieutenant,
with all the privileges
and responsibilities therein.
Your performance on this ship
over the past year
has been exemplary.
I expect more of the same.
You won't
be disappointed.
Congratulations...
Lieutenant.
I didn't notice a little box
on my chair.
( helm beeping )
Hiding a cake
in the console?
Looks like a distress call.
Put it through.
I'm getting a carrier wave,
but no message.
Origin?
TUVOK: An asteroid,
approximately two light-years
from here.
Yellow Alert.
Set a course.
We're in range.
Drop to impulse.
On screen.
JANEWAY:
Magnify.
I am reading
artificial structures.
It's a colony of some kind.
Open a channel.
This is Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
We've received
your distress call.
Life signs?
None.
I'm detecting residual
weapons signatures.
They're Borg.
Any vessels?
One.
A cube at the edge
of this system.
Resume our previous course,
Mr. Paris. Warp 6.
Make a note
in the ship's record:
We responded to a distress call
at 0900 hours,
arrived at the colony
two hours later.
No survivors.
We don't know
who these people were,
but we know
the Borg destroyed them.
( gasps )
Come with me.
I'm regenerating.
This is only a dream.
You're not dreaming.
I brought you here.
This is Unimatrix Zero.
There is no Unimatrix Zero.
Who are you?
Five of Twelve--
Secondary Adjunct
of Trimatrix 942.
But when I'm here,
my name is Axum.
Axum.
Sound familiar?
Yes.
Good. It's starting
to come back to you.
CHILD:
Is anyone here?
Hello.
I think I'm lost.
I'm Axum.
This is Annika.
My father's ship
started shaking.
Men came aboard.
They looked like machines.
Will you help me
find my father?
I'll see what I can do.
There are
other children here.
Would you like
to meet them?
I just got here, too.
This environment
is intimidating,
but I believe it's safe.
He was just assimilated.
He's probably still
in a maturation chamber.
Are you telling me
this isn't a real place?
It's some kind of
virtual construct?
We come here during
our regeneration cycles.
We can exist
as individuals here.
Unimatrix Zero.
You used to come here,
before you escaped
the collective.
You have the recessive
mutation, too.
Don't you remember
any of it?
No. What mutation?
Only one out of a
million drones has it.
Why did you
bring me here now?
The collective has
found a way to detect us.
It's a lengthy procedure,
but they've managed to identify
and deactivate nearly 200 of us
over the last few months.
It's only a matter of time
before they find enough of us
to isolate
the interlink frequency.
Once they've done that...
You can help us stop them.
Clarify.
We've designed
a nanovirus
that should mask
the biochemical signature
of the mutation,
but we need someone
to release it into
the collective.
You're already
on a Borg vessel.
Why don't you do it?
When we've completed
our regeneration cycles,
we have no memory
of this place.
But you're not a part of
the collective anymore.
You're our only
connection to
the real world.
Scan the node
for residual harmonics.
It's a shame you're not alive
to experience disembodiment.
It's the epitome of perfection.
Give it to me.
We have isolated
the carrier band,
but it's useless to us
without the precise frequency.
We need additional data.
Two more of the mutations
have been discovered
in Spatial Grid 649.
Have their cortical nodes
removed and analyzed.
Bring me the results.
( children laughing )
AXUM:
Unimatrix Zero
is our sanctuary.
When we're here,
our thoughts are our own.
What was my function?
You're thinking like a Borg.
Our only function here
is to try and regain
a fragment of the
lives we lost when
we were assimilated.
Mr. Axum?
Go introduce yourself.
They won't mind.
Hello.
Do you want to play?
Sure.
FEMALE:
Siral. Over here.
Ah.
I was hoping
you'd come.
It's great to see you.
SIRAL:
It's always
good to be back.
I remember him.
You were friends.
You knew a lot
of people here.
You were part of our
lives for 18 years.
I'm willing to help...
but I can't
do it alone.
I'm part of a
starship crew now.
I'll have to
inform my Captain.
I told you
not to bring her here.
We can't do this
by ourselves.
It's too great a risk.
We don't have
a choice.
You do not speak
for all of us!
What would you
rather do?
Have us wait until
we're all discovered?
You disappoint me.
Where's your
warrior spirit?
pahtk!
I'll rip your
heart out.
Go ahead.
Kill me.
I'll be back when I begin
my next regeneration cycle.
You can't stop me, Korok.
If you come here again...
you'll be putting
your starship at risk
and all of us as well.
Shouldn't you be off
sharpening your teeth?
( growls )
I know you.
Your name is Laura.
You're human.
I was assimilated
at Wolf 359.
It's good to see you again.
But you look out of place.
Your cybernetic implants...
Our Doctor was unable to remove
all of my Borg components.
You don't have to
look that way here.
My appearance
is irrelevant.
No, it's not.
They may have turned
us into drones,
but they can't change
the essence of who we are.
My cycle is about to end.
Talk to your Captain.
We can't do this without...
PARIS:
Another round with the Borg?
We'd only need to infiltrate
a single vessel.
Oh. Just one?
I am prepared to take a
shuttle and do this alone.
No offense,
but how do you know
that this wasn't
some kind of a dream?
Seven was wearing
a cortical monitor.
She never reached REM sleep.
She wasn't dreaming.
Unimatrix Zero
is real,
and so are the people
who go there.
They need our help.
What else can you tell
us about this place?
How many drones?
No one is certain.
Axum told me
there could be tens of...
Axum?
He's... someone
I used to know.
He told me there could be
tens of thousands,
perhaps more.
How was it created?
Some of them believe
it began as a random malfunction
during the assimilation
of a single drone
and eventually spread
to the others.
Well, this is all
very interesting,
but are we sure it's worth
putting our lives on the line?
It's my understanding
that when we receive
a distress call, we respond--
Starfleet protocols.
She's right.
This is no different.
I understand
your reluctance,
but Seven's discovered
a potential weakness
in the collective.
Before we decide
how to proceed,
I'd like to learn
as much about it as we can.
Too bad you don't
have the luxury
of an interlink node.
There is another
possibility.
A Vulcan technique known
as "the bridging of minds."
Go on.
I would need to
initiate a mind-meld
with both you and
Seven, acting as a
telepathic conduit.
You make it sound
like a conference call.
Captain, it is my
professional opinion
that we wait until...
Objection noted.
I think you'll be
turning in early tonight.
Stay at Yellow Alert.
Maintain long-range scans
for Borg vessels.
Any sign of trouble,
you know where to find me.
This will be one
away mission for
the record books.
Mind-melds. The last time
I heard the words
"my mind to your mind,"
I had a headache
for two weeks.
I'm willing to volunteer
if you'd rather
hold down the fort.
I appreciate
your trying to protect me,
but a chance
to see this place...
it's worth a headache.
How many times
have you actually performed
this "bridging of heads"?
"Minds." Never.
Then how can you be
certain it'll work?
Nothing is certain, Doctor.
However, I once observed
a Vulcan master
perform the technique.
I am reasonably confident
I can duplicate his success.
Watching and doing
are two different things.
As always, your
logic is impeccable.
What a comfort.
We're ready,
Captain.
Let's do it.
As the conduit,
I'll be aware
of both your
perceptions.
If something goes wrong,
I'll break the meld.
Understood.
Your minds
to my mind.
Your thoughts
to my thoughts.
Your minds
to my mind.
Your thoughts to my thoughts.
Welcome to
Unimatrix Zero.
Seven?
Annika.
That's what I'm called here.
( laughter )
( laughing and talking )
Drones?
Come on, let's find Axum.
We're close.
I can almost hear them.
Bring us closer.
There.
Amplify.
Disrupt the frequency.
It's not working.
They're using
a triaxialating modulation.
You're making this
very difficult.
If we can't terminate
their link...
then we'll simply
have to pay them a visit.
You can see why we want
to protect this place.
We're prepared
to help you,
but I'm concerned that we'd
only be putting
off the inevitable.
Even if we succeeded,
and you could remain hidden
for a year, ten years,
the Borg would eventually
find you again.
Have you ever considered
a more permanent solution?
More permanent?
You've got a remarkable
sanctuary here,
but that's all it is.
Maybe it's time to stop hiding
and find a way to fight back.
That's not possible.
If you could find a way
to carry your individualities
into the real world--
to wake up from
your regeneration cycles
with your memories
intact--
you could begin to undermine
the Borg's control over you.
That sounds like
you're suggesting a civil war.
I'd prefer to call it...
a resistance movement.
That's very
ambitious, Captain,
but we can't retain
our memories.
Not yet,
but we know a good deal
about Borg technology.
Maybe we could...
( shouting )
( gasping )
( panicked yelling )
We've found another.
Spatial Grid 326.
Cube 1184.
Continue.
( gasping )
( screaming )
( groaning )
Welcome back.
Spatial Grid 982.
Cube 461.
No.
( panting )
( warlike roar )
( grunting )
( Klingon gagging )
Janeway.
( grunts )
How's your headache?
I'm guessing
it didn't go well.
Let's just say
we ran into a little trouble.
Have a seat, Commander.
I prefer to stand.
The collective's found a way
to infiltrate Unimatrix Zero.
It won't be long
before they learn enough
to destroy it
from the inside out.
I plan to stop them.
What have you got
in mind?
The people there
are vulnerable.
They don't have
the ability
to take action
in the real world.
We're going to give
them that ability.
How?
The Doctor and B'Elanna
are working on it.
I know what you're thinking.
We'd be violating
half a dozen
Starfleet protocols,
and if the collective ever
learned we were involved,
we'd be putting Voyager
in the middle of a civil war.
Valid objections.
Chakotay...
we've had our disagreements,
and there have been times
when I've chosen to proceed
without your support.
But this can't be
one of those times.
I won't do this
without my First Officer.
The way I see it,
risking the safety
of Voyager is a small
price to pay.
If we help these people,
this could be the turning point
in our battle against the Borg.
I'm glad we agree,
because I almost talked myself
out of it.
Somehow, I don't think
you were ever in danger
of doing that.
You'll inform the crew?
DOCTOR:
This is the nanovirus
Axum designed to prevent
the Borg from detecting those
with the genetic mutation,
but I've modified it
to nullify
their cortical inhibitors
instead.
Once they're infected,
they should retain
their memories
of Unimatrix Zero
after they leave
their alcoves.
Does that mean they'll be able
to function as individuals?
Stand up to the collective?
There's no way to tell.
This is highly
experimental.
How do we deploy it?
TORRES:
Correct me
if I'm wrong,
but each Borg vessel
has a device
that links it
to every other Borg ship.
The central plexus.
If we can gain access
to one of those
and release the virus there,
it should be transmitted
throughout the collective...
instantly.
Any Borg activity
in the region?
They just dropped out of
transwarp 3.6 light-years
from here.
This is a class-4
tactical vessel, heavily armed.
The central plexus is protected
by multiregenerative
security grids.
We'd be detected
long before we could reach it.
Meet me
in Engineering.
We're going
to find a way in.
Prepare the virus.
Aye, Captain.
I think it's time for you
to take another nap.
Pay a visit
to Unimatrix Zero.
Tell our friends
we haven't forgotten them.
I couldn't help
but notice
you were a little different
in Unimatrix Zero,
and I don't mean
your lack of Borg implants.
You seemed more...
Human.
If you don't mind
my saying so, it suited you.
I've been told
I spent a great
deal of time there,
but since I don't
remember Unimatrix Zero
any more than
I remember Earth,
it's irrelevant.
To you, maybe,
but if what I saw
was any indication,
Annika would disagree.
AXUM:
The Klingons
have banded together,
and they're giving
bat'leths to anybody
who can handle one.
Hirogen hunters
are moving
through the forest,
targeting drones,
but we're losing
people every hour.
Captain Janeway intends
to keep her promise.
This isn't your battle.
You don't owe us anything.
Voyager won't abandon you.
A gift from Korok.
Takes some
getting used to.
I'm sure you'll adapt.
11 more drones.
300 meters.
( crowd murmuring )
( footsteps approaching )
Sorry.
That felt... familiar--
our touching.
I told you, we were friends.
Elaborate.
Now is not the best time.
We were more than friends...
weren't we?
Why didn't you tell me?
You'd forgotten.
It wasn't my place.
How long?
Six years.
Only while we were
regenerating.
A very memorable six years.
For me, anyway.
I should return
to Voyager.
Annika...
My name is Seven of Nine.
DOCTOR:
Can't we find another Borg ship?
A sphere, maybe?
Something less
imposing?
I rechecked
long-range sensors.
There's nothing.
This is our target.
You'll keep a transporter
lock on me.
Once I make it
to the central plexus
and release the virus,
you can beam me back.
In how many pieces?
It's ridiculous!
Agreed.
I should go.
I'm the only one
with experience.
You're our only connection
to Unimatrix Zero.
You're needed here.
It was my decision
to help these people.
This is
my responsibility.
Starfleet Tactical
Directive 36:
"The Captain
will not engage
a hostile force
without the protection
of a security officer."
The probability of
success is greater
if there are two of us.
Make that three.
If you're going
to pull this off,
you'll need an engineer
in there.
B'Elanna...
Tactical Directive 36-A.
There is no
Directive 36-A.
There is now.
I appreciate the offer,
but if that cube attacks
Voyager,
you'll be needed here.
Now you have
your orders.
Set a course, Mr. Paris.
Remember when I said
I didn't have
any objections?
Can't this wait
till I get back?
I realize I'm not going
to talk you out of this,
but I'll be damned
if you're going
in there alone.
We've got a lot of
work to do, Commander.
You said you
wanted my support.
Then take Tuvok and
B'Elanna with you.
And if I don't?
I may only be First Officer,
but I still pull a few
strings around here.
The Doctor could be persuaded
to question your
medical fitness.
I was hoping for
your unconditional support.
This is the best I can do.
Tell them to pack light.
Janeway to Bridge. Report.
Someone's trying to tap
into the main computer.
Source?
It's some kind
of transwarp signal.
It's activating the com system.
( pressing buttons )
Captain...
I think it's for you.
Captain.
It's been a long time.
How are things
in the collective?
Perfect...
for the most part.
Voyager?
Never better.
I understand
you've established contact
with Starfleet.
Perhaps you'll be getting home
sooner than you expected.
Perhaps.
We could help you.
How so?
Transwarp technology.
You'd find that we can
be quite accommodating...
but we'd expect the same
in return.
I'm not sure
I know what you mean.
You know exactly what I mean.
Tend to your own crew.
Stay away from things
that don't concern you.
I'm afraid I can't do that,
but thanks for the offer.
I won't be as accommodating
next time.
Reconsider.
I'm sorry.
We'll see you soon, Harry.
What does she
mean by that?
Why this stab
at diplomacy?
She's trying to find
out what we're up to.
She's worried.
Have B'Elanna and Tuvok
meet me in Sick Bay.
Watch the starboard
plasma injectors.
They tend to run
a little hot at
high impulse.
I'll keep an eye on it.
And the warp matrix
is out of alignment.
By .3 microns.
Since when are you
so meticulous?
Since you volunteered
for this insane mission.
You know...
( chuckles )
I could sabotage
the helm.
You'd never make it
out the launch doors.
And I'd have to put you
on report.
You might lose
that new pip of yours.
It'd be a small
price to pay.
TUVOK:
We're in visual range.
On screen.
Magnify.
Torres to Bridge.
Go ahead.
The Delta Flyer
is ready for launch.
On my way.
( sighs )
Guess I'd better be going, huh?
Anything you'd like done
around here while you're gone?
Gravity plating recalibrated,
carpets cleaned?
Surprise me.
You have the Bridge.
You need to prepare
the others.
When they leave
their alcoves,
they may be startled,
disoriented.
But they have to behave
like drones,
or we could all be exposed.
Our ships are scattered
across the galaxy.
Most of us will be
the only drone on board
who knows about
this place.
She's right.
What can we hope to achieve?
We should each gather as much
tactical data as we can--
what kind of ship we're on,
its armaments, location.
Then we'll coordinate
our efforts from here.
If all goes well,
we'll be working
very closely together.
As colleagues.
Nothing more.
Our previous...
friendship...
Yes?
It's irrelevant.
"Irrelevant."
Well, now that I'll be able
to retain my memory,
I'll keep that in mind.
Report!
Direct hit to their
shield emitters! No damage!
Increase phaser yield.
Where's the Flyer?
They're approaching.
Heading 017 mark 3.
Status?
Voyager has sustained damage,
but they are continuing
their assault.
( quietly ):
Come on, Chakotay.
One of the cube's shield grids
is fluctuating--
ventral axis,
secondary emitter.
Cut primary power.
Thrusters only.
( alarm sounding )
Tactical Cube 138
is under attack.
Our forward shields
are down!
The Flyer.
They're closing.
50 kilometers.
Maintain fire.
30 kilometers.
Twenty.
They're in range.
Enhance Grid 6119.
Captain...
I expected something
more cunning from you.
TORRES:
It's time.
Their ventral shield grid?
Still fluctuating at
a rate of .06 terahertz.
Align our transporters to match.
Aye.
They've detected them.
They're inside.
Direct hit to the port nacelle!
We're venting plasma!
Should I back off?
No.
We need to stay close.
They've adapted.
Hull breach! Deck 11!
Aah! They're targeting
our warp core.
No change yet.
We'll have to take
the long way around.
( whispers ):
Tuvok.
( grunts in pain )
( yells )
( inhales deeply )
Their life signs
are destabilizing.
So far, so good.
You can take us
out of here now, Tom.