What's the matter, Harry?
You look a little pale.
I volunteered for a test flight,
not a suicide mission.
How can we put the new
Delta Flyer through her paces
without taking a few risks?
[groans]
Another risk like that, and we'll have
to rebuild her all over again.
-[chuckles]
-[console beeping]
There's a vessel coming up fast
off our starboard beam.
Shields.
Range, 50 kilometers.
Ten.
It's pulling alongside.
Wow. Nice ship.
-It's scanning us.
-[intercom beeps]
This is Lieutenant Tom Paris.
Please identify yourself.
[woman] Vectored exhaust ports,
accelerated driver coils...
Your vessel must be fast.
Gets us where we want to go.
Check your scanners. You'll see a comet
on the other side of the asteroid field.
I wonder which of our ships
could get there first.
Sounds like a challenge.
Are you going to accept?
We are not going to race her.
-This is a test flight, right?
-Yeah, but--
What better way to test the new ship
than to see how it stands up
to a little competition.
We're ready over here.
Should I count to three?
Guess not.
She's a lot more maneuverable
than we are.
Not that I'm endorsing
this misguided exercise,
but maybe we can even the odds.
-The new impulse thrusters.
-Ah. Now, that's the spirit, Harry.
We're catching up.
A hundred meters. Fifty.
Bring the backup generators on line
and reroute power to the thrusters.
And it's the Delta Flyer by a nose.
-[alarm beeps]
-Something's wrong with her ship.
The cabin's filling up with nyocene gas.
Stand by for emergency transport.
[coughs]
You all right?
I think so.
I told you this wasn't a good idea.
Oh, does that mean
you're afraid to try again?
Yeah, Harry? You afraid?
No. Of course not. It's just...
your ship is in no shape for a rematch.
My power transformer overloaded.
I bet we could find you a spare
back on Voyager.
We were about to head back
anyway. Right, Tom?
Yeah, whatever you say, Ensign Eager.
I've been looking forward
to my holodeck time all week.
Why can't you borrow three hours
from someone else?
Yours are the last piece to the puzzle.
Tom and I have finally managed
to get a weekend off together.
I've been trading favors
with members of the crew,
so that we could get
the holodeck to ourselves.
-A romantic getaway.
-Well, that's the idea. Yes.
Well... ordinarily,
I wouldn't hesitate to oblige,
but I've been looking forward
to indulging myself in a new hobby.
Something human doctors have
been enjoying for centuries.
I've already booked a tee time.
[sighs]
Well...
if your tee time is more important
than our happiness...
our first chance to be alone in months...
Fine.
Take my three hours.
Thank you.
So, what program are you planning to run?
-Something new called Gedi Prime.
-I've heard of that.
The vacation paradise
that makes Risa look like a tourist trap.
Endless kilometers of crystalline beaches,
mood reefs, bioluminescent waterfalls...
And a championship golf course,
if I'm not mistaken.
Why don't I just join you?
Somehow, I don't think
that would add to the mood.
Don't be so sure.
You haven't seen me in a bathing suit.
Could you hand me
the veridium injector?
Veridium injector...
Uh... let's see.
The one with the long handle.
Of course!
[sighs]
-Comfortable.
-My copilot thinks so, too.
Copilot?
I was on my way to meet him
when I ran into you.
So, tell me more
about where you're from.
It's a small trinary system
about half a parsec from here.
Three suns. It must make
for some long days.
Are you always this inquisitive?
That depends on who I'm talking to.
Your new power transformer
is installed and ready to go.
Thanks.
And your impulse drive
is a real beauty.
I designed it myself.
But I couldn't help noticing,
your warp system seems so rudimentary.
Warp's fine, if you like
going fast in a straight line,
but, to me, that's just physics,
not flying.
I guess it's a matter of taste.
Anyway, for the kind of flying
I'm here for, warp is not a factor.
The race course is only
two billion kilometers long.
Race course?
What kind of race course?
[Paris]
The Antarian Trans-Stellar Rally.
Three segments covering
2.3 billion kilometers.
With obstacles ranging from
dwarf star clusters to K-class anomalies.
Two-man crews, and most importantly,
each ship is limited to sublight speeds.
It... It is the ultimate test
of ship design and piloting skills.
Not to mention a serious drain
on Voyager's resources.
You're suggesting we reassign 15 crewmen
to modify the Delta Flyer?
The race has very specific guidelines.
All of the ships have to use
enriched deuterium fuel.
The Delta Flyer's not equipped for that.
Irina agreed to lend us a fuel converter.
Captain, this race is more
than just a sporting event.
Until recently,
this region was a war zone.
Four different species fought
for nearly a century to control it.
Now, for the first time,
they're competing peacefully
to commemorate the new treaty
that ended the war.
This race embodies everything
the Federation values...
a peaceful coexistence,
a free exchange of ideas--
I think it's a great idea.
-You do?
Absolutely.
This competition is just
the sort of break we need.
It would give us a chance
to make some friends
and allow the crew a little R&amp;R.
Request granted.
Thank you, Captain.
One thing, gentlemen.
Now that we're in this race,
we're in it to win.
After all, Starfleet's honor is at stake.
-Don't worry. It's in good hands.
-[door opens, closes]
[door opens, closes]
A little tip, Doc.
This game was not meant
to be played indoors.
Here to rub salt in the wound?
I beg your pardon?
I planned to be putting
the greens at St. Andrews.
Instead, I'm putting into beakers
in Sick Bay, thanks to you.
-Me?
-Oh, don't be coy.
I've already approved your time off.
The captain's told you
about the race already?
What race? I was referring
to your romantic getaway.
Oh, no.
Don't tell me you forgot.
Uh, do me a favor, Doc.
Keep a lock on my bio-signs.
What for?
Because, in about five minutes, there may
be a medical emergency in Engineering.
Maybe I can get that tee time back.
Oh.
-Hi.
-You're early.
You packed?
Not yet.
Um, actually...
there might be a little problem.
Problem?
I have a chance to pilot the Flyer
in a race, a really unique race,
and the captain thinks it's a great idea.
So, I guess I got so excited
that I forgot about our plans.
But I don't have to do it.
The captain would understand.
-It's all right.
-No, no, I should have remembered.
It's just that this seemed like
such an amazing opportunity.
-Pilots from all over--
-I said it's okay.
Really?
The holodeck will always be here.
This race won't.
I do not deserve you.
You're right about that.
So, um, we'll plan this vacation
for another time.
-Sure.
-Okay. I'm going to make this up to you.
I promise.
Late night?
-Can I get you anything?
-No, thanks.
[groans]
-Are you okay?
-Oh, my feet. Ah!
I haven't had a chance
to sit down all day.
If you're thinking of cheering me up,
don't bother.
[groans]
Who, me? Never.
And, by the way, you can have
your holodeck time back.
What about your weekend with Tom?
He just canceled it.
Does he have any idea
how much planning it took?
No. And you're not going
to tell him, either.
He just entered this big race,
and he's really excited, and...
I don't want to spoil it for him.
Well, I'm sure if you tell him
how important this weekend was to you,
he'll reconsider.
Probably.
But he should be able
to do what makes him happy.
What about what makes you happy?
It's time I faced facts, Neelix.
Tom and I just don't belong together.
Then you're not in love
with him anymore?
I didn't say that.
But, B'Elanna,
if you still love each other...
Maybe that isn't enough.
Call me a hopeless romantic,
but I still think it is.
Yeah, well, there's a Klingon phrase
that my grandmother used to use.
Mok'tah.
It means "bad match."
That's what Tom and I are.
I just hate that it's taken me
three years to realize it.
If you're really such a mok'tah,
it must have been an awful three years.
No.
Tom is a great guy,
and we've had a lot of fun together.
And that seems to be enough for him.
But not for me.
Why aren't you saying
all this to Tom?
I plan to... after the race.
By which time, he'll already
have disappointed you again.
I may not know as much about
Klingon tradition as your grandmother,
but, somehow, keeping Tom in the dark
doesn't seem very honorable.
My feet are feeling better.
I should go back to work.
[Janeway]
Captain's Log, Stardate 54058.6.
Our request to enter the Delta Flyer
into the rally has been accepted.
I'm meeting with the race coordinator,
Ambassador O'Zaal,
to work out the details.
We have teams that have traveled
quite a distance, Captain,
but none from as far
as the Alpha Quadrant.
We're always willing to go
that extra light-year for a good cause.
Well, your, uh, entrance petition
seems to be in order.
The Delta Flyer meets our guidelines.
Now, all you have to do is win.
Something tells me the other teams
aren't going to make that too easy.
-[intercom beeps]
-[Tuvok] Bridge to the captain.
Go ahead, Commander.
There is an incoming transmission
for the ambassador.
Route it here.
I asked not to be disturbed.
I'm sorry, but the Aksani
are threatening to withdraw
unless they're allowed to host
the post-race ceremony.
Did you explain that we've already
promised that to the Chessu?
Yes. They said
that was... unacceptable.
Arrange for another meeting. I'll have
to find some way of appeasing them.
[ends transmission]
Well, I hope the race you just entered
doesn't end before it begins.
-It's that serious?
-The peace is still very fragile.
Every decision I make, no matter
how trivial, is looked upon as symbolic.
So, every time you make a concession
to one participant...
-Another is offended, yes.
-Maybe we can help.
That would be wonderful, but how?
By providing neutral ground
for the pre- and post-race activities.
Since we've never taken sides
in your conflict,
you couldn't be accused
of showing favoritism.
If your racing skills are as sharp
as your diplomatic instincts,
the other teams won't have a chance.
[people speaking indistinctly]
There's someone to watch out for.
What's his story?
His name is Assan. He was a fighter pilot,
one of the most ruthless.
[clears throat]
-Uh, where you going?
-A little personal reconnaissance.
We are the hosts.
Lieutenant Tom Paris.
Welcome aboard.
Could I get you something? A drink?
Something to eat? Tour of the ship?
Were you assigned to serve me?
Um, not exactly.
Are we friends?
I guess not.
Then you must be one of those pilots
who believes in the fellowship of combat.
[chuckles]
Correct me if I'm wrong, but...
I thought this was
a friendly race, not a battle.
If that's what you believe,
then you've already lost.
Well...
Nice chatting with you.
Learn anything?
Yeah, I should leave
the hosting to Neelix.
-Joxom!
-Who?
-My copilot.
-Irina. Hi.
Oh, looks like they're good friends.
-They're teammates.
-Mm.
Close, personal teammates.
Oh, it was nice while it lasted.
Come on.
Seven, I need you to run a diagnostic
on the lateral sensor array.
-As soon as I'm finished.
-With what?
Plotting the most efficient course
for the first segment of the rally.
Seems like the entire crew
has come down with race fever.
Perhaps you could persuade the Doctor
to develop a vaccine.
I'm surprised you're
putting time into this.
Initially, I did find
the activity irrelevant,
but then, I realized that it's important
for the crew's morale
and for my relationship
with Lieutenant Paris.
[scoffs] Your relationship
with Lieutenant Paris?
I was speaking professionally.
I often work with him
on navigational problems.
He can be an erratic individual,
but he's also a very competent officer
and, clearly, a skilled pilot.
It's the erratic individual
that takes getting used to.
No doubt.
But I've learned that if I embrace
some of his interests,
support him in his personal goals,
we're able to function
more efficiently as crewmates.
[hatch opens]
Harry, where have you been?
[Torres]
Say "Qapla'."
It means "success."
I just wanted to capture the moment,
not to mention that cute,
bewildered expression.
What are you doing in that flight suit?
There's been a change of plans.
I'm your new copilot.
[chuckles]
Look, I don't have time
for practical jokes.
Neither do I. Ready to bring
that impulse drive on line?
-B'Elanna--
-Okay.
I was upset that you canceled
our weekend, but then, I realized...
why should we spend this time apart
when we can be together
doing something you like?
What about Harry?
I assigned him to a level-5
diagnostic in Engineering.
Oh, that's terrible.
I'm just kidding.
I told him how hard it was for us
to get time together, and he understood.
Anyway, the way I see it, you're trading
an ensign for a chief engineer.
Well, you don't have to convince me.
I couldn't ask for a better copilot.
Now, just remember,
we're not on vacation.
The point is to win.
And you know how much I hate to lose.
Thrusters on line.
Opening Shuttle Bay doors.
The racers are moving into position.
Ambassador.
Welcome to the first running
of the Antarian Trans-Stellar Rally.
This moment marks a hopeful point
in our shared history,
a chance to put aside old animosities
and come together in a spirit of peace
and friendly competition.
Good luck to all of you.
Prepare for the starting signal.
Captain, the honor is yours.
Mr. Tuvok...
Fire.
We passed two more ships,
three still ahead of us.
How's my impulse engine?
Hot, but stable,
thanks to the new fuel converter.
That was the Number 8 ship.
Assan.
Whoever it is just grazed our shields.
Port thrusters are off-line.
Compensating.
Well, that was an old trick.
Back at the Academy,
we used to call that "scraping."
Well, Assan just almost
scraped us out of the race.
-How are we doing on time?
-Twenty seconds to the third marker.
Assan's already rounding it,
thanks to his little tactic.
Well, it's a long race.
We'll catch him.
How's our team doing?
I announced the Delta Flyer's progress
over the comm 11 minutes ago.
In a race like this,
11 minutes can be an eternity!
The Delta Flyer is in fourth position,
having completed 62% of the course.
The Aksani vessel is in third position,
having completed 68% of the course.
-You don't make it sound very exciting.
-I'm relaying the relevant information.
It's all in the delivery. Do you mind?
-[intercom beeps]
-Attention, all hands.
Stand by for a race update!
With only 58 million kilometers
left in the first segment,
the Aksani, Imhotep, and Terrellian ships
are still battling for the lead.
Wait. The Number 8 ship just cut off
the Number 3 in the Darla system.
Now, 3's changing course.
Using the gravity from a gas giant
to boost its speed,
it's making up for lost ground!
-Sounds like quite a race.
-Apparently, it's all in the delivery.
So much for the Aksani.
Now, it's just down to Irina and Assan.
In a few minutes, they'll just be echoes
in our aft scanners.
[chuckles] Well, we've still got
the Mobius Inversion coming up.
The what?
Tell me you read the course manual.
I skimmed it... more or less.
Oh, great.
So, what exactly
is this Mobius whatever?
Take a look.
Covers the entire last third
of the course.
Level-6 subspace distortions,
gravimetric shears.
Just think of it as a little wormhole
with a big attitude.
The Terrellian and Imhotep ships
are still in the lead,
the Delta Flyer trailing
by a few seconds.
Meanwhile, the two Chessu ships
are continuing to advance,
claiming fourth and fifth position.
-My weekly security report.
-I'll read it later.
There are a few matters
we should discuss.
She said later, Tuvok.
Something's wrong.
They're disappearing.
Radiation from the Mobius Inversion
is blocking our sensors.
How will we track their progress?
We can't. Not until they emerge
from the other side of the anomaly.
Want to talk about
that report now, Tuvok?
Later, if that's permissible.
Fifty meters.
Forty.
We can get through.
-No, they're too close to each other.
-I'm reversing our deflector polarity.
It'll repel their shields. Why wait
for an opening when you can make one?
-No, it's too risky.
-Too risky?
That doesn't sound
like the Tom Paris I know.
-What are you doing?
-Deploying auxiliary thrusters.
We'll need the extra maneuvering power
to get through the gap.
-B'Elanna--
-Just steer the ship.
[sighs]
It's them. It's the Delta Flyer.
They're in the lead!
They're pulling away!
-We did it!
-You should have waited.
-I saw a chance and I took it.
-I'm the pilot.
-That means I do the flying.
-[intercom beeps]
[O'Zaal] Attention, all racers.
There's been an accident.
Stay in order
and shut down your engines.
[tricorder beeping]
-Report.
-[Doctor] His condition is stabilizing.
I should be able to start
dermal regeneration in a few hours.
-[Irina] This was Assan's fault.
-Why?
He collided with me so many times,
my shield generator overloaded.
Joxom's console exploded.
He's lucky he's alive.
If I'm guilty of anything,
it's of coming in second,
a situation I'll remedy in the next leg.
[sighs] You're doing a poor job
of defending yourself.
We may have had something
to do with this, too.
We grazed both of their shields
while in the anomaly.
Intentionally?
It was a tight course.
Everyone was flying very aggressively.
Your team is not responsible, Captain.
My generators were already overloading
when they made contact.
Perhaps none of you is to blame.
I found this interfaced
with her ship's shield generator.
I ran an analysis. It's a phase inverter,
designed to cause a system overload.
It's hard to believe someone would go
this far just to knock a competitor
out of the race.
This may be more than a simple case
of cheating, Captain.
I think someone's trying
to end the peace.
Maybe I'm missing something, but we're
talking about a single act of sabotage.
How does that threaten your treaty?
By itself, it wouldn't...
but we've received several threats
of a more serious nature.
-From whom?
-Groups opposed to the alliance.
Arms dealers, isolationists,
political extremists.
Up until now, I wasn't sure
how seriously to take them.
-Clearly, they pose a security threat.
-Yes, yes.
We've done everything we could to protect
the racers, but that may not be enough.
I don't want to risk any more lives.
We should cancel the race
or at least postpone it,
until we can guarantee
everyone's safety.
No. If we stop now,
we'll be letting these extremists win.
She's right.
Very well, then.
If that's the consensus,
we'll resume tomorrow as scheduled.
Of course, Captain, if you decide
to withdraw, we'd understand.
Well, the last time I checked,
I believe we were winning.
There you are.
Congratulations on taking the lead.
-Thanks.
-Of course, uh, you're not going to win.
-Why is that?
-Because we are.
You're looking at your new copilot.
I checked with one of the race officials.
It's perfectly legal,
and it's a chance for both of us
to get back in the race.
I appreciate the gesture,
but my ship's damaged.
You don't know our Harry.
Once he sets his mind on something...
He'll not only fix your ship,
he'll polish the bulkheads.
How can you turn me down?
Apparently, I can't.
Come on, you can say it.
It's embarrassing.
I just want to make sure
we're clear on what we're doing.
"Right at the light,
then readjust my sight."
Meaning?
Come about 86 degrees at the red giant,
then recalibrate sensors to compensate
for photonic interference.
Great. Next?
Do I really have to spend my morning
reciting nursery rhymes?
It got me through the Academy.
You were expelled.
Okay, repeat after me.
"I am not the pilot.
I will not attempt to fly this ship."
That one doesn't even rhyme.
-Uh...
-[hatch opens]
Anyone home?
-Well, if it isn't our competition.
-Here to spy on us?
I just stopped by to borrow
a hyperspanner.
Looks like you didn't get much sleep.
-Irina and I were up all night.
-Oh, really?
-Making repairs.
-Uh-huh.
To be honest, I can't remember
the last time I had so much fun.
She's funny, smart,
we get along without trying.
I'm going to ask her if she wants to spend
some time on Voyager after the race.
What about Joxom?
Turns out they're just teammates.
-I know what you're going to say.
-No, no.
Actually, I was just going
to congratulate you.
I mean, she's not a Borg,
she's not a hologram, and she's not dead.
Looks like you might have finally
found yourself the perfect woman.
-[intercom beeps]
-[O'Zaal] All teams report to your ships.
The race will resume in 30 minutes.
See you on the course.
-[intercom beeps]
-[Neelix] Attention, all hands.
Stand by for another race update.
After fighting off a formidable challenge
from the Terrellian team,
the Delta Flyer has managed
to hold onto its lead
going into the third and final segment.
Approaching the pulsars.
[Torres]
"Straight through the gate."
"Then remodulate."
Harry sure had that glow, didn't he?
What glow?
You know, that look you get
when you first meet someone.
Yeah. His cheeks were
a little redder than usual.
We're through the pulsars.
Harry and Irina are right behind us.
You can ease up off the thrusters now.
I want to conserve some fuel
for the final leg.
If circumstances were right,
they might even have a future together.
What?
Harry and Irina.
[scoffs]
Well, they just met.
It's a little early
to be planning a wedding.
No, I just meant that some people just
fit together without having to work at it.
And other people,
no matter how much they try...
Are we talking about them or us?
What?
No, I didn't--
If something's bothering you,
let's talk about it.
We should concentrate on the race.
[sighs]
[console beeping]
Well, maybe Harry and Irina
aren't such a great team after all.
They're falling behind.
I'm reading malfunctions
in the EPS relays,
but we double-checked
all of them last night.
We must have missed something.
At this rate, we're going to be
out of the race in a couple of minutes.
I think I can reroute power
through the impulse manifold.
No.
-Why not?
-It could damage the reactor coils.
What do the reactor coils have to do
with the impulse manifolds?
These systems are different
than what you're used to.
You do want to win, don't you?
Of course I do.
It just seems like every time
I make a suggestion,
you find a reason to reject it.
I'm more familiar with my ship
than you are.
-[beeping]
-Now what?
I think it's the injector ports.
No, it's an overload in my console!
[grunts]
That's the second time
your copilot's console exploded.
Quite a coincidence.
I'm sorry, Harry.
I really am.
You sabotaged your own ship... twice.
Why are you trying so hard
to get out of this race?
[both grunt]
What the hell is going on?
Sit down and hold still!
All right. If you won't talk to me...
maybe you'll talk to Antarian Security.
[console beeping]
You disabled the comm system.
We'll just wait.
Someone will come along eventually.
We're past the last marker.
Time to deploy the thrusters?
Whatever you say.
What happened to "I'm the pilot"?
That really bothered you, didn't it?
It's why you think we don't fit together
as well as Harry and Irina?
Could we talk about this later?
Assan is gaining on us.
[sighs] Well, then, I guess
you'd better deploy the thrusters.
Thrusters deployed.
-This isn't about the race anymore, is it?
-You tell me.
If we're going to just sit here,
we might as well see who's winning.
You're not exactly in a position
to be making requests.
Admit it, Harry, you're curious, too.
[sighs]
The Delta Flyer is still in the lead.
Good for them.
I thought that if we could do
this one thing together,
something that you cared about,
that it might help our relationship.
I didn't know it needed help.
Well, that's part of the problem.
-What's the rest?
-You know the rest.
[sighs]
So, we scrape shields occasionally.
It keeps things interesting.
Maybe interesting isn't enough for me.
What are you doing?
[Harry]
They're stopping.
They're dead in the water.
Ah-ah.
How far from the finish line?
Less than a million kilometers.
That was Assan!
Why are we just sitting here?
If we've got a problem, we're going
to resolve it right here, right now.
You've done everything possible
to take yourself out of the race,
and now you seem worried
that the Delta Flyer
won't reach the finish line.
I'm counting more
than a dozen ships there.
Spectators, officials...
All congregated in the name of peace.
Touching, isn't it?
You've planned some sort of attack.
There are hundreds
of innocent people there.
How can you do that?
[sighs]
Not everyone is as comfortable
mixing with other species
as you are, Harry.
Some of us believe it was better
when we were separate.
Hey, I never asked you
to give up this race,
or anything else that you care about.
I never asked you
to stop being yourself.
The only self that I want to be
is the guy that you're in love with.
Wow.
-I didn't know you felt that way.
-How can you say that?
Well, you always seem
to have other priorities.
I'm showing you my priorities right now.
The Delta Flyer wouldn't even be in
this race if you hadn't told us about it.
You gave us the fuel converter
so we could qualify.
The fuel converter.
That's why you're so concerned
about Tom and B'Elanna's
crossing the finish line.
What'd you do to it?
Rig it to explode?
How come you never talked to me
about this before?
Well, you've got that tough
Klingon exterior, and...
I didn't think you liked the mushy stuff.
Do I look that tough right now?
Well, does that mean you're
in the mood for some mushy stuff?
Maybe.
Exactly what kind of mush
are we talking about?
You tell me.
Well, there's, um...
kissy stuff.
That was nice.
And there's the...
"you're the most important person
in the world to me."
I like that one, too.
And there's the "happily ever after."
-How does that one work?
-[both chuckle]
Well, traditionally,
it requires a proposal...
[alarm beeping]
We're being scanned by some kind
of modulating pulse.
-It's from Irina's ship.
-They must be wondering why we stopped.
There's something odd
about the amplitude.
Wait a minute. Di-di-da...
That's Morse code.
Harry and I use it
in the Captain Proton holoprogram.
What's he saying?
"Fuel...
converter...
rigged.
Eject."
What does he mean by "rigged"?
That converter's leaking
veridium isotopes.
Why didn't the computer warn us?
The on-line sensors
have been tampered with.
Can you contain the leak?
Too late. The veridium is already reacting
with the warp plasma.
-That'll cause a warp core breach.
-In less than a minute.
Then do what Harry said.
Eject the converter.
It's too late. I have to eject the core.
Here?
We'll never survive the blast.
Neither will anyone else
within a million kilometers.
[flipping switches]
They're moving again.
Away... from the finish line.
[computer]
Warp core breach in 30 seconds.
-Where are we going?
-A J-class nebula filled with ionized gas.
Should contain the explosion.
I can't get the ejection
subroutines on line.
Warp core breach in 20 seconds.
[sighs]
So, what's your answer?
My answer?
Will you marry me?
Warp core breach in 15 seconds.
-You're proposing now?
-It's as good a time as any.
-Warp core breach in ten seconds.
-Subroutines back on line.
Nine, eight...
Clear!
-...four...
-Go!
...three...
[crowd murmuring]
Damn.
I'm sorry your team didn't win, Captain.
Janeway to the Bridge. Report.
[Tuvok] That was a shock wave
from an antimatter explosion
approximately 1.2 million
kilometers from here.
Excuse me.
[groans]
B'Elanna...
[sighs]
-I guess we lost.
-That depends.
On what?
On how you answer my question.
I thought you only asked it
because we were about to explode.
Well, we're still alive...
and I'm still asking.
How come you never asked me before?
How come you're still
avoiding the question?
-I'm thinking.
-Think faster.
Why? You're going
to withdraw the question?
No, but I might start to beg.
Could get embarrassing.
[Janeway]
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The Antarians have invited us to
participate in the post-race festivities,
which has allowed me to give
two of my senior officers time off
for a well-deserved romantic getaway.
The Delta Flyer still needs
a new warp core,
but I don't think they're in a hurry
to get anywhere.
To... the winners.
"B'Elanna Paris."
That has a nice ring to it.
Thanks, but I already have a ring.
[both chuckle]
Anyway, I kind of like
the sound of "Tom Torres."
-I hope you're kidding.
-Hey...
it is the 24th century.