[thunder rumbling]
[man]
He's got temporal narcosis delirium.
[man on P.A.]
Trauma Team 4 to Level Red.
[groans in pain]
[woman on P.A.]
Code 4 Nursing Unit, report to Level Red.
[man] No. He does have a sensor.
It's not working.
[electronic beeping]
[Allocator] Negative for dysplasia,
viremia, necrobiosis.
Please extend your arms.
Species: Dralian. Identity: Gar.
T.C. 15. You may proceed.
[electronic beeping]
[coughs]
Chellick. Lucky I caught you.
Mr. Gar, I wish I had time to talk.
Well, all you have to do is listen.
I have a new supply of cytogenics.
Your last supply was useless.
Expired lots, diluted samples...
Oh, I have something special this time.
The latest in substandard
technology, no doubt.
Oh, this item is far from substandard.
And as a gesture of goodwill,
I'm offering it to you first.
We don't need another neural monitor.
Mm, this is much more
sophisticated than that.
I'm sure it has some ingenious use,
but I'm not interested.
Please state the nature...
of the medical emergency?
Where have you taken me?
It's a holographic construct,
programmed with over
five million medical protocols.
I demand to be returned
to Voyager at once.
What's Voyager?
The Federation starship
to which I'm assigned.
This man is a kidnapper.
[scoffs] I would never offer you
stolen property.
I traded warp-grade dilithium
for this program.
What's your price?
This negotiation is pointless.
I'm not about to perform medical services
for a pair of common thieves!
It doesn't seem to be in working order.
-[sighs]
-[electronic beeping]
[Allocator] Trauma victims are now
arriving at Emergency Intake 7.
What caused their injuries?
A generator explosion
at the Gammadan Mining Facility.
You'd better start cooperating,
or I will dismantle your program
and sell it off one subroutine at a time.
When Captain Janeway discovers
what you've done...
-Let's go. Clear a path.
-We're going to lose this guy.
-Come on.
-Here we go.
-Move!
-All right, tuck him in there.
I can't find any coagulant.
Somebody check the reserves.
-There are no reserves.
-This one's got grade-4 pulmonary burns.
[Allocator] Patient's T.C. is 4.
Transfer to Level Green.
-Level Green isn't equipped for this.
-His T.C.'s only 4. Take him to Green.
Don't touch that.
This patient's bleeding seriously.
He needs an immediate infusion.
What are you doing?
Get away from him.
With technology this primitive,
you may as well be using leeches.
-Who is this man?
-A doctor, of sorts.
I thought you were
withholding your services.
Fortunately for these patients,
I am programmed with the Hippocratic oath.
It requires me to treat anyone who's ill.
This patient needs 20 milligrams
anesthezine. Get me a hypospray.
A what?
[sighs]
I'm sorry, this may hurt a little.
[patient groans]
Did you have to program that
Nausicaan guard to high stick so much?
Well, you play hockey,
you've got to expect a few lumps.
[sighs]
-What are we going to tell the Doctor?
-Hmm.
You know how he feels
about our juvenile holoprograms.
Relax. I'll come up with something.
Hey, Doc.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
[both sigh]
I know what you're thinking,
but there's a simple explanation.
Tell him, Tom.
Right. Well, um...
see, Doc, we were running
these invasion scenarios
when this species of proto-humanoid--
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Are you okay, Doc?
Please take an analgesic
and return in 24 hours.
It's a replicated fake.
The program running in Sick Bay
is from one of Doc's old training files.
I want someone to tell me
how this snake oil salesman
managed to evade
every security protocol on the ship.
-I take full responsibility.
-I'm not interested in fault.
I just want to know how it happened.
Um, Gar spent the night in Sick Bay.
He claimed to have gotten
food poisoning at dinner.
He had plenty of time to learn
about the mobile emitter from the Doctor.
Who I'm sure was more than willing
to extol its virtues.
Medical logs show the training file was
activated just before Gar left Voyager.
Scan for his ion trail,
and let's review safeguards for accessing
low-security files, shall we, Mr. Tuvok?
Captain, don't blame Tuvok
for what happened. It was my fault.
How so?
Gar kept complaining
how bland his dinner was,
so I added a few exotic spices.
I'm not sure I see your point.
I was trying so hard
to create something he liked
that I didn't take his alien
physiology into account.
Everyone's assuming he faked his illness,
but I might have really made him sick.
It's not as if your cooking
turned him into a thief.
No, but if he hadn't gone to Sick Bay,
he may never have come up
with a plan to kidnap the Doctor,
much less have the opportunity to do it.
In my experience, Neelix,
men like Gar have no trouble
finding opportunities
to take advantage of other people.
Well, I just hope there's something
I can do to help find the Doctor.
Well, when and if that opportunity arises,
I'm sure you'll make the most of it.
[sighs] That was the most impressive
cortical bypass I've ever seen.
It's just a question
of possessing the basic skills.
Ah, if I had basic skills like yours,
they'd move me up to Level Blue.
Take this patient to Yellow.
You seem a little low on resources here.
If I could contact my medical staff,
I might be able to get you
some additional supplies.
Communication is usually restricted, but
the Allocator might give you clearance.
-Good. Where can I find him?
-Uh, the Allocator isn't a "him."
It's our main computer.
-Well...
-[coughing]
Perhaps it could establish
a communications link
with Voyager's main computer.
[sighs] You'll have to submit
a formal request to Chellick
and support it
with Form 83-W in triplicate.
-[coughing continues]
-Even then...
Why hasn't this patient been treated yet?
He's waiting for proton imaging.
There are a lot of other people
ahead of him.
It's nice to see someone knows
what's going on.
-What's your name?
-Tebbis.
Well, Tebbis,
this doesn't look too serious.
Uh, it's just a little
osteal extravasation.
Excellent diagnosis.
I hope to be a doctor someday.
Really?
Well, I hope your working conditions
are better than these.
It wouldn't be so bad
if they'd let us listen to music.
It would certainly improve my mood.
It's not just that,
but music has great healing power.
I couldn't agree with you more.
-[groans]
-Uh, exhale slowly.
[exhales]
-Can't you give him a neural blocker?
-He's already had his allocation.
[low rhythmic beeping]
The leg injury isn't all I'm picking up.
He's got some kind of systemic disease.
It's a chromo-viral infection.
We have 12 cases down here.
-He's in the final stage.
-Is there an established treatment?
Cytoglobin injections.
These scans don't show
any cytoglobin in his bloodstream.
-He hasn't been given any.
-Why not?
-He doesn't have a high enough T.C.
-"T.C."? What's that?
Ah, there you are. I'm happy to report
that I've acquired your program from Gar.
-Please come with me.
-I will not.
May I remind you
I'm being illegally detained?
Or hasn't the rule of law
reached this society yet?
We follow the Allocator's rules,
and it's determined that your services
are required on Level Blue.
Uh, please, Doctor, the Allocator knows
which patients need help the most.
[sighs]
Level Blue is your critical care area,
I presume.
Level Blue is the area
where it's most critical
that we provide excellent care.
[door opens]
These patients will be
your chief responsibility from now on.
Do whatever you can
to make them well.
Why are these patients
getting preferential treatment?
They have a higher T.C. than the others.
Indulge me. What's T.C.?
Treatment Coefficient.
The Allocator assigns one
to every patient.
It determines the level of care
they receive.
How is this coefficient derived?
Through a complex formula that involves
profession, skills, accomplishments.
How is any of that relevant
to medical treatment?
An agricultural engineer is obviously
more important than a waste processor.
-Important to whom?
-Society.
When your resources are limited,
you have to prioritize.
So, you base treatment on whether
patients have particular abilities?
It's much more complicated than that.
The Allocator assesses
the entire individual.
And reduces his life to a number.
It may seem impersonal, but it's what
the Dinaali have contracted us to do.
Chellick's people are known
throughout the sector
for their administrative skills.
Before they came here,
we were a dying race.
Eco-disasters, famine...
Dr. Dysek, Chief of Medicine.
The medical hologram I told you about.
Are you in charge of what passes
for care on Level Red?
Because those people are suffering.
Intriguing technology.
Can we use him to treat patients yet?
That's what he's here for.
In some societies, it's considered rude
to refer to someone in the third person
while he's standing in front of you.
I'm sure you'll make good use of him.
The warp trail ends here.
Gar should be directly ahead.
All stop.
Red Alert.
On screen.
It's emitting a false warp signature.
Looks like we've underestimated
Mr. Gar again.
Now what?
-There may be another way to find him.
-What do you have in mind?
He traded us high-grade iridium,
which has a very brief half-life.
His ship is slow.
Logic suggests he acquired the substance
within a radius of three light-years.
Cross-reference our sensor logs
and long-range scans.
Two planets,
no atmosphere or technology,
a T-class nebula...
Here's something.
An asteroid with approximately
200 humanoid life signs,
subterranean structures.
Sounds like a mining operation.
If that's where Mr. Gar
acquired the iridium,
they may be able to help us find him.
Tom, how fast can you get us there?
Less than two hours.
Do it.
-We're being hailed.
-Open a channel.
I want my iridium back now.
I beg your pardon?
I've scanned your ship.
I know you've got it on board.
Yes, we obtained it
from a man called Gar, a merchant--
You mean thief.
So, you have had
the pleasure of meeting him.
He was here two days ago.
He sold us 3,000 induction units.
He was gone a day before we realized
he'd also stolen 20 kilos of ore.
[scoffs]
We had a similar experience.
Maybe we can help each other.
How?
Do you have any idea
where we might find him?
Will you return my iridium?
By all means, but Gar only traded us
half of what he stole from you.
However, we might be able
to get the rest of it back.
All I can tell you
is that the induction units came
from a planetoid called Velos.
[sighs]
You may go.
Your surgical technique is impressive.
Well, you've obviously had
experience with cellular repair.
As a matter of fact, I've done
extensive research on the subject.
I'd be happy to share it with you, but
we'll have to contact Voyager to get it.
You'll have to discuss that with Chellick.
He authorizes all communications.
It's time for this patient's
next injection.
Requesting one cytoglobin injection
for patient B-3, priority Blue-7 gamma.
[Allocator]
One cytoglobin injection authorized.
Does this patient have
a chromo-viral infection?
No. Why?
I was told cytoglobin is the standard
treatment for that disease.
Cytoglobin also prevents arterial aging.
Will that be all?
You may go.
This patient's arteries
appear to be healthy.
At the moment, but daily injections
increase life expectancy up to 40%.
We prescribe them
for all Level Blue patients.
I just saw a boy
on Level Red who's dying.
This medicine could save his life.
This woman is a chief engineer
of an irrigation facility
which provides water
to half the subcontinent.
So, her life is more valuable?
Keeping her healthy
contributes to our survival.
Can you say the same
for the boy on Level Red?
Who knows what he'll accomplish
if he has the chance?
If he becomes more valuable
to society, his T.C. will rise,
and then he'll receive better treatment.
He may not be around long enough.
I'm sorry he's sick,
but our society is much better off
since we began following
the Allocator's protocols.
Some of you are.
-I never expected to see you again.
-Why do you say that?
-Level Blue is much more prestigious.
-Prestige is the least of my concerns.
-How is he?
-Not well.
[beeping]
-His condition's deteriorated so rapidly.
-His coenzyme allotment's been reduced.
[sighs] Are we here to help
these people or kill them?
His T.C. is just too low.
-Maybe we can raise it.
-That's not possible.
If it's purely a function of statistics,
we can simply input more data.
-We're not authorized to do--
-Voje.
When you look
at your patient lying there,
you have to ask yourself,
"What can I do? What must I do?"
We can amend his database
to include additional skills.
-Such as?
-His extensive knowledge of neutronics.
He doesn't know anything
about neutronics.
We can say he does.
What's the harm in trying?
Amend patient R-12's T.C.
to include an expertise in neutronics.
[Allocator]
Unable to verify. Amendment denied.
You see?
-[weakly] Hello.
-Lie still.
What are you doing?
Trying to get you
the proper medication.
You're wasting time you could
be spending with other patients.
You have as much right
to treatment as anyone.
It's not your fault.
There's nothing you can do.
-Nurse.
-Yes, Doctor?
Why hasn't this patient received
her additional cytoglobin injection?
Additional?
If you'd examine her chart,
you'd see that I've increased her dosage.
-Dr. Dysek didn't say anything--
-Dr. Dysek is at home with his family.
Would you like me to contact him so you
can explain why you're not doing your job?
No, Doctor.
Requesting one cytoglobin injection
for patient B-3, priority Blue-7 gamma.
[Allocator]
One cytoglobin injection authorized.
I'll do it myself.
Can I assist you?
You may go.
[people groaning]
[people coughing]
[pained groaning]
[coughing]
[man grunts]
[groaning]
[sighs]
He convinced me to let him take
the induction units on consignment.
That was more than ten days ago.
I haven't heard from him since.
You appear to be
an experienced merchant, Mr. Kipp.
Why would you trust someone like Gar?
He came highly recommended.
By whom?
A buyer I know. He said he's been
trading with Gar for years.
Do you know where
we can find this buyer?
Yes, Captain. I am the fool
who said that Gar could be trusted.
Sounds like you've changed your mind.
[sighs] I should have known
it was a mistake, but...
Well... you see, I have never
been able to say no to my wife.
What does she have to do with it?
Well, she's the one who asked me
to recommend Gar.
Then she must know him well.
They're... friends.
May we speak with her?
She's, uh...
She's not here.
Do you know where we might find her?
[voice breaking]
She left me.
You're a woman. You saw my husband
with your own eyes.
Overweight, depressed...
You would have left him, too,
especially if you had met
someone as exciting as Gar.
Yes, he's very exciting.
That's why you're looking for him,
isn't it? You want him for yourself.
I assure you, I have no romantic
interest in him whatsoever.
Why? Not good enough for you?
No, it's not that. It's just that...
I already have a man.
We have a business opportunity
for Mr. Gar,
one that will expire
if we don't find him soon.
He's on his way to the gambling
tournament on Selek IV.
When you see him,
tell him to hurry home.
[transmission ends]
[sighs]
How are you feeling?
Better.
That's what happens
when you get the proper treatment.
But I'm not authorized
to receive cytoglobin.
You are now.
You'll need several more injections,
but you can expect a complete recovery.
Whatever you did, they'll find out.
They'll punish you.
You're assuming
I've done something illicit.
-Didn't you?
-Of course not.
I simply had a talk with Chellick,
explained to him
what a bright young man you are,
and he had the Allocator
recalculate your T.C.
I've never met a doctor like you.
Well... it's not hard to stand out when
the general level of competence is so low.
There are patients on this level
who deserve a higher T.C. than I do.
Could you talk to Chellick about them?
[sighs]
Thank you.
[coughing]
Ah, Voje.
-You're not busy, are you?
-Well, actually--
Good. I want you to help me
dispense these injections.
-Where did you get the cytoglobin?
-Level Blue. Where else?
You stole it?
I'd prefer to think of it
as "reallocation."
We're going to treat
every chromo-virus patient on this level.
Do you have any idea
what kind of trouble we could get into?
"We?" Then you will help me.
No! Absolutely not!
Modifying data files was bad enough.
Well, I certainly wouldn't want you
to do anything to compromise your ethics.
[Tebbis]
I'll help you.
-You should be in bed.
-Actually, now that he's improving,
a little activity will do him good.
You can go back to doing...
whatever you were doing.
The best place to inject him is here,
in the lateral artery.
Excellent work!
It's nice to see someone in this hospital
has a future as a healer.
[sighs] If we each take
a third of the patients,
maybe we can finish
before someone catches us.
Who do you think you are, prescribing
unnecessary medications for my patients?
It wasn't unnecessary.
If you believe that, you're incompetent,
or perhaps malfunctioning.
I was simply trying to increase
our allocation of resources.
-What are you talking about?
-I did some checking.
Last month, Level Blue's total
medication requests were down by 6%.
-Because our cure rate was higher.
-Exactly.
Because you performed
so efficiently last month,
the Allocator will determine
you're able to do with less next month.
If we don't order more medication now,
we may not get it when we need it.
Think about it, Doctor.
If you don't have the proper resources,
your cure rate could go down.
[whispering]
If that happens,
the Allocator may assign you
to a lower level.
Mm-hmm.
Are we having a problem
with our newest piece of technology?
Actually...
he seems to be learning
the system quite well.
Oh. Three of the patients we injected
are practically virus-free.
What did you expect?
Um, maybe we could "reallocate"
other medications, treat more patients.
Now, you're thinking like a doctor,
and to support your efforts,
I've arranged for resources
from Level Blue to be diverted here
on a regular basis.
How did you manage that?
Let's just say, Dr. Dysek and I have
developed a professional rapport.
Sometimes, I even surprise myself.
We may actually make
these people better.
That feeling you get
from healing someone...
infectious, isn't it?
Where did you get that?
One of the technicians was going
to recycle it because it wasn't working,
but I think I fixed it.
Hmm.
[beeping]
Seems to be in good condition.
And so do you.
You'll be well enough to leave soon.
Couldn't you say I'm still sick?
Don't you want to go home?
If I do, they'll send me to work
in the refinery with my father.
What about school?
Your medical training?
I would never be authorized for that.
He's right.
If I stay here, you can teach me,
and I can help you treat your patients.
I'm not planning on being here
that long myself.
Then I can help Dr. Voje.
We'll see what we can do.
I have picked up Gar's ship,
directly ahead.
Again?
[Tuvok]
I'm reading his bio-signs.
Any sign of the Doctor
or his emitter?
-Not yet.
-Should I hail Gar?
If we let him know we're here,
he may try to slip away.
We could drop out of warp
at close range
and grab him before he knows
what's happening.
I like it.
Tom, Tuvok.
He's hailing.
I guess we put him in the mood to talk.
On screen.
I thought we were friends, Captain.
Why am I being treated this way?
I think I deserve better.
-Where's our Doctor?
-I have no idea.
I certainly hope
nothing's happened to him.
Scans are complete.
Neither the mobile emitter
nor the Doctor's program
are aboard Gar's ship.
Well, of course they're not.
He's trying to destabilize
the tractor beam with a feedback pulse.
-Compensating.
-Don't bother, Harry.
Just beam him to the brig.
[whispering]
Tebbis, wake up.
Time to make our rounds.
Locate patient R-12.
[Allocator] Patient R-12 has been
transferred to Level White.
-Tebbis has been moved.
-I know.
What's Level White?
Some kind of patient recovery area?
It's the morgue.
I demand an explanation
for the death of that boy.
I'm responsible for thousands of patients.
You'll have to be more specific.
His name was Tebbis.
Patient R-12!
Acute chromo-viral disease.
He was recovering.
Apparently, he developed complications.
What kind of complications?
A secondary infection.
It spread rapidly.
-How was it treated?
-It wasn't.
The patient had exceeded
his medication allotment.
It seems someone had given him
unauthorized injections.
Did you think I wouldn't find out?
Don't you have any ethical standards?
You are hardly in a position
to speak to me of ethics.
Lying, stealing...
Any other crimes you wish to confess?
I was trying to save lives.
And I am trying to save a society!
Do you really think patient R-12
is going to help me do that?
His name was Tebbis.
He wasn't contributing.
He was a drain on resources.
You're not just rationing
health care here.
You're getting rid of the sick
and the weak!
If the boy had been fit,
he would have survived.
Why don't you just put a phaser
to their heads?
We're healers, not killers.
[sighs]
-I'm going to expose you.
-To whom? The people who employ me?
They brought me here to make
the hard choices they don't want to make.
From now on,
I'm restricting you to Level Blue.
You've done enough damage on Red.
You mean those patients that I treated?
Yes, that was inconsiderate of me.
It was. You managed to exceed their annual
medication allotment in a matter of days.
They're being sent home.
They'll die!
You should have considered
the consequences of your actions.
Please, don't make them suffer
for my mistakes.
-It won't happen again.
-I'm making certain of that.
From now on, your time
will be strictly regulated.
Meaning what?
I've interfaced your holo-matrix
with the Allocator.
Starting now, it will determine
where you go, when you go,
and what you do when you get there.
[Allocator] The medical hologram will
now commence treatment on Level Blue.
You have six minutes to treat patient B-3.
I don't know where he is.
Not now, perhaps,
but you know where you took him.
The last time I saw him,
he was in your Sick Bay.
If you refuse to cooperate, your knowledge
of his location can be extracted.
How?
A mind-meld.
What's that?
An invasive and disturbing procedure.
-[gulps]
-[Neelix] Dinnertime!
Mr. Neelix, I am in the middle
of an interrogation.
Commander, you know
better than anyone
that Starfleet has strict guidelines
about allowing prisoners to eat.
Very well. I'll wait.
There we are.
I'm glad to see you enjoying a meal.
When you got sick last time,
I thought my food was to blame,
until I realized it was just a ruse
for you to get close to the Doctor.
I used Talaxian wormroot as the base.
Mm-hmm.
I'm glad you like it.
Some people react badly.
[groans]
React how?
Oh, dear, I hope you're not getting sick.
If it's the wormroot,
it's going to get a lot worse.
What have you done to me?
The usual symptoms are abdominal spasms,
which increase in severity for 30 hours.
Forty at the most.
-Tuvok to Sick Bay.
-Don't worry, Mr. Tuvok, it's not fatal.
It's horribly unpleasant,
but, uh... there's an antidote.
Then give it to me!
Unfortunately, our Doctor is the only one
authorized to administer it.
Maybe if you remembered
where he was...
[groans]
Mr. Neelix...
have you deliberately
poisoned this man?
Relax. He's just having gas pains.
Your actions are not only
against regulations--
Didn't I hear someone
threaten a mind-meld?
I was merely trying to encourage
the suspect to be more forthcoming.
-Yeah.
-[Gar groans]
I think he's getting
all the encouragement he needs.
-Excuse me, Doctor.
-What is it?
I need to prepare this patient
for discharge.
-I'm not finished with him yet.
-But Chellick's orders are to--
Are to discharge the patient
at the end of the shift!
The shift isn't over, is it?
-No, sir, but I need time in order--
-I'll tell you when he's ready.
[Allocator] Dr. Voje, report to Level Blue
to assist Dr. Dysek in surgery.
[quietly]
Voje!
I didn't realize
that any of this even existed.
-I need to talk to you.
-I don't have time.
I just got a message from the Allocator
that Dysek needs me.
I'm the one who sent for you.
I used his access codes.
Oh.
I need you to smuggle
my mobile emitter off Level Blue.
[Allocator] Time has expired
for treatment of patient B-1.
Proceed to patient B-3.
[sighs]
[Allocator] The medical hologram
has one minute to treat patient B-3.
You have to help me.
Twelve patients on Level Red are
being sent home because of you.
That's why we have to hurry.
We may still be able to save them.
You've already endangered my patients,
and now you're asking me
to risk my career?
Why should I help you?
Because I have a plan
to heal those patients.
That's what doctors do. We heal.
So, choose. What kind of doctor
are you going to be?
[Allocator] The medical hologram
has 30 seconds to deactivation.
You hear that?
How can I get you off this level?
Deactivate my mobile emitter
and put it inside this selenide medkit.
-It'll shield the signature.
-And then what?
Take it to Level Red
and reactivate me.
[sighs] What are you going to do
once you get to Level Red?
[Allocator] The medical hologram
has ten seconds to deactivation.
There's no time to explain.
You'll have to trust me.
I suspect young Dr. Voje
helped you escape.
He had nothing to do with it.
No matter. You're becoming
far too troublesome.
I'm going to have
to deactivate your program.
-Voje!
-[groans]
What's wrong with him?
-What are you doing?
-A little experiment in empathy.
You told me you were just developing
new treatment protocols.
A single protocol, actually.
You're only making things
worse for yourself.
As a matter of fact,
I'm making things worse for you.
I'm going to make you a patient
in your own hospital.
-What was in that injector?
-A neural blocker...
combined with the same virus
that afflicted Tebbis.
-I trusted you.
-And Tebbis trusted me.
You remember Tebbis, don't you?
Patient R-12?
-Maybe this will jog your memory.
-[electronic beeping]
-What are you doing?
-[Allocator] Patient R-12.
Species: Dinaal. Identity: Tebbis.
This is ridiculous! I'm not Tebbis!
But the Allocator thinks you are.
-How did you--?
-Simple.
The Allocator identifies patients
by reading blood factors.
I altered Chellick's by injecting him
with antigens from Tebbis.
Now, why don't we see
if we can get your condition treated?
Requesting one cytoglobin injection
for patient R-12.
-[electronic beeping]
-[Allocator] Treatment denied.
I order you to medicate me now.
Ordinarily, I would...
but if the Allocator says no...
-Is this some sort of revenge?
-Not revenge.
Leverage.
I want enough cytoglobin to cure
every infected patient on this level.
We don't have an adequate supply.
There's plenty on Level Blue.
Where it's being used
to prevent arterial aging.
Those patients will survive without it,
but a dozen people on this level won't.
I will not let them die.
-Entering orbit.
-Scan for the Doctor's signature.
[sighs]
He's dying.
As soon as we get the cytoglobin,
we'll be able to treat
all of the Level Red patients,
including him.
You said it yourself. Doctors heal.
We don't make patients sick!
I don't know any other way
to help these people.
[Chellick]
Dr. Voje...
I need the medicine now.
Sir, I only have a Level Red clearance.
You know I'm not authorized.
Then find someone who is.
I've got him. He's aboard a vessel
above the northern continent.
-Can you get a lock?
-It's not going to be easy.
His program seems to be interfaced
with the main computer.
Hail the ship.
They're responding, audio only.
[Allocator] This is Hospital Ship 42.
Allocation Module Alpha.
This is Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
I would like to speak with someone
regarding a member of my crew
who is aboard your vessel.
Administrator Chellick
is currently unavailable.
Then may I speak with someone else?
Only Administrator Chellick is authorized
to communicate with alien species.
Are we having a problem here?
Dysek. Finally.
I'm sorry. I had to tell him.
What are you waiting for?
Give me the cytoglobin.
-I don't think I can.
-What are you saying?
Cytoglobin isn't authorized
for Level Red patients.
-Dysek!
-I don't want to break the rules.
I made the rules!
Then you should be pleased
I hold them in such high regard.
I'm sorry, Captain. I can't transport him
without damaging his matrix.
Then you'll have to go
down there and get him.
[Torres]
Aye, Captain.
Chakotay.
Don't tell me you're allied
with this defective hologram.
No, but he has given me insight into
some of the intricacies of our system.
For example, did you know
if I don't request enough resources
for Level Blue this month,
I won't get what I need next month?
What are you talking about?
You know, Doctor, one way to increase
your allocation of resources on Level Blue
would be to increase
the number of patients.
I know at least a dozen people who
should be treated for... arterial aging.
Saving their lives would
be just a side effect.
Hmm. Perhaps we should have them
transferred to Level Blue.
If you're looking
for a second opinion, I concur.
Well... Chellick, what do you think?
It's absurd!
We'd have to transfer you
to Level Blue as well.
You'd get your cytoglobin.
Doctor.
-It's nice to see some friendly faces.
-We're going to get you out of here.
Who do we talk to about accessing
their main computer?
I'll be with you in a moment.
I'm with a... patient.
Do we have an agreement?
Yes.
You've managed to stay well
while I was away.
I'm giving you a clean bill of health.
You were only away four days.
A lot can happen in four days.
Injuries, infections... malfunctions.
As you said, I'm fine. Thank you.
I was wondering
if you'd mind doing me a favor.
I'd like you to give me a checkup.
Have you been experiencing problems?
No, but as you said,
I've been off the ship for a while,
interfaced with an alien computer...
Your program appears to be operating
within normal parameters.
Really?
What about over the past several days?
There's no indication
of diminished capacity.
No problems with my ethical subroutines?
None.
I see.
You seem disappointed.
While I was aboard that ship...
I poisoned a man.
-Deliberately?
-Yes.
I was trying to force him to let me
treat patients who were dying.
You were prepared to sacrifice
an individual to benefit a collective.
No offense, Seven,
but I don't exactly aspire to Borg ideals.
You were hoping your behavior
was the result of a malfunction.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but I must give you
a clean bill of health.