[Janeway] Captain's Log,
Stardate 54208.3.
Last month's datastream
from Starfleet never arrived,
so the crew is looking
forward to this one
with even more anticipation
than usual.
We could all use
some news from home.
Ah. There he is,
the man of the hour.
You sure are in a good mood.
Well, rumor has it you snared
the latest datastream last night.
Technically, it was this morning--
0200 to be exact.
- So where's my mail?
- Hmm?
Oh. Don't tell me
you lost another one.
I didn't lose
last month's datastream.
It never arrived.
- So what's the holdup this time?
- [sighs]
The transmission was
a little larger than usual.
It's jammed the transceiver.
Seven and I have been up
all night trying to download it.
Harry...
we can't go another month
without mail.
Oh, you won't. Trust me.
[sarcastic chuckle]
Any luck?
I've determined why
we've been having difficulties.
[beeping]
A hologram.
The transceiver wasn't designed
to store photonic data.
We have to get it out of there
before it degrades.
What are you doing?
Tying the transceiver into
the holodeck's pattern buffer.
Those systems aren't compatible.
You'll depolarize the relays.
Starfleet wouldn't have sent
this hologram if it weren't important.
I'm sure it's worth
a few burnt-out relays.
[electricity snaps]
[alerts bleeping]
You've overloaded
the transceiver.
But I saved the hologram.
Okay, ready when you are.
Lieutenant Barclay?
Uh, no, but he did design me.
I'm a walking, talking,
problem-solving interactive hologram.
You can call me Reg.
It's nice to meet you, Reg.
The pleasure's mine, Captain.
Harry, Seven...
I've been looking forward
to working with you.
- You have?
- I know--
You were expecting letters
from your friends and families.
But with any luck,
in a few days,
you'll be seeing them
face-to-face.
In three days' time,
Voyager is going to be
passing through Grid 898--
a sector of space occupied
by a red giant star.
Sensors detected it
a few days ago.
At this very moment,
a team of Federation scientists
is orbiting another red giant
in the Alpha Quadrant.
In 72 hours, they will target
its magnetic field
with a verteron beam,
creating a geodesic fold.
As a result,
a corresponding fold will open here
in the magnetic field of the red giant
that Voyager is approaching.
Space will be punctured...
these two points
creating a gateway
between the quadrants.
Our shields are useless
against geodesic radiation.
We toyed with the idea
of opening a fold ourselves,
but it didn't take us long to realize
we wouldn't survive the trip.
A lot's happened in geodesic research
since you've been gone.
I've brought schematics
for shield upgrades
to deflect the radiation
from the fold,
medical technology to provide
additional protection for the crew.
We've thought of everything.
Starfleet never mentioned you
in any of the previous datastreams.
Well, Lieutenant Barclay
didn't want to raise your hopes,
in case the plan
didn't live up to expectation,
but lucky for you,
it surpassed them.
What about
last month's datastream?
Why didn't we receive it?
Pathfinder tried sending
an unabridged version of my program.
It overloaded the MIDAS Array.
And the only casualty this time
was our transceiver.
If everything goes according to plan,
you won't need it anymore.
If we were to attempt this,
you'd need access
to areas of this ship
that aren't equipped
with holo-emitters.
Not to worry, Captain.
We've thought of that, too.
My emitter is your emitter.
Computer, transfer the Barclay
hologram to the mobile emitter.
- [beeping]
- [Computer] Transfer complete.
On Lieutenant Barclay's
behalf, I thank you.
Just make sure to return it
when we get to Earth. [chuckling]
[Chakotay] We're ready for you
in the briefing room, Captain.
Excuse us, Doctor.
I'm sure you have a full day planned,
but if you have time,
I'd like to get
better acquainted.
I'll stop by
the first chance I get.
You'll know where to find me.
This is our destination--
Red Giant 23139.
The geodesic fold
will open here,
adjacent to the giant's
northern pole.
We'll have exactly 16 seconds
to take Voyager through.
Reg has prepared
a list of assignments.
I expect you to give him
your full cooperation.
Mr. Paris, you have the honor
of plotting our course to Big Red 2.
Lieutenant Torres,
Commander Tuvok,
I'd like you to start working
on shield modifications.
And in the meantime,
I've asked the Doctor
to prepare a series
of inoculations
that will protect the crew
from the radiation.
We should discuss
the possibility
of applying Borg technology
to Starfleet's plan.
It could increase
our chances of success.
I look forward to hearing
your thoughts.
How long before
the transceiver's back on line?
No more than two hours.
Then we'll still have time
to transmit a response to Starfleet.
Keep us posted.
I'd like to send
Lieutenant Barclay
a little thank-you note
for all his hard work.
Um, uh, is there...
is there anything
I can do, Reg?
Your job might be
the most important one of all.
The next few days
will be difficult.
The crew will be working
extremely long hours.
They're going to need an
experienced Morale Officer
to keep their spirits high.
You can count on me.
If this were any other ship...
I'd have my doubts.
But this is Voyager,
"the miracle ship."
You've survived six years
in the Delta Quadrant.
You've evaded the Kazon,
the Vidiians, the Hirogen.
You've even faced down the Borg.
I think, with a little teamwork,
we can pull off one more miracle
and take Voyager home.
I can taste
my mom's cooking.
Don't forget what
the hologram said, Harry:
- "This is Voyager".
- "The miracle ship"!
Uh, not when it comes
to getting us home.
Our shortcuts have a tendency
to blow up in our faces.
Well, that's looking
on the bright side.
Well, remember Arturis
and his quantum slipstream drive?
Or, um, or how about
the telepathic pitcher plant
that made us think
we were on our way home
right before it tried
to eat the ship.
This is the best opportunity
we've had.
Yeah, which is why we'll probably
end up in the Gamma Quadrant.
I'll remind you of that
when we get back to Earth.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
[Seven] When a Borg cube
enters a transwarp conduit,
it's subject to extreme
gravimetric shear.
To compensate, the Borg project
a structural integrity field
ahead of the cube.
By modifying
Voyager's deflector,
we may be able
to do the same.
No one at Starfleet
would have thought of this.
So, what's the first thing
you're going to do
when you get back?
Begin repairs to Voyager.
Even with the structural
integrity field,
it's likely the ship
will suffer significant damage.
Yes, but, I mean, there are
people at Utopia Planitia
who will take care of that.
There are engineering crews
and technicians...
Are you implying that
I am superfluous?
Of course not.
I only meant that if
you're too busy working,
you're going to miss all
the "welcome home" hoopla.
Starfleet's planning parties.
They'll have ceremonies
and speeches.
There, there's a ticker-tape
parade down Market Street.
I won't be attending
any of those events.
But you'd be
the guest of honor.
When I first arrived
on Voyager,
it was difficult
for the crew to accept me.
I'm anticipating
a similar welcome on Earth.
You don't have
any idea, do you?
I didn't mention this earlier.
I didn't want to hurt
anybody's feelings...
but you are the one
who people are most
looking forward to seeing.
That's difficult to believe.
- Why?
- I was Borg.
Exactly.
You were Borg,
but you escaped.
And despite incredible odds,
you managed to reclaim
your humanity.
No one's ever done that before.
You're famous.
Fame is irrelevant.
Maybe...
but you've given hope
to everyone who's ever
lost somebody to the Borg.
You've inspired millions.
If you think my participation
in the "hoopla"
would be beneficial to others,
then I'll comply.
Is this going to take
much longer, Reg?
Well, the computer
is still inputting data.
That should do it.
All right. Computer,
display the intended trajectory
of the datastream transmitted
at 0600 this morning.
Now, display the actual trajectory
and identify the termination point.
[Computer] The trajectory
ends in Sector 395...
42, Grid 8.
[sighs]
Does that sound familiar?
That's exactly where the datastream
dissipated last month.
There is something there.
There is something preventing
the datastream from reaching Voyager.
Uh, a micro-wormhole,
a radiogenic field...
Long-range scans
didn't pick up anything unusual.
Well, still, we could send
a ship to investigate.
We could confirm my theory.
What about my theory, Reg?
The hologram
was too complex.
It caused the data streams
to degrade
before they reached
their destination.
Well, to be honest,
I... I don't agree.
The truth is, we don't know
what happened to my hologram.
Then let's stick
to what we do know.
For the second month
in a row,
we tried sending
your hologram to Voyager.
And for the second month
in a row, it failed to get there.
And I want to know why,
so it doesn't happen a third time.
It won't happen a third time.
Next month, we go back
to standard transmissions.
But a holographic matrix
carries twice the information,
interact with the crew...
Admiral Paris wants us
to send more practical data,
like tactical upgrades,
letters from the crew's families.
But, Pete...
Sending a hologram to Voyager
was a good idea,
but it didn't work.
It's time to move on.
And this is
the research lab,
where most of Pathfinder's
homework gets done.
All the datastreams
are compressed here
and then transmitted all the way
to the Delta Quadrant.
Your teacher tells me
you've been studying
some of the Delta
Quadrant races
that Voyager
has described to us.
Who can name one for me?
The Talaxians.
Very good.
The Ocampa.
That's right. Who else?
[Barclay]
The Borg! The Borg!
They assimilated my hologram.
That's how it disappeared.
Reg, now isn't the time.
Look at this-- last month,
a spacecraft passed within 20 meters
of the MIDAS Array,
just hours before
we sent the first hologram.
- What is your point?
- 20 meters.
It's awfully close,
don't you think?
- Ensign--
- Look, the Borg must have sent
a transwarp probe
to steal my hologram.
Maybe because they-- they thought
that it was carrying
anti-Borg technology
to Voyager.
It wasn't the Borg, Reg.
Then it was the Romulans
using a cloaked ship.
They've been curious
about Voyager for years...
- That is enough.
- But, you...
I am sorry your idea
didn't work,
but I can't have you
going off on a tangent.
Not again.
You'll be no good
to Pathfinder or Voyager.
How much leave
do you have saved up?
Not that much.
50... maybe 60 days.
Take a week, go home.
Try to relax.
- But, Pete...
- No.
That was not a request, Lieutenant.
Maybe I'll go somewhere...
take a vacation.
Now that is the most sensible thing
I've heard you say all day.
My cousin has
a beach house in Malaysia.
She'd be happy
to lend it to you.
Thanks, um, but I have
someplace else in mind.
You, you wanted to see me?
I've been going over
the instructions from Starfleet Medical.
As far as I can tell, their "new"
inoculations aren't much different
from run-of-the-mill
radiogenic vaccines.
I don't think
they'll protect the crew.
Did you try incorporating
a synthetic antigen?
Yes, but it only improved
the resistance by 10 percent.
That should be enough.
[sighs] We can't afford
to be cavalier, Reg.
If these treatments don't work,
the crew will wind up liquefied.
You're forgetting
that the inoculations
aren't designed
to work alone.
They were intended to work
in combination
with the shield modifications.
It's the medicinal "ying"
to the shields' "yang."
A-and what if the "yang"
doesn't work?
That's not going to happen.
Now, listen, Lieutenant Barclay
has a special affinity for this crew.
So do I.
I promise you,
we won't let them down.
Of course you won't.
Tell me...
do you also share
Lieutenant Barclay's affinity for golf?
[laughs]
We have identical handicaps.
Well, if you're not busy later,
perhaps we could play nine holes
on the holodeck.
Eh, it's tempting, but I still have
a few dozen
progress reports to look over.
Well, in that case,
maybe you could
look over them here,
so that I could borrow
the mobile emitter.
Providing that the rest
of the day's work goes smoothly,
- consider it yours.
- I...
I thought it was mine.
Commander Chakotay tells me
that you finished
repairing the transceiver.
We were just about to send
the Captain's reply to Lieutenant Barclay.
Do you have enough room
to include a progress report from me?
I think we can squeeze that in.
Computer, download Barclay Hologram
File 01 to the data block.
[Computer]
Download complete.
Transmitting.
[beeping]
It's about time.
[Janeway] Greetings from
the Delta Quadrant, Lieutenant.
You'll be happy to know that
your hologram reached us safely...
Get to the important part.
In accordance with the
74th Rule of Acquisition,
"Knowledge Equals Profit",
I've enclosed the specifications
you've requested.
See you soon.
Oh, look at those hands.
I bet she gives great oo-mox.
Too bad she'll be dead
when she gets here.
Forget the hands.
Show me the nanoprobes.
How many are there?
3.6 million.
That's 20 percent more
than we predicted.
3.6 million nanoprobes
at six bars of latinum per unit.
Uh, that comes to...
More profit than
we ever dreamed of.
[all laughing]
[laughing and conversing]
Your drink, sir.
Thank you.
Something to drink,
ma'am?
- I'm fine, thanks.
- Are you sure?
I've got a chocolate passion punch
with your name on it.
[laughing]
Reg?
Surprise.
Where's Commander Riker?
- He doesn't arrive until Friday.
- Oh.
The question is,
what are you doing here?
Just had some time off.
Your letter made this place
sound fun,
and just thought I'd join you.
Do you have any idea
how inappropriate it is
to follow your therapist
on vacation?
Please.
They might be watching.
Who?
The Borg, the Romulans.
I'm not sure yet.
Please...
Deanna, I need your help.
Commander Harkins is usually
willing to hear me out,
but this time, he wouldn't even
look at my evidence.
I'm not sure any of this
qualifies as evidence, Reg.
You don't believe me, either.
You think I'm imagining this?
Just like Pete?
The last time I saw you,
you were laughing, telling jokes.
You even sang a duet
with Data.
[laughing]
That was Commander La Forge's
birthday party.
You were a completely
different Reg that night.
Oh... things were better then.
- How?
- Well, for one thing
I had just finished the matrix
for my hologram,
and I showed Geordi
some of the specs that night.
He said he was proud of me.
What else?
Oh... the Dragons
had just won the pennant,
and I was still seeing Leosa.
You mentioned her at the party.
A teacher, right?
Everything was going so well--
my job, my personal life.
I started to think
maybe my luck was changing.
- And then you lost your hologram.
- [yells]
Admiral Paris was furious.
He said we'd-- we'd wasted
a transmission to Voyager.
Pete talked him into
giving us another chance,
but there was so much
pressure after that.
Did it put a strain
on your relationship with Leosa?
- She left me.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I went to her apartment.
She was gone.
There was no furniture,
no forwarding address,
not even a "Dear Reg" letter.
That must have been
very upsetting.
Mmm.
It's just my luck, right?
Lose the hologram
and the girl.
[Troi]
Tell me more about Leosa.
Oh. You would have
liked her.
She was sweet,
she was thoughtful
and such
a wonderful listener.
She would let me--
let me go on for hours.
[chuckles]
What did you talk about?
Oh. She was fascinated
by my work at Pathfinder
and, uh...
she didn't, uh...
she didn't find
any of it boring.
She made me feel...
interesting.
What do you feel
when we talk about her now?
Um, sadness, I suppose.
A little confusion.
I'm sensing
something else...
something beneath
the surface.
What?
I think you might be
sensing it, too.
What?
Suspicion, Reg.
You suspect her of something.
I suspect that she's happier
without me, if that's what you mean.
You think Leosa had something to do
with your disappearing hologram,
but you can't bring yourself
to admit it.
That's why you're projecting
your suspicions onto others.
You're in denial.
If there's any chance Leosa
did breach Pathfinder security,
you need to tell
your superiors.
I-- I'd be humiliated... again.
I'll go with you.
What about your vacation?
I'll be back here
before Will arrives.
Do you really think it's possible
that Leosa stole my hologram?
Why would she do that?
Maybe... maybe she wanted
something to remember me by.
[Janeway]
Captain's Log, supplemental.
With the help
of the Barclay hologram,
we've nearly completed
the modifications to Voyager.
As for Reg, he's becoming
extremely popular with the crew.
[Janeway's voice]
Imagine my disappointment
when I discovered that Lieutenant Paris
had eaten all the scrambled eggs.
[laughter]
It was pure,
unadulterated gluttony,
gastronomic conduct
unbecoming a Starfleet officer.
He knows it's my favorite breakfast,
but he ate them anyway.
We have an egg-mergency
here, people.
I want to know
what you plan to do about it.
Maybe I can replicate
some more, Captain.
Do it.
[applause and laughter]
[normal voice] Thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
He's not only programmed
to get us home, he does impressions.
You see, it's always bothered
Lieutenant Barclay
that he was uncomfortable
in large groups.
So he designed me
to be the life of the party.
[laughter]
I hope he's not too shy.
He's going to have 150 new friends
when we get back home.
If we get home, Harry, if.
Pardon my friend here.
He's convinced we're destined
to live out our days
in the Delta Quadrant.
[Tuvok's voice]
Your pessimism is illogical.
Perhaps a mind-meld would help
to alleviate your concern.
[laughter]
[Doctor]
Sickbay to Reg.
Please report to Holodeck 2.
On my way.
I was starting to think
you'd forgotten our tee time.
So, what'll it be?
Pebble Beach at sunset?
The back nine at Gedi Prime?
Actually, Doctor...
I'm afraid
something's come up.
I'm going to meet
with Seven of Nine.
Oh, really?
She's going to teach me
to play Kadis-Kot.
Uh, Reg...
when I agreed
to lend you my emitter,
I did it with the understanding
that you needed it for official business.
What's your point?
My point is that board games
aren't exactly crucial to your mission.
And I suppose golf is?
Reg...
I'll tell you what.
When we get back home,
we'll play as much golf
as you like.
Until then, let's try to keep out
of each other's hair.
What do you say?
[Admiral Paris]
State your name for the record.
Leosa.
L-e-o
s-a.
Occupation?
Dabo girl.
[Paris]
Dabo?
It's a Ferengi game.
I work aboard
one of their casino ships.
You-- You told me
you were a teacher.
Is this true?
Sometimes I'm a teacher.
Sometimes I'm a Bajoran vedek.
[laughs]
Whatever the customer wants.
Lieutenant Barclay tells me
that the two of you
have spent a significant amount
of time together.
Did he ever discuss his work
at Pathfinder with you?
Oh. Wouldn't talk about
anything else.
It was always holograms this
and cyclic pulsars that.
And who did you share
that information with?
Nobody.
I have a theory.
Would you like to hear it?
Why not?
I think that some
of your Ferengi friends
found a way to profit
from Lieutenant Barclay's work.
I think you were encouraged
to get close to him,
and when you had all
the information you needed,
you left him.
I left Reg
for one simple reason.
He's boring.
[door opens, closes]
Don't tell me you never noticed.
With the Admiral's permission,
I'd like a moment alone
with Leosa.
I don't think therapy is what
this woman needs, Counselor.
Five minutes, Admiral.
Five minutes.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Did you know
I'm a Betazoid?
I'm empathic,
which means I know
when people are lying.
Tell me, what's the longest
you've ever been incarcerated?
[laughs]
You can't send me
to prison, Counselor.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Maybe not, but I can order you
held for psychiatric observation.
Extended observation.
I may not be a Betazoid
but I work a dabo table,
and I know
when somebody's bluffing.
Try me.
You were correct, Admiral.
The Ferengi did steal
Reg's hologram-- twice.
This is the ship
you need to look for.
[Leosa]
That's it.
That's Nunk's ship.
- Nunk?
- My... employer.
Scans indicate they've been
in the vicinity
of that star
for the last 43 hours.
Why?
I don't know.
She's telling
the truth...
for once.
The Ferengi wouldn't
have stolen the hologram
if they didn't think
it was valuable.
They're probably waiting
to rendezvous with a buyer.
Are there any Starfleet ships
in that area?
The Carolina is
.7 light-years away.
At maximum warp,
it could reach them in two hours.
Open a channel.
Computer, open a secure channel
to the Carolina.
[Paris] Tell Captain Peterson
to adjust his course immediately.
Was everything that happened
between us a lie?
Not everything.
Just the parts where I expressed
affection for you.
[groans]
Oh...
if it makes any difference,
it wasn't personal.
It was just... business.
What exactly is a broken heart
worth these days, hmm?
Ten percent.
Of what?
Profits from
the nanoprobes.
- Nanoprobes?
- Mm-hmm.
- Borg nanoprobes?
- Yeah.
Gegis says they're worth
two billion times their weight in latinum.
Oh.
I don't think I quite understand
the problem, Doctor.
Are you aware that he's been
doing impressions of you?
You should hear
his Tuvok-- it's eerie.
It's disrespectful.
What do you want me
to do, deactivate him?
Just long enough to run
a diagnostic of his program.
His recent behavior may be indicative
of a more serious problem.
I haven't seen
any evidence of that.
Of course not.
In front of you, he's all smiles,
but I've seen him be...
rude and careless,
two traits the real
Lieutenant Barclay never exhibited.
I know the real Barclay
is a friend of yours,
and I'm sorry
if the holographic version
hasn't lived up
to your expectations,
but that's hardly reason
to deactivate him.
Are the lives of 150 crewmen
reason enough?
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I am overreacting,
but what if I'm right?
We're less than a light-year away
from the geodesic fold.
Do you want to risk
being led through it
by a malfunctioning hologram?
Captain, you saved us
a com call.
We're ready to bring the
enhanced shielding on line.
Good work.
I need a moment alone with Reg.
Your program has been
running continuously
for how many hours now?
56 hours, 11 minutes
and 21 seconds.
I'd like to run
a diagnostic of your matrix,
make sure you haven't
suffered any degradation
over the last few days.
This isn't the, uh...
Doctor's idea, is it?
He expressed some concern
for your well-being, yes.
I bet he did.
Believe me, Reg, the crew and I
are grateful for everything you've done,
but we need to take
every precaution.
I understand perfectly.
And if the ship's Doctor thinks
I need a checkup,
who am I to argue?
Why are you hiding
in the corner?
I'm not hiding.
I'm working on a way
to foil the Ferengi's plans.
Reg, there's nothing
left to foil.
The Carolina will have them
in custody within the hour.
Leosa said the Ferengi
were going to be selling
Borg nanoprobes.
What does that have to do
with Voyager?
They have a Borg crewman.
Think about it.
The Ferengi stole the original
Barclay hologram a month ago.
That gave them time
to reprogram it
and then smuggle it to Voyager
in the next transmission.
Reprogram it to do what?
Steal Seven of Nine's
nanoprobes.
For all we know, he could be
dissecting her right now.
What would the Ferengi want
with assimilation technology?
Oh, nanoprobes
aren't just for assimilating.
They can reanimate
necrotic tissue,
slow down the aging process.
They'd be priceless
for the Ferengi.
Reg, even if the Ferengi
did reprogram your hologram
to steal the nanoprobes,
how would they get
their hands on them?
Voyager's
30,000 light-years away.
I haven't figured
that part out yet.
Maybe they discovered a--
a wormhole or a subspace corridor.
Have you mentioned any of this
to Commander Harkins?
Not yet. I can't.
If I don't bring him
hard evidence,
he'll just think
that I'm fantasizing.
For the time being, we need
to keep this between us.
That tickles, Lieutenant.
Sorry, Reg,
we're almost finished.
Have you identified
any problems yet?
I've gone over
his entire matrix.
He's working perfectly.
Maybe I'm not the one
who needs a diagnostic, hmm?
I'm a big enough hologram
to admit when I'm wrong.
I'm sorry I doubted you.
Well, if anyone is owed
an apology, it's you.
I should've been more sensitive.
Friends?
Friends.
Now that that's
out of the way, Captain,
what do you say we get
this ship back to Earth?
[beeping]
It's time.
Initiate the geodesic pulse.
[Admiral Paris] Would someone care
to tell me what that is?
It's a geodesic fold, Admiral.
That's how they're going
to get the nanoprobes.
Two million kilometers
and closing, Captain.
Take us to
one-quarter impulse.
Bridge to Astrometrics.
Bring the enhanced
shielding on line.
Aye, Commander.
[alarm sounds]
What's wrong?
The fold contains three radiation types
we didn't account for.
The shield modifications
are not enough.
Well, the shields
were modified
to work in combination
with the inoculations.
We'll be fine.
If the shields fail,
the inoculations will be irrelevant.
- Astrometrics to the Bridge.
- [Janeway] Go ahead.
[electrical crackling]
What is it, Seven?
[Seven's voice]
There was a problem, Captain,
but I've corrected it.
[beeping]
I'm using the MIDAS Array to tap
into the Ferengi ship's sensors.
They're receiving telemetry
through the fold.
If I'm reading this correctly,
Voyager's headed right for it.
Captain Janeway knows better
than to take her ship
into such a dangerous anomaly.
If the Ferengi did alter
my hologram, then...
it might... might be possible
for him to have taken over the ship.
One hologram
against an entire crew?
He may have found a way
to incapacitate the crew
or to commandeer
the ship's systems,
but either way, we've got to get
the Carolina to close the fold.
The Carolina isn't
equipped to do that.
Then they'll have to commandeer
the Ferengi ship and do it from there.
The Carolina's still
half a light-year away.
They won't make it in time.
Can we transmit a message,
warn Voyager?
Not through
a geodesic fold.
Our own starship,
with multiphasic shielding
and a gold-pressed
latinum hull.
We'll have enough left over
to buy a fleet of casino ships!
I have a better idea--
lobe enlargements!
- [console beeping]
- Shh!
Ooh, someone's
hailing us.
Who?
I can't tell.
There's too much interference.
Answer it.
It's the hologram.
You said it was impossible
to communicate through the fold.
I thought it was.
I guess I did a better job
of reprogramming the hologram
than I thought.
[static]
We must close
the geodesic fold immediately.
Captain Janeway
has found out about our plan.
If that's true,
then why is she still
headed for the fold?
Because she...
found a way
to protect her ship.
Impossible.
You don't know Janeway.
She's uncanny
when it comes to shields.
She's furious.
She said she was going to kill
whoever tried to harm her crew.
I strongly suggest
you abort the mission.
What should we do?
Go to warp before Janeway
makes it through.
No, you mustn't!
Voyager has Borg interquadrental
warp drives and...
Hirogen hunting sensors
and Vidiian phase torpedoes.
No matter where you run,
Voyager will find you.
Your only hope...
is to close the fold.
Harkins to Holodeck 1.
[Barclay]
Go ahead, Pete.
It worked, Reg.
They've started
to close the fold.
[sighs]
Computer, end program.
[console beeping]
Something's wrong, Captain.
[Barclay]
Astrometrics to the Bridge.
Why are we stopping?
The fold's collapsing, Reg.
We didn't make it in time.
It's not too late
if we remodulate the shields.
I appreciate your determination,
but we can't risk it.
You did everything you could.
[console beeping]
Captain, someone just initiated
a site-to-site transport.
Who?
Seven and Reg.
They've beamed
to an escape pod.
Bridge to Seven of Nine.
What's going on?
The pod's been launched.
Put a tractor beam on it.
There is too much interference
from the fold.
Harry, can you get
a transporter lock?
[beeping]
What now?
There's something
coming through the fold.
- Voyager?
- No, it's too small.
A phase torpedo!
Raise shields!
Brace for impact!
[muffled crash]
It's an escape pod.
Maybe the hologram
sent us the drone.
Ooh...!
Check what's in there.
Nothing.
No Borg corpse,
no nanoprobes.
No profit.
[all sigh]
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Seven of Nine has recovered
from her injuries
and "Reg" has been deactivated.
Until we finish
analyzing his program,
his motivations
remain a mystery.
Making first contact
with a new life-form?
"Mom's apple pie."
Neelix thought a little home cooking
might cheer me up.
And...?
I haven't worked up the courage
to taste it yet.
Have you figured out
what went wrong with Reg?
Well, Seven thinks our proximity
to the fold degraded his matrix,
but if you ask me, it was
a recursive error in his logic subroutine.
[sighs]
Not bad...
but it would have tasted better
in San Francisco.
If it'll make you
feel any better,
I'll let you in
on a little secret.
I was on the Bridge
this morning
when we received a hail
from an Iconian scientist.
He claims to have
a transdimensional gateway
that can take us anywhere
in the galaxy.
I'm not that gullible.
It's true. I was there.
The Captain doesn't want us
to get our hopes up,
but personally, I think we'll
be home by the end of the week.
Are you serious?
[chuckles]
You were right about him.
Computer, install Barclay
Security Protocol 21-Alpha.
Installation complete.
Identify yourself.
C-computer, deactivate
Barclay program.
I'm sorry.
I-- I've been programming him
with new security precautions
s-so he can't be stolen again.
You seem to be off
to a good start.
I thought you'd, uh,
be back at the beach.
Will and I decided to spend
the rest of our vacation in Tiburon.
We were wondering
if you're free for dinner tonight.
Uh, I, oh...
Oh, I, uh, I-I wouldn't want
to be a "third nacelle."
Not possible.
Will's bringing
a friend for you.
Her name's Maril.
You're going to adore her.
I'd like to,
but I-- I still have, uh...
dozens of protocols to install.
Maybe next time.
Look, Reg,
I know Leosa hurt you,
but hiding inside a hologrid
isn't the answer.
You need to get out,
meet new people.
This Maril wouldn't happen to be
a dabo girl by any chance?
She's a teacher, actually--
a real one.
- Are you sure?
- Don't worry, Reg.
We've taken
security precautions.