[groans] Ensign Kim,
please try and hold us steady.
This material is extremely fragile.
Sorry, Doc,
I'm doing the best I can.
Maybe I should have insisted
on a more experienced pilot,
like Mr. Paris.
Oh, I'd give anything
to trade places with him right now.
Seven, can you join me, please?
On my way.
I don't know if I can take three more days
of chasing comets with him.
The time might pass more easily
if we disable his vocal processor.
I thought you might
find this interesting.
Pre-animate biomatter.
Look deeper.
An undeveloped nucleus contained
in a cytoplasmic matrix.
And buried deep inside
that nucleus--
primitive strands of DNA.
The beginnings of life, Seven.
What's your point?
When I look at this,
I don't see a mere cell.
I see the potential
for literature and art,
empires and kingdoms.
Perhaps your visual subroutines
are malfunctioning.
[sighs]
Someday...
this cytoplasmic matrix may fall
into the primordial sea
of a distant world,
where it could ignite
an evolutionary process.
Eons from now,
a creature not unlike you
could emerge,
look up at the stars
and ask, "Who am I?
How did I come to be?"
It's the miracle of creation,
Seven.
Doesn't that excite you?
Ensign Kim, I asked you
to hold us steady.
We're under attack!
This is the Federation Ship
Delta Flyer.
We're on a peaceful mission.
Hold your fire.
[Male] You're transporting
a suspected photonic insurgent
through Lokirrim space.
Drop your shields
and prepare to be boarded.
Photonic insurgent?
I--If you're referring
to the hologram,
he's our Doctor.
Seven, we've lost thrusters.
I'll try reinitializing
the driver coils.
[Kim] Voyager, this is the Flyer.
Mayday!
Come in.
[Computer] Subspace
communications are off-line.
[Seven]
It's a tractor beam.
Remodulate our shields.
That should break us free.
Shields are down.
[garbled]
What's happening?
They're using
some kind of disruption field.
It's decompiling your matrix.
[Male] Federation vessel,
power down your systems
and prepare to surrender
the photonic.
Seven, they're pulling us in.
You're going to have to hide
the Doctor's program.
Do something, please.
We don't want to hurt you.
We're here for the insurgent.
Where's the photonic?
You decompiled his matrix.
You murdered him.
Seven?
I'm sorry.
There wasn't enough time.
Biogenic material.
It could be used
to create viral weapons.
Confiscate it.
Our Doctor was using
these spores
to synthesize new medicines,
not weapons.
What's this?
It's my portable
regeneration unit.
I have a unique physiology.
This device maintains
my cybernetic systems.
- Have this analyzed.
- [Male] Yes, sir.
There's no one else aboard.
Take them to detention,
and secure their ship
in the Docking Bay.
You got what you wanted.
Let us go.
Transporting photonics
and manufacturing biogenic
weapons are serious charges.
Let's go.
I want to talk
to your superior!
[grunting]
[grunts]
Careful, Ensign,
or you'll fracture a metacarpal.
That'd be the least
of our problems.
The situation is not
as desperate as it appears.
Not as desperate?
We're prisoners
on an alien ship.
Voyager has no idea
we're missing,
and the Doctor's
been decompiled.
The reports of my decompilation
have been greatly exaggerated.
Doc?
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Seven downloaded my program
into her cybernetic matrix.
An interesting sensation,
to say the least.
And now you're in control
of Seven's body?
Total control, it seems.
What about Seven?
Is she all right?
I scanned her before the aliens
came aboard.
Physiologically, she's fine.
As for her consciousness,
I'm assuming it's submerged,
but there's no way to be sure,
until I vacate her systems
and conduct a neurological exam.
Then we need
the mobile emitter.
This experience will make
a fascinating article
for the Starfleet
Medical Journal.
Ow.
Careful.
That's not your body, remember?
I knew Seven's senses were more acute
than the average humanoid, but...
I had no idea.
[sniffs]
What is that?
What?
That smell.
[sniffs]
I don't smell anything.
[sniffs] It could be
an airborne toxin.
Do you think
they're trying to poison us?
[both sniffing]
[sniffing]
It's you.
[sniffs]
It's been a busy day.
I guess I'm perspiring a little.
A little?
[sniffs]
Seven's had a busy day, too,
and she's come through it
smelling like
the proverbial rose.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54238.3.
We've completed
our maintenance layover
at the Maldorian Station,
and we're on our way
to rendezvous with the Delta Flyer.
We expect to reach them
in 48 hours.
[Paris]
Headache, fever,
respiratory distress,
tremors.
Looks like some kind of virus.
It is not a virus.
You want to tell me
what's going on?
In the Doctor's database,
you'll find a medication
under file Theta-12-Alpha.
Please replicate it
immediately.
You know I can't give out medicine
without knowing what it's for.
If you must know, I am suffering
from a neurochemical imbalance.
An "imbalance"?
It is native to my species.
Oh... this wouldn't be
the kind of imbalance
that comes around
once every seven years?
My pon farr is
in the early stages.
The urges are still controllable.
You never fail
to amaze me, Tuvok.
A man of your advanced years
still driven by the mating instinct?
Unlike in humans, the Vulcan
libido increases with time.
Well, I guess there has to be
some kind of reward
for all that Vulcan discipline.
The Doctor anticipated my needs
and developed a treatment.
Combined with meditation,
it will enable me
to control the symptoms.
Well, if that doesn't work,
there's always a cold sonic shower.
I'll tell the Captain
that you'll be out of commission
for a couple of days.
She will want to know why.
Well, according to my tricorder,
all we've got here
is a mild case of the Tarkalean flu.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
[door opens, closes]
Mmm! I had no idea
that eating was such a...
sensual experience.
The tastes, the textures,
feeling it slide down
Seven's esophagus.
It's... it's exquisite!
They're prison rations.
My uniform probably tastes better.
You know,
I was thinking.
When we get back to Voyager,
perhaps you and Seven
could help me modify
my physical parameters.
- Why?
- So I can eat, of course,
like any other member
of the crew.
There's just one small problem--
you don't have a stomach.
Where is the food gonna go?
I believe we can construct
a holographic stomach.
It can store the food
for eventual recycling.
Eh... maybe we should focus
on something more productive,
like getting out of here.
Relax, Ensign.
Our shipmates have never
let us down before.
I'm sure the Captain will clear up
this little misunderstanding.
In the meantime,
are you going to finish that?
[clattering]
[giggling]
[Female] You!
Come with us.
I'm the senior officer.
If you're going
to take someone, take me.
My orders were specific.
Don't worry, Ensign.
I can take care of myself.
Mmm. My compliments
to the chef.
The prisoner, sir.
Pulse-phased weapons,
duranium-enforced hull. Hmm.
Much more sophisticated than
the typical smuggler's vessel.
How many ways do you
want me to say this?
We are not smugglers
or terrorists.
We are explorers.
Let us contact our ship.
Our Captain
will explain everything.
If you're innocent,
then you won't mind
telling me more
about this vessel.
[sighs]
For instance, um...
this device.
What does it do?
That's a standard
food replicator.
Can it be used to create
bioweapons?
Not unless you count
Mr. Neelix's Bolian soufflé.
Let me show you.
Computer, one slice
of New York cheesecake.
This is an old
Earth delicacy.
How do I know you're not trying
to poison me?
Oh, please.
Mmm...
Mmm!
Oh...
Oh, I never imagined... Mmm!
Is this the first time
you've tried that?
Of course not,
but it's just that I usually...
avoid foods
that are this... rich.
I do have a figure to maintain.
Oh, I better get
another for you.
Uh, computer,
another slice of cheesecake.
Uh... here.
Mmm.
What other foods
can that device create?
Hmm...
[Seven and Ranek laughing]
[Seven]
Oh... during my time with the collective,
we assimilated
thousands of cultures
from one end of the galaxy
to the other.
I'll say this for the Borg,
we certainly do travel.
[chuckling]
Oh, of course, my life
didn't truly begin
until I came aboard Voyager
and met the person who...
who changed my life,
the only one who
truly believed in me,
saw my true potential...
Your Captain?
Our Doctor.
That's right, the "photonic."
If only you could have
known him.
Ruggedly handsome, a sharp wit,
a towering intellect...
If he and I hadn't been
colleagues, well...
Now we'll never know
what heights he could have reached.
I hope you understand,
I had no choice.
"I was just following orders."
I've heard that before.
Maybe there's something
I could do for you.
Uh, I-I'll speak to my superiors,
ask for leniency.
Hmm. If I survive that long.
What do you mean?
My cybernetic components
are already depolarizing.
I need my regener...
regeneration device.
As you can see, my motor functions
are already impaired.
Right.
If I give this... back to you,
will you do something for me?
It was so nice of you
to escort me.
Ah, nice to see you, Ensign.
- Are you drunk?
- It wasn't my fault.
Seven's unique physiology
is... unique.
It doesn't react well
to synthehol.
What happened?
Captain Ranek and I shared
a meal aboard the Flyer.
He's really a gentleman
once you get to know him.
You had a dinner date
in Seven's body?
It wasn't a "date."
It was a tactical maneuver,
designed to win the trust
of our captors,
and it worked.
I won't ask what you
had to do to get this.
Nothing unladylike,
I assure you.
They lost their medic
in a recent skirmish,
and I offered
to take his place.
Let's download your program
before they change their mind.
Hey, careful where you point
those tubules.
Sorry.
Easy.
How do you feel?
I'm impaired.
You've had quite a shock
to your system.
Let me explain what's happened.
I know exactly
what's happened.
You've been abusing
my body.
- I'm a doctor!
- Shh!
I would never abuse
your body.
I was trying to get information.
Sometimes a, a glass
of wine can...
loosen the tongue.
One glass.
That doesn't excuse
the other eight.
Was it that many?
[chuckling]
[Kim] Seven, you were aware
of everything?
Painfully.
I'm afraid the role of "spy"
wasn't written into my program.
I was forced to...
improvise.
You "improvised" your way
through an entire cheesecake,
as well as three servings
of Ktarian chocolate puffs.
Now I have to suffer
the consequences.
I apologize if I...
overindulged.
I'll be more careful next time.
There won't be a next time.
I'll be discovered.
They'll decompile my program.
Shh!
I know this is difficult for you,
but you're going to have
to put up with it
until we can get out of here.
How do you propose
we do that?
Maybe you can tap
into their com system,
get a message to Voyager.
Deciphering alien computers
isn't exactly my forte.
But it is one of mine.
If you can get close enough
while they're accessing their systems,
I'll be able to observe
their command protocols.
[Male]
What's the situation?
[Female] The Captain wants
the female prisoner in the Medical Bay.
We should proceed.
[groans]
You're saving my life.
I want you to know
how grateful I am.
Try to remember that
the next time you're tempted
to overindulge.
[deeply inhales and exhales]
Photonics' viral weapon
attacks the cerebral cortex.
Within days, the victims suffer
complete synaptic failure.
Well, if we can't stop the virus,
we may be able
to slow its progress.
We need to synthesize
a neural inhibitor.
Forgive me, but aren't you
the ship's Tactical Officer?
Tactical Officer,
Medic, Engineer.
We've lost nearly a third
of our crew to the photonics.
Well, you certainly know your way
around a medical bay.
[chuckles] You may have
missed your true calling.
Actually, Emmik always thought
I'd become a teacher.
He used to call me
"the little professor."
Who's Emmik?
The photonic who helped
raise my brother and me.
He knew more about treating
scrapes and bruises
than any organic doctor
I ever met.
Sounds like someone
I'd enjoy meeting.
Maybe...
before he joined the insurgency.
Why did he do that?
I ask myself that question
every day.
We never treated him
like a servant,
but he turned against us anyway.
Is it... possible
he felt... subjugated?
I don't see how.
He lived his own life,
pursued his own interests.
He was part of our family.
At least I thought he was.
We should get back
to the patient.
It could take up to a day
to determine if the inhibitor is working.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
Thank my ship's doctor.
He taught me everything
I know about medicine.
And remember--
he was a photonic.
Actually, you have a lot
in common with him.
He was something
of a jack-of-all-trades, too.
I suspect you'd have
gotten along famously.
I'm certain he would've taken
a liking to you.
[panting]
Your neurotransmitters
aren't absorbing the medication.
Can you increase
the dosage?
Not without causing damage
to your neocortex.
The Doc might be able to synthesize
a stronger medicine, but...
I'll make the best
of the situation until he returns.
I do have one area of expertise
that might help--
the holodeck.
I am a married man.
Look, it's the holodeck, Tuvok.
It doesn't count.
Is that what you tell
your wife?
No, of course not.
My days of rescuing slave girls
from Planet 10 are history.
Look, you have photographs
of your wife, right?
Well, the computer can
use them to create a replica.
It wouldn't be breaking your vows
if it's a hologram of your wife.
As it was in the dawn
of our days,
as it will be
for all tomorrows,
to you, my husband,
I consecrate all that I am.
T'Pel, my wife,
from you I receive
all that I am.
As it was in the beginning,
so shall it be now.
Two bodies; one mind.
I'm picking up a vessel
closing at high impulse.
They're firing.
- Shields are holding.
- Open a channel.
This is Captain
Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
We're on a peaceful mission.
We've detected photonic activity
aboard your vessel.
Drop your shields
and prepare to be boarded.
Photonic activity?
Tuvok-- he's in Holodeck 2.
They're firing again.
It's some kind of photonic disrupter
directed at Holodeck 2.
Target their weapons array
and fire.
[console beeps]
- They're hailing.
- On screen.
Drop your shields and prepare
to receive our inspection teams.
You're not in a position
to be making demands.
Why did you fire on us?
Your vessel is carrying photonics
through Lokirrim space.
We didn't realize
that was forbidden.
We'd be happy to shut down
our holodecks.
Your sensors should confirm
they've been deactivated.
You're still required
to submit to inspection.
Your sensors should also confirm
that our weapons are ready to fire.
We're both reasonable people.
I suggest a compromise.
Your vessel will escort us
through Lokirrim territory.
That way,
you can keep an eye on us,
make sure we don't reactivate
our holodecks.
The other alternative is...
we destroy your ship.
Your proposal is acceptable.
Sometimes diplomacy requires
a little saber rattling.
Begin long-range scans.
I can picture them now--
my father in his airponics bay
pruning his cona vines,
my mother reading
in her favorite chair.
Nothing in that home
ever changes.
It must be comforting to have
a place like that to go back to.
I've never been away
this long before.
His progress is remarkable.
I want you to know,
I'm going to tell my superiors
everything you've done for us.
First Ranek and now you.
I may become the first prisoner of war
to be decorated by his captors.
I know someone
who'd really enjoy meeting you.
Who?
My brother, Lohden.
Your brother?
You'd like him.
He's ambitious,
accomplished,
and he'd love
your sense of humor.
Hmm. Apparently,
it's my most attractive quality.
[Ranek] Seven of Nine,
please report to the Bridge.
Let me guess-- your crew
decided to abandon ship.
I wanted to thank you.
I had a wonderful time
the other night.
It's not often that I...
indulge myself like that.
It's been a long time
for me, too.
I remembered your interest
in stellar phenomenon,
so I requested a course change
to show you something.
What is it?
To an astronomer,
it's simply a pulsar cluster,
but our poets call it
the "Window of Dreams."
You could travel from one end
of the Quadrant to the other
and never see anything like it.
Lovely! Hmm.
[echoing sound]
It's the pulsar's EM fields
vibrating against our hull.
Huh.
I once thought this was
the most beautiful sight in the sector.
Hmm.
I see now
that I was wrong.
Hmm.
Oh. I almost forgot.
Oh, I promised a friend
I'd go easy on the synthehol.
[rhythmical beating]
Do you hear that?
It's identical to the rhythm
produced
by the eight-chambered
Ktarian heart.
Hmm.
Is something wrong?
Rapid pulse,
respiratory distress.
You may be having a reaction
to the pulsar's radiation.
We should get you
to the Medical Bay.
No, I'm not going to
the Medical Bay.
You starship captains
are all alike.
You can stare down the barrel
of a phaser cannon,
but you can't stomach
a simple medical exam.
I don't need an exam to know
what I'm suffering from.
[grunts]
[clears throat]
- I'm sorry. I thought...
- You were wrong.
I didn't mean to offend you.
It's just...
I've never met a woman
like you before.
That's because there are
no women like me.
- [annoyed sigh]
- Is something wrong?
Ranek summoned me
to the Bridge
under the pretext
of a little stargazing.
What he really wanted was to use
my face as a tongue depressor.
I'm surprised to hear that.
It was completely inappropriate!
That kind of behavior
would get a Starfleet Captain
reassigned to a garbage scow.
I'm not defending
what he did, but...
you have to understand,
we've been out here for a long time.
It's difficult to hide your feelings,
especially when you work closely
with someone you're attracted to.
You... have feelings for him?
[sighs]
I've known Lotharios
like Ranek.
Trust me, you don't want
anything to do with him.
You need someone who...
who can appreciate
your many talents.
Someone... overflowing
with intelligence
and compassion,
someone capable...
Ow!
[groans]
It looks like a spasm
in the trapezius.
I had no idea it could be...
so excruciating.
That's what happens when
you work so long without rest.
[groans]
Our last medic showed me
a technique that might help.
- I'll try it, if you like.
- Please, anything!
Oh, that...
that feels... wonderful.
Oh...
- Did I hurt you?
- No, no-no, no, no, no.
Well, then what's wrong?
[sighs]
There's something
you don't know about me,
something I have to tell you.
It's all right.
I know.
You do?
How could you?
Your cybernetic implants,
your portable regenerator?
You're not going
to tell anyone, are you?
I would never say anything
to the crew,
but Ranek knows.
He does?
Of course, it was apparent
the moment we scanned you.
I can't believe
you didn't say anything.
It wouldn't have been
appropriate.
You're part Borg.
It's nothing
to be ashamed of.
Ah. Mmm.
- Security to Medical Bay.
- This is Lieutenant Jaryn.
The prisoner is ill.
He's requesting treatment
by his crewmate.
Hmm.
[groaning]
Ensign.
Where the hell have you been?
I had to fake a seizure before
the guard would let me see you.
Calm down.
Seven and I have been
making progress.
- [sighs]
- Did you get a look at their computer?
During the one brief moment when
the Doctor wasn't indulging himself.
I think I've shown considerable restraint,
under the circumstances.
Kissing Ranek on the Bridge?
Is that your idea of restraint?
Kissing?
Not that it's any
of your business,
but if you must know,
Ranek kissed me.
And the massage you got
from Lieutenant Jaryn?
Entirely therapeutic.
You became sexually aroused
in my body.
When did it become a crime
to enjoy a sensation or two?
Of course, you'd be the last
person to understand that.
What do you mean?
The whole world is full
of experiences and sensations,
but you insist
on denying yourself.
Instead of replicating caviar,
you choose
nutritional supplement 13-Alpha.
Caviar is an indulgence.
Indulgences are what
make life worth living!
Shh!
These last few days
have been a revelation.
Feeling your lungs
fill with air,
the surge of adrenaline
through your veins.
Until I spent a day in your skin,
I never knew what I was missing.
You may have been
better off not knowing.
We're quite a pair.
Me, trapped by the limitations
of photons and force fields.
You, by a drone's obsession
with efficiency.
- You'd make an excellent hologram.
- All right!
Listen, you can argue all you want
when we get back to Voyager,
but that's not going to happen
unless we come up with a plan.
Did you learn anything
about their com system?
It can only be accessed
from the Bridge,
but I saw Ranek
enter his command codes.
If we can get
those codes to Voyager,
they may be able to disable
the shields and beam us out.
[sighs]
How are we going to do that?
The subspace transceiver
on the Flyer.
- Can you get aboard?
- It's heavily guarded.
I can get us aboard.
Captain, may I speak with you?
Privately.
I owe you an apology.
Well, I was the one
who acted inappropriately.
Oh, a kiss is hardly
a court-martial offense.
It's just that you...
caught me by surprise.
I-I won't make
that mistake again.
Perhaps, we should...
start over.
What did you have in mind?
Oh, we could start
with a toast.
- I thought synth...
- Oh, I can make an exception
for a... special occasion.
Computer, champagne,
two glasses.
To new beginnings.
Maybe there's
some hope for us yet.
As I've discovered recently,
anything is possible.
[exhales]
Computer, dim the lights.
Play EMH Music File
Gamma-12.
[waltz plays]
Oh.
This is interesting.
It's called a waltz.
Something else I learned
from our Doctor.
Captain Ranek,
please come to the Bridge.
What is it?
We've received
an encrypted transmission.
Oh, I'll be right there.
You're not leaving?
Um...
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
I really think
you should stay.
[groans then exhales]
Never play hard to get
with a hologram.
Still no sign of the Flyer's
warp signature.
I appreciate your
sense of duty, Tuvok,
but we can handle
the situation without you.
Under the circumstances,
abandoning my post
would be a dereliction of duty.
My illness is still
in the early stages.
I can control it.
If I remember correctly,
the last time you came down
with the Tarkalean flu
was seven years ago.
As soon as this is over,
the holodeck is at your disposal.
There you are, Commander.
Now, a person in your condition
really ought to be in bed.
This is my
grandmother's recipe,
guaranteed to cure even
the most stubborn flu.
Now... smell that?
- I don't smell anything.
- Exactly.
I prepared it
just the way you like it.
No herbs or spices
of any kind.
It's practically tasteless.
[communications beep]
We're receiving a hail.
- It's the Delta Flyer.
- On screen.
Seven, it's good
to see you.
I'm afraid there's no time
for pleasantries, Captain.
We're being held prisoner
on a Lokirrim patrol ship.
I'm sending you our precise location
and the command codes
to disable their shields.
Are the Doctor and Harry
all right?
Ensign Kim
is his usual chipper self.
As for me, I'm looking forward
to a long, uneventful shift in Sick Bay.
Doctor?
It's a long story, Captain.
Delta Flyer out.
They may be in more trouble
than we thought.
Set a course.
[Paris] Our escort isn't going
to take kindly to a detour.
What's the status
of their weapons?
They've repaired
their forward phasers.
Target their power matrix.
We may only get one shot,
so make it count.
Ready.
Do it.
Direct hit.
Get us out of here,
maximum warp.
What's wrong with him?
Apparently, Captain Ranek
has an even lower tolerance
for synthehol than I do.
That doesn't sound like Ranek.
It's probably not something
he'd admit to his crew.
We should keep this
between us.
What are you doing?
Reviving him.
I-I wouldn't recommend that.
Take her to detention.
Separate her
from the other prisoner.
There are traces of sedative
in your bloodstream.
What was your plan?
To aid the insurgents?
There was no plan.
We trusted you.
I'm still a prisoner
on your ship,
and despite our friendship,
my first obligation is to escape.
We were going
to recommend leniency.
If you knew who I really was,
I doubt you'd be trying
to help me.
Alien vessel approaching.
I want her
where I can see her.
[Tuvok]
They are raising shields.
Stand by with those
command codes.
Open a channel.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway.
We don't want a fight.
Return my people
and we'll be on our way.
Your people were caught
transporting
a photonic insurgent
and biogenic material.
We don't want
to disable your ship,
but we will if we have to.
We're losing
our ventral shield grid.
Compensate.
I'm trying.
They've tapped into
the shield matrix.
They're using your
command authorization.
They're rerouting power.
He's tying their shields
directly into the warp matrix.
If you fire on us,
you'll trigger a core breach.
You'll be killing the people
you're here to rescue.
End transmission.
Tractor beam.
Full reverse!
Target their emitters.
They've broken free.
Chakotay, can you send
a com signal
directly to Seven's cortical node?
[Janeway] Doctor, if you can hear me,
we need your help.
Try to disable their shields.
[grunting]
It's a photonic.
Cover me.
Stay back!
I'm not afraid to use this.
Hey. Whoa!
Step away.
[beeping]
She destabilized
the shield grid.
It's failing.
Watch them.
If you try to reinitialize the grid,
it'll overload.
We could all die.
Ranek, don't!
[yells]
Stay back.
I'm a doctor. Let me help.
Their shields are down.
I have a lock.
Away team,
stand by for transport.
I have injured here, Captain.
I can't leave yet.
He'll die
without immediate surgery.
I know this is difficult to grasp,
but I'm the person you've been
getting to know the last few days.
My program was in control
of Seven's body.
You're lying.
I know you have feelings
for Ranek.
If he dies, you're never going
to forgive yourself.
Your vital signs are stable.
Suppose I should be,
uh, grateful.
A "thank you" is customary
after someone saves your life.
What happened
was between me
and Seven of Nine, not you.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
The truth is, aside from
a few awkward moments,
I enjoyed our time together.
There are many women
who'd appreciate
an attractive man like you.
I'm just not one of them.
Um, more of our vessels
are on the way.
You should leave
while you can.
Thank you.
I guess you won't be
introducing me to your brother.
I'm not sure you're the kind
of person he's interested in.
You mean because
I'm a hologram.
[chuckles]
I don't imagine this experience
is going to change your feelings
about photonics.
But I wanted you to know...
I'm grateful for the time
we've spent together.
You're a talented doctor.
We're the ones
who should be grateful.
I'm glad I could help.
Doctor to Voyager.
One to beam out.
Commander...
it's good to see
you're over the flu.
I have fully recovered.
Thank you
for your assistance.
Oh, don't mention it.
I just hope everything was okay.
Not exactly.
My wife's ears are four millimeters
shorter than your facsimile's.
So I took a little
artistic license.
Aside from that,
was everything all right?
The hologram was adequate,
but no substitute for my wife.
Of course not.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
There isn't one... yet.
The Mess Hall
is three decks up.
In case you've forgotten,
I've lost my appetite...
permanently.
That doesn't mean you're
incapable of enjoying a meal.
Foie gras with truffles,
an ancient Earth delicacy.
Chateau d'Yquem.
According to
the culinary database,
the ideal accompaniment.
Not your usual fare.
It's come to my attention
that nutritional supplements
don't fully meet my needs.
I see.
I thought we could share
this experience.
I'll describe the meal to you...
the tastes, the sensations.
Perhaps you can enjoy it
vicariously.
What about the wine?
It doesn't exactly agree
with you.
If I become sick,
I won't have far to go.
To shared experiences.
Hear, hear.