Captain's Log,
Stardate 54274.7.
Lieutenant Torres
has finally convinced me
that I can't put off a major
maintenance overhaul any longer.
We've set down on
an uninhabited planet,
and I've sent shuttles
to search for supplies.
- What about the impulse upgrades?
- Day after tomorrow.
Put a new phase compensator
on that relay.
Environmental control?
The thermal regulators
are still running a little hot.
Too bad we can't just keep
the windows open.
How long until the warp drive
is back on line?
Six days.
You sure you can't get it done
any faster?
Captain, I don't like sitting
still any more than you do,
but repairs this extensive
take time.
[equipment powering down]
Mendez, track down
that power drain.
Right away.
I know this ship
has been through a lot,
but you told me this would
only take a few days.
That was before I discovered
the microfractures
in the starboard nacelle
and the fused relays
in the main computer.
Who did that?
I noticed a charge imbalance
in the EPS feed.
I'm sorry if I...
It could have taken us hours
to find that.
I have a tactical
systems report for you.
It's from Commander Tuvok.
I'd say you're capable of a lot more
than delivering padds, Icheb.
[Janeway]
I agree.
Until we get underway again,
he's assigned to you.
With him on your team, maybe
you'll get this job done a little faster.
[snoring]
Neelix?
[alarm blares]
Rise and shine.
It's 0500.
Already?
Oh!
Oh, I was dreaming
we found the dilithium
and were back aboard Voyager.
Dreaming is
an accurate description.
Didn't we already
scan this nebula?
Four times.
I thought the Borg
were known for being thorough.
The Borg value efficiency,
not redundancy.
I've got a hunch
about this nebula.
There's dilithium
in there somewhere.
[console beeping]
I'm getting some fluctuating
energy readings.
From the nebula?
No, it's weapons fire.
Let's get out of here.
We're receiving a distress call.
[staticky]
...have casualties.
Please help us.
We're on a humanitarian mission
delivering medical supplies.
Reverse course.
We can't just leave them.
Starfleet policy.
Interference in alien conflicts
is strictly prohibited.
You heard their Captain.
It's a medical ship.
- [beeping]
- Their shields are down.
Life support is failing
on at least three decks.
Open a channel to the other ship.
This is Ensign Kim
of the Delta Flyer.
I don't know what you're fighting about,
but it looks like you've won.
The people on the other ship
have casualties. We'd like to...
This isn't your concern.
I'm not taking sides.
I only want to help the wounded.
[rumbling]
Withdraw immediately.
They're charging weapons.
Neelix, set our deflector beam
for a narrow pulse.
Seven, let me know the second
their weapons array is fully charged.
I might be able to trigger
an overload.
[Neelix] The deflector bandwidth
is at .4 microns.
Now.
Their weapons are off-line.
Shields are down.
They're retreating.
Take the helm.
Neelix, you're with me.
[staticky popping]
[groaning]
Who's in charge here?
He is.
What are we going to do?
It's okay.
We're here to help.
The ship that attacked you
is gone.
Who are you?
Harry Kim from
the Starship Voyager.
We're responding
to your distress call.
We can treat your wounded.
The Captain?
Dead, sir.
So are the rest
of the officers.
I'm reading a total
of 27 life-forms aboard the ship.
There were 56 of us.
How are we going to get home
without the officers?
We need to restore main power.
Where's the warp interface?
We're passengers,
not crewmen.
You can access
engineering systems from here.
[sighs]
[Kim]
Your warp core's intact.
I think I can bring it
back on line.
Can you monitor
antimatter flow?
I'm not sure. I...
Just watch this readout,
and tell me if it starts to fluctuate.
[core powering up]
[Kim] I'm routing emergency power
to structural integrity.
Atmospheric pressure
is returning to normal.
Neelix, we'll go through the ship
deck by deck-- find the survivors.
We need to get our cloak
back on line.
I'll take a look at it as soon
as I've repaired the engines.
No. The cloak
is more important.
The Annari have far more powerful
weapons than we do.
If they come back,
the cloak is our best defense.
We'll try to get it
back on line.
- Kim to Delta Flyer.
- [Seven] Go ahead.
I need your help, Seven.
It looks like we're going
to be here for awhile.
How did you do it?
[Kim] Do what?
Disable the Annari warship
so quickly?
Uh, basically, we used
their own weapons against them.
How?
We used a deflector pulse
to overload their phaser banks.
[power whirring on]
[groans]
You know a lot
about engineering.
It's all part
of my Starfleet training.
Starfleet?
Yeah. The organization
I work for.
And they teach you
all these things?
We train at an academy,
and I guess I've picked up
a few new tricks
during my time on Voyager.
How long have you been Captain?
[laughs]
I'm just an Ensign.
Ensign? E... What's that?
A junior officer.
The lowest ranked officer,
actually.
This is my first
deep space assignment.
It hasn't gone very well.
Could you hand me that?
My first week on the job
didn't go very well, either.
We ended up 70,000
light-years from home,
lost over a dozen crew members,
but I got through it,
and so will you.
I hope so.
If you're going to be
a starship officer,
you've got to accept that
adversity comes with the job.
What's that?
It's a diagnostic
of the antimatter injectors.
No, I meant that stuff
you're eating.
Nutritional supplements,
replicated to meet
my metabolic requirements.
Sounds delicious.
You know,
in the Mess Hall,
they actually have tables
and chairs for that.
I prefer to work while I eat.
It's a more efficient use
of my time.
You did a great job today.
We're ahead of schedule
thanks to you.
Here's what we're going
to work on tomorrow.
I'll see you at 0600.
Icheb.
Yes?
What do you do for fun?
- Fun?
- Recreation.
How do you spend your time
when you're off duty?
Between my work and my studies,
I don't have much time for recreation.
I've learned that you've got
to take a break once in awhile.
I've been doing a lot
of rock climbing on the holodeck.
Maybe when we're finished
tightening all the nuts and bolts,
you'd like to join me.
I do have an interest
in geology.
It's not about the rocks, Icheb.
It's about the climbing.
Main power
has been restored.
All stations responding.
The cloak's back on line.
Impulse and warp drives
are standing by.
Shields are at 96 percent.
I'd say you're ready
to get back on course.
We appreciate your help.
- I hope you have a safe journey.
- Mr. Kim...
I feel guilty
asking even more of you,
but no one on this ship
knows how to fly it.
None of you
has ever piloted a starship?
I've trained in shuttles,
but nothing like this.
[sighs]
I'll enter a flight plan
in the auto-navigation system
and give you a quick course
in helm operations.
You shouldn't have any trouble.
Couldn't you take us?
This ship needs an experienced
commanding officer.
I'm sorry, but we've already gotten
more involved than we should have,
and they need us back on Voyager.
It's not just my ship
that concerns me.
You've made an enemy
of the Annari now,
but if you dock your ship
in our Shuttle Bay
our cloak will protect you.
That's a generous offer,
but we'll be fine.
Please, Mr. Kim,
we can't afford to fail.
- This ship is...
- Loken, don't.
We can trust these people.
[Loken]
I'm a doctor.
These people
are my research team.
We're carrying new vaccines
to our homeland.
They'll save thousands of lives.
Sir, I looked at their flight plan.
It takes them pretty
close to Voyager.
I'll bring you
as far as our ship.
When we get there,
you can discuss your situation
with my Captain.
Thank you.
What about
Starfleet policy?
This is a humanitarian
mission.
Dock the Flyer
in their Shuttle Bay.
We're approaching the planet.
Take us out of warp.
- Disengage the cloak.
- Wait.
I'm detecting three
alien vessels in orbit.
On screen.
[Crewman]
Those are Annari warships.
Your people are in danger.
I apologize
for the state of my ship.
- We weren't expecting company.
- I hope we're not imposing.
Not at all.
Making contact with new cultures
is a priority for us.
For us, too.
This is a fine ship, Captain.
One of the best in the fleet,
but it could use
a new set of deuterium injectors.
Any chance you could
provide them?
I think we can arrange something.
What are you offering
in exchange?
Zeolitic ore.
We mined several tons of it
from an asteroid field.
It's high-grade, easy to refine.
I'll speak to my supply officer.
[console beeps]
We're being hailed
by Ensign Kim, audio only.
Hello, Harry.
- Is everything all right?
- Of course. Why wouldn't it be?
Our long-range scans detected
several alien ships orbiting the planet.
I appreciate your concern,
but there's nothing to worry about.
We've made some new friends,
that's all.
When can we expect you back?
We've run into a slight delay.
Nothing serious, I hope.
No. Everything's under control.
Good.
Any luck finding dilithium?
Uh, I'm afraid not.
I'll tell the other teams
to keep looking.
- See you soon, Ensign.
- Yes, ma'am. Kim out.
Dilithium...
We can get that
for you, too.
Really?
She's formed an alliance
with our enemy.
Just because they're talking
doesn't mean they formed an alliance.
It's probably just
a friendly meeting.
That's how the Annari operate.
They come to you as friends,
and when they've won your trust,
they declare you subjects
of the Annari Empire.
Kim to Voyager.
We didn't expect you so soon.
Actually, Captain,
I'm closer than I let on,
and I've brought
some new friends of my own.
Our chances of getting home
without your help aren't very good.
We'd appreciate any assistance
you could offer.
I hope you understand.
I need to give this some thought.
You've put me in
a difficult position, Ensign.
We could use the help
the Annari are offering,
but if they find out
we're aiding their enemy...
I couldn't just stand by
and do nothing.
That doesn't justify getting involved
in somebody else's fight.
What would you
have done?
Probably exactly what you did.
I guess I learned from the best.
If this were simply an errand
of mercy, I wouldn't hesitate.
But the fact is, these people
are involved in an interplanetary war.
Captain, I've gotten to know them
over the last couple of days.
You met Loken.
They're scientists, not soldiers.
You've only heard
one side of the story.
You've taken sides before.
The Borg resistance,
the Vaadwaur...
Those were
different circumstances.
You were trying to help people
in need.
How is this any different?
Have you thought about applying
to the Advocate General's office?
You'd make a good lawyer.
[sighs]
I suppose I could spare
Chakotay or Tuvok for a few days.
That won't be necessary.
The Kraylor know me.
They trust me.
I'm sure they'd find Tuvok
or Chakotay just as trustworthy.
But they outrank me.
If you send one of them,
it won't be my mission anymore.
Your mission.
My first real command.
You've been in command
on Voyager before.
On the night shift,
for a few hours...
It's not the same thing.
You and Chakotay are always
a couple of decks away,
ready to take over
if anything goes wrong.
I've been on Voyager
for almost seven years,
and I'm still an Ensign.
If this is your way
of bucking for a promotion...
No, no, I understand
there's a command structure
and that our circumstances
are unique.
But the fact is,
if we were back home,
I'd be a Lieutenant by now,
maybe even
a Lieutenant Commander.
You're pretty sure
of yourself, aren't you?
I know I can do this,
and the Kraylor are giving me
a chance to prove it.
I expect you back before
we complete our repairs.
Yes, ma'am.
And I'm not
sending you alone.
- Captain.
- I want you to take Seven.
Since she has no rank,
you clearly outrank her.
Lieutenant Torres asked me to repair
a malfunctioning holo-emitter.
[sighs]
It's about time.
Whenever I move
to the far corner
of the Surgical Bay,
my legs disappear.
Seven of Nine told me
you gave her social lessons.
Hmm. She wanted to get along
better with the crew.
Social skills are one thing
the Borg never assimilated.
I was hoping
you could instruct me, as well.
I'd be delighted.
Lesson One:
"Making a First Impression."
Actually, I wanted to ask you
about something specific.
Fire away.
How can you tell
when someone has...
romantic feelings for you?
Icheb, this is a surprise.
Have you caught
someone's eye?
I'm speaking hypothetically.
Ah.
[clears throat]
Hypothetically,
there are various indications
of romantic attraction.
Compliments, for example,
invitations to social activities,
finding excuses to be
in close proximity with someone.
Yes, but couldn't those things happen
in a relationship that wasn't romantic?
I suppose.
Is there a way
to be absolutely certain?
Well, short of an open
declaration of affection,
there are some fairly reliable
physiological responses:
elevated blood pressure, increased
beta-endorphin production...
Thank you, Doctor.
You've been very helpful.
With my guidance,
you will master the nuances
of social interaction
in no time!
[Paris]
Harry!
[sighs]
Take me with you, buddy.
Sorry, Tom.
This is my mission.
Oh, come on, I've been itching
to get back into space
ever since we set down
on this dust bowl.
I'm tired of cleaning conduits
and replacing relays.
You're a married man now.
You've got family responsibilities.
Just leave the away missions
to the young, unattached guys.
That ship is in pretty bad shape.
You're going to need a good pilot.
No, thanks.
Wait a minute...
I know what this is about.
You do?
Sure. You've got a girl on that ship
you don't want me to know about.
[laughing]
There's no girl.
Not this time.
Then what is it?
[sighs]
I don't know how else to say this,
so I'll just say it.
You've always been
Captain Proton.
I have always been Buster Kincaid.
It's my turn this time.
[indistinct chatter]
I'm glad you're not planning to leave
on an empty stomach, "Captain."
I have plomeek soup
and eggplant parmesan.
- Either's fine.
- Wrong answer.
Excuse me?
If you're going to be a Captain,
you have to act like a Captain.
Never admit you're
uncertain about anything.
You can't be indecisive
in front of your crew.
It's just a snack, Neelix.
When Captain Janeway
comes in here,
she knows exactly
what she wants.
Maybe I'm just not as picky
about my food.
Whatever you say... Ensign.
Neelix.
Plomeek soup,
and make sure it's hot.
Captain on the Bridge.
Where did you learn that?
I've been studying
that Starfleet manual you loaned me.
Take your station,
Mr. Terek.
Aye, sir.
Course?
I'll do it.
Laying in a course,
heading 115 mark 37.
Does this ship
have a name?
Medical Transport 136.
I think we can do
better than that.
Nightingale.
The name of someone
from my homeworld.
She was famous for treating
wounded soldiers on the battlefield.
It's perfect.
Hail Voyager.
[communications beep]
Kim to Voyager.
We're ready to get underway.
[Janeway]
Acknowledged. Good luck.
See you in a few days.
Kim out.
Main power.
- On line.
- Tactical.
Shields and weapons
standing by.
Bring the cloak on line.
Warp 6.
Engage.
[Kim] Acting Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 54277.3.
My first day in command
has been challenging,
but I've loved
every minute of it.
I can't help feeling that this was
something I was born to do.
The hourly status report
you requested.
Thanks.
Why have you brought
these items aboard?
They make me
feel more at home.
We'll only be on this vessel
for a few days.
Decorating is an inefficient
use of your time.
It's important to forge
a personal connection
with your vessel;
make the ship your own.
Ask Captain Janeway.
I'll discuss it with her
the moment we return.
Is there anything else?
I asked Terek
to make a course correction.
He's never done that before.
I'd better check on him.
I believe he's capable
of doing it himself.
[sighs]
Status?
I've entered the new heading.
Looks like the guidance vector
is off by a couple of microns.
I was about to correct that.
You need to realign
the primary navigational sensor first.
Yes, sir.
And make sure it stays locked
on your guide star.
Here, let me show you.
I'm-I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
Don't worry about it.
Bumping elbows
comes with the job,
and you can call me B'Elanna.
Put this with the others.
These relays should have been
replaced a while ago.
It's amazing
they've held up this long.
I am really looking forward
to our climb.
Wouldn't you prefer to spend
your free time with your husband?
[laughs]
If it doesn't involve
a race car, a shuttle,
or something else he can drive,
Tom's not interested.
Besides, since we got married,
I see more than enough of him.
Hold still.
[alarm beeps]
What's that?
I'm reading a power fluctuation
somewhere in the propulsion system.
- It's destabilizing the cloak.
- All stop.
Core is stable.
That should take care of it.
Are you absolutely certain?
As a scientist, you should know
there's no such thing
as absolute certainty.
Perhaps we could run
a diagnostic before we...
That would take hours.
Captain Janeway wants us back
before Voyager finishes its overhaul.
The cloaking system is delicate.
It requires constant attention.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
you're a physician.
You have to trust me on this.
We'll monitor it closely.
Don't worry.
I simply want to ensure
that our mission is a success.
You asked me
to take command of this ship,
and that's what I'm doing.
Tell Terek to resume course.
I've discovered a serious flaw
in one of the ship's systems.
- Which one?
- The Captain.
The Captain's main function
is to issue orders, correct?
- Right.
- And the crew's function
is to support the Captain
and carry out those orders.
What's your point?
Every time you give an order,
you carry it out yourself.
And when someone else
makes a suggestion, you dismiss it.
These people are inexperienced.
They need my help.
When you first came aboard Voyager,
did Captain Janeway help you?
Sure. She looked after
all the junior officers.
By doing your work for you?
No. She gave me a lot to do,
actually.
Because she felt you were
more capable than she was?
Of course not.
She wanted me to learn,
to gain confidence.
Interesting.
Emergency power.
- Repolarize the containment field.
- I can't.
The cloak is going to fail again.
Don't panic.
This is a minor malfunction.
Minor? We're losing
our main defense system.
- [alarm sounds]
- [Terek] We've been detected.
Two Annari vessels are
closing on our position.
Correction--
six Annari vessels.
[rumbling, alarm sounds]
Evasive maneuvers!
Kim to Engineering.
Go ahead.
We need that cloak
back on line.
The primary generator
has failed.
I'm trying to...
[yells]
[Kim]
Seven?
Seven, come in.
You have the Bridge.
- We need you here.
- I'll go, sir.
All right. I'll give you
instructions over the com.
Charge phaser banks.
Target their weapons array.
Which ship?
The closest one,
off our port bow.
[groans]
Dayla to the Bridge.
Life support's failing
down here.
I've gotten everyone out.
Good work.
Now go
to the cloaking generator.
What's the field polarity?
206.4.
That's too low.
We're going to have to raise it.
I'm bypassing
the phase converter.
Wait. I didn't tell you
to do that.
Won't that increase
the field polarity?
- Yes, but...
- [coughing]
Listen to me carefully.
I want you to try...
Dayla, it's Loken.
- Take the warp core off-line.
- What are you talking about?
Bypass the driver coil and shunt power
directly to the polaron matrix.
[coughing]
The cloak is back on line.
Get us out of here,
full impulse.
Dayla, secure the Engineering section
and get back to the Bridge.
Dayla!
I'm not reading
any life signs in Engineering.
- Dayla?
- She's dead.
How's Seven?
She may be in shock.
I'm not sure.
Have a look.
Your opinion, Doctor?
I believe
she may be in shock.
Do you think we should give her
a cortical stimulant?
That might be indicated.
You are no doctor, are you?
You and I need to talk...
alone.
What the hell is going on?
I don't know
what you mean.
Nothing about this mission
is adding up.
It's obvious
you know a lot more
about cloaking systems
than biology.
So did Dayla.
And the second
our cloak failed,
half a dozen Annari warships
came after us--
one little medical transport.
The truth!
My colleagues and I have
been working at a secret base
but not to create vaccines.
We've been developing
cloaking devices for our fleet.
This ship is a prototype.
The Annari know we have it,
and they don't want us
to get it home.
I never would have agreed to this
if I had known
you had a military objective.
Our world has been under
an Annari blockade for three years.
The planet is protected
by a shield grid,
but it's almost impossible
to get our ships in or out.
I convinced Captain Janeway
this was a humanitarian mission.
It is.
The Annari are choking us
to death slowly.
If we can't get supply ships
through the blockade,
we can't get food
to our people...
or medicine.
For all I know,
that's another lie.
[door shuts]
Reverse course.
Sir?
- We're heading back to Voyager.
- I don't understand.
He knows about the cloak.
I would've told you...
- I gave you an order.
- What about the mission?
That's not your concern.
You want to be a starship officer?
Your job is to follow orders.
- Sir, I don't think you...
- This is not a debate.
You're under my command.
No, sir.
Not anymore.
You're relieved.
You, take the helm.
I believe you're the one
who's been relieved.
[humming]
Where are you going
in such a hurry?
Engineering,
to assist B'Elanna...
Lieutenant Torres.
Well, you've been seeing
a lot of my wife lately.
Should I be worried?
Mm, the repairs are extensive.
- It's a lot of work.
- You can't fool me.
I heard you two were planning
on scaling some cliffs together.
It was her idea.
Hey, relax.
Spending time on the holodeck
is good for you,
but if you really want
to have fun, forget climbing.
Try my race car program.
"Race car"?
You get to chase me around a track
in an old Earth ground vehicle.
300 kph.
It'll really get
your blood pumping.
Are you challenging me
to a competition?
Well, you think
you can take me?
Tomorrow, Holodeck 2,
1900 hours.
There is something
we need to discuss.
Sure, as soon as you help me
finish this diagnostic.
- I can't do this.
- Of course you can.
- You've done dozens of them.
- I'm not talking about the diagnostic.
- I'm talking about us.
- "Us"?
Your interest in me--
it's inappropriate.
I don't think I understand.
It's obvious you desire
a romantic involvement.
Excuse me?
You've made all
the customary overtures--
finding reasons
to spend time with me,
complimenting me,
inviting me to engage
in recreational activities.
Your husband even challenged me
to a ritual contest.
What are you talking about?
According to my research,
it's a traditional Klingon practice.
Look... I'm sorry,
but you've got the wrong idea.
You seemed a little lonely.
I was just trying to be friendly.
- I scanned you.
- You scanned me?
In the Jefferies tube.
Your blood pressure
and neurotransmitter readings
indicated a state of arousal.
It was hot, and I've been
under a lot of pressure,
but I certainly
wasn't aroused.
Look, Icheb, I like you...
but aside from the fact
that I am a much older woman,
I'm married.
That's why we have to do
the honorable thing.
We should stop seeing each other.
You're right.
As much as it hurts,
I'll just have to face the truth.
It's for the best.
Mm.
[quietly]
Seven?
Feeling better?
Well enough to return to duty.
You won't be returning to duty,
not on this ship anyway.
Loken lied to us.
There's no vaccine.
The cloak is the real cargo.
I ordered the crew to take us
back to Voyager, but they refused.
They mutinied.
I guess that's what you'd call it.
I've packed some supplies.
We'll take an escape pod.
I'm hoping the Annari
will leave us alone,
treat us as neutral parties.
We're not "neutral parties."
This is a military mission.
We can't get involved.
We've been "involved" since
you first fired on that Annari ship.
I thought I was helping people
in distress.
Don't they still need your help?
Are you abandoning this ship
because the mission
wasn't what you expected
or because being a Captain
wasn't what you expected?
I am perfectly capable
of commanding a starship.
Are you?
Clearly, you're uncomfortable
with the role--
delegating tasks, giving orders.
Someone died
following my orders!
You can't blame yourself
for that.
A Captain's responsible
for the lives of his crew.
People sometimes die on missions,
despite the Captain's best efforts.
I should have stuck
to playing Buster Kincaid.
A holodeck program can be turned off
when it no longer suits you.
Reality can't.
If you really feel responsible
for this crew,
you'll help them get home,
because they won't survive
without you.
Is that some new kind
of weapon?
They're scanning pulses
designed to illuminate cloaked ships.
If we hit one,
we'll be exposed.
How are we going
to get through?
We'll find a way.
I thought you were leaving.
I get claustrophobic
in escape pods.
Switch to manual helm control.
Full power to shields.
Aye, Captain.
[sighs]
Two Annari ships
have entered orbit.
- They are hailing.
- On screen.
Captain Geral, we have
12 isotons of ore for you.
I'm under orders to escort you
out of Annari space,
immediately.
You've been
supporting our enemy.
You must be mistaken.
A shuttlecraft
matching your hull composition
fired on one of our ships
several days ago.
And we recently detected
two human bio-signatures
on a Kraylor warship.
- I can explain that.
- If you don't leave immediately,
we'll be forced to fire on you.
Our warp drive
is still being repaired.
Then we'll escort you at impulse.
You have five minutes
to lift off.
So much for our new
deuterium injectors.
What about Harry and Seven?
[Janeway]
We'll go looking for them,
as soon as we get rid
of our escort.
Evasive maneuvers.
- There are too many of them.
- You're doing fine.
Just try to stay at least 100 meters
ahead of the closest pulse.
Yes, sir.
We should return fire.
No, that would only give them
another way to triangulate our position.
Our shields are failing.
We're losing structural integrity
on the lower decks.
Reroute emergency power.
It's insufficient.
Open a channel
to the lead Annari ship.
- Sir?
- Do it.
Aye, sir.
This is Captain Kim of
the Kraylor Vessel Nightingale.
I'm prepared to discuss terms
for our surrender.
End transmission.
We trusted you.
And you still should.
They're responding.
I don't have time to explain.
On screen.
Your surrender
will be unconditional.
No, it won't.
Either you allow my crew
to evacuate to the surface,
or I'll put this ship
on self-destruct.
You'll never get
the cloaking technology.
Something tells me your superiors
won't be happy about that.
Your crew will be taken
aboard my vessel
and brought
to an Annari detention center.
My crew is going to the surface
in escape pods.
Once they're clear, you can lock on
to this ship with a tractor beam.
Agreed.
You've two minutes to evacuate.
I will not abandon this ship.
I'm glad to hear that,
because I'm going to need you here.
Get your people into
the pods... quickly.
But the cloak...
I've got a plan to save it.
If I fail, at least
the scientist who designed it
will be alive
to create another one.
Seven, scan the Annari's
tractor emitters.
I need to know
the exact beam polarity.
What are we going to do?
Once they lock on to us,
they're going to come about
and pull us away
from the planet.
As soon as they do,
we're going to reverse
our shield polarity.
If we time it right, it should
give us enough momentum
to outrun them
to the defense perimeter.
We're going to use their
own weapons against them?
The escape pods are away.
[sighs]
Disengage the cloak.
They've locked on.
Sir?
Not yet.
Steady.
Now!
Status?
Shields are failing.
Four Annari vessels
are in pursuit.
- They're closing.
- Full thrusters!
[alarm bleeping]
Shields are down.
Get us through that defense
perimeter, Mr. Terek.
Yes, sir.
We're inside.
The Annari have
broken off their pursuit.
Take us to the surface,
Mr. Terek.
We've just crossed out
of Annari space.
Our escorts have broken off.
They're going to warp.
Bring the long-range sensors
on line.
You and Tom, take the Flyer.
Start your search
at Harry's last known position.
Tuvok, send an encrypted message
to the Kraylor homeworld.
See if they know
where Harry and Seven are.
That won't be necessary,
Captain.
Ensign Kim is hailing us.
From where?
A cloaked vessel.
It's directly astern.
[Kim] Acting Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 54282.5.
Final entry.
New cloaking systems are being
installed in other Kraylor ships,
so I guess the mission
was a success.
Still, I wish
I felt better about it.
Welcome home.
It's good to be back.
So, what'll it be tonight?
I have a light
Tula cheese souffl
or a zesty lasagna.
You know, Neelix,
the truth is, I'm not sure.
I thought
we talked about this.
- A Captain has to be deci...
- I'm not a Captain, Neelix.
Not yet, anyway.