For our third course...
[Chakotay]
Another course!
Luhvian quail in truffle sauce,
served with roasted chadre kab.
[Torres laughs]
My compliments to the chef.
[Paris]
Hear, hear.
[applause]
Thank you, captain.
Cream of leola soup,
fetran risotto, Luhvian quail,
it just keeps getting better.
I knew you'd been
expanding your palate,
but I didn't realize
you'd become a gourmet cook.
Preparing meals myself
is the best way to ensure quality.
I suppose I should be insulted,
but everything is so delicious,
I may just have to admit defeat
and hang up my apron.
No, that'd be a real tragedy, Neelix.
Pinot Noir, Commander?
I'll have another glass
of the Chardonnay.
Each course has been paired
with a specific wine.
Substitutions are not recommended.
The Pinot Noir sounds perfect.
-Is there any salt?
-Additional seasoning is not required.
Oh, I'm sorry, I--
If the quail hasn't been prepared
to your satisfaction,
I could replicate something
more to your liking.
A peanut butter and jelly sandwich,
perhaps.
Actually,
it's delicious just the way it is.
[Chakotay chuckles]
Captain to the Bridge. Report.
We're being pulled off-course.
[Janeway]
How?
I'm not certain.
It appears to be
some kind of graviton surge.
On my way.
We've rerouted
all available power to the thrusters,
but we can't break free.
-Try reversing the shield polarity.
-No effect.
[grunting]
What happened to the stars?
[Tuvok]
Shields at 65 percent!
Hail them.
[Kim]
They're not responding.
Return fire.
Can you identify them?
Their weapon signature is Vaadwaur,
but the ship has technology
from several different species.
There's another vessel approaching.
-It's charging weapons.
-Evasive pattern Beta-6.
Maybe we've got an ally.
The Vaadwaur ship is retreating.
Hail the second ship.
No response.
I stand corrected.
They have penetrated our aft shields.
Reroute power to the auxiliary emitters
and return fire.
They've transported material
off Decks 5, 7 and 8.
Disable their engines.
Follow them.
Navigational sensors are malfunctioning.
Something to do with this environment.
I want a full damage report
and an inventory of everything
that was taken off this ship.
And I want to know where we are.
They got more than 90 percent
of our food stores,
including almost everything
in the Airponics Bay.
They also got a computer console
from Engineering,
and they emptied three
of our deuterium tanks.
Why would anyone steal deuterium?
You could find it anywhere.
Apparently not here.
I'm not detecting any gases,
stellar bodies, or matter of any kind.
Except for the ships that attacked us.
Scan for other vessels.
I want to know
how many we're dealing with.
There are more than 150 ships
within scanning range,
but I'm only detecting life signs
on 29 of them.
Captain, there's another vessel
approaching at high impulse.
Quite a welcoming committee
they've got here.
-What's the status of our shields?
-They're at 28 percent.
That'll have to do. Charge weapons.
Captain, this one wants to talk.
On screen.
I'm Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
General Valen.
Welcome to the Void.
You're the first ship we've seen here
that hasn't tried to fire on us,
but in case you change your mind,
we're prepared to defend ourselves.
I know;
I've been observing you on sensors.
The way you fought those ships
was impressive.
Most vessels don't survive
the first few minutes.
I'd appreciate any information
you could give us about where we are.
[Valen]
The anomaly's a closed structure,
encased by an inert layer of subspace.
Matter and energy can't penetrate it.
Our ships certainly penetrated it
when we were pulled in.
By the funnels.
But they only pull matter
in one direction,
into the Void.
Have you explored the entire anomaly?
There's nothing to explore, but it's big.
We've calculated the outer circumference
at approximately nine light-years,
but we've never been able to breach it.
How long have you been here?
More than five years.
There must be a way to escape.
New arrivals are always thinking
about escape.
We have a sophisticated starship.
Maybe if we work together,
we can find a way out.
You're being naive.
No one ever gets out.
We may be able to devise
a new approach.
Many have tried.
All they did was waste resources
that could've kept them alive longer.
Don't be foolish. I can help you.
How?
The only source
of food and energy in the Void
comes from new ships
that are drawn in.
If you want to survive here,
you'll have to compete
for their resources.
And I suppose you can help us do that.
I have tactical data on some
of the more dangerous predators.
But you want something in return.
My scans show
you have photon torpedoes.
I'm sorry, we don't trade weapons.
Why not?
Because we have no way of knowing
what they'll be used for.
Plundering innocent ships, for example.
Wait a few weeks
until your resources start to run out.
Morality won't keep
your life support systems running.
I'm sorry, General.
There are some compromises
I won't make.
Not yet.
Report, Lieutenant.
We're using power at almost ten times
the usual rate.
While we're standing still?
The same graviton forces
that pulled us into the anomaly
seem to be draining the warp core.
At this rate, our deuterium
will be gone in about ten days.
Shut down all nonessential systems.
-Where are you going?
-To find a way out of here.
Using fractal algorithms
with the Borg sensors,
I believe I can predict where and when
these funnels will occur.
Well, that's impressive,
but how does it help us?
The funnels originate
inside the anomaly,
creating massive graviton forces
before they erupt.
If we were to enter one of the funnels
just as that happened,
we might be able to use those forces
to propel us into normal space.
Not without compromising
structural integrity.
I might be able to reinforce
the shields to compensate.
There's another problem.
When the graviton forces
reach critical levels,
the polarity suddenly reverses,
pulling everything near the funnel
back into the anomaly.
We'd have to jump to warp
at exactly the right moment.
We'd need to achieve
a velocity of warp 8.2.
Question is,
will we have enough power?
At the rate we're losing it,
we may only get one shot at this.
The sooner we try, the better.
[Seven]
There's a funnel forming
70,000 meters off the port bow,
bearing 130 mark 24.
[Kim]
Graviton surge in 34 seconds.
Full power to shields
and structural integrity.
Take us in, Mr. Paris.
Five seconds, four, three...
Structural integrity at 20 percent.
Ten percent!
Fifty-thousand kilometers
to normal space.
Prepare to go to warp.
[sighs]
[Torres]
Engineering to the Bridge.
Go ahead.
[Torres]
The warp core is off-line.
If nothing else,
we learned some things
that'll help us next time.
With all due respect, captain,
we don't even have warp drive anymore.
I may be able to get it back on line,
but we still need deuterium
to keep our basic systems running.
How long will our reserves last?
[Torres]
If we shut down life support
on all but a few decks,
deactivate Astrometrics, turbolifts,
ration replicator use,
maybe a week.
I used to make a living
scavenging for supplies.
Let me take one of the shuttles.
I might be able to find deuterium
on one of those abandoned ships.
A shuttle would be too easy a target.
I appreciate the offer, Neelix,
but we're safer if we stay together.
The shuttles may be useful
in another capacity.
We could use their warp cores
to augment power on Voyager.
We're still going to need
more deuterium.
Let's track down the ship that raided us
and get back what they stole.
We should do it quickly.
I've detected a number of vessels
monitoring us.
The vultures are circling.
Vultures eat the dead, Mr. Paris.
We're not dead yet.
The vessel's in visual range.
Shields.
On screen.
Looks like somebody got to them
before we did.
-No life signs.
-Scan for ion trails.
Whoever did this
probably has our deuterium.
[Tuvok]
Aye, captain.
Is there anything left aboard that ship
worth salvaging?
Their technology and supplies
have been picked clean.
Not everything of value has been taken.
The warp core has been removed,
but the casing that protected it
is intact.
It's composed of tricesium.
-We can convert it into a power source.
-Every little bit helps.
Lock onto the core casing
and beam it to the Cargo Bay.
With the additional power,
we could reactivate
the Astrometrics Lab.
I can think of some better uses.
For example?
Oh, I don't know,
making sure there's air to breathe.
[scanner beeping]
This must be where they cut
through the casing to remove the core.
Crude but effective.
[Torres]
Something's in there.
Identify yourself.
Torres to Security. Intruder alert.
[Tuvok]
Acknowledged.
[Seven]
There.
Stay where you are.
He appears to be injured.
[door opens]
How is he?
His injury doesn't seem serious,
but he won't let me close enough
to treat him.
My name's Captain Janeway.
You're safe here.
[doctor]
I've tried communicating with him.
He doesn't appear to have
any verbal skills.
Do we know how he got on board?
I believe he was transported
along with the core casing.
We should have picked up
his life signs.
We're trying to determine
why we didn't detect him.
That vessel he was on
had no atmosphere.
How did he survive?
My scans show
he can conserve oxygen.
He has unusually large lung capacity
and a voracious appetite.
Do you think that ship was his home?
Maybe, but we can't send him back.
He can't survive
without oxygen indefinitely.
We'll run scans
for other members of his species,
but until we can find
a safe place for him,
let's make him
as comfortable as possible.
Computer, replicate a portion
of nutritional supplements
from my daily allotment.
You've found something?
We think we know
who has our deuterium.
It's someone we've already met.
I knew I'd see you again, captain.
I expect you've reconsidered
my proposal.
We're not here to trade.
We're here to take back
what belongs to us.
I don't know what you mean.
Our scans indicate
you've got some of our food,
one of our consoles,
and a large quantity of our deuterium.
We didn't take any of that from you.
No, apparently you killed
the crew of another ship
and took it from them.
We want it back.
That's not the way things work here.
Either you give it back, or we'll take it.
[computer beeping]
-He's powering his engines.
-Target his shields and fire.
Lock onto whatever belongs to us
and transport it to the Cargo Bay.
I'm detecting large quantities of food
on his supply deck.
Maybe we should take it
while we have the chance.
Is it ours?
No, but our own reserves
are running out.
Valen wouldn't hesitate
to take it from us.
No, he wouldn't.
We've got what's ours. Reverse course.
[door chimes]
Come in.
An updated inventory of our supplies.
We got back less than half
of what was stolen.
Doesn't take two of you
to deliver a padd.
What's on your mind?
We want to be clear
about what our policy's going to be
while we're here in the Void.
You think we should
have taken Valen's food.
Logic suggests
we may have to be more opportunistic
if we intend to survive.
We may not like Valen's tactics,
but he and his crew are still alive
after five years in here.
I was thinking about that myself.
I thought maybe
I could get some guidance
from the Federation Charter.
I was hoping I'd find a loophole
that would allow us to...
take actions we ordinarily wouldn't take.
Any luck?
The Charter's a statement of principles,
not a practical document.
-No section on how to exist in a void.
-No.
But I've become convinced
that we've got to stick
to our principles,
not abandon them.
Should the crew be ready to die
for those principles?
If the alternative means
becoming thieves
and killers ourselves, yes.
But I'm betting that our principles
are going to keep us alive.
Captain?
The Federation is based
on mutual cooperation,
the idea that the whole is greater
than the sum of its parts.
Voyager can't survive here alone,
but if we form a temporary alliance
with other ships,
maybe we can pool
our resources and escape.
As you've pointed out,
the people we've encountered
in this void
are thieves and killers.
Such individuals
are hardly ideal allies.
I agree.
Then who are we going to form
an alliance with?
Anyone who agrees
to play by our rules:
no killing, no stealing,
and no giving up.
Forgive me, captain,
but why would anyone
who has survived
by killing and stealing
suddenly agree to those terms?
We'll offer to share
our food and medical supplies
and defend ships
that are attacked by raiders.
Captain, maybe you'd better take
another look at that inventory.
Our food and power reserves
will be gone within a week.
If we start giving everything away--
Then maybe we'll only survive
for two days instead of seven.
On the other hand,
if we share what we have,
instead of hoarding it,
we might find other people
willing to do the same.
If we combine our technology,
we can find ways
of improving our situation
and ultimately
get the hell out of this place.
We may lose a little weight, gentlemen,
but we won't lose who we are.
[Janeway]
Captain's Log, Stardate 54553.4.
For the past several days,
we've been making every effort
to recruit members into an alliance,
but it hasn't been easy.
Whenever a new ship
gets pulled into the Void,
they're immediately attacked.
Instead of attacking it,
you'd have to help
defend the new ship.
And how is that in my interest?
It would encourage them
to join our alliance.
And if they refuse, then we raid them?
Everyone in the alliance must agree
not to launch unprovoked attacks.
Then how are we supposed
to get supplies?
The idea is to recruit new members,
share technology and resources.
We almost escaped the Void
on our own.
If we work together,
I believe we'll succeed.
How many ships do you have
in this alliance?
You'd be the first.
Technically, captain,
that's not correct.
I consider myself the first member
of the captain's coalition.
Six years ago,
I offered her my services
and the resources of my ship,
and she has never failed to help me
when I needed her.
It's a noble idea, captain,
but good intentions
are like deuterium reserves,
they tend to get lost in the Void.
All I ask is that you consider
our proposal.
I will.
[Janeway]
In the meantime,
we'd like to offer you
food and medical supplies.
What do you expect in return?
Nothing.
Compliments of the alliance.
I tried.
Captain, there's been a theft.
-What's missing?
-My phase compensator.
No doubt, it was stolen
by one of your prospective members.
It wasn't stolen.
I gave it to the Nygeans.
They needed it
to repair their sensor array.
I presume you obtained something
equally valuable in return.
I think I did.
The goodwill of a potential ally.
-Did they join?
-Not yet.
-Captain...
-I know.
It's not exactly
the most "efficient" policy.
But, then, you don't always do
what's most efficient either.
I don't know what you're implying.
You gave up your rations
to our guest in Sick Bay.
He needed food.
You're a valuable member of this crew.
Your friend in Sick Bay
is nothing but a drain on resources.
What's efficient
about wasting food on him?
You think I'm being inefficient,
Tuvok thinks I'm being illogical.
You both could be right.
But maybe the best way to get help
is to give it.
-Oh, and, Seven?
-Yes?
I'm sorry I gave away your favourite
phase compensator.
[sighs]
[aria from Rigoletto playing]
[door opens]
-How is he?
-Much better.
He seemed to relax when he heard me
humming an aria from Rigoletto,
so I had the computer play
the full orchestral version.
Fantome seems to be a music lover.
"Fantome"?
After The Phantom of the Opera,
a tormented character
who is soothed by music.
In six years,
you haven't chosen a name for yourself,
but you've given Fantome one
in a few days.
Choosing the right name for myself
is extremely difficult.
I'm a complex individual.
-And Fantome isn't?
-On the contrary.
I believe he's quite intelligent,
and his physiology's very sophisticated.
Did you know
he has the ability to refract
his own life signs?
That would explain
why our sensors didn't detect him.
[chuckles]
I wish we could find a way
to communicate with him.
I suspect he'd have a lot to tell us.
[aria continues]
[music stops]
-We were enjoying that.
-Exactly.
He may not be able to speak,
but he can hear.
[high-pitched tone beeping]
[low-pitched tone beeping]
He understands.
So it would seem.
[lower-pitched tone beeping]
What's the occasion?
Oh, Seven's not the only one
who knows how to set an elegant table.
You have heard
there is a food shortage.
That's no reason why you two
can't enjoy a romantic dinner.
Unfortunately, I can't light this.
It would be a waste of oxygen.
Still, it is festive.
We appreciate the effort.
I believe there's been a mistake
here, waiter.
I didn't order this.
Close your eyes and pretend
that it's Seven's fetran risotto.
[clears throat]
It tastes more like chicken.
-What's this?
-A preserved Olian guava.
I had a few left.
-Neelix...
-No arguments.
You're eating for two.
[Tuvok over radio]
Senior officers,
report to stations immediately.
Sorry, Neelix.
Charge weapons. Shields to full.
-What's going on?
-A funnel just opened.
It pulled in a new vessel.
Two warships are approaching it.
One of them is Valen's.
Target Valen's weapons and hail him.
[computer beeping]
My fight's not with you, captain.
Then stand down.
This new ship
has impressive technology.
-We can share it.
-I'm not here to divide the spoils.
Then why are you here?
To protect the ship you're firing on.
What are they to you?
Just some people in a bad situation,
like the rest of us.
Save your speeches.
I've got a crew to feed.
He's targeting our shields.
Take his weapons out.
Hail the new ship.
[computer beeping]
I surrender.
[Janeway]
We're here to help you.
Can you target the smaller warship?
We're a survey vessel.
We're not equipped to fight.
Shields at 60 percent.
Fire torpedoes.
Shields on Valen's lead ship
are holding at 80 percent.
It appears he's upgraded them
since we last met.
-Ours?
-Thirty.
The smaller ship
is outmaneuvering us.
We have hull breaches
on Decks 5 and 6.
Seal them.
Shields at 15 percent.
[Torres over radio]
Engineering to the Bridge.
Go ahead.
[alarm beeping]
We're losing containment.
At this rate,
we'll be dead in the water
in less than three minutes.
We should retreat, captain.
-Not yet.
-We might want to reconsider.
There's another ship approaching.
We can't defend ourselves
against three ships.
[Tuvok]
We may not have to.
The third vessel belongs to Mr. Garon.
He's firing at the other two.
Valen's shields are down.
The smaller ship is leaking plasma.
They're both retreating.
Garon's hailing.
Get a weapons lock on him.
We've been fooled
by unexpected allies before.
Why are you targeting me?
Because I don't know
what your intentions are.
Haven't I just made them clear?
I've decided to accept your offer.
Well, in that case,
welcome to the alliance.
[Janeway]
Captain's Log, Stardate 54562.7.
Since Garon and the survey ship
became our charter members,
finding new allies
has gotten a little easier.
My latest prospect
is Commander Bosaal,
whose ship has technology
that could help us escape.
Neelix,
we have another guest for dinner.
Ah, always room for one more, captain.
Who did you raid
to get fresh vegetables?
They're replicated.
One of the crews that joined us
had technology that tripled
our replicator efficiency.
It may not be a gourmet feast,
but we can feed
500 people a day now,
using half the power
it took us a few days ago.
Why don't we sit down?
[electronic tones beeps]
[Tuvok]
Doctor.
-Hello, Commander.
-How's your patient?
Technically,
he's not a patient anymore,
but it's taken me this long
to coax him out of Sick Bay.
He's quite shy.
[electronic tones beeps]
I'm telling him not to worry
that you're the one
who keeps us all safe.
[electronic tones beeps]
He says, "Thank you."
An ingenious method
of communication.
It began with a few simple words,
but now we're capable
of rudimentary conversation.
Tell him I'm pleased
he's feeling better.
I will.
[electronic tones beep]
[electronic tones continue beeping]
[chuckles]
What's that parasite
doing aboard your ship?
-I beg your pardon?
-They're vermin.
I don't know who you are, sir,
but your choice of words is offensive.
What is offensive is the way
they slip aboard during transport,
hide in conduits,
steal food, spread disease.
Fantome is perfectly healthy,
and unlike some people in this void,
he hasn't stolen anything.
If my sensors could detect
where they are on my ship,
I'd exterminate them.
I suggest you do the same.
-Captain, this is outrageous!
-Doctor!
One of the principles of our alliance
is that we don't discriminate.
Everyone's welcome,
as long as they follow the rules.
But if you're having a bad experience
with the members of this species
on your ship,
I'd be happy to bring them to Voyager.
If you could find them.
Now that we've had a chance to analyze
Fantome's physiology,
I think we can get
a transporter lock on them.
Is this your way of enticing me
to join your alliance?
I'm simply trying to demonstrate
how cooperation and tolerance
can benefit everyone.
Then we have an agreement.
Okay, now connect
the primary emitter relay.
On line.
-How is it coming?
-Pretty well.
We just need to...
I guess I was being
a little optimistic.
What's the problem, exactly?
Uh, we think we can establish
a shield bubble
large enough
to encompass all our ships,
but we have no way to compensate
for the graviton stress.
Wouldn't a polaron modulator
be able to do that?
Unfortunately,
nobody in the alliance has one.
We've been trying to build our own,
but so far...
Maybe we could trade for one,
or find a new ally who has one.
[Garon]
Well, it's not a common piece
of technology, and it's valuable.
It may be difficult to convince anyone
to part with it.
[Janeway]
You never know unless you ask...
You are not authorized to be in here.
We're making a valuable contribution
to the alliance.
By spying on restricted meetings?
We've devised
a new surveillance technique.
[Janeway]
Ask Harry to give you a...
You've bypassed my security measures.
We can observe activity
on any ship in the Void
without being detected.
This is the cargo hold
on the Jelinian freighter.
Now, if I'm not mistaken,
the Jelinians
are a member of our alliance.
[Tuvok]
Which is why you shouldn't be
spying on them.
And why they
shouldn't be hoarding their ale.
[electronic tones beeping]
[musical tones begin]
[various musical tones sounding]
[musical tones continue playing]
Lovely piece.
-Did they compose it, or did you?
-They did.
Though strictly speaking,
it's not a composition.
-It's more of a conversation.
-I'm impressed.
I wish I could take credit,
but it was Fantome
who taught the others
in a fraction of the time
it took him to learn.
They're a highly intelligent species.
The language is already developing
its own grammar and syntax.
That suggests they have
a language of their own.
[doctor]
Mm-hmm.
It could be telepathic,
but they seem just as comfortable
communicating with music now.
Could their species
be native to the Void?
It's certainly possible.
They told us they were born here.
Just when you think
nothing in the galaxy
can surprise you anymore...
[Torres over radio]
Captain Janeway,
please report to Engineering.
Just what we needed, captain,
a fully compatible polaron modulator.
-Where did you get it?
-A Kinjal frigate.
-Do they want to join our alliance?
-They're not interested.
-How did you get this?
-I traded for it.
What did you give them?
I don't answer to you.
Did you steal it?
Disconnect the modulator.
[Torres]
Captain...?
We're returning it
to the people it belongs to.
They have no more use for it.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
-You killed them.
-Captain.
I don't like his tactics
any more than you do,
but why waste this technology
when we're so close to escaping?
Because it's a violation
of everything this alliance stands for.
Refusing the modulator
won't bring back the people he killed.
No, but using it would make us
accessories to murder.
Take it and get out.
[modulator powers down]
The Jelinians and the Kraylor
have left with Bosaal.
-They felt you were being--
-Impulsive and self-righteous?
-Is that what you think?
-You did what you had to do.
-Still, I made a mistake.
-By telling Bosaal to leave?
Allowing him to join in the first place.
You couldn't have known
what he was going to do.
Oh, I had a pretty good idea
what kind of person he was.
That bigoted reaction he had
to the doctor's friend
told me all I needed to know,
but I ignored my instincts.
Why?
Because I thought his ship
could help us escape.
You weren't the only one
who wanted him in the alliance.
Maybe not, but if I'd listened
to my doubts in the first place,
we wouldn't have lost
the other two ships.
We'll find a way out of here
without them.
Where do we stand with the modulator?
B'Elanna and the other engineers
are working around
the clock to build one.
She thinks they'll be ready to test
in a couple of days.
So everyone's pulling together
to make up for my mistake?
They have to.
It says so in the Federation Charter.
[door opens]
-Good news, I hope.
-I'm afraid not.
It appears Commander Bosaal
is attempting to form an alliance
of his own
with one of our adversaries.
We recorded a tactical conversation
that took place between them
just a few minutes ago.
[Valen]
Don't underestimate Janeway.
I've been in battle with her twice.
Then you know Janeway's tactics.
I have two other ships.
We can take Voyager's food
and weapons if we work together.
The rest of their conversation suggests
they will attack within the next 48 hours.
I'm so glad we taught them
the value of cooperation.
Our power reserves
will be severely depleted
if we're forced to defend ourselves.
[sighs]
Tell B'Elanna we don't have time
to test her modulator.
We've got to try to escape now.
[musical tones playing]
Sorry to interrupt,
but we've got a situation developing.
[musical tones stop]
We're going to try
to break free of the anomaly.
Your friends are welcome to join us,
but they should be aware
of the dangers.
[musical tones beeping]
The Void's their home.
They want to stay.
Where would they like us
to transport them?
They're nomads. Any ship will do.
[musical tones beeping]
They say they're grateful for our help.
They want to help us now.
[tones continue beeping]
[dramatic, suspenseful music
playing over montage]
[console beeping]
[indistinct conversation]
[console beeps]
There's a funnel forming in Grid IV.
Graviton surge in 98 seconds.
Alert the other ships.
-Take us in, Tom.
-Aye, captain.
Bosaal and his fleet are approaching.
They are charging weapons.
Janeway to Engineering. Status.
[Torres over radio]
I need two more minutes.
You've got one.
[Kim]
Surge in 50 seconds!
Voyager to all alliance ships.
Begin firing at your designated targets.
We've penetrated shields
on both vessels.
Janeway to the doctor.
Initiate transport.
Acknowledged.
[musical tone beeps]
Yes. Goodbye and good luck.
Energize.
Transport complete, captain.
They're in the engine rooms
of both ships.
Acknowledged.
30 seconds.
Janeway to Engineering.
We need that modulator.
[Torres over radio]
Just a few more seconds.
We're receiving a hail
from Valen's ship, audio only.
Let's hear it.
[musical tones playing]
What's he saying, doctor?
Mission accomplished.
Fantome shut down power
on Valen's ship.
Confirmed.
Bosaal's ship has lost power, as well.
Who says gremlins in the engine
are a myth.
Surge in five seconds, four...
Now, B'Elanna.
All ships are in formation.
Structural integrity at 30 percent.
Forty thousand meters
to normal space.
Twenty percent.
Ten percent.
Do it, Tom.
Gentlemen, it's been a privilege
to have you as allies.
I never believed we'd escape.
Then why did you join?
Captain Janeway is very persuasive,
-and the food was good.
-[chuckles]
You're welcome to have
a meal with us anytime.
Ah, unfortunately,
we're headed in the opposite direction.
Safe journey to you
and your crew, captain.
-And to all of yours, as well.
-Thank you.
It was almost like being part
of the Federation again.
The real one's only
30,000 light-years away.
Then what are we standing around for?