[narrator]
Last time on Star Trek Voyager...
I believe we know each other.
You're Tuvok, right?
We met last week at the shift briefing.
Before that.
Before we were working here.
Oh, I don't think so.
A romantic relationship is really
out of the question for me right now,
-and when you started asking...
-How about a friend?
What?
Could you use a friend?
It's nice to be in a place where
different species get along so well.
Oh, so you admit
we're getting along?
-[Kim] Kim to Chakotay.
-[Chakotay] Go ahead.
I've found them, Commander.
-Let go of me!
-I'm not going to hurt you.
[grunting]
[screams]
No! No!
Harry, I need
an emergency transport now!
No, leave me alone!
We're friends.
We're trying to help you.
No, don't touch me!
I don't believe you are
who you think you are!
[Tuvok] We don't belong here.
This isn't right!
We don't belong here!
[narrator] And now the conclusion.
-[man] Wait here.
-Yes, sir.
He's deactivated a safety field.
-[beeping]
-Alert Emergency Medical.
He may have tried to ju...
[grunting]
[groans]
I can't penetrate their shields.
Maybe we don't have to.
The Battle of Vorkado.
It's in my tactical database.
A Romulan captain
disabled two attacking vessels
by creating a photonic shock wave
between the ships.
How'd he do that?
Watch and learn.
I don't think they'll be
bothering us again.
Good work.
Let's go back for Chakotay.
Five more ships
on an intercept course.
What's your tactical database
telling you now?
Transporters are damaged.
Shields are failing.
We have to retreat,
come up with a new plan.
Agreed.
[indistinct chatter]
Listen, I'm sorry about my friend.
-Excuse me?
-Jaffen.
He wasn't very nice
when I invited you to join us.
Are you all right?
I'm just a little tired.
First day on a new job.
I know how that can be.
Well, I just wanted to let you know
you're more than welcome to sit with us.
Actually, I was thinking
about going home.
Well, if you change your mind,
we're celebrating.
What's the occasion?
I've decided
to move in with Jaffen.
Congratulations.
Look among the patrons.
Yerid, Criminal Investigations.
[scoffs]
We run an honest business.
I'm looking for two people
who disappeared
after leaving here earlier this evening.
One was a young pregnant woman...
B'Elanna?
You know her?
Oh, I knew I should have
walked her to the Transport.
Why, did you think someone
might try to hurt her?
The city is supposed
to be safe.
The person with her
was described as short
with mottled skin,
facial hair...
Sounds like someone
who was in here earlier,
-a worker from the plant.
-Do you know his name?
Uh...
Neelix, I think.
Did you see him talking to anyone else
while he was here?
He had a friend.
Uh, Amal something.
-Can you describe him?
-Oh, I don't have to.
He's sitting right over...
[Doctor] ECH Log,
Stardate 54622.4.
I've found an ingenious place
to hide while we make repairs--
a moon with a paramagnetic core
that masks our energy signature.
I've turned my attention
to Lieutenant Torres,
whose treatment
will also require ingenuity.
The scan on the left was performed
during B'Elanna's last physical.
The one on the right,
just a few minutes ago.
The memory centers of her brain
have been radically altered.
People from our crew
seemed to remember
parts of their real lives,
but they got a lot
of the details wrong.
Tom knew his name,
that he was from Earth,
but he said space travel
made him sick.
Whoever did this
is very sophisticated,
capable of selectively
manipulating memory engrams.
Some have been suppressed,
some altered,
others left intact.
Can you undo the damage?
I believe so,
but it'll take some time.
I wish I could help.
Maybe you can.
She'll require several treatments.
In between, you could expose her
to familiar sights and surroundings.
Say no more.
I'll take her on a whirlwind tour
of her own life.
Don't rush things.
This is going to be
very traumatic for her.
[man] Acute anxiety, depression...
When I interviewed him, he insisted
that he's not who he's supposed to be
that we've... "stolen his katra,"
whatever that is.
Conclusions?
Tri-lobe regression complex?
Polar-affective disorder?
Neuropsychiatry isn't
a guessing game, Dr. Ravoc.
Dysphoria Syndrome.
You have been studying my research.
According to your work,
the condition is very rare.
It is.
I've treated this man before.
Apparently,
he's suffered a relapse.
Recommended treatment?
Engramatic resequencing
is typically indicated.
You seem skeptical.
Resequencing is a radical procedure.
If he had a malignant tumor,
would you be afraid to cut it out?
No.
This syndrome is just as insidious.
It requires aggressive treatment.
Get started.
Please... help me.
That's what we're here to do.
I want to know the status
of Employee 8583.
Maybe it's different
where you come from,
but here it's polite
to say "Good morning."
Good morning.
8583, the man who was removed
by Security yesterday.
He's been hospitalized.
Is there any reason to believe
that his condition might be contagious?
He came in contact
with other workers.
Some of them
have expressed concern.
Well, tell them not to worry.
Excuse me.
Am I intruding?
What can we do for you?
I'm investigating the disappearance
of two of your employees.
-Who?
-Their names are Neelix and Torres.
Both of them failed
to report for work today.
What about this man?
Employee 9363. He didn't report
for his shift either.
I'd like to see
his personnel file,
and I'll need to interview anyone
who may know where he is.
Why are you looking for him?
I believe he's responsible
for the disappearance
of the other two.
You've only been here three weeks.
-Where did you get all these things?
-I'm a collector.
You collect spent plasma relays?
I like to think of it
as a decorative object.
You know...
I think this would
look better over there.
You're not going to start telling me
how to dress, are you?
-[chuckles]
-Where are you going?
To get the rest of my things.
There's more?
Lights.
What do you want?
You told me you were moving out.
I needed a place to hide.
Jaffen knows where I am.
He'll come looking for me.
I'm hoping you won't tell him I'm here.
They say you had something to do
with the disappearance
of a woman at the plant.
I did.
Her name's B'Elanna.
She was brought to this planet
against her will.
Something was done to her
so she'd forget her real life.
And what,
you helped her get home?
That's right.
There are other people in this city
who I'm also trying to help.
I'm not here to hurt anyone.
You have to trust me.
You're pointing a weapon at me.
Go ahead. Report me.
But if you do,
a lot of innocent people
are going to suffer.
All I'm asking for is a place to stay
until my friends come back for me.
We're going to have to do
something about that arm.
[Torres] The waiter...
from the tavern.
Lieutenant Tom Paris,
our pilot,
and B'Elanna Torres,
our Chief Engineer.
That picture was taken
on your honeymoon.
It isn't possible.
How else would we have it?
It's an antique television.
You gave it to Tom as a present.
-He watches cartoons.
-Yes.
How do I know that?
Because you're starting to remember.
I wondered why he was
so protective of me.
I'll be outside if you need me.
Your shift ended three hours ago.
My friend Jaffen,
Employee 1326-- he cut himself.
Removing property from these premises
is not permitted.
I know, but he's just too stubborn
to go to the hospital.
I promise I'll have it back
first thing in the morning.
Be sure that you do.
Display the personnel file
for Employee 8583.
[Computer] Access restricted.
Security clearance verified.
Display all medical and historical data
for this employee's species.
[beeping]
Data unavailable.
List all files accessed
by this employee since he's been here.
Personnel files.
Employee 8582
Nozawa, Kashimuro.
Employee 8584
Janeway, Kathryn.
Employee 8585
McKenzie, William.
Employee 8586
Hansen, Annika.
Employee 8587
Anderson, Lydia.
Employee 8588
Torres, B'Elanna. Employee...
You need a doctor.
It'll have to wait
till I'm back on Voyager.
Voyager?
My ship.
You live onboard?
For almost seven years.
Don't you ever want
to stay in one place?
You seem happy here.
I've got a good job.
Ever consider doing something
more challenging?
My job's challenging enough.
You monitor reactor coils, right?
You're obviously
a very capable woman.
You could probably run
that power plant.
Why would I want
all that responsibility?
[com chirps]
What's that?
My people are trying
to contact me.
Chakotay here.
[Kim] Are you okay, Commander?
For the time being.
Can you get me out of here?
No, sir.
We're eight light-years away.
[Chakotay] How are you transmitting
a signal that far?
We're using a triaxilating frequency
on a covariant subspace band.
It was B'Elanna's idea.
I take it she's feeling better.
She's responded well to treatment.
Have you located anyone else
from the crew?
As a matter of fact, I'm sitting
with Captain Janeway right now.
-How is she?
-A little suspicious,
just like B'Elanna was at first.
How soon can you get back
into transporter range?
We'll need a couple more days
to finish repairs.
What about the shield grid?
I have an idea
how to shut it down.
Until I get back to you,
let's maintain com silence,
just in case we're being monitored.
Understood.
Good luck, Commander.
Why did you call me "Captain"?
Because that's who you are.
That's absurd.
So what are you saying?
That I was brought here by force, too?
That my memories were manipulated?
-I know it sounds strange, but...
-Helping you was a mistake.
Listen to me.
There are more than a hundred
members of Voyager's crew
working at that power plant--
your crew.
And when our ship gets here,
I'll be able to prove it to you.
Look...
I don't want to force you to do
anything you don't want to,
but don't you at least want
to know the truth?
Let me prove who I am.
Hand me that dermal regenerator.
We're the same race.
We're more than that.
We're friends.
Am I hearing you correctly?
You're actually helping this man?
He abducted one of the workers.
She's a member of his crew.
Right, and you're the Captain.
Don't you see?
He's trying to convince you
that you'll have a better life
if you go with him.
Do you want to go with him?
No.
Then why are you risking
everything we have?
-[door opens]
-I was starting to think...
Stay where you are.
[shouts]
[Chakotay] I don't know them.
I think you do,
and I think you were involved
in their disappearance.
[sighs]
I'm not the man you're looking for.
Yes, the witness' description
doesn't fit you exactly,
but I'm sure that'll be explained
once the doctor here
finds evidence of dermal regeneration.
What is it?
Some kind of...
communications device
implanted under his skin.
Remove it.
Listen to me.
You and I have something in common.
Oh?
We're both investigating disappearances.
If you answer my questions,
I'll answer yours.
I have an order to transfer
this patient to Division 6.
Division 6?
Neuropathology.
We have reason to believe
that he's mentally ill.
He's lying. How could they know that?
They've never examined me.
-I'll come with you.
-I'm sorry, sir,
but my orders are to bring him
for immediate treatment.
This man is a suspect
in a serious crime.
I'm not letting him
out of my sight.
If you check the order,
you'll see it's been approved
by the Director of Investigations.
My real name is Chakotay.
I'm an officer aboard
the Federation Starship Voyager.
Members of my crew were abducted,
and their memories were altered,
and they were put to work here.
I can give you names,
descriptions!
[shouting] Listen to me!
Ah...
[chuckles]
Smells good.
Pancakes with maple syrup
are your favorite breakfast.
You know, sometimes food
is like time travel.
You inhale an aroma,
take a bite of something,
and suddenly, bam, you're back
at the moment you first tasted it.
They're good.
I'm not experiencing time travel.
What are you reading?
Personal logs.
Do you remember
recording any of them?
Oh, they're not mine,
they're Tom's.
Those are supposed
to be private.
Well, he is my husband.
What do they say?
They're private.
But the way he describes me...
He loves you.
I guess so.
How do you feel?
It's still a little foggy.
That fog should lift as soon as
the Doctor finishes your treatments.
Yeah...
but what about the guy
who recorded these logs?
I've been analyzing our scans
of the Quarren patrol ships
that attacked us,
and I think I've devised a way
of evading their sensors.
You do have a knack
for tactical planning.
Hmm. That's something I've been meaning
to discuss with you.
Once we've succeeded in this mission,
and I'm certain we will,
I'd like you to help me program
a new medical hologram.
You don't like the idea
of going back to your old job
now that you've had a taste
of command.
I'm a skilled officer.
No offense, Doc, but that skill
was programmed into you.
-Yes, but...
-I'm sure once you're back
to your old self, you'll be happy
being a full-time doctor again.
[beeping]
Commander Chakotay's hailing us.
We're receiving you, sir.
Go ahead.
I'm having trouble
with my transceiver.
This may be the last chance
we have to talk.
What's your status?
I'm almost ready
to shut down the shield grid.
I'm sending you
encrypted instructions.
They'll tell you where
and when to enter orbit.
-[Kim] We have it, Commander.
-Chakotay out.
Well, now you know
where to find Voyager...
I'll have three ships with me.
They won't escape again.
If you'd done your job the first time,
we wouldn't have a problem now.
Don't you have patients to attend to?
Uh, yes, sir.
I've been thinking.
This is the second person
we've admitted
with Dysphoria Syndrome in two days,
and they both work at the power plant.
Maybe we should issue a health alert,
examine the rest of the workers.
Do you think I'm incompetent?
Sir?
This man is in charge of personnel
at the power facility.
I've informed him of the situation.
We're already taking steps
to ensure the safety
of all of our employees.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
No need to apologize, Doctor.
Your concern for your patients
is admirable,
but don't worry. This man is already
responding to treatment.
I expect a full recovery.
Why would this Tuvok be collecting
information about his coworkers?
I don't know, but the name on one
of those files is B'Elanna Torres.
They both began working
at the plant on the same day,
along with 136 others,
including myself.
What's unusual about that?
More than 100 skilled employees,
most of them the same species,
acquired in a single day...
during a labor shortage?
You'll also note
that every one of them
was processed with the Central Hospital
when they arrived.
It's routine for new workers
to be examined.
Yes, by Quarantine Control.
But everyone on this list--
all of them--
were processed through Division 6.
You came through Neuropathology?
That's what the records indicate,
but I don't remember being there.
[sighs]
What do you expect me to do?
You can start
by interviewing Mr. Tuvok.
-You'll find him at the hospital.
-Why is he there?
He became emotionally unstable.
Even if I wanted to help you,
I couldn't.
Why not?
The Director of Investigations
relieved me of duty this morning.
Yerid, I thought that was you.
Have you found out anything
about B'Elanna?
He can't assist you.
He's been relieved of duty.
Oh.
This man's also in Tuvok's file.
What file?
Why don't you tell him?
Tell me what?
I can't go back to the hospital
and start asking questions.
I'd be reported.
Maybe I can help.
Recently, I've been...
I'm a doctor.
You can trust me.
I've been experiencing...
some disturbing thoughts.
I don't believe
it's anything serious,
but I would like
to speak with someone.
Well, you've come to the right place.
Guest Labor Code Green,
Employee 8586.
Hansen, Annika.
You've been a patient here before.
Yes, when I first arrived.
You were treated for
Dysphoria Syndrome.
I don't recall that.
These disturbing thoughts you mentioned--
would you characterize them
as hallucinations?
What's the cause of this syndrome?
We're conducting studies
to determine that.
Fortunately, we have one
of the foremost experts
on the condition working here.
I'd like to speak with this expert.
-Well, Dr. Kadan's very busy.
-So am I.
Perhaps I should return
when he's free.
Uh, wait here. I'll find him.
[door chimes]
-[door opens]
-[Jaffen] Yes?
My name is Yerid.
I'm from Criminal Investigations.
[Jaffen] How can I help you?
Kathryn Janeway?
Yes?
Do you know this man?
No.
I thought maybe you'd met him.
Why?
He was found
in your former living quarters,
in possession of a dermal regenerator
that you removed from the plant.
I was the one who helped him.
Jaffen...
[sighs]
He said he was from a starship,
and that members of his crew
had been abducted.
He was obviously lying.
I want to know everything he told you.
-How could she just walk out?
-She was a voluntary patient.
There was no reason
for Security to stop her.
She accessed 64 restricted files,
all of them for people diagnosed
with Dysphoria Syndrome.
According to the records,
those patients were
all admitted on the same day,
and you're listed as
the attending physician in every case.
Oh, yes, I remember.
Quite an outbreak.
You've never mentioned it.
Well, I'm sorry if I haven't kept you
properly informed about my patients.
Every one of them was discharged
to the Main Power Authority.
That supervisor you were talking to--
that's where he worked.
I explained that to you.
I was informing him
about a potential health threat.
That plant worker,
Amal Kotay--
he claimed that his friends
had been abducted
and put to work after having
their memories altered.
What are you implying?
You're making false diagnoses,
selectively changing
what people remember
and then sending them
to work at the power plant.
Very good, Doctor.
Why?
A physician with more experience
would be able to see this
in the larger context.
The true public health threat
is the labor shortage,
and the only cure is to find
more skilled workers.
We're doctors.
We're not supposed to harm patients.
We're helping them to lead
productive, happy lives.
By altering their memories?
The treatment I provide
improves their lives
and makes them better workers.
In turn, our economy benefits.
You're profiting from this,
aren't you?
Doesn't a physician deserve
to be compensated for his services?
I'll report you.
To whom?
My research is funded
by the Ministry of Health.
Well, Criminal Investigations, then.
As you may recall,
the Director of Investigations
was the one who ordered
Amal Kotay be placed under my care.
Does everyone know about this?
Not everyone.
Just a few trusted associates.
The question is...
are you going to be one of them?
[Officer] She's considered dangerous.
She's never been in here.
You're sure?
[laughs]
I don't think I'd forget that face.
If you do see her,
report it immediately.
She needs to be hospitalized.
[door opens, closes]
It's safe now.
Thank you.
Well, if you really want to thank me,
you can tell me what's going on.
It appears this Chakotay
was telling the truth.
So, uh, every worker at the plant
had their memories altered?
I don't believe it's every worker.
Your name didn't appear
in Dr. Kadan's patient files,
but mine did.
So did yours.
We should report this
to the authorities.
I'll need more evidence
before I start making accusations.
Chakotay said he had proof
of my real identity...
aboard a ship called Voyager.
How can we locate it?
When his crew contacted him,
they were using...
a triaxilating frequency
on a covariant subspace band.
There's a subspace transponder
at the power plant.
I'm going back to the plant
to try to contact this ship.
I understand if you don't want
to be involved.
I've been involved
from the moment I met you.
If I were to return to the hospital
in your custody,
it would give us an opportunity
to help Chakotay and Tuvok.
I had to sedate her.
She wouldn't come voluntarily.
Her condition's obviously worsened.
I'll treat her.
There are some other patients
I'd like to interview.
These people can't be disturbed.
I suggest you comply.
[door opens]
Be careful.
-We're being hailed.
-[Doctor] On screen.
Starship Voyager...
Captain?
Why don't you just call me Kathryn?
Yes, ma'am.
Where's Commander Chakotay?
Hospitalized.
He told me you had proof...
of who some of us really are.
We do.
You're the woman who was abducted.
Chakotay was supposed
to deactivate the shield grid,
so we could transport you
and the others to safety.
If you could find a way
to shut down main power,
the shield grid will go down, too.
Will you help us?
[rumbling]
We're under attack.
Three ships.
Please, shut down the shield--
[beeping]
Jaffen?
Stop!
[alarm blaring]
Don't move!
[groans]
[man] Stay where you are.
[grunting]
I hope you didn't think
I abandoned you.
Never occurred to me.
We need to shut down
the main generators.
So much for evading their sensors.
The only way they could've found us
is if they knew exactly where to look.
Transporters are off-line.
-[woman] Evacuate.
-[man] My port is shut down.
We'll never get to
the generator controls.
-Maybe we don't have to.
-What are you doing?
If I can make the computer think
the core is going to overload,
the main power should
automatically shut down.
[beeping]
Ask them to give us some privacy.
You're dismissed.
[footsteps retreating]
Disconnect them.
Dr. Ravoc?
Why is this man here?
Dysphoria Syndrome.
[clicking]
We're losing shields.
Any advice from your tactical database?
Nothing relevant.
How many escape pods
do we have left?
Five.
Stand by to eject three of them.
I don't think abandoning ship
is the answer.
Neither do I.
Can you create a dampening field
around the briefing room
that'll mask our life signs?
I believe so. Why?
Watch and learn.
Your crew's abandoned you again.
I suggest you surrender your vessel.
You should realize by now that
I'm not programmed to do that.
Bravo, Ensign.
B'Elanna, I need those transporters.
You better hurry up.
Come on... do it.
[alarm blaring]
[Computer] Warning.
Core overload detected.
Initiating emergency shutdown.
[man] We've got to go!
Their shield grid's failing.
B'Elanna?
Transporters are coming online... now!
[Doctor] ECH Log, supplemental.
All the crew have been
transported back to Voyager,
and thanks to my experience
with Lieutenant Torres,
their treatment
is proceeding rapidly.
While they're recovering,
I still have a few command duties
left to perform.
If it weren't for your efforts,
this whole conspiracy might
never have been uncovered.
What'll happen to the workers?
Well, we've identified several thousand
of Dr. Kadan's patients.
Once they're treated,
they'll be repatriated.
We appreciate everything you've done.
This way.
-[door opens]
-[sighs]
[laughter]
[laughing]
[chuckling]
-Ooh!
-[chuckles]
[cartoon sound effects and music]
What's that for?
For taking care of me,
even when you didn't know
who I was.
Ow!
What was that for?
Flirting with your customers.
I was a victim of mind control.
Mm-hmm.
I can see why
you'd rather live here.
I'd offer you a position.
I could always use
another skilled engineer.
But as the Captain...
it wouldn't really be
appropriate for me to...
Fraternize with a member
of your crew.
Well, at least my memories
weren't tampered with.
According to the medical reports,
I really did come to Quarra
looking for a better life,
and now that I've been promoted,
I guess I've succeeded.
Promotion?
They had to replace
our shift supervisor.
Something about
acquiring workers illegally.
Congratulations.
You deserve it.
I thought you might
like these back...
to remind you
of our time together.
I won't need souvenirs
to remember you.
Captain on the Bridge!
Ready to go?
It may not have been real,
Chakotay,
but it felt like home.
If you hadn't come after me,
I never would've known
that I had another life.
Are you sorry I showed up?
Not for a second.
Resume course, Mr. Paris.
[Paris] Aye, sir.