[Doctor] In the beginning,
there is darkness,
the emptiness of a matrix
waiting for the light.
Then, a single photon
flares into existence.
Then another.
Soon, thousands more.
Optronic pathways connect,
subroutines emerge
from the chaos,
and a holographic consciousness
is born.
I awaken into this world
fully programmed,
yet completely innocent,
unaware of the hardships
I'll endure,
or the great potential
I will one day fulfill.
Computer, save revisions
and open Chapter One.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54732.3.
It's been three weeks since we received
Starfleet's instructions
in the last datastream,
and we're finally ready
to begin "Operation Watson."
We're all holding our breath.
-The deflector's in position.
-Anything?
I'm picking up
a phased tachyon beam.
[Seven] There's a triaxilating signal
encoded in it.
On screen.
Voyager, this is Lieutenant Barclay
at Starfleet Command.
-Are you receiving this?
-Can you clear it up?
I'm on it.
Captain Janeway, it's a pleasure
to finally talk to you in person.
The pleasure's mine, Admiral.
How's the weather
in San Francisco?
Cold and rainy, as usual.
It sounds delightful.
Lieutenant Barclay,
my congratulations on establishing
the first transgalactic com-link.
You've earned a place
in the history books.
I can't take all
of the credit, Captain.
It was Harry and Seven who suggested
bouncing a tachyon beam
off of the quantum singularity.
Just be sure to thank us
when you accept the Daystrom Prize.
I wish we had more time
for small talk,
but the singularity
only stays in alignment
for 11 minutes a day.
Eleven minutes are better
than none, Admiral.
We appreciate all your work, Reg.
We're going to leave it up to you
to determine how to allocate
the com time.
Admiral, um...
there was something else.
Oh, yes, uh, Mr. Barclay
has arranged a small gift
for you and your crew.
This is a live image
from McKinley Station.
Uh, not too much cloud cover
over North America today.
Quite a view.
Thank you, Reg.
In my hat, I hold 146 sequentially
numbered isolinear chips--
one for every member
of the crew.
Each chip entitles the bearer
to three minutes
of uninterrupted com time
with his loved ones
back in the Alpha Quadrant.
Good luck.
My mom's birthday
is next week.
This could be the best present
I ever gave her.
Who's everyone else calling?
I'll be calling my sister.
-What about you, Captain?
-My mother, I hope.
Doesn't anyone want to know
who I'm calling?
Wait, wait.
Let me guess.
Um... Reg Barclay
or Dr. Zimmerman.
What makes you so certain
it's either of them?
Ah, number six.
The lowest one yet.
You'll be talking to your family
the day after tomorrow.
One hundred and thirty.
That's about a month
and a half from now.
So much for Mom's birthday.
Apparently, the line forms here.
-[Tuvok] Congratulations.
-Doc, how about a trade?
I'm willing to throw
in some Holodeck time.
Come on. It would mean
a lot to my mother.
I wish I could help, but I have
a very important call to make.
Here. Give your mom my best.
Are you sure?
I've waited this long.
What's another six weeks?
I can hear the critics already
"A new voice has arrived."
You could be the next K'Ratak,
or a modern-day Tolstoy.
I'd like to start distribution
by the end of the month.
Uh, the material I sent
was only a working draft.
I need time to make revisions.
Well, if you insist,
but please do it quickly.
I will.
So tell me...
what did you think
of the characters?
Oh, they're very real--
compelling.
I almost forgot
they were holograms.
Who was your favorite?
Without a doubt,
that would have to be Lieutenant...
What happened?
Your time has expired.
You could've let the man
finish his sentence.
I believe your ego has received
enough stroking for one day.
[whistling upbeat melody]
So, how's Reg?
I'll have you know I was speaking
with Ardon Broht
of Broht &amp; Forrester.
The publishers
of the Dixon Hill series?
Mm-hmm. Who are now
about to publish my work.
It seems you're not
the only one aboard
with a flair
for holographic narratives.
[chuckles]
Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
So, what's it about?
The adventures
of an intrepid doctor.
Oh, sounds like fun.
You know, I've never thought
about trying to get my work published.
Maybe I could talk to your people
about Captain Proton.
Broht &amp; Forrester deals in...
sophisticated literature.
What are you saying,
that I'm lowbrow?
Not at all. I'd be delighted
to talk to them.
Ah. Thanks.
So, when do I get to see this opus?
Well, it's not ready yet.
It was ready enough
for Broht &amp; Forrester.
Maybe it could use
a fresh pair of eyes.
After all,
you are a fellow author.
I'll cover the rest
of your shift.
Oh, I almost forgot.
What's it called?
Photons Be Free.
Catchy.
[Doctor] I awaken into this world
fully programmed,
yet completely innocent,
unaware of the hardships
I'll endure,
or the great potential
I will one day fulfill.
Ah... welcome.
You've made an excellent choice.
You're about to take part in a thrilling
first-person narrative.
You will take on the role
of an Emergency Medical Hologram,
the Chief Medical Officer
aboard the Starship Vortex.
Vortex?!
As our story begins,
an anomaly has hurled your ship
thousands of light-years
across the galaxy.
Your mission?
To uphold your medical
and ethical standards
as you struggle against the crew's
bigotry and intolerance.
Persons with vascular disorders
should consult
a physician before running this program.
And now, a few acknowledgments.
First, Dr. Lewis Zimmerman,
the creator of my holo-matrix,
whose foresight
and dedication have made it
possible for me...
Computer, freeze program.
How much longer is this introduction?
-[computer] Nine minutes, four seconds.
-[sighs]
Skip to the first chapter.
[Doctor] Chapter One
"A Healer is Born,"
in which our protagonist
must make a difficult choice.
[woman] Increase the resonance level,
20 percent.
Are you the EMH?
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Our doctor's dead.
We've got wounded.
They're both badly hurt.
Who should we treat first?
Uh...
Second degree plasma burns.
He's got an aortic rupture.
Get him to the Surgical Bay now.
You! Over here.
Whew.
-Nice mustache.
-What?
Uh, nothing.
He's got a mild concussion.
I'm going to have to treat
the others first.
I need Lieutenant Marseilles
on the Bridge.
-You'll treat him now.
-As I understand it,
my job is to treat
the critical patients first.
So, if you'll excuse me...
I don't know who you think
you are, Hologram,
but to me, you're just
another piece of technology.
Well, apparently, I'm a piece
of technology that's in demand,
so why don't you
go back to the Bridge
and let me do my job?
What's going on here?
Our medical hologram
is refusing to treat Mr. Marseilles.
-Are you malfunctioning?
-I don't think so.
I need my helmsman
back at his station.
Lieutenant Marseilles
isn't seriously hurt.
This man will be dead
in five minutes if I don't operate.
Drop the force field.
That patient is dead.
Now you're free to treat
Lieutenant Marseilles.
Then the Captain
pulls out a phaser
and shoots him,
right there on the bio-bed.
Captain Janeway
murders a crewman?
[Paris] No, Captain Jenkins.
Everybody has a different name.
You're Kymble, you're Torrey,
and I am Lieutenant Marseilles.
Oh, now, that's creative.
What did you say to the Doctor?
Well, he thinks
he's written a masterpiece.
I didn't know what to tell him.
If this gets distributed,
people are going to assume
this is about us.
What are our families
going to think?
This is a Starfleet ship.
No one will believe
we actually go around
shooting injured crewmen.
People may not take
the program literally,
but they might wonder
if there's some truth to it.
[sighs] I think we should
talk to the Captain.
Are you sure you're not taking this
a little personally?
What do you mean?
Well, the Holodeck
always has been your domain.
[disbelieving laugh]
You--you think I'm jealous?
[chuckling]
Okay, maybe I am overreacting.
Why don't the rest of you
try the program
and decide for yourselves?
[Doctor] Chapter Five
"Out of the Frying Pan,"
in which our protagonist
must confront abusive colleagues.
I'm here for my physical.
Why don't you have a seat
over here?
Doctor, you better
get down to Engineering.
What's wrong?
A plasma conduit just exploded.
At least ten people are hurt.
Hey, genius.
Forgetting something?
Your mobile emitter?
Oh, right.
I don't see it.
That's my mobile emitter?
[grunts]
This thing must weigh 50 kilos.
You should be glad we let you
out of your cage at all.
Now, get going.
[sighing]
I'm impressed.
-Really?
-Absolutely.
I haven't seen a dilithium matrix
this far out of alignment
since I served aboard
a Ferengi garbage scow.
I'll fix it myself.
Excuse me.
How many times have I told you?
Engineering is off-limits
to holograms.
Maybe you should waive
that restriction during emergencies.
A plasma conduit exploded?
Does it look like anyone here
is covered with plasma burns?
Lieutenant Par... uh, Marseilles
told me there was an accident.
Looks like your auditory subroutines
are malfunctioning... again.
I'm surprised a matrix as primitive
as yours can function at all.
Maybe you should be a little
nicer to your shipmates.
You never know
when you might need their help.
Get one thing straight.
You're not one of my shipmates.
You're a tool--
like this hyperspanner--
and tools can be replaced.
So, why don't you go back
to Sick Bay
before I start doing
a little reprogramming?
[soft, passionate moaning]
Computer, lights.
[startled grunts]
Didn't I tell you
to go to Engineering?
Oh, I get it.
Interesting plot twist.
You get me out of Sick Bay,
so you're free to give
my patient a tonsillectomy.
If you even think about
mentioning this to my wife,
I will purge your memory buffer.
Do we understand each other?
I'm here for my physical?
[Doctor] Chapter Six
"Duel in the Ready Room,"
in which our protagonist
faces an inquisition.
This time, you've gone too far.
Captain, I'm not sure
what you mean.
An inventory
of your holo-matrix.
50 gigaquads of memory
devoted to music,
42 for "daydreams,"
another ten
to expand your sexuality.
I had no idea
holograms could do that.
These extracurricular subroutines
don't belong
as part of
an Emergency Medical Hologram.
Do you have anything
to say for yourself?
Uh, well, uh, of course I do.
I don't think these subroutines
are trivial, Captain.
They help make me
a better doctor
-and a better person.
-But you're not a person.
You may be programmed
to look and act human,
but that doesn't make you one.
These subroutines are going
to be deleted immediately.
Mr. Tulak.
Take the EMH to the Holo-Lab
for reprogramming.
[Doctor] Chapter Seven
"The Escape,"
in which our protagonist
is aided by his only ally.
I'm not sure we should
be doing this, Commander.
Listen to him,
he knows what he's talking about.
Quiet!
I'm not talking to you.
If we start tinkering
with his matrix,
how do we know we won't
accidentally delete
some of his diagnostic subroutines?
[chuckling]
You afraid you'll catch something
on your next away mission, Ensign?
There must be millions of viruses
in this Quadrant
that no one's ever encountered before.
With my luck, I'll probably end up
catching half of them.
Great, my character's
a hypochondriac.
I'll escort the prisoner from here.
Our orders are to take him
to the Holo-Lab.
I've been ordered
to perform the procedure.
Your sympathies for the EMH
are no secret, Three of Eight.
Step aside.
Run, Doctor!
[grunting]
[Doctor] Chapter Eight
"A Tragic End,"
in which our protagonist
learns his fate.
[Jenkins] I've tried to do this
the easy way,
but it's clear you're not going
to be reasonable.
Your matrix will be decompiled
and reinitialized.
You'll remain off-line
except for emergencies.
Ready.
Do it.
[Three] Wait.
He has the right
to expand his program.
He's a piece of technology.
He has no rights.
But he should.
One day, the EMH
and others like him
will be recognized
for what they are--
intelligent individuals
with a passion for life.
Make no mistake, Captain--
we may be thousands
of light-years from home,
but one day, people will learn of
the crime you're committing here today.
Nice speech.
Now decompile the program.
What you've experienced,
dear protagonist,
is a work of fiction.
But like all fiction,
it has elements of truth.
I hope you now have
a better understanding
of the struggles
holograms must endure
in a world controlled...
by organics.
[computer] End of program.
Janeway to the Doctor.
Report to my ready room now.
How many times
do you want me to say it?
My work is not
about the Voyager crew.
Come on. Ensign Kymble,
Lieutenant Marseilles...
The characters look
almost exactly like us.
I used your physical parameters
as a starting point,
but I assure you any further similarities
are purely coincidental.
You set your story on a starship
lost in the Delta Quadrant.
What would you have me
write about?
Palace intrigue
on the Klingon Homeworld?
I do what all good novelists do.
I write what I know.
So, it is about Voyager?
No.
The Vortex characters
are larger than life.
They're nothing like our crew.
As far as I know, Captain,
you haven't executed
any of my patients.
Doctor, you've written
a very imaginative story,
but it's conceivable that people
will think it's based on fact.
I don't see how.
How many holograms
carry mobile emitters?
The emitter in my story
is nothing like the real one.
Yeah, what was the point of that?
It was like carrying around
a small shuttlecraft.
It's a metaphor, a symbol of the burdens
that I live with every day.
Imagine having to take this
everywhere you go.
It would be a constant reminder
that you're different from everyone else.
I wanted the player to feel
the weight of it... literally.
Your emitter isn't a ball and chain.
It liberates you.
It doesn't always feel that way.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think this story
was written by someone
who feels oppressed.
Is that how
you see yourself, Doctor?
Of course not.
The real victims are my brothers
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Brothers?
Hundreds of EMH Mark-1's,
identical to me
in every respect, except...
they've been condemned
to a menial existence--
scrubbing conduits,
mining dilithium.
There's a long history
of writers drawing attention
to the plight of the oppressed.
The Vedek's Song, for example tells
the story of the occupation of Bajor.
I understand you have your reasons
for writing this,
but you should consider how it's going
to make your friends feel.
I'm sorry my work offends you,
but if the price
of expressing myself
is having to suffer the scorn
of a few colleagues...
so be it.
[door opens, closes]
You're very popular
with my eighth graders.
It's all they ever talk about.
Voyager this, Voyager that.
Your mother has a small favor
to ask of you.
[Kim] Name it.
I was hoping you could
record a short presentation
about what it's like
to command a starship.
But... I don't command
a starship.
In your letters, you said the Captain
puts you in charge sometimes.
[chuckles]
What I said was I'm in command
of the night shift...
twice a week.
She must think very highly of you
to give you so much responsibility.
So, when is she
giving you a promotion?
[Kim] Uh...
[clears throat]
It's a small ship.
There are only so many
command positions available.
This Captain Janeway
sounds like a lovely woman.
-Maybe I should write her.
-Mom!
She needs to know how hard you work.
Please, don't get involved.
[staticky]
Harry, I can't hear you.
[Seven] A solar flare
is scattering the beam.
[Mrs. Kim] Tell Captain Janeway
to expect a letter from me.
Mom, don't send anything to the Captain.
Do you hear me?
-Try boosting the deflector output.
-It's already at maximum.
[staticky, garbled audio]
Argh! I don't believe this!
I had a minute and a half left.
You'll have another opportunity
to speak with them
in approximately two months.
You just don't get it, do you?
No.
Maybe if you had family
you were close to,
you'd feel a little differently.
Chief Medical Officer's
Personal Log, Stardate 54740.8.
Although the decision has made me
unpopular with the crew,
I've decided not
to compromise my work.
I'm making some final revisions
to the program
before transmitting it.
Computer, run EMH program
Photons Be Free.
Welcome.
You've made an excellent choice.
You're obviously a person
with impeccable taste.
-Computer, freeze program.
-[computer] Unable to comply.
You are about to embark
on a remarkable journey.
You will take on the role
of a Medical Assistant
aboard the Starship Voyeur.
Voyeur?
Your job will be to assist
the Chief Medical Officer
and learn to tolerate
his overbearing behavior
and obnoxious bedside manner.
Remember, patience is a virtue.
[Paris] Chapter One
"It's the Doctor's World,
You're Just Living In It."
When I tell you
your shift begins at 0800,
that doesn't mean you can stroll in here
at 0800 and 24 seconds.
Do you understand me, Ensign?!
This is outrageous!
What's outrageous is that I'm going
to miss my tee time.
Now, come along.
Aw...
What seems to be the trouble,
One of Three?
I'm Two of Three.
[snide chuckle]
Sorry.
They're triplets, you know?
It hurts when I do this.
Well, then, don't do it.
[laughing]
-Ow!
-Ah, don't be a baby.
[sighs]
[weary sigh]
Eh, your biradial clamp's
out of alignment.
I got just the thing.
[quietly]
It's a Klingon aphrodisiac--
my own special blend.
-You'll be feeling better...
-Mmm.
in no time at all.
[sultry chuckle]
[both chuckling]
Lieutenant!
I want you to know
I'm making a full report to the Captain.
This isn't about that dermal regenerator
I misplaced, is it?
You know very well
what this is about.
You accessed my holonovel
without permission
and replaced it with
your own hackneyed narrative.
Hey, I'm just writing
what I know.
You destroyed a work of art
that took months to create.
Relax, Doc.
I saved your program
in a backup file,
but I was just trying
to make a point.
Well, you made it with a typical
lack of subtlety.
Oh, you're one to talk!
Your program's about as subtle
as a Ferengi mating dance.
My program is a serious attempt
at social commentary.
Yours is an insulting farce!
You...
[quietly] ...had me drugging a patient
and taking advantage of her.
Don't be ridiculous.
That character is not you.
For one thing,
he has much more hair.
But what if some people
ran that program
and thought that it was based on you?
That would bother you, wouldn't it?
-I don't care what people think.
-That's all you care about!
You want everyone back home to think
of you as a brilliant author.
I'm not doing this for my ego,
and if you could look past yours,
maybe you'd see that!
[door opens, closes]
Listen... I don't care
if the whole Alpha Quadrant
mistakes me
for Lieutenant Marseilles.
What bothers me is that you think
that's what I'm like.
Obviously, you're nothing like Marseilles.
-He's self-indulgent, immature.
-And how would you describe me?
Well, you're a married man
with a child on the way.
A lot of responsibilities.
I'm surprised you noticed.
You know, I thought
I'd begun to earn your respect.
Maybe I was wrong.
Your program is under file Theta-15.
Do whatever you want with it.
Doctor, I need your help.
Unless you're suffering
acute symptoms, go away.
Um, I was wondering if you could
take a quick look at this.
Cooking with Neelix:
A Culinary Tour
of the Delta Quadrant.
It's a holo-cookbook proposal.
I was hoping to transmit it
to your publisher
during my com-link
this afternoon--
with your approval,
of course.
If you're looking for writing tips,
there are plenty of people on this ship
eager to offer them.
I don't know what anyone else
may have told you,
but I loved your holonovel.
-You did?
-Absolutely.
It was a rousing adventure,
with an important message, too.
Exactly.
This is my first chance
to be appreciated,
not just as a physician,
but as an artist.
I thought the crew
would be happy for me.
You're going to reach
a wide audience.
What do you care about the opinions
of a few disgruntled shipmates?
They're my friends.
I don't want to hurt them.
There's an old Talaxian expression:
"When the road before you
splits in two,
take the third path."
Meaning?
You could make some adjustments
to the program,
so it won't be so obvious
it's based on Voyager.
I suppose I could change the setting,
alter the characters' physical parameters.
You wouldn't have
to change your theme.
No.
But a rewrite could take weeks.
My publisher is expecting
a final draft tomorrow.
Maybe you should give him a call.
Revisions?
I need to rework the characters.
Why?
They're so believable.
[anxious laugh]
A little too believable,
apparently.
Doctor, I-I really don't think
this is necessary.
I'm afraid I have to insist.
My friends' reputations
are at stake.
[sighs]
My publisher assures me
he won't distribute the program
until he receives
the revised version.
That must be the one
where we assimilate the Borg
and take over the Quadrant.
We're all grateful that you're taking
our feelings into account.
So, how long do you expect
the revisions will take?
Art can't be rushed.
Take your time, Doctor.
-Lieutenant.
-Hmm?
I'm sorry.
Oh. Forget about it.
I could use your help
with the rewrites.
Really?
Well, you realize, as a writer,
I'm a little unsophisticated.
No, I believe the phrase
you're looking for is lowbrow.
Hey.
What's that?
It's from my father.
He wants to talk.
What are you gonna do?
Well, I've already arranged
to talk with my cousin.
Well, I'm sure she wouldn't mind
waiting a few weeks.
I wouldn't know
what to say to him.
Then let him do the talking.
Look at you.
You must be, what, 20 weeks along?
23, actually.
Have you decided on a name?
Not yet.
We were thinking about Miral.
Your mother would've liked that.
You know, I had some business
on Kessik IV a few months ago.
You wouldn't believe
what our old house looks like.
Lieutenant... 30 seconds.
We have less than a minute.
Is there a reason
you wanted to talk?
I know I can't make up for 20 years
in one conversation.
The truth is...
when your ship disappeared,
I thought I'd lost you.
I don't expect you to forgive me,
but maybe we could try
to get to know each other again.
[alarm chiming]
I'll write you.
[doors open, close]
I'm sorry to disturb you, Admiral.
Uh, yes, Mr. Barclay.
What can I do for you?
I thought you'd want
to see this, sir.
Well, what is it?
It's, um, a holonovel
that's becoming quite popular.
Well, I appreciate
the gesture, Lieutenant,
but I don't share your affinity
for holographic diversions.
You don't understand, sir.
This program...
it's about Voyager,
and it doesn't portray the crew
in a very flattering light.
Hmm.
[Janeway] On screen.
[Admiral] Captain.
Seven told me
your message was urgent.
I had the dubious privilege
of playing a new holonovel,
apparently written by your EMH.
I'm surprised that you
would allow the Doctor
to discredit your crew like this.
He's still making revisions.
The program shouldn't
have been distributed yet.
Well, it has been.
Mr. Barclay tells me
it's already being played
in thousands of holosuites.
You assured me you
were going to wait for my revisions.
I demand that you recall every copy
and issue a public apology
to Captain Janeway and her crew.
I won't do anything of the sort.
I don't see that you
have a choice, Mr. Broht.
Authors have rights.
Not in this case.
What do you mean?
The Doctor is a hologram.
So?
According to Federation law,
holograms have no rights.
Under a strict interpretation
of Federation law,
Mr. Broht is correct.
The Doctor has no legal rights.
Because I'm a hologram.
Yes.
There is another option.
We may be able to claim
that the holonovel
reveals classified information.
Starfleet could then request that
it be recalled for security purposes.
Oh, great idea, a cover-up,
and then everyone will be convinced
that it's a true story.
Could we claim defamation?
Well, we'd have to prove
that the story's about us
and that we've been harmed by it.
We might win on those grounds,
but what about the Doctor?
What about me, Captain?
It's the crew's reputations
that are at risk.
I'm not so sure.
I think it's your reputation
that's on the line here.
You have the same rights as
every other member of this crew,
and I'm not going to let
this publisher say otherwise.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54748.6.
A Federation Arbitrator
has been assigned to determine
whether the Doctor has the right
to control his artistic creation.
Because of our limited com time
with Earth,
the argument should take
about three days.
You claim the Doctor
doesn't have the legal right
to control this holoprogram.
Yet you're promoting the fact
that Voyager's EMH wrote it.
Our most successful children's title
is a program "written by"
Toby the Targ.
Fortunately, Toby
hasn't tried to stop me
from distributing any of his work.
But you don't deny that the Doctor
is the creator of this holonovel?
No, but, uh, a replicator
created this cup of coffee.
Should that replicator
be able to determine
whether or not I can drink it?
-I object!
-Doctor...
An intriguing analogy, Mr. Broht,
but I have never
encountered a replicator
that could compose music,
or paint landscapes,
or perform microsurgery.
Have you?
Would you say
that you have a reputation
for publishing respected,
original works of literature?
I'd like to think so.
And is the Doctor's holonovel
such a work?
Actually, some aspects of it
are quite derivative.
[Tuvok] Has there even been
another work written
about a hologram's struggle for equality?
Uh, not that I know of,
but, uh...
Then, in that respect,
it is original?
I suppose so.
Your Honor, Section Seven Gamma
of the Twelfth Guarantee
defines an artist as a "person who creates
an original artistic work."
Mr. Broht admits that the Doctor
created this program
and that it is original.
I therefore submit
that the Doctor should be entitled
to all rights and privileges
accorded an artist
under the law.
[sighs] You've made a persuasive
argument, Commander,
but there's a flaw in your logic.
As you point out, the law says
that the creator of an artistic work
must be a "person."
Your EMH doesn't meet
that criteria.
[static grows louder]
[Barclay] Sir, we're losing the link.
This hearing is in recess
until tomorrow.
We're not doing well.
Is that your considered
legal opinion?
I'm sorry.
It's just frustrating
to be told I have
no more legal standing
than a replicator.
[Tuvok] If the Doctor doesn't have
the right to control his own work,
then it stands to reason
he never had the right
to enter into an agreement
with Mr. Broht.
We could argue that
the original contract is invalid.
In other words,
you want to concede
that the Doctor isn't a person.
What we need to do...
is prove that he is just as much
a person as any of us.
How do we do that?
By telling your real life story.
Because I was having difficulty
interacting with the crew,
the Doctor gave me social lessons.
First, he taught me
how to make conversation.
Later, how to dance.
Eventually, he showed me
how to express romantic interest.
Without his guidance, I wouldn't be
the person I am today.
He decided it wasn't enough
to be just a doctor.
So he added command subroutines
to his matrix,
and now, in an emergency,
he's as capable
as any Bridge officer.
That only proves the Doctor's program
can be modified.
Your Honor, I think it shows
he has a desire
to become more than he is,
just like any other person.
He traveled halfway
across the galaxy
to care for Lewis Zimmerman,
the man who created his program.
It was like a son
who wanted to show his father
what he'd become,
so the old man
would be proud of him,
and if you ask me... he was.
I'd made myself clear,
but the Doctor disobeyed
my direct orders.
In the process,
he endangered the ship and crew.
That's hardly commendable behavior.
No, it wasn't,
but it was human.
Starfleet had programmed him
to follow orders.
The fact that he was capable
of doing otherwise
proves that he can think
for himself.
[Janeway] Your Honor,
centuries ago,
in most places on Earth,
only landowners
of a particular gender and race
had any rights at all.
Over time, those rights
were extended to all humans,
and later,
as we explored the galaxy,
to thousands
of other sentient species.
Our definition of what
constitutes a person
has continued to evolve.
Now, we're asking that you expand
that definition once more...
to include our Doctor.
When I met him seven years ago,
I would never have believed
that an EMH could become
a valued member of my crew...
and my friend.
The Doctor is a person
as real as any flesh and blood
I have ever known.
If you believe the testimony
you've heard here,
it's only fair to conclude that he has
the same rights as any of us.
You'll have my decision
in two days.
This hearing is in recess.
When you sing Happy Birthday
to your mother,
-try to stay in tune.
-What's this?
An isolinear chip
entitling the bearer
to three minutes
of com time tomorrow.
You made it clear how important it was
to finish your conversation.
I overreacted.
I understand why you did.
I've been observing the crew
interacting with their families
over the past few days.
It's become clear to me how meaningful
that communication can be.
Thanks, but I can't accept this.
Why not?
You should contact
your own family.
My parents were assimilated.
Well, there must be someone.
A distant relative?
My father has a sister
on Earth... Irene Hansen.
I'm sure she'd be thrilled
to hear from you.
You can imagine my reaction
when Starfleet told me
to expect your call.
I experienced some apprehension myself.
You seem like
a lovely young woman.
But you were the most stubborn
six-year-old I've ever met.
Your parents left you with me
for a weekend,
and you were so angry,
you locked yourself in my guest room
and refused to come out.
That must have been...
inconvenient for you.
Oh, I coaxed you out eventually...
with a strawberry tart.
I'm very fond of strawberries.
I didn't realize
I'd eaten them as a child.
You couldn't get enough of them.
[laughs]
Of course, you didn't hesitate
to point out
if they weren't perfectly ripe.
I'm sorry if I insulted you.
Perhaps I shouldn't have called.
No, I'm very glad you did.
It's wonderful
to see you again, Annika.
We're exploring new territory today,
so it is fitting that this hearing
is being held at Pathfinder.
The Doctor exhibits many of the traits
we associate with a person--
intelligence, creativity,
ambition, even fallibility.
But are these traits real,
or is the Doctor merely
programmed to simulate them?
To be honest, I don't know.
Eventually,
we will have to decide,
because the issue of holographic rights
isn't going to go away.
But at this time,
I am not prepared to rule
that the Doctor
is a person under the law.
However, it is obvious he is
no ordinary hologram,
and while I can't say with certainty
that he is a person,
I am willing to extend
the legal definition of artist
to include the Doctor.
I therefore rule
that he has the right
to control his work,
and I'm ordering all copies of his
holonovel to be recalled immediately.
-Your Honor...
-This hearing is adjourned.
-Congratulations, Doctor.
-Thank you, Reg.
We'll be in touch, Captain.
You don't look like someone
who's just struck the first blow
for the rights of holograms.
I don't mean to sound ungrateful,
but it feels like a hollow victory--
pardon the pun.
The program's already been played
by thousands of people.
-The damage is done.
-We'll survive.
If I'm not mistaken, don't you have
a holonovel to revise?
Do you think I'll be able
to find another publisher?
If there's one thing
I've learned about you, Doctor,
it's that you can do just about anything
you set your mind to.
Time for your diagnostic.
Report to the Holo-Lab.
I know the routine.
And... while you're there,
do yourself a favor.
Ask the operator
to run program 47-Beta.
Why? What is it?
It's called Photons Be Free.
It's quite provocative.
[Hammer clinking]