[man distorted, staticky]
We, the people of Earth,
greet you in a spirit
of peace and humility.
As we venture out
of our solar system,
we hope to earn the trust
and friendship of other worlds.
[Vivaldi's Spring Concerto playing]
[transmission static]
-Can you reduce the interference?
-I'm trying.
-[music swells]
-What is it?
I don't know.
Distance?
It just entered the atmosphere.
They evolved from dinosaurs?
Hadrosaurs, to be precise.
Their ancestors settled
in the Delta Quadrant
20 million years ago.
The Voth, the Kobali,
the Vaadwaur.
You've made first contact
with more species
than any captain
since James Kirk.
It helps being
the only Starfleet ship
within 30,000 light-years.
You are being too humble.
From the first time you spoke up
in my classroom,
I knew you'd go far.
A little farther than
I expected, Professor.
I have my Admiral hat
on today, Kathryn,
and I didn't call
just to catch up.
Starfleet has
a mission for you.
[man] We, the people of Earth
greet you in a spirit
of peace and humility.
As we venture out
of our solar system,
we hope to earn the trust
and friendship of other worlds.
Friendship I.
I had to memorize
that recording in third grade.
[chuckles]
Me, too.
I even built a model
of the probe.
Then this should look familiar.
It was launched in 2067.
Just four years
after Zefram Cochrane
tested his first warp engine.
What was it
designed to do?
Reach out to other species.
Pave the way for all the manned missions
that would follow.
They packed it
with information--
translation matrices,
scientific and culture databases.
Computer chip designs, instructions
for building transceivers.
It's practically a how-to manual.
[Seven] If the Borg
had intercepted this probe,
humanity would have been assimilated
centuries ago.
Our ancestors had no idea
what was out here.
This must have been before
your Prime Directive.
It was before Starfleet existed.
In any case, we lost contact
with the probe 130 years ago.
But its last-known coordinates...
[Torres] Let me guess.
We're in the neighborhood.
Starfleet's mapped out
a search grid.
It'll take us
a little off course,
but if the probe
is still intact,
and we're lucky enough
to find it,
we'll be retrieving
a little piece of history.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54775.4.
We've been searching for five days
without any sign of the probe,
but we're not about
to disappoint Starfleet
on our first official assignment
in seven years.
Nothing in Grid 295.
Mr. Paris.
Moving on.
We should try skipping ahead a little
to Grid 310.
I stayed up all night
re-extrapolating
the probe's trajectory.
I've compensated for
solar winds, ionic interference,
and a few local anomalies
Starfleet wouldn't know about.
Alter course to Grid 310.
Trying to impress
the Starfleet brass?
-Just doing my job.
-[chuckles]
I'm detecting a titanium signature
that matches the probe's parameters.
Location?
A planet two light-years away.
Confirmed.
Good job, Harry.
[Seven] The readings are coming
from the northern subcontinent.
Can you localize them?
There are high levels
of antimatter radiation
in the atmosphere, scattering
the probe's signature.
Any life signs?
None.
Assemble an away team and take the Flyer
down for a closer look.
[whistling tune]
You seem to be
in a good mood, Doctor.
Just excited to be doing my part
for our first official mission,
Mr. Carey.
An inoculation a day
keeps the radiation away.
I took a look at
those atmospheric readings.
Thermal eddies,
gravimetric shear.
You're going to need
your best pilot.
Are you volunteering?
Well, if the Doc can spare me.
I'll muddle through.
If you're here
for your fetal resonance scan,
you're a day early.
I'm here for my inoculation.
You are not going
on this mission.
Chakotay said he needed
an engineer.
[Paris] He's already got one.
Now he's got two.
Will you excuse us?
Any bets on this one?
My money's on B'Elanna.
It's been months since I've been
on an away mission.
Then try the holodeck.
The Flyer is full.
You can make room.
Neelix doesn't have to go.
He's not six months pregnant.
Being pregnant doesn't
make me an invalid.
[sighs]
No, it doesn't.
But there's a toxic atmosphere
down there,
and you're breathing for two.
[sighs]
All right, you win.
But if we have another baby,
you carry it,
and I'll go on
the away missions.
It's a deal.
Sorry for the bumpy ride.
We'll be clearing the stratosphere
in about a minute.
I had a cousin who used
to transport disulfides
from a gas giant.
He claimed
to love the turbulence.
Of course, disulfides
are known to cause delusions.
Hang on.
I thought it was uninhabited.
[Kim] There's nothing alive
down there now.
Radiation levels
are at 6,000 isorems.
I've localized the signature
to a three-kilometer radius.
Transfer the coordinates
to the helm.
When we find the probe,
we'll beam it to the cargo hold.
That may not be easy
with all this radiation.
We'd better bring
transport enhancers.
Set us down, Tom.
Yes, sir.
Gently, please.
I should have brought
a holo-camera,
so I could show B'Elanna
she's not missing anything.
Can you believe she actually wanted
to come with us?
[Carey] When my wife was pregnant,
she didn't want
to be coddled, either.
[laughs]
And she's not half Klingon.
Oh, maybe it's us.
Something about fatherhood
seems to regress the male psyche
a few thousand years.
[tricorders beeping]
Tom, be careful.
[classical music playing]
[Paris] It's a toy.
Like a music box.
Vivaldi.
[beeping]
I'm getting something.
90 meters this way.
[music stops]
Souvenir.
[Kim] Commander, I'm detecting
an antimatter signature ahead.
[Chakotay] Looks like missile silos.
[Paris] Paris to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
We've got a reading
that could be the probe.
It's inside a cave.
[Chakotay] Keep us posted.
The warhead is still active.
It wouldn't have taken
many of these
to trigger a nuclear winter.
[Neelix] People must have
taken shelter here.
[Carey] Well, it makes sense.
The magnesite in these caves
would have provided
partial shielding
from the radiation.
[tricorder beeps insistently]
[Paris] Over here!
[Carey] What'd you find?
[Paris] Some kind of control room
or laboratory.
[Carey] Laboratory?
[Paris] Lots of diagnostic equipment.
Looks like it was salvaged
from a junk heap.
[Neelix] Or scavenged
from the ruins.
[Carey] Particle scanners,
circuit analyzers.
Most of it's still functional.
They were working on something.
[Paris] This is what we came for.
Whoever lived here
must have been studying it.
The datacore is still intact.
Start setting up
the transport enhancers.
[Paris] Paris to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
We found the probe.
Well, pieces of it, anyway.
We're getting ready to beam it
back up to the Flyer.
We'll meet you there.
[rattling]
[Neelix] Hello?
Is someone there?
The tricorder isn't
reading any life signs.
[weapons being charged]
[console beeping]
[sighs]
[grunting]
Don't move.
[grunts]
-[grunts]
-You okay?
Delta Flyer to Paris.
Chakotay to away team.
Respond.
[explosion]
They're antimatter weapons.
Shields are off-line.
What are you doing?
Getting us out of here.
What about the others?
We can't do them any good
if we're dead.
We'll come back for them.
Look, you're making a mistake...
[grunting]
[groans]
[Verin] Leave them alone!
Who are you?
I'm Lieutenant Tom Paris.
We're from the Federation
Starship Voyager.
What are these?
They're transport enhancers.
We were going to use them
to retrieve our probe.
Your probe?
Too bad you didn't come
for it sooner.
You would have saved us
a lot of suffering.
We still can't contact the others
or get a fix on their life signs.
Why didn't we detect the aliens?
I don't know.
Whoever they are,
they have antimatter weapons.
Antimatter?
[Tuvok] Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
We are being hailed
from the surface.
The away team?
No.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway.
Who am I speaking with?
My name is Verin.
Your crewmen are my prisoners.
Why? We haven't done
anything to harm you.
You committed genocide.
I think there's been
a misunderstanding.
-We arrived here just...
-You're from Earth?
Yes.
Then you're going to pay
for what your people did to us.
I'm sorry, I don't know
what you're talking about.
We're not as naive as you seem
to think we are, Captain, not anymore.
What is it you want?
I want you
to get us off this planet.
Find us a new home.
Release my crewmen and
we can talk about it.
No more talking.
Your people won't be safe
until mine are.
Listen, I don't
respond well to threats.
And I don't want to kill anyone,
but I will if you don't cooperate.
You have three hours
to begin evacuating us.
Start scanning
for the nearest M-Class planet.
You intend
to meet his demands?
I'm just keeping my options open.
You're with me.
I've analyzed his garment.
It's lined with magnesite.
A makeshift environmental suit.
Unfortunately, the protection
it offers is limited.
His tissues are saturated
with antimatter radiation.
It explains why we couldn't
detect his life signs.
They're virtually indistinguishable
from the environment.
Now that we know that, maybe we can
adjust our sensors to detect them.
Let's wake him.
[soft groaning]
What were you doing
aboard our shuttle?
Trying to undo the damage
you caused.
If you're referring
to what's happened on your planet,
we had nothing to do with it.
Your people sent the probe...
[wheezes]
...didn't they?
Our ancestors sent it
300 years ago,
to make contact
with other species.
They did a little more than that.
Am I your prisoner?
No. You're suffering from
prolonged radiation exposure.
I can treat you.
You can?
I believe I can.
In exchange for what?
Nothing.
I have a wife, friends.
We might be able
to help them, too,
but not while our crewmen
are being held hostage.
You said you were trying
to undo the damage we caused.
What did you mean by that?
I was aboard your shuttle
looking for technology
that might help us
neutralize the radiation.
We saw missiles
on the surface.
Was the destruction
caused by war?
Those missiles were built for defense.
They were never launched.
Then what accounts
for the devastation?
A containment failure
in our power grid.
Once the antimatter was released,
it destroyed everything.
I'm sorry, but I still don't see
how we're responsible.
Before the probe,
my people never conceived
of anything like antimatter.
"We offer this information freely
with the hope
that one day
we will stand on your soil
and extend our hands
in friendship."
I'm sure you recognize those words.
The recording from the probe.
Your people sent us technology
that they knew would destroy us.
I don't understand.
We didn't either at first,
but we had decades
to think about it,
and now it seems so obvious.
You send us new technology,
encourage us to use it,
and then you wait for us
to obliterate ourselves.
Why would we do that?
Because it's easier
than invading us.
Do you really believe we'd contaminate
a world we intended to conquer?
I'm a scientist.
I believe what I see.
And today, I saw your people
standing on our soil
just as you promised,
and they were wearing equipment that
protected them from the radiation,
because they knew
exactly what to expect.
If you were in my position,
what would you believe?
He might have a concussion.
I need the medkit
from my pack.
I was told not to let you
use your equipment.
[sighs]
When's your baby due?
My wife's pregnant, too.
We're expecting a little girl
in a couple of months.
How do you know it's a girl?
Well, we have technology
that allows us to
examine the fetus.
She has my eyes
and her mother's cranial ridges.
Is this your first?
No.
Oh.
Boys? Girls?
Two boys and a girl.
What are their names?
They were all stillborn.
I'm sorry.
You're... a doctor?
No, I'm just a medic.
But we have the best doctor
in the Quadrant back on Voyager.
-He might be able to help...
-I shouldn't be talking to you.
[Tuvok] Our current coordinates
and the nearest M-Class planet--
132 light-years away.
At maximum warp, that's about
two months round trip.
How many people
are we talking about?
If these sensor modifications
are correct,
about 5,500.
It would take
at least 17 trips--
almost three years--
to complete the relocation.
We've made sacrifices
to help people before.
What about Tom
and the others?
Are they supposed
to rot down there
until this relocation's finished?
I don't think Verin's going to let go
of his only bargaining chips.
Then we may have
to use force.
Not until we've exhausted
every other option.
These people believe
that we're violent.
I'm not going to do anything
to reinforce that belief,
unless it becomes
absolutely necessary.
-I've extracted the nanoprobes.
-I'll begin reprogramming them.
Nanoprobes?
Microscopic machines.
Hopefully they'll help us
repair your damaged tissue.
You said you extracted them.
From where?
My bloodstream.
They maintain
my cybernetic implants.
Nanoprobes, cybernetic implants.
Are others on your crew like you?
No, I'm... unique.
You certainly are.
I need a word
with your patient.
You told me you've been
looking for ways
to neutralize the radiation.
All my life.
Tell me about your work.
[low, indistinct chatter]
[groaning]
Lieutenant?
I'm okay.
My stomach's just
a little queasy.
Our inoculations
must be wearing off.
I thought these caves
were naturally shielded.
They're no substitute
for an environmental suit.
These people have lived here all
their lives without environmental suits.
These people have lived here
without much of anything.
[rattling]
Hello.
It's all right.
We're not going to hurt you.
What's your name?
Yun.
Uh, mine's Tom.
This is Joe and Neelix.
You're not like them.
We're different species,
but they're my friends.
They say you're going
to take us on your ship
and find us a new home.
I'm sure our Captain
is trying to help you.
Neelix...
where's our "souvenir"?
In my pack.
Uh, excuse me.
Um, we'd like to
give her something.
It's in the equipment bag.
It's a toy.
[Vivaldi's Spring Concerto playing]
That could be a weapon.
[music stops]
It's harmless.
These men are dangerous.
I want you to stay away
from them.
Understood?
Well, so much
for making friends.
Mr. Verin?
What are you doing?
My job.
I'm Voyager's ambassador, remember?
Can I have a word with you?
Just between us...
I understand why you
don't trust humans.
Then why are you with them?
They're not so bad once
you get to know them.
When I first met them,
I thought they were arrogant,
self-righteous.
I suppose you're going to tell me
you've changed your mind.
Well, not completely.
I still think
they take themselves
far too seriously
for my taste.
But one thing they don't do
is harm other people.
Are you blind?
No, I see very clearly
what's happened to you,
and I'd like to help.
How?
My Captain listens to me.
I can speak to her
on your behalf,
help her understand your situation.
What do you know
about our "situation"?
I know what you've been through.
My planet was destroyed
by a weapon
called a metreon cascade.
Hundreds of thousands
of people were killed...
including my family.
How did you survive?
I was on a neighboring planet
when the weapon was detonated.
I went back with a rescue team,
but there was no one left.
I'm sorry about what happened
to your family...
but don't compare your life
to mine.
The nearest suitable planet
is simply too far away,
so I'd like to propose
an alternative.
There is no alternative.
Please, hear me out.
We have one of your people
aboard, a Mr. Otrin.
He has some interesting ideas
about counteracting the radiation.
Otrin has too many ideas.
I think his theories have merit.
What he's lacked until now
is the means to carry them out.
If you release the hostages,
we can work together.
There's a good chance
we could undo some of the damage
to your environment.
This isn't a negotiation.
You don't seem to understand.
It would take years to evacuate
the entire planet.
So instead,
you once again offer us
the benefits of your technology.
What I'm offering you
is a realistic alternative.
If I release the hostages,
what's to prevent you
from leaving or attacking us?
Look, I know you've suffered,
and I know you don't trust us.
You haven't given me
any reason to.
Then why don't we start
with a small step?
You return one of the hostages,
and I'll send you a supply
of food and medicine.
You... what's your name?
Joe Carey.
Set up your...
transport enhancers.
I'm sorry... Mr. Carey.
Sorry?
Your crewman's ready, Captain.
Transport him to Sick Bay.
Hey, what the hell
are you doing?!
-[fires weapon]
-Tom?
[Doctor] Sick Bay to Bridge.
-[steady tone sounds]
-They've killed Lieutenant Carey.
If you think murdering
one of my crewmen
is going to make me more receptive
to your demands, you're mistaken.
Don't force me
to kill anyone else.
All right.
I'll evacuate your people.
But our transporters aren't designed
to accommodate large groups.
We'll need time to modify them.
We'll be ready within the hour.
If you're not...
I understand.
My ready room.
You have radiation poisoning.
This will make you feel better.
Thank you.
Why are you helping us?
Your child's going to need a father.
Isn't she?
The first phase
of your therapy is complete.
How do you feel?
I can breathe more easily.
Your lungs were damaged
by the radiation.
The nanoprobes are repairing them.
It's incredible.
If we could manufacture
more of these,
we might be able
to treat everyone.
Unfortunately, Mr. Verin
has refused our help.
Did you expect him to cooperate?
His behavior is irrational.
To you, maybe,
but you haven't lived like we have.
No, but that doesn't mean
that we're responsible
for what's happened here.
You can't deny
your people sent the probe.
They made an error in judgment.
They failed to anticipate
the consequences of their actions,
but they never meant
to destroy your world.
Human culture has evolved,
learned from its mistakes.
So can yours.
Even if I believed you,
Verin never would.
Then your people may need
a change of leadership.
Someone more open
to new ideas.
I'm not a leader.
But you're a scientist.
Someone who can see a problem
and envision a solution.
The same definition
could apply to a leader.
[Paris] Doesn't seem fair, does it?
My daughter...
she'll have food,
medical care,
everything she needs.
-[female groans]
-What's wrong?
[woman] We need help.
-It's the baby.
-[gasping]
It's too soon.
Let him help me.
Can you?
I think so,
but I'll need my medkit.
Inform Verin.
I'm losing the heartbeat.
Oh, no!
-What are you doing?
-Speeding up the contractions.
[groaning]
Their ship's returned.
Send out patrols.
Double the guard
at the entrance.
[female groaning]
[groaning]
[shouting]
I've got him!
He's not breathing.
Cardio-stimulator.
Three millijoules.
Now.
Don't move.
I'll take him to Verin.
Find the others.
This way. Move!
Increase the charge
to five millijoules.
-[female crying]
-Again.
I'm reading a heartbeat.
[gasps]
Oh!
[baby crying]
You have a son.
Oh.
One of the patrols
took another prisoner.
Put him with the others.
[baby crying]
We need to get him
to Voyager.
He stays here.
[Neelix] Mr. Tuvok?
Your Captain was foolish enough
to think she could rescue you.
Instead, she's given me
another hostage.
[grunting]
-[sighs]
-Doc?
When you need to infiltrate
a toxic environment,
it helps to be a hologram.
Prepare the transport enhancers.
Tuvok to Chakotay.
We've secured the hostages.
Good work.
Chakotay to Delta Flyer.
Two to beam out.
Thank you.
Now, Mr. Paris.
Your baby won't survive
without treatment.
I promise we'll bring him back.
Take good care of him.
I will.
Tuvok to Voyager.
Five to beam up.
[Doctor] Cute little fellow,
isn't he?
He's already responding
to treatment.
Once he's stabilized,
we'll transport him to the surface,
and send along some food
and medical supplies.
We're leaving?
As soon as I report to Starfleet.
Captain.
Once the baby's back
in that environment,
he's just going
to get sick again.
I'm sorry, we can't keep him
from his mother.
I'm not suggesting that.
You told those people
that we might be able to
neutralize the radiation.
-Was that true?
-Yes, but they didn't want our help.
-I can't force it on them.
-Maybe you should.
If we help them without
asking anything in return,
it'll prove they're wrong about us.
You're forgetting something.
They killed Mr. Carey.
I'm not about to risk any more lives
to help murderers.
Captain, it was one man
who killed Carey.
If you saw how they were living,
how desperate they are...
I'm not saying we should
ignore what happened,
but humans did play a part
in their suffering.
Intentional or not, that probe had
a terrible impact on these people.
If there's anything we can do
to make up for that now,
we at least have to try.
[Otrin] I've adjusted
the radiation levels
to match the conditions
on the surface.
Watch.
An isolitic chain reaction.
It recombines the nucleonic particles
in the atmosphere.
How do we apply your methods
on a planetary scale?
Atmospheric processors
are one possibility.
Too bad we don't have a corps
of engineers to build them.
What if we encased
the catalytic agent
in photon torpedoes,
used the concussive force
to start the reaction?
It would require multiple detonations
at low altitude,
but I believe it could work.
Captain, an isolitic reaction
of that magnitude
would expand exponentially.
Your ship might not survive.
We'll have to modify our shields,
reinforce structural integrity.
Well, let's get started.
He's beautiful.
And they can give us enough medicine
to treat everyone.
Can they rebuild our cities?
Bring back the people who died?
They're offering to help,
and this time
no one's coercing them.
We can't trust these people.
They just sent armed men
to attack us.
They only wanted
to rescue their hostages.
Who knows what they wanted?
You're being irrational.
What's irrational
is cooperating with the enemy.
Look at my child.
They said that
they would treat him,
and they kept their word.
Shield modifications on line.
Torpedoes?
-Ready.
-Hail them.
-Listen to me.
-[Janeway] Otrin, we're ready to begin.
Understood.
Good luck.
Tom, take us down.
We're 10,000 meters
into the troposphere.
Fire the first sequence.
[rumbling]
[grunting]
They're attacking us!
It's only the shock wave
from the detonations.
-[booming]
-[female] No.
Shields?
Holding at 18 percent.
Are you going to stand there
while he helps them destroy us?
[indistinct chatter]
-[alarm sounds]
-What are you doing?
Fighting back.
Captain, they're opening
missile silos.
They're targeting Voyager.
At 18 percent, our shields won't withstand
an antimatter explosion.
We should return to orbit.
Not yet.
Fire the next sequence.
You can't launch those missiles!
Hold him!
Stop!
What are you doing?
I won't let you ruin
our only chance for survival.
You'd kill me?
To save my child...
yes.
Get that weapon away from her.
No... sir.
I've kept you alive...
all of you!
And we're grateful for that.
But survival isn't enough anymore.
Are you in command now?
If I have to be.
Everyone,
come outside! Hurry!
-[female] All right, come on.
-[male] What's going on?
Bring him.
[female] This way.
[indistinct chatter]
[Yun] It's beautiful.
[laughter]
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've retrieved Friendship I
and resumed our course
to the Alpha Quadrant,
but the success of our mission
had a very high price.
Impressive, isn't it?
The detail's amazing.
Carey spent months
working on it.
He used to joke
that it wouldn't be finished
by the time
we got back to Earth.
He only had
one nacelle to go.
We were able to download
the probe's memory core.
We'll transmit the telemetry
in the next datastream.
I think about our ancestors...
thousands of years
wondering if they were alone
in the universe,
finally discovering they weren't.
You can't blame them
for wanting to reach out,
see how many other species
were out there
asking the same questions.
The urge to explore
is pretty powerful.
But it can't justify
the loss of lives...
whether it's millions...
[clinking]
...or just one.