Beautiful, isn't it?
A sensor analysis would have
provided the necessary information.
Just admiring the view.
The conference begins
in less than an hour.
There's always time
for warp field dynamics,
but you don't see natural beauty
like this every day.
What was that?
Some kind of energy barrier
directly below us.
It spans thousands
of square kilometers.
Why didn't our sensors detect it?
I'm not certain.
It has an unusual tetryon signature.
Species 312 used a similar technology.
There's a power surge
coming from the barrier.
Shields at full.
They're creating
some kind of feedback.
We've lost impulse engines.
Go to warp.
The warp core is off-line.
Warp engines don't just shut down
when you scrape an energy barrier.
It's affecting all our systems.
[Computer] Warning.
Structural failure in 30 seconds.
We'll have to beam to the surface.
We can't transport through the barrier.
Transfer auxiliary power
to the weapons array.
What are you trying to do?
If I can realign our phasers
to the correct frequency,
I may be able to open a rift.
Big enough to get
a shuttle through, I hope.
[Computer] Warning. Structural failure
in ten seconds...
nine... eight...
-Phasers reconfigured.
-...five...
The barrier's closed again.
-[groans]
-I should examine you.
I don't think it's serious.
You have a hairline fracture.
We've got bigger problems.
I'll be fine.
[tricorder beeping insistently]
I'm detecting shuttle debris scattered
over several square kilometers.
-Some of it might still be functional.
-If we can find the right components,
we may be able to construct a beacon,
send a distress signal.
-Through the barrier?
-[sighs] Maybe.
If we hurry, we might
still make that conference.
Well, if we have
to be stranded somewhere,
you couldn't ask for a nicer place.
We wouldn't be stranded at all
if you hadn't insisted
on admiring the view.
Guest Vessel 74656,
this is Ledos Port Control.
Shut down your engines.
This is Lieutenant Tom Paris.
Is there a problem?
You were observed committing
Piloting Violation 256.
[sighs] I'm sorry, I'm not familiar
with your regulations.
It won't happen again.
You will be informed of the penalty.
What kind of "penalty"?
That's not my decision.
Your docking permit says you're assigned
to the Starship Voyager.
That's right.
Your commanding officer will be
notified of your infraction.
Piloting lessons?
Well, apparently, the standard penalty
for your infraction
is a three-day course in flight safety
followed by a test.
Well, did you explain to them
that we wouldn't be here that long?
Well, actually, while you were
completing your mission,
Seven was invited
to a four-day conference.
Here on Ledos?
I decided to give
the entire crew shore leave.
It'll give you plenty of time
to brush up on your piloting skills.
I don't need lessons.
Apparently, the authorities disagree.
-[scoffs] But, Captain...
-You may not have known
the Ledosians' rules,
but you know ours.
Comply with local law, understood?
Yes, ma'am.
[tricorder beeping]
The relays are fused.
It's useless.
[tricorder beeping]
Looks like we're not
the only ones here.
Indigenous wildlife, perhaps.
I'm reading residual life signs.
They're humanoid.
Ledosian?
No, but they share
the same genetic traits.
Whoever they are,
they may be able to help us.
Unless they're hostile.
Why don't we give them
the benefit of the doubt?
The life signs
lead in that direction.
I suggest you rest your leg
while I investigate.
It's better if we stick together.
At least until we know
whether they're hostile.
I'm guessing they're pre-warp.
Obviously, they can't help us.
No... I don't suppose they can.
But they're fascinating,
aren't they?
I never expected
to run into people like these
on such a technologically
advanced planet.
This isn't an anthropological
mission, Commander.
You're right.
We should keep searching for debris...
[groans]
You're developing an infection.
You should rest.
I'll have to stay here
and try to keep out of sight.
I'll contact you
if I find anything useful.
I guess I don't have to tell you
to avoid interacting with these people.
Seven of Nine to Chakotay.
Commander, respond.
I found something.
-Seven of Nine to Chakotay.
-Don't...!
[sighs]
Step away from him.
[Chakotay] It's all right, Seven.
They're friendly.
They're treating my wound.
You said we were supposed
to avoid interaction.
They found me.
There was nothing I could do.
You should have tried
to contact me.
I didn't want to expose them
to our technology.
You hid your combadge?
Actually, your call scared them.
They broke it.
I suggest we leave
before they break anything else.
Look, they're friendly...
and I am hurt.
-What are you suggesting?
-We may as well stay the night.
-Commander...
-It's good shelter.
And my leg feels better
since they put this dressing on.
I'm going to get some rest.
I suggest you do the same.
Chell says we shouldn't
miss the flame gardens.
I hear the arboretum
is beautiful, too.
We can do both.
Tom!
You joining us?
Oh, that's right.
-You have to go to pilot school.
-[chuckling]
I hear the course takes days.
Yeah, for most people,
but I did a little research.
If the instructor agrees,
you can skip the lessons
and go right to the test.
So, I will be seeing you
in a couple of hours.
You have to admire his optimism.
Just a moment, sir.
I am Mr. Kleg,
the flying instructor.
Are you Lieutenant Paris?
He is.
It's an honor to meet you, sir.
May I show you to the Delta Flyer?
Why?
So you can explain what I did wrong
and then administer the test.
It sounds to me like you need
lessons in patience, as well.
Oh, Tom is very patient, sir.
Never impulsive.
Take all the time you need.
He'll enjoy the extra attention.
Well, I'm pleased to hear it.
We'll start with a review
of safety procedures.
Do you have a visual display system
I can access?
I think I can find one.
Have fun.
Energize.
So, how long will this "review" take?
Oh, typically about four hours,
but there's no rush.
[chuckles]
Of course not.
River.
Mountain.
[Chakotay] Mountain.
Where... are we?
This?
You want to trade.
Well, I suppose it won't hurt.
I'll take that as a "thank you."
Did you make
a favorable exchange?
I didn't want to
insult their customs.
Any luck?
I may have found a way
of communicating.
[Chakotay] Me, too.
I've learned how to say "thank you."
I was referring to communication
with Voyager.
It may be possible to construct a beacon
by connecting these components
-to the shuttle's deflector.
-Did you find it?
I detected it
six kilometers from here.
I believe it's intact.
I'm not sure I'm up
to that long a trip.
I'll go.
I've started mapping the area.
Here's the river we passed.
This is where we beamed down
and we're here now.
Then the deflector
should be approximately here.
[Chakotay] Six kilometers is a long way.
Maybe one of them
could guide you.
I'm still trying to limit our contact
with these people.
[Chakotay] The sooner we get
to the deflector,
the sooner we can get out of here.
They know the terrain.
Maybe they can
get you there faster.
And watch me construct
a tetryon-based signaling device?
All right, but be careful.
Seven.
This is how they say "good-bye."
[case thumps]
[grunts]
Thank you.
Hello.
[thunder crashing]
[thunder rumbling]
[rustling]
Identify yourself.
An exothermic reaction.
I'm not hungry.
[Kleg] Inadequate system integration.
Visibility impaired
by lateral sensor array.
Insufficient console accessibility...
You know, I couldn't agree more.
Those are just some of the defects
that led to my so-called "pilot error."
Polarity thrusters?
Oh! They've been known to cause
accidental acceleration.
Exactly my point.
Why should I be held responsible
for the ship's design flaws?
According to the maintenance records,
you were this vessel's
chief designer.
I make it a point
of professional pride
to research every case
I'm assigned to.
Are you familiar with that term,
Lieutenant?
Professional pride?
Yes, sir.
In fact, that is why
I am so eager to get underway.
I want to prove to you
that I am a good pilot.
There are protocols,
Mr. Paris.
System by system diagnostics,
preflight simulations.
You must have other students
who need your attention.
-It wouldn't be fair to...
-Don't worry, Lieutenant.
I'm planning to spend as much time
with you as you need.
[birds twittering]
[footsteps]
Good morning.
I'm trying to go here.
Can you show me?
Yes.
I thought it was this way.
Yes, it's quite
an impressive view,
but now we really have...
My friend...
She hasn't come back.
I need to find her.
She looks like this.
Where?
Where did you get this?
My friend.
Where?
Don't touch that!
Please.
Problem?
Commander Chakotay failed to report in
at the scheduled time.
We tried hailing,
but there was no response.
We contacted
the conference coordinator.
He said Seven and Chakotay
never showed up.
Anything on sensors?
We located a hull signature
over the southern subcontinent,
but it's only a wing.
Nothing else?
No life signs?
No, ma'am.
That's awfully low
for something to be in orbit.
It's not in orbit.
It's resting on
an energy barrier.
We think the shuttle
may have collided with it.
Why didn't they see it?
Standard scans
didn't reveal its presence.
We were only able to detect it
with our Borg sensors.
If all you found was a wing,
maybe the rest of the shuttle
made it through the barrier.
Logic suggests that possibility.
Unfortunately, the barrier
is deflecting all our scans.
There's no way to know if the shuttle
or its occupants are on the other side.
Hail the Ledosian Ambassador.
We'd have warned your Commander,
but his flight plan didn't go
anywhere near that area.
He must have altered his route
for some reason.
And collided with the barrier.
I'm sorry.
We're not assuming they're dead.
We believe they may
have found a way through.
That's very unlikely.
They're resourceful people.
Can you tell us anything
about the barrier?
It shields the territory
of an indigenous society-- the Ventu.
Then the area's habitable.
If you lowered the barrier,
we could scan for our people's life signs.
-I'm afraid we can't do that.
-Why not?
It was erected by aliens
hundreds of years ago.
They haven't been back.
The technology
is a mystery to us.
Why did these aliens
build the barrier?
-To protect the Ventu.
-From whom?
Us.
Our ancestors fought them,
polluted their habitat.
I'm afraid we weren't
very enlightened back then.
Earth went through its
dark periods too, Ambassador.
Would you have any objections
if we tried to lower the barrier
just to scan for our people?
I told you, it's not possible.
Perhaps if you gave us information
about the barrier's power source.
The generator is inside.
There's no way to access it.
Even if your people did survive,
I'm afraid there's no way to get them out.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54827.7.
Although the Ledosians
are skeptical,
they're allowing us
to try to locate our people.
Meanwhile, we've begun to analyze
the shuttle fragment.
The burn pattern suggests
a tetryon flux.
We found a reference
to similar technology
in Seven's Borg database.
You think the Borg erected it?
No, but it may have been
constructed by people
they later assimilated--
Species 312.
If Seven were here,
she might be able to figure out
a way to get through it.
Maybe she already did.
Some of the damage
to the wing was caused
by feedback from
the shuttle's phasers.
Seven and Chakotay
might have used them
to penetrate the barrier
for some reason.
If I can determine
the appropriate frequency,
I may be able
to do the same thing.
But there is risk involved.
What sort of risk?
It looks like the feedback
from the barrier
is what destroyed the shuttle.
If we're not careful, the same thing
could happen to Voyager.
[electronic pulsing]
[whirring and pulsing]
[electrical crackling]
-[sound dies away]
-[sighs]
May I see those?
Seven.
-Is everything all right?
-I need your tricorder.
Nice to see you, too.
I lost mine.
There's a strong magnetic field here
that's preventing me from
generating a deflector beam.
But the field drops off approximately
4.8 kilometers in that direction.
-Can you transmit the signal from there?
-Not through the barrier,
but I may be able to neutralize it
by generating a dampening field
with our deflector.
Even if you're right,
this must weigh 500 kilos.
How would we move it?
Some of them could help us.
We shouldn't involve them.
Do I detect a change
in attitude, Commander?
Your concern was justified.
They've been gathering debris
from the shuttle,
using it to imitate us.
I don't want them helping.
What's the alternative?
Staying here?
Allowing them to find
all of the debris?
If we neutralize the barrier,
Voyager can transport us
and our technology off the surface.
Is there a possibility
that this dampening field
-could disrupt the barrier permanently?
-Unlikely.
Once the deflector is deactivated,
the barrier should reinitialize.
Let's hope you're right.
[Kleg] So, you can execute a turn
at less than 300 KPH.
-Well done, Lieutenant.
-Thanks.
You know, I don't want
to seem impatient again,
but is there any way
that you'd let me take that test now?
I thought I made myself clear
about that.
All my students
complete the entire course.
Well, I understand, sir,
but two of my friends are missing,
and I'd like to help find them.
Well, that's an admirable sentiment,
but if I give you special treatment,
it wouldn't be fair to the others
who have to take this course.
Besides...
why stop now?
You're getting very close
to becoming an adequate pilot.
[tricorder beeping]
[Seven] Here, Commander.
Not so close.
Phasers are starting to overload.
Can we divert any more power
to the shields?
The shields are amplifying
the feedback.
The barrier's interfering
with every system we activate.
Cease fire.
I'm open to suggestions.
We may be able
to reconfigure a photon torpedo
to detonate at the appropriate frequency.
What about feedback?
A torpedo shouldn't create any...
theoretically.
Do it.
They're too close.
Back...
behind the rise.
Stay back.
[whirring]
[volume increases]
[electrical crackling]
The energy barrier's coming down.
I thought you were still
reconfiguring the torpedo.
I am. It's being deactivated
from the inside.
Harry, scan for life signs.
Aye, Captain.
Take it off!
I'm only reading one combadge.
It's Seven's.
Open a channel.
Janeway to Seven.
Are you and Chakotay all right?
Yes, Captain.
Stand by for transport.
Lock on to Commander Chakotay.
I need more time.
Is there a problem?
Someone's been injured.
She requires medical attention.
Do you need the Doctor?
I believe I can treat her.
A medkit would be useful.
Acknowledged.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Seven has remained on the surface
to tend to the injured Ventu girl
while Chakotay's
being treated in Sick Bay.
The poultice healed
the fracture and the infection.
I'm impressed.
They're impressive people.
I just hope we haven't
traumatized them.
You did what you had to do
to get out of there.
Still, I think we should transport
all the shuttle debris back to Voyager
-as soon as possible.
-Agreed.
Would you like some breakfast?
I'm not hungry, either.
I admire your curiosity,
but you should be more careful.
It's time for me to leave.
Back to my home.
That's very kind,
but I have no use for it.
I suppose I should respect
your customs.
Thank you.
[Man] These botanical specimens
indicate a high level
of serum nitrates.
Catalog those foliates.
-Explain your presence here.
-Oh.
You must be from Voyager.
Who are you?
My name is Barus.
I'm the expedition leader.
What kind of expedition
are you leading?
We're conducting scans to evaluate
the potential of this habitat.
Potential for what?
Anthropological research,
resource development...
We've been waiting years for this.
What about the people
who live here?
-We'll help them, of course.
-How?
With medicine,
infrastructure, education...
Whoever lowered this barrier
did the Ventu a great favor.
That barrier has to go back up.
Isn't it possible the Ledosians
will improve the lives of the Ventu?
Improve them... how?
They're intelligent people.
Exposure to education and technology
may give them better opportunities.
Can you honestly say that you know
what's better for them?
No, I can't.
Then what do you think
we should do?
I'm uncertain.
It's not like you
to be on the fence.
When Commander Chakotay and I
first encountered the Ventu,
I found them primitive,
of little interest to me.
But as I spent more time with them,
I came to realize that they're
a resourceful,
self-reliant people.
Their isolation may limit
their potential,
but if that isolation ends,
so will a unique way of life.
We appreciate your help
in opening this territory
to exploration, Captain.
It's an unprecedented opportunity.
A short-lived opportunity,
I'm afraid.
I don't understand.
After I transport our deflector
back to Voyager,
the energy barrier
will go back up.
Naturally, you'll want
to get your people out,
so they won't be trapped inside,
as ours were.
You have no right to limit
our access to our own territory.
I'm not trying to do that,
but we have a strict policy
about leaving our technology
in the hands of other cultures.
It often has damaging consequences.
I don't think you realize
how important it is.
It's not only the resources
that interest us.
The Ventu are
our evolutionary ancestors--
our living history.
I understand
this is disappointing for you,
but I'm afraid I have no choice.
In the spirit of cooperation,
I hope you'll reconsider.
We're eager to resume course.
Would an hour be enough time
for you to evacuate your people?
I'll make the arrangements.
We've transported all the remaining debris
to the cargo bay.
I have a lock
on the deflector assembly.
What is it?
There's a Ledosian vessel
on an intercept course.
-It's charging weapons.
-Shields.
Direct hit to the transporters.
They're off-line.
Get a weapons lock
and hail them.
[Kim] They're hailing us.
-[Ambassador] Captain Janeway.
-What's going on?
Our government has decided
not to let you restore the barrier.
And that justifies
an unprovoked attack?
We only targeted your transporters
to avoid harming your crew.
I hope you'll show
the same restraint.
I don't find weapons fire
of any kind restrained.
If you want to avoid further conflict,
I suggest you leave.
Take us out of orbit.
What about the deflector?
Is Tom still in the Flyer?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Hail him.
Excellent, Mr. Paris.
Now, come about slowly.
Janeway to Paris.
Respond.
Captain, I would appreciate it
if you wouldn't interrupt my student
during his examination.
-I'm sorry, but something's come up.
-[Paris] What is it, Captain?
Tom, I'm sending you
some encrypted orders.
Yes, ma'am.
This is highly irregular.
You're going much too fast!
Yes, sir.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
If you have any desire
to pass this test,
you'll reduce your speed immediately.
I wish I could do that, sir.
I really do.
-What was that?
-Paris to Voyager.
I'm under attack.
Give him some help, Mr. Tuvok.
What have you done?
We had to get you out of there
before we closed the barrier.
You can't do that.
Sit back and enjoy the ride.
Paris to Voyager.
I've got them.
Find the deflector.
I'm getting a lock on it now.
My transporters are off-line.
You better get out of there, Tom.
Not yet.
I've got an idea.
I am sorry to inform you, Mr. Paris,
but you have failed this examination.
You will no longer be allowed
to operate a vessel
within Ledosian space.
Something tells me that's
not going to be a problem.
This is a beautiful blanket.
Take it if you like.
I don't need it.
If environmental systems ever go down,
you might get cold.
-I...
-You know...
-You first.
-Please, continue.
In all the excitement,
I never apologized.
For what?
Causing you to miss
that conference.
As a matter of fact, I...
wanted to thank you for that.
-I thought you were angry.
-I was.
But you were right-- warp mechanics
can be studied anytime.
The Ventu, on the other hand...
Something's still bothering you.
I'm concerned for their well-being.
They know how
to take care of themselves.
That's not what I mean.
Members of the Ledosian expedition
had the opportunity
to scan my deflector modifications.
In time, they may find a way
to duplicate our technology
and remove the barrier themselves.
I suppose it's possible.
If I had never made
those modifications...
We might still be stranded there.
I don't know about you,
but I'm glad to be back on Voyager.
As am I.