[rock 'n' roll playing]
[buzz of conversation]
Now these are delicious.
-Uh, leave some for the rest of us.
-Hey, I'm eating for two.
Great party, Neelix.
Everybody seems to be enjoying it.
Yeah, except the Doc.
Those are for eating,
not scanning.
What exactly are they?
Cheese pierogies.
Zefram Cochrane's favorite.
They have absolutely
no nutritional value.
[sighs]
This is a party, Doctor.
Sometimes you have to forget
about nutrition.
You could include a vitamin supplement
when you replicate.
Replicate?
I made them myself.
You two have outdone yourselves.
I've never seen First Contact Day
celebrated quite like this.
When I was your age, all it meant
was a day off from school.
Well, Neelix and I thought
we should make it more fun.
Well, you certainly succeeded.
When is Commander Tuvok
making his presentation?
Well, now's as good a time as any.
Captain.
Uh, may I have everyone's
attention, please?
-[music stops]
-In honor of the 315th anniversary
of his ancestors' arrival on Earth,
I've asked Mr. Tuvok
to recite the first words
spoken to humans by a Vulcan.
Commander?
Is this really necessary?
You promised.
Very well.
Live long and prosper.
-[man] Ah.
-[applause]
And now, for some more
of Zefram Cochrane's favorite music.
[rock 'n' roll playing]
[quiet chatter]
[laughs]
[laughter]
Hey, come on, Mr. Vulcan.
Vulcans do not dance.
But it's tradition.
There is no tradition, Mr. Neelix.
This ceremony
is entirely your invention.
This is an official
ship function, Commander.
Don't make me order you to dance.
Sorry to interrupt, but I've got
some interesting news.
Neelix, you might want to hear this.
Huh?
Long-range sensors have detected
several hundred life signs
approximately 4.9 light-years away.
They're Talaxian.
-Are we there yet?
-Not exactly.
The life signs appear to be coming
from inside that asteroid field.
[Neelix]
From a ship?
We are not detecting any vessels.
-No response from hails?
-Not yet.
I hope they're all right.
There's a lot of interference.
Maybe they haven't received
our transmissions.
Can we move in any closer?
Voyager is too big
to maneuver safely in there.
We could take the Flyer.
It wouldn't have hurt you
to do a few steps.
I am trying to concentrate
on the shields, Mr. Neelix.
I think you were just afraid.
-That's absurd.
-It's understandable.
-There were a lot of people watching.
-Vulcans don't experience fear.
I'm going to make it
my personal mission
to get you to dance at least once
before we reach Earth.
Then I suggest you find
a more productive hobby.
If you two don't stop it,
I'm going to come back there
and separate you.
[console beeping]
I've localized the life signs.
Bearing 108, mark 26.
They appear to be inside
a large asteroid.
-Inside?
-[rumbling]
-What was that?
-A thermalyte explosive.
30.6 kilometers to port.
I'm detecting another projectile,
heading directly toward us.
Evasive maneuvers.
We've lost shields.
Main propulsion is off-line.
We're going to have
to make an emergency landing.
Where?
The Talaxians' asteroid
is the closest.
The surface is covered
with craters, ice fields.
[sighs]
We don't have a choice.
Hold on.
Problem?
We've lost contact
with the away team.
I also detected some unusual energy
discharges in the asteroid field.
-What kind of discharges?
-It's difficult to tell
because of the interference,
but they appear
to be thermalytic explosions.
I believe several of them
were in close proximity to the Flyer.
Source?
Unknown.
[sighs]
We'll need to send a rescue team.
Work with B'Elanna.
Try to modify the shields
on one of the shuttles
to withstand these explosions.
Stay still.
Don't worry.
It's not serious.
Am I inside the asteroid?
Yes.
This is my home.
Where are my friends?
If you mean the aliens who were
on the ship with you, they're safe.
I'd like to see them.
You need to rest.
What were you doing
in the asteroid field?
Looking for you.
Well, not you specifically,
but my ship detected Talaxians.
I haven't come across any in years, so...
I'm sorry.
I'm Neelix.
Dexa.
I had an uncle named Neelix.
Are there other Talaxians
on your ship?
I'm the only one.
Why are you living with aliens?
They're my friends.
Did you receive our hails?
Yes.
Why didn't you respond?
We avoid contact with outsiders.
We were attacked.
There were explosions.
-Did you...?
-No.
We're not violent.
Who fired at us?
No one fired at you.
There are miners
who use explosive charges
to break apart the asteroids,
so they can collect minerals
from the debris.
I wish we'd known.
Why were you carrying weapons?
It's standard procedure
for an away mission.
Hello. What's your name?
Brax. What's yours?
I told you not to come in here.
I just wanted to see him.
You're supposed to be helping Oxilon.
He doesn't look dangerous to me.
I think you have the wrong idea
about us.
I'm not supposed to be
talking to you at all.
I'm feeling better.
I'd like to see my friends now.
-What are you doing?
-I've been told not to let you leave.
Harry?
Still no response to hails.
-Janeway to the Shuttle Bay.
-[Seven] Go ahead, Captain.
What's the status
of the shield modifications?
Lieutenant Torres and I will be
finished in a few minutes.
Good. Take an away team
and find them.
[electronic beeping]
Captain, there's a ship
approaching from astern.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Identify yourselves.
I'm Captain Janeway
of the Federation Starship Voyager.
Commander Nocona.
This is our asteroid field.
We weren't aware of that.
Now you are.
We lost one of our shuttles
inside the field.
We're preparing
to send a rescue team.
All the resources belong to us.
We're not interested
in the resources.
We were only trying
to make contact with the Talaxians.
What's your interest in them?
One of my crewmen is from Talax.
He was eager to meet some of his people.
You should have requested permission
before sending in a shuttle.
We have a mining operation in progress.
Does that explain
the explosions we detected?
Mining charges.
We'd appreciate it
if you'd stop using them,
until we can get our people out.
I'm sorry.
We're on a strict deadline.
But I'll conduct a search
for your crew.
If they need help,
we'll provide it.
That's kind of you.
But we're prepared to go in
and get them ourselves.
I cannot guarantee your safety
if you enter the asteroid field.
Stay here.
We'll contact you
when we find your people.
I don't think
you're supposed to be here.
This is my home.
You can't tell me what to do.
No, of course not.
I just don't want you
to get in trouble.
Is that a model ship?
What's it called?
How about the Two-Tailed Talchok?
The Fur Fly?
[giggles]
The ship I come from
is called the Voyager.
Is it big?
And fast.
Can I see it?
I think it would be
a little difficult
to take you there
while I'm stuck here.
But if your mother
would let me out...
-[door closing]
-That's her.
[whispers]
You'd better hide.
You won't tell her I'm here?
No, of course not.
Neelix, this is Oxilon,
our council regent.
I wish I could say
it was nice to meet you,
but this wasn't exactly
the welcome I was expecting.
You're free to go now.
What about my friends?
We've determined
they aren't hostile.
They've been treated for their injuries
and asked to leave.
They're aboard your shuttle
making repairs.
I'll take you there.
Well, now that everything
has been cleared up,
maybe we could talk...
get to know each other a little?
If you'd like.
My friends, too?
I'm sorry.
Why not?
We've learned from experience
to keep to ourselves.
Well, if they're not welcome,
I'm not staying, either.
That's your choice.
I know Oxilon seems overly cautious,
but we're not used to having visitors.
How many of you live here?
Close to 500.
All of our homes are connected
to the central cavern
by tunnels and lifts.
They allow us to move easily
from one section
of the asteroid to another.
It must have taken years
to build all of this.
Almost five.
It still isn't finished.
[male voice] ...group five,
report to the lower level...
Where did the technology come from?
We arrived here
with a caravan of six ships.
We disassembled all but one of them
and modified their components.
We converted torpedo launchers
to blast away rock
and excavate these tunnels.
These conduits run
into the asteroid's core.
We use geothermal energy to melt the ice
that covers most of the outer surface.
It provides us with oxygen and water.
Who'd have imagined all of this
inside an asteroid?
Your son seems like
a wonderful boy.
How would you know?
You only met him for a few seconds.
True, but I'm a quick
judge of character.
He came to see you
while I was out, didn't he?
You can't blame him
for being curious.
Hmm. He's a lot like his father--
no fear.
I'd like to meet your husband.
He's dead.
I'm sorry.
-I didn't mean to...
-It's... It's all right.
You didn't know.
Neelix.
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine.
Dexa, this is Lieutenant Paris
and Commander Tuvok.
Thanks for bringing him back.
We were getting worried.
It was nice to meet you.
So, what can I do to help?
Well, you can give me a hand
with this plasma manifold.
How did it go?
Well, uh, they didn't exactly
send out a welcoming committee,
but I'm sure they have their reasons.
I guess my expectations
were a little high.
I regret that you didn't have
a more fulfilling experience.
That's nice of you to say,
Commander,
but it wasn't a complete
waste of time.
I got to meet some
of my people again...
even if it was a short visit.
Who knows?
It's probably the last time
I'll ever see another Talaxian.
Good work.
Now we need to run a systems...
-[beeping]
-[computer] Intruder alert.
At least we know internal sensors
are working.
[beeping]
[gasps]
[Neelix]
Brax!
-You know him?
-We're old friends.
You said you'd take me
to see Voyager.
I don't think your mother would approve.
You won't tell her
I was here, will you?
Here?
Why, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
I'll be right back.
[Oxilon] Three days isn't nearly
enough time for us
to dismantle all our equipment.
[Nocona] You should have begun
the first time we asked.
We can't wait any longer.
Demolition of the asteroid
is going to start
whether you're here or not.
You'd kill us?
We don't want to hurt anyone,
but our patience has run out.
We've only got one ship.
There won't be enough room
for any of our belongings.
It's not our fault you took apart
your other vessels.
-You can't do this.
-Dexa, don't provoke him.
Where are we supposed to go?
I'm sure you'll find a home somewhere.
This is our home!
You have no right to make us go.
-[groans]
-Leave her alone!
Bring him here!
-Don't touch him!
-Are you going to stop me?
[grunts]
[grunting]
You've said what you've come to say,
and now I suggest you leave.
You have three days to evacuate.
You can see now
why we're suspicious of outsiders.
Thank you for protecting the boy...
but I'm afraid your actions
might make things worse.
How could they get any worse?
Fighting back has never done anything
but cause us more trouble.
And what has running away
ever done for us?
It's kept us alive.
Maybe it's time we stayed
and defended ourselves.
Will you help us?
I agree with Oxilon.
Fighting isn't the answer.
-But I'll try to help.
-How?
Well, uh...
we could talk to my captain.
Maybe she can negotiate
with the miners,
uh, get them to agree
to let you stay.
Your captain would be willing to do that?
The best thing would be for you
to come to Voyager--
talk to her yourself.
-I want to go, too.
-Shh, Brax.
Why don't you both come?
I've seen your home.
I'd like you to see mine.
[doors open]
Commander Chakotay.
I'd like you to meet Dexa...
and Brax.
Welcome to the Bridge.
And this is Ensign Kim.
What's this?
This... is an engineering station.
And over there is Tactical.
And down there is the Helm.
And this...
is the Captain's chair.
Which station is yours?
Well, actually, I don't have a specific...
See, I'm-I'm more of a, uh...
Neelix does too many things
to have just one station.
He's our ambassador,
morale officer, trade negotiator.
Without a doubt, he's the most
versatile member of our crew.
[sighs]
[Seven] As you can see,
our sensors are extremely precise.
We can scan for life signs
light-years away.
That's how we found you.
I have something else
that may interest you.
-What is it?
-Talax.
You can scan that far away?
No, this image is from our database.
It's as beautiful as I remember.
There's the Godo Mountain Range.
And the Axiana Lakes.
That was always one
of my favorite places.
Mine, too.
Why don't we just go back to Talax?
We could live there.
It's still controlled by the Haakonians.
They don't treat Talaxians very well.
That's why we left.
Maybe Neelix could go with us,
and we could fight them.
Take the planet back.
If tomorrow's negotiations go well,
you won't have to go anywhere.
Next stop... Engineering.
The warp core!
Neelix!
Naomi.
I'm sorry. I forgot all about
our Kadis-Kot game.
That's all right.
I know you're busy.
I just want to meet your friends.
Of course. Dexa, Brax...
this is my goddaughter, Naomi.
Hi.
-You live on a beautiful ship.
-Thanks.
Maybe Brax would like to go
to the holodeck.
-That's a great idea.
-Lieutenant Paris has a new program.
"Invaders from the Ninth Dimension."
-Sounds scary.
-Very.
What's a holodeck?
Neelix is right.
Might be too scary for you.
I'm not afraid. Can I?
You're lucky to have found these people.
They obviously think
a great deal of you.
The feeling's mutual.
To the Axiana Lakes.
It really is delicious.
I've been saving it for 15 years.
I wasn't sure I'd ever open it.
But tonight...
seemed like the right occasion.
Would you like some more...
taga cake?
A little, please.
I haven't had this in years.
I'm glad you like it.
-Mmm.
-It's a family recipe.
You're a good cook.
I haven't seen Brax this happy
since his father was alive.
How did he...?
I'm sorry. You probably
don't want to talk about it.
I don't mind.
We'd settled on a planet
called Phanos.
There was a lot
of unoccupied territory,
but the government restricted us
to a very small area.
-Why?
-They said it was a quarantine,
to protect the population
from alien diseases.
But it was just an excuse.
We were outsiders. They didn't want us
mixing with their people.
It wasn't long before we realized
we didn't have enough land
to grow what we needed
to feed ourselves.
Oxilon said we'd just have
to conserve our resources.
But my husband was tired
of being told what to do.
So, he started farming
outside the restricted zone.
They didn't like that.
A security patrol confronted him.
He told them he had
to provide for his family,
that he wasn't afraid of them.
There was a fight. He was killed.
I'm sorry.
After that, we came here.
We thought we'd finally found a place
where no one would bother us.
Maybe this time it'll be different.
Maybe.
But even if it isn't...
thank you for trying.
I should get
a good night's sleep,
if I'm going to be my best
at the negotiations tomorrow.
Uh, Neelix?
It's been a wonderful day.
Isn't there enough to mine here,
without destroying their home?
Their home contains more
than 30 percent of the field's ore.
Without that asteroid...
the operation isn't worth the expense.
Would you be open
to some kind of compensation?
All we want are the minerals.
And you'd kill us to get them.
Wait.
The Talaxians have found a way
to produce a lot of geothermal energy.
Maybe they could share it with you.
What do you mean "share"?
You could convert it into fuel
to power your ships.
The energy they generate isn't
compatible with our technology.
We'd be willing to help you
make the modifications.
We have quotas to meet.
We don't have time for that.
Commander, the future of more
than 500 people is at stake here.
And once, there was
a transporter accident.
Neelix and Commander Tuvok
got combined
to make a completely different person.
Really?
You don't think I could make up
a story like that, do you?
Hello, Neelix.
-Do you want to play Kadis-Kot?
-Maybe later.
[indistinct chatter]
I knew it wouldn't work.
We did get them
to make a small concession.
They've extended the deadline.
You'll have enough time
to dismantle your equipment.
Thanks, but there's too much
to take with us.
Captain Janeway has agreed
to ferry all of you
and your supplies
to the nearest M-Class planet.
Come on, Brax.
We're going home.
-Why?
-We have to pack. Come on.
-You said you were gonna help us.
-Brax.
You wanted to see me?
I've detected five warp-capable species
within two light-years of the planet
where we're taking the Talaxians.
I'm worried they might be
vulnerable to attack.
-They would be vulnerable anywhere.
-I thought maybe you could help me
devise some defense strategies
for their new home.
Frankly, Mr. Neelix, they don't seem
inclined to defend themselves.
No, I suppose not...
But if they were going
to make a stand...
their emotional attachment
to their present home
might be an asset.
Are you saying they should stay?
I'm speaking hypothetically.
Hypothetically...
if they wanted to defend the asteroid,
how would they do it?
To begin with, they would need
to establish some kind of perimeter.
-You mean shields?
-Yes.
The miners are monitoring
the asteroid.
If they detected the Talaxians
erecting a shield,
they would attempt to stop them.
I suppose so.
Your people would need competent
leadership to defend against
a preemptive attack.
If you had the Captain's permission,
would you be willing
to provide that leadership?
Certainly not.
It would be a violation
of the Prime Directive.
And even if it weren't,
I don't believe that I am the person
most qualified to assume that role.
You mean me?
I am merely speaking hypothetically.
I couldn't lead those people,
Mr. Tuvok.
I'm not a fighter.
I'm just a cook...
who sometimes imagines himself
to be a diplomat.
On the contrary, Mr. Neelix...
you are much more than that.
You are perhaps the most resourceful
individual I have ever known.
I always thought you
just tolerated me.
You do have some annoying habits.
However, during your time on Voyager,
you've developed many valuable skills.
Skills that would serve you well
if you ever decided
to assume a leadership role.
You really think so?
Let me be clear.
I'm not urging you to do anything.
I am simply telling you that I believe
that you are more than capable.
Going somewhere, Mr. Neelix?
Just to see my friends.
Chakotay tells me you're
using your own ship.
Why not have Tom
take you in the Flyer?
I didn't want to bother anyone.
You wouldn't be planning
anything foolish, would you?
Whatever I do, I promise
it won't involve Voyager.
That wasn't my question.
I know you have
Prime Directive issues,
but I'm not officially
part of your crew,
so I don't have
the same constraints.
You're as much a part of this crew
as anyone else.
Are you ordering me not to go?
That depends on what
you're going to do.
It's up to the Talaxians.
Safe journey, Mr. Neelix.
I know from personal experience
that you have force field emitters.
We could use them
to establish a shield grid.
We'd need to deploy
a series of them
on the asteroid's surface,
along bisecting diameters.
16 emitters should be enough
to form a grid.
Even if you're right, it'd take weeks
to dig that many tunnels to the surface.
Commander Tuvok suggested
that we could modify the emitters,
so they could be fired
from torpedo tubes on your ship...
implanted in the surface.
As soon as the miners realize
what we are doing, they'd attack.
I could provide cover
from my ship.
But you're right,
we'd have to work quickly.
We could route power to the emitters
directly from the core.
-They'd have a permanent energy supply.
-Good idea.
If we do what you're suggesting,
people are going to be hurt.
This is your home!
The miners have no right
to force you out.
I agree, but fighting?
I don't like it either,
but, at some point,
you have to stand up for yourselves.
How do you know
there won't be someone else
to terrorize you
the next place you go?!
[loud chatter]
You know he's right.
No one has worked harder
to build this place than you.
Isn't it worth defending?
Wait for my comm call.
As soon as the last emitter's in place,
start routing power to the grid.
Understood.
You're scared, aren't you?
-You?
-Terrified.
-Be careful.
-I will.
-[beeping]
-Oxilon to Neelix.
The emitters are loaded.
We're ready.
I'll see you soon.
-Two more, and we're done.
-[Oxilon] Acknowledged.
We're moving into position
for the next one.
[alarm sounds]
The miners' ship
is on an intercept course.
Evasive maneuvers!
-They're targeting our shields.
-[Neelix] I'll deal with them.
Just focus on your job.
All right, Mr. Vulcan, let's see
if you were right about me.
-[loud chatter]
-[alarm sounds]
Neelix, you have to hurry.
Just one more emitter,
and you can activate the shield.
[alarm sounds]
Neelix to Oxilon.
-My weapons are off-line.
-We're not in position yet.
You have to get there.
They're going to launch another charge.
-Neelix, what are you doing?
-[Neelix] Don't worry about me.
Just get ready
to bring the grid online.
Delta Flyer to Neelix.
Are you all right?
Fine, Captain,
but you shouldn't be here.
You're violating the Prime Directive.
We're just helping a friend in distress.
Dexa to Neelix.
The shield's holding. You did it.
We did it.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54868.6.
Commander Nocona
seems to have given up
his attempts to penetrate
the Talaxians' shield.
Voyager's ready to get underway,
but we're giving Mr. Neelix time
to say a difficult good-bye
to his new friends.
We're grateful
for everything you've done.
I'm just happy things worked out.
And I'm glad that I could
spend some time here...
with all of you.
-I'd better go.
-Stay here!
He can't, Brax.
He has responsibilities on Voyager.
I promise I'll stay in touch
as long as I can.
-[door chimes]
-Come in.
Hi.
Neelix!
What are you working on?
A report on proto-humanoid cultures...
for Commander Chakotay's
paleontology class.
A-ha. Need some help?
I'm almost finished.
Oh.
Do you have time
for a game of Kadis-Kot?
I have to get up early.
Oh.
I guess you'd better
get to sleep then.
Do you want me to tuck you in?
Tell you a bedtime story?
[scoffs]
You haven't done that in years.
Just think of all the stories
you've missed.
Thanks, Neelix,
but I can put myself to bed.
I'm not a little girl anymore.
I didn't think anyone else
stayed up this late.
Well, I wouldn't want you
to have coffee all by yourself.
Have a seat.
[sighs]
I've been thinking about something.
It's a little hard to put into words.
And I haven't really made
a decision yet.
And, of course, I would never ignore
my responsibilities on Voyager.
Of course not.
I take them very seriously.
I know you do.
I've been thinking about something, too.
Maybe you could help me.
I'd be happy to.
It's an idea I'd need to talk
to Starfleet Command about.
-It must be important.
-It is.
Now that we've established
two-way communication with Earth...
it seems to me Starfleet could use
a permanent ambassador
in the Delta Quadrant.
This ambassador would have to stay
in frequent contact with Voyager.
[quietly]
Certainly.
It would be difficult for me
to run this ship without you, Neelix.
But that might be a sacrifice
I'd be willing to make...
for the greater good of Starfleet.
Of course, the assignment
would be entirely voluntary.
You wouldn't be interested, would you?
Good-bye...
and good luck, Ambassador.
Mr. Neelix.
Live long and prosper.
[door opens]
[sighs]