[Doctor singing
upbeat opera loudly]
[singing continues]
[singing continuing]
Captain...
Computer, pause music.
I didn't wake you, did I?
That's all right, Doctor.
15 minutes of sleep
is really all I need.
Coffee, black.
Maybe you should pay
a little more attention to flying
and a little less to singing.
As a hologram, I can handle
a variety of tasks at once.
In addition to piloting the Flyer,
I'm writing a paper
on the physiological stresses
of long-duration space flight
and... taking holo-images
of this Mutara-class nebula.
With a hologram on board,
who needs a crew?
I'd never admit this
to anyone else,
but there was a time when
I would have given anything
to be flesh and blood,
but I've come to realize that
being a hologram is far superior.
Really?
No offense.
I'll always enjoy the company
of organics.
In fact, I'm delighted
you were able to attend
this medical symposium with me.
It's been a pleasure
spending time with you.
Actually, I was hoping we might
do this sort of thing more often.
[console beeping]
Hmm.
We're passing
through a subspace eddy.
It could be the wake
of another ship.
No.
There's nothing on sensors.
It's probably just the gravimetric
shear from the nebula.
Maybe I should
take the controls.
Sit down and relax, Captain.
You've got a hologram
at the helm.
The plasma surges have to be coming
from one of these relays.
Try realigning
the deuterium manifolds.
-Paris to Torres.
-Go ahead.
Can you pull yourself away from
Engineering for a few minutes?
I've got a shuttle down here
with a faulty deflector array.
I'm a little busy right now.
It's kind of urgent.
What's this?
Well, I thought you'd enjoy
a romantic lunch
under the glow of a red giant.
Oh, you replicated potato salad.
With extra paprika--
just the way you like it.
This is so sweet... but I can't.
Sure you can.
I've already cleared it
with Chakotay.
I told the Captain
I'd have the dilithium matrix
recalibrated before she got back.
You know, this might be
our last chance
to be alone...
for the next 18 years.
I will make some time
before the baby comes, I promise.
Oh, I've got to get back.
[sighs]
Report.
There's some kind of pulse being
directed at our transceiver array.
It's coming
from the Delta Flyer.
Hail them.
No response.
Looks like they've encoded
the pulse with a com signal.
Captain...
Sorry about the image, Ensign.
Our com system's been damaged.
The only way I could send you a signal
was through the main deflector.
Are you and the Doctor
all right?
We're fine.
Tell Commander Chakotay
to meet me in my ready room
as soon as we've docked.
Janeway out.
Harry tells me the Flyer
took some damage.
That's an understatement.
We almost didn't make it
back in one piece.
They're called the R'Kaal.
Their technology
is decades ahead of ours.
Transphasic warp drive,
multispectral cloaking systems.
They could destroy this ship before
our sensors knew they were there.
They sound like people
we should avoid.
I wish that were possible.
They control
thousands of parsecs
from here to the edge
of the Beta Quadrant.
They're ecological extremists.
They believe conventional
warp engines damage subspace,
so they've outlawed warp travel
through their territory.
Then we should reverse course
and find a way around.
That's the problem.
We've already been in their space
for three weeks without knowing it.
You'd think they'd mark
their borders
-a little more clearly.
-As punishment,
their law demands
that our ship be dismantled.
Obviously, we're not going
to let that happen.
I spent three hours
explaining our situation
to their "Supreme Archon"--
a thoroughly unpleasant man.
I convinced him
to spare Voyager...
but at a price.
We're going to rendezvous
with their armada
and surrender our warp core...
at a Class-M planet
where they've agreed to let us settle.
Settle?
I didn't make this decision
lightly, Chakotay.
We have to bring
the senior staff in on this.
We can find a way
to evade their ships
or adapt our sensors
to their cloaking technology.
We could try that, and we might
make it past their armada,
but we could lose a lot of people
in the process, maybe the entire ship.
Kathyrn, there's got to be
another way.
I'm tired, Chakotay,
tired of casualty reports,
of continually risking my people
on the slim chance
that we'll make it home in one piece.
We've found our way
out of worse situations.
-Set a course.
-What am I supposed to tell the crew?
For now, I'd like to keep this
between us.
It's not like you to keep
your people in the dark...
I'll make an announcement
when the time is right.
Dismissed.
-Captain.
-I'm sorry to interrupt,
but I could use your input
on a hypothetical scenario.
Of course.
If we were to eject the core,
could it be towed safely at warp?
In theory, but a tractor beam might
destabilize the containment field.
You'd be risking a breach.
Could you compensate
for that?
You could configure the tractor emitters
to generate a resonance pulse.
That should stabilize the field.
Can you make those modifications
to the Delta Flyer's tractor emitters?
I suppose.
How long would it take?
Um, a few hours.
Get started.
I thought you said this was
a hypothetical scenario.
We should be prepared,
just in case.
In case of what?
Let me know as soon
as you're finished.
-Torres to Chakotay.
-Go ahead.
Have you got a minute?
B'Elanna tells me you ordered
some modifications to the Flyer.
That's right.
Maybe I misunderstood.
I thought the plan was to hand over
the core when we reached the planet.
Are we taking it somewhere else?
[whispering]
I heard you the first time.
Captain?
You've already made
your concerns clear, Commander,
but there's been
a slight change of plans.
Were you going to tell me?
Kathryn...
what's going on?
I don't feel well.
I've got a headache.
I'm going to my quarters,
and I'd prefer not to be disturbed.
You have the Bridge.
[whispering]
Not now.
I beg your pardon, Captain?
Carry on, Commander.
Chakotay to the Doctor.
-Go ahead, Commander.
-Report to Sick Bay immediately.
Something wrong with the turbolifts?
You did say immediately.
How can I help you?
[sighs] I'm concerned
about the Captain.
-She doesn't seem to be feeling well.
-What's wrong?
I'm not sure.
She went to her quarters
with a headache.
I'll bring her an analgesic.
I was wondering
if this could be related
to your encounter
with the aliens.
You think they harmed her?
You tell me.
What did they do to her?
I'm not sure, exactly.
The aliens took my program off-line
as soon as they boarded the Flyer.
The Captain reactivated me
a few hours later
and told me
she'd been interrogated.
Naturally, I examined her
to make sure she was all right.
Did you find anything unusual?
I suppose I'm violating
doctor-patient confidentiality
by telling you this, but...
she was fine.
I'd like you to give her
a more thorough examination.
Gladly, but you know how
she feels about physicals.
You can be very persuasive,
Doctor.
Contact me as soon
as you're done.
Aye, sir.
Anything interesting on sensors
this morning?
Nothing extraordinary.
A red giant and two G-type stars,
a Golorian trading vessel
bearing 156 mark 4.
If there were a fleet
of cloaked ships in the vicinity,
could you devise a way
to detect them?
A cloaked fleet would generate
significant subspace distortions.
Why do you ask?
[Kim] Commander,
we're receiving a transmission.
Source?
I'm having trouble pinpointing it.
Should I notify the Captain?
No, she didn't want
to be disturbed.
Route the call here.
I'm Commander Chakotay
of the Starship Voyager.
This is Supreme Archon Loth
of the R'Kaal Imperium.
Why haven't you ejected your warp core
as your Captain agreed?
We're en route
to the planet you specified.
We can't jettison the core
until we get there.
If we don't receive the core
within ten hours,
my armada
will destroy your ship.
This is your only warning.
Work with Harry.
I want to know the source
of that transmission.
Understood.
Ah, Commander,
you'll be relieved to know
I've given the Captain
a clean bill of health.
Did you run a neurological scan?
Mm-hmm. Her brain activity
and cognitive functions
are completely normal.
As far as I can tell she's perfectly fit,
physically and mentally.
Thank you, Doctor.
Chakotay to the Captain.
Computer,
locate Captain Janeway.
Computer, belay that.
My quarters, now.
Really, Chakotay,
sending the Doctor
to check up on me?
I'm concerned.
Then why didn't you
come to me directly?
-I thought we trusted each other.
-So did I.
Something happened on that away mission
that you're not telling me.
I've told you everything
you need to know.
You've consulted me
on every major decision
over the last seven years
except this one.
Why?
There are some decisions
a captain has to make on her own.
I understand that, but every instinct
tells me what you're doing is wrong.
Don't you remember
what happened on Lessek Prime?
I don't see how that's relevant.
I think you do.
15 years ago, you were the Lieutenant
who was kept in the dark.
If you hadn't questioned
your Captain's orders,
the entire away team
would've been lost.
This situation's entirely different.
You never told me
that story.
I made it up.
Chakotay to Tuvok.
I've erected a dampening field
around these quarters.
I'm sorry, Commander.
[groaning]
Computer, secure the doors
and establish
a level-5 dampening field
around the morgue.
[computer beeps]
I can't do my job with the two of you
constantly talking in my head.
No!
I'm not doing anything else
until I speak with the Captain.
Fine!
What's your
encryption frequency?
Captain, are you all right?
Doctor, listen to me.
Under no circumstances
are you to eject the warp core.
If I don't do what they ask,
they'll kill you.
I'm giving you a direct order.
Stop what you're doing.
I'm sorry, Captain.
I can't obey that order.
Doctor, I want you
to go to the Bridge right now
and alert Commander Tuvok...
Put her behind the force field!
We have another assignment
for you.
I've been going over
the schematics of your vessel,
and I'm intrigued
by this bio-neural circuitry.
I want you to bring us
a series of these gel packs.
The gel packs are integrated
into the ship's systems.
I can't just remove them
without someone noticing.
You've proven yourself
to be very resourceful, Doctor.
You'll find a way.
Remember--
we're monitoring
your perceptual subroutines.
We can see and hear everything.
Tuvok to Chakotay.
You know what will happen to her
if you alert your crew.
[clears throat]
[hoarse voice]
Go ahead.
Are you all right,
Commander?
Uh, just a scratchy throat.
The Doctor's treating me now.
Could you come to the Shuttle Bay
when you're finished?
I'll be right there.
Chakotay out.
Computer,
access the holodeck database
and locate Commander Chakotay's
holographic template.
Download the physical parameters
into my program.
[coughing]
You wanted to see me?
I've completed the diagnostic
as you requested.
The Flyer's com system
is functioning normally.
You find that unusual?
The Captain did report
that it was damaged
during the attack
by the R'Kaal.
[Chakotay]
I'll have a talk with her.
Did you find anything else
out of the ordinary?
[Tuvok]
No.
Get out of there
before you arouse suspicion.
I'll be on the Bridge
if you need me.
You're doing
a wonderful job, Doctor.
I'm just giving him
a little encouragement.
That's why I'm in command.
If all goes well, we should have
the warp core in less than six hours.
He's making excellent progress.
That's exactly what
he wants you to believe.
What do you mean?
Did you really think you could
outsmart a hologram?
Everything appears
to be normal.
How do you know you're not looking
at a holographic projection?
The Doctor isn't just
a physician.
His emergency command
subroutines
contain thousands
of tactical scenarios.
I wouldn't be surprised
if Voyager was already
on its way here.
You do have an option.
Leave me behind
in an escape pod,
and I'll forget
any of this ever happened.
Maybe we should let her go.
Are you delusional?
It took months to plan this.
We've already found a buyer
for the warp core.
Now you want
to abandon everything?
It's better than being sent
to a rehabilitation center.
We made our choice
when we stole this vessel.
I am not going back
to the Hierarchy,
and neither are you.
She's just trying to trick you.
A month from now,
we'll be soaking
in the mud baths of Eblar Prime.
Trust me.
[sizzle]
[Janeway's voice]
Janeway to Torres.
Torres here.
I'm having a little trouble
with my replicator again.
Can you take a look at it?
I'm still working on those
modifications you asked for.
I'll send somebody else.
I'd consider it a personal favor
if you'd do it yourself, Lieutenant.
I'll be there in five minutes.
Thank you.
Janeway out.
[normal voice] Computer, access
Lieutenant Torres' holographic template
and download the physical parameters
into my program.
Computer, access
medical file: Torres-3
and update
her holographic template.
Did you forget something,
Lieutenant?
I did, actually.
Where do we keep
the spare gel packs?
Locker Gamma 5.
Of course, Gamma 5.
On the upper level.
I know where it is, Ensign.
You left me no choice.
Lieutenant.
Oh, are we calling each other
by our rank now?
Uh, you startled me.
Oh, sorry.
Well, I thought
since you didn't have time
for lunch under the stars,
maybe you'd settle for the glow
of the warp core.
How thoughtful,
but I'm... not hungry.
Well, I'm sure the baby
is famished.
A pregnant woman
shouldn't eat this kind of food.
Do you want to give me
an arterial occlusion?
[scoffs] One drumstick
isn't going to kill you.
Besides, I won't tell the Doctor...
if you won't.
You know...
this all looks so delicious.
Why don't we save it
for a romantic dinner this evening?
All right.
1900 hours,
but if you're not there,
I'm sending Security after you.
I'll be there... sweetheart.
"Sweetheart"?
Well, aren't you getting affectionate
in your third trimester.
I'll see you later.
Kim to Chakotay.
Can you come to Astrometrics?
[Chakotay's voice] Harry,
I'll be right there. Chakotay out.
The transmission was encoded
with a false subspace signature.
The signal didn't originate
on another vessel.
It came from inside Voyager.
We traced it to Holodeck 2.
Do you know who sent it?
I'm on my way
to check the access logs.
I'll go with you.
Whoever sent this transmission
knew how to cover his tracks.
The holodeck logs
have been erased.
Doesn't look like
we'll get any answers here.
I might be able to find
some residual photonic displacement.
There we go.
I think I can clarify the image
with a recursive algorithm.
Our alien's a hologram.
The question is,
who programmed him?
Good work, Ensign.
I'll take it from here.
Wait a minute.
I'm picking up
two holographic signatures.
It looks like a second image
was superimposed
over an existing template.
I'll see if I can isolate
the first image.
["Blue Danube Waltz" playing]
[sighs]
Doctor...
what are you doing?
If you don't mind,
I've had a stressful day.
[music continues]
I'm extremely busy, Commander.
This will only take a moment.
I've been reviewing
the communication logs.
There's a discrepancy
I was hoping you could explain.
At the precise moment the Flyer
transmitted a deflector pulse,
you apparently accessed
Voyager's holographic database.
I haven't the faintest idea
what you're talking about.
Your access code was used
to download the Captain's
physical parameters.
Exactly what are you insinuating,
Commander?
Perhaps we should have
a word with the Captain.
Fine.
Computer,
deactivate the EMH.
EMH protocols are off-line.
Security to Sick Bay.
Remain where you are.
You haven't forgotten
I'm a hologram, have you?
If necessary, I'll disable
all of your holo-emitters.
Computer, transfer the EMH
to the mobile emitter!
All hands, Red Alert.
Security teams,
apprehend the Doctor.
Computer,
open the holodeck doors.
Unable to comply.
Access to the holodeck
has been restricted.
Security override:
Tuvok-sigma-four.
Computer, end program.
Unable to comply.
Holodeck controls are off-line.
Tuvok to Engineering.
Shut down power to Holodeck 2.
It looks like the Doctor's
rerouted the power relays.
It'll take a minute to bypass them.
Doctor, I've reconfigured my phaser
to disrupt your holo-matrix.
Surrender yourself now.
Tuvok to Bridge.
Can you locate the Doctor
on internal sensors?
I'm not reading him.
He must've masked
his signature somehow.
Try scanning for the polydeutonic
alloy in his emitter.
Shut down all turbolifts
and transporters.
[Paris]
Acknowledged.
Get your people out of here.
The core's about to breach.
I'm not detecting
an overload.
You're getting false readings.
The Doctor's reprogrammed
your sensors.
All right, everybody out!
Now! Move it!
You too, B'Elanna.
I might be able to stabilize
the containment field.
You're not putting
your baby in danger. Go!
-You'd better be right behind me.
-Paris to Torres.
I'm picking up the Doctor's
emitter in your section.
-Where?
-Right next to the warp core.
Computer...
activate Emergency
Command Hologram.
All command codes have been
transferred to the ECH.
Prepare to eject the warp core.
Authorization: ECH-omega-four-two.
Doctor, don't do this.
[computer]
Warp ejection system enabled.
Computer... eject the core.
Computer, lock on
to my mobile emitter
and transport me
to the Delta Flyer.
Transporters are off-line.
Tuvok, we just lost main power,
and internal sensors are down.
The Doctor has entered
Jefferies Tube 11-Alpha.
Send a security team
to the Shuttle Bay.
[grunting]
[panting]
Lieutenant.
I think the Doctor's heading
for the escape pods.
You wouldn't shoot
a pregnant woman, would you?
Come with me, Doctor.
Tuvok, someone's
launching the Flyer.
Tuvok?
Ow!
[sighs]
You might try disconnecting
the phase discriminator.
[laughs]
I've rebuilt dozens
of these units,
but I've never seen
this configuration before.
Do you know how I can
stabilize the ion flow?
That looks like
the charge inverter.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Your ship must need
a lot of replacement parts.
Oh... those aren't for this ship.
I've been collecting and repairing
spare components for years.
This is from an old
impulse drive.
Would you believe I found it
sitting in a waste depository?
I'll be able to find a buyer
now that it's working.
These parts could be worth
a small fortune.
That's exactly what I think.
I'm going to use
my quarter of the profits
to establish an outpost specializing
in obsolete engine components.
I'm certain
there's a demand for them.
My Chief Engineer is always
looking for spare parts.
She might be interested
in acquiring your entire inventory.
[Alien 1]
Captain.
[clucking tongue]
You're not trying to take advantage
of my subordinate, are you?
No one's ever going
to buy this junk.
It's almost as useless as you.
[beeping]
There's a ship approaching.
This is the Delta Flyer.
I've got the warp core,
but you're not getting it
until you release the Captain.
Are you insane?
You almost destabilized
the core.
Both of our ships
would've been destroyed!
This isn't a negotiation!
Release your tractor beam now!
All right.
It's in the Cargo Hold.
Lower your shields, and we'll
beam your Captain to you.
[computer beeps]
Ready.
We had an agreement.
[laughing]
To spare your Captain.
As you can see,
she's still alive.
Let the Doctor go.
I'm the more valuable hostage.
Actually, you're not.
We'll leave you
in the Vinri system.
The inhabitants are
mostly harmless.
The Doctor will be
working for us now.
I'll do no such thing.
I'm sure you'll feel differently
after I make a few adjustments
to your program.
I had no idea
he was going to do this.
I'm sorry.
I hope you realize you've stranded
Voyager in the Delta Quadrant.
What did you expect me to do,
let them kill you?
I expected you
to follow my orders.
You might as well have been ordering me
to put a phaser to your head.
Voyager can survive without a warp core,
but not without a captain.
Now it doesn't have either.
[Tuvok] Chief Tactical Officer's Log,
Stardate 54890.7.
With internal sensors off-line,
I've had to order a section-by-section
search for our missing crew members.
Until main power is restored,
Voyager remains immobilized
and defenseless.
They're just unconscious.
Paris to Tuvok.
I found them.
It is logical to assume
the Captain never returned
from the away mission.
Do you have any idea
where the Flyer is?
The Doctor masked his ion trail.
Engineering to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
We're ready to restart
the impulse reactors.
Acknowledged.
["Blue Danube Waltz" playing]
[discordant notes]
[music continues
with discordant notes]
It's playing on every
com channel on the ship.
Computer, pause music.
Unable to comply.
Didn't the Doctor play this
at his recital last month?
Yes, and as I recall,
he performed the piece flawlessly.
Maybe the recording was
damaged by the power loss.
Or perhaps the Doctor altered
the music deliberately.
Why would he do that?
I performed a Fourier analysis
on the recording.
The harmonics
have been modified.
It could be a com frequency.
Unlikely.
There's no carrier wave.
I could be wrong, but it looks
like a warp signature.
The power utilization curve
would be about right.
Try scanning for it.
I'm detecting
a matching signature.
Distance: 6.7 light-years.
We can't follow them
at impulse.
You and Tom take a shuttle.
What are you doing?
If I can amplify your matrix,
I might be able to disrupt
the force field.
I'm sorry I put us
in this position, Captain.
You said you wanted us
to spend more time together.
This isn't what I had in mind.
Maybe... if we get
back to the ship,
we could try
socializing a little more.
This really isn't the place
to be talking about this.
Besides, I don't do
a lot of socializing.
You have meals with
Commander Chakotay...
...and you play velocity
with Seven.
We going to have
to discuss this later.
I need to upload
your first assignment.
[sighs]
You want me to infiltrate
the Hierarchy's surveillance complex?
The data stored there is worth
a hundred warp cores.
How do you expect me to get past
their security perimeter?
I'm glad you asked.
I trust this won't be
permanent?
I've given you the rank
of a Class-One Overseer.
You'll be able to walk into Central
Command without anyone noticing.
I've also uploaded several other
holographic templates
you might find useful.
What's wrong?
I'm not certain.
The compression algorithms
are breaking down.
I told you his program
couldn't handle that much data.
[various voices, garbled]
What have you done to me?
I'm detecting
a human life sign aboard...
and a holographic
signature.
The vessel's weapons
are polaron-based,
and they have
auto-regenerative shielding.
We still have
the element of surprise.
If you don't get him
back to Voyager,
his matrix will be
permanently damaged.
Please do something.
He won't be any use to us
if he decompiles.
Someone's boarded
the Delta Flyer.
They're moving away.
Fire at both vessels.
Now, Mr. Paris!
[alarm blaring]
Our shield generator
isn't going to last.
If we give them what they want,
maybe they'll leave.
Prepare to jettison
their warp core.
What are you doing?
Arming a torpedo.
If we detonate their core,
the blast wave should give us
enough time to escape.
That would kill them.
Captain, get down!
[grunting]
Lieutenant, lock a tractor beam
onto the core and get it back to Voyager.
[Paris]
Acknowledged.
[grunting]
[groans]
[grunts]
[both grunting]
Nar, get this hologram off me!
Guess this wasn't so useless
after all.
[groans]
Are you still interested
in acquiring my inventory?
Computer, transfer the EMH
back into the holodeck buffer.
Can you stabilize
his matrix?
Not until we purge
the excess subroutines.
There's more than a thousand
teraquads of new data in here.
-How is he?
-We're not sure yet.
Captain,
if I don't survive,
I need you to do
something for me.
You're going to be all right.
If I'm not, when you reach Earth,
I want you to donate my emitter
to the Daystrom Institute.
They may be able
to replicate it someday
so that other holograms can know
the freedom I've enjoyed.
I've had something
on my conscience for a long time.
After I was first activated,
I kept a record
of what I considered to be
your most... questionable
command decisions.
It's in my personal database.
I hope you'll delete the file
without reading it.
Mr. Tuvok... I violated
the most sacred trust
between a physician
and his patient.
I told Mr. Neelix
about the cutaneous eruption
you developed on your...
That was indiscreet.
I hope you can forgive me.
Ensign... at your recital
last month,
I told Lieutenant Torres
that your saxophone playing
reminded me of a wounded targ.
I should've put it more delicately.
I'm sorry.
Seven...
You should remain still.
You have no idea
how difficult it's been
hiding my true feelings
all these years,
averting my eyes during
your regular maintenance exams.
I know you could never have
the same feelings for me,
but I want you to know the truth.
I love you, Seven.
Your cognitive algorithms
are malfunctioning.
Goodbye, my friends.
Speak well of me.
-Is he...?
-No, I've got him.
What happened?
I deleted the extraneous subroutines.
I'm not going to decompile?
You'll probably outlive us all.
[Paris]
Doc...
anything else
you'd like to confess?
Captain's Log,
Stardate 54912.4.
Lieutenant Torres
has restored our warp drive
in less than a week.
The Doctor's dignity, however,
might take a little longer.
He hasn't left Sick Bay once
since he returned to the ship.
Captain...
do you need...
do you need
medical attention?
No.
You've been keeping
to yourself lately.
Your friends
are worried about you.
After my deathbed confession,
I wasn't sure
I had any friends left.
I overstepped my bounds
in documenting your command decisions.
It happened a long time ago,
before I considered myself
to be a part of your crew.
Oh, I'm not here
to make you grovel.
I'm here to punish you for your
insubordinate behavior.
I understand.
You're hereby denied the use
of your mobile emitter for six days.
Since you haven't left
Sick Bay for a week,
we'll call it time served.
I appreciate the gesture, Captain,
but I've got a lot of work
to catch up on.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I was hoping you might be free
for a cup of coffee on the holodeck.
I know a little sidewalk caf
in Buenos Aires.
You said you wanted us
to socialize more.
I suppose Mr. Paris
can finish this.
Now, when you're on
the holodeck with the Captain,
-there are two rules you have to follow.
-I understand.
First: leave your rank
at the door.
Not a problem.
The second?
No opera.
Hmm.