[narrator]
These should be familiar images
to everyone who remembers
the USS Voyager's
triumphant return to Earth
after 23 years in the Delta quadrant.
Voyager captivated the hearts
and minds of the people
throughout the Federation,
so it seems fitting
that on this, the tenth
anniversary of their return,
we take a moment to recall
the sacrifices made by the crew.
Corruption charges were brought
today against a Ferengi...
Computer, end display.
[indistinct conversation]
Hi! Good to see you!
-[woman] We must get together.
-[man] Dinner next week, then.
-Great.
-I'm looking forward to it.
Okay.
Hello.
-What's your name?
-Harry. What's yours?
Sabrina.
-Naomi's daughter?
-Uh-huh.
You've gotten so big.
I don't remember you.
I haven't come to one of these
reunions in four years.
Why?
I've been on
a deep space assignment.
For four years?
Compared to how long
I was on Voyager,
it seemed like a long weekend.
Can you find your mother for me?
-Uh-huh.
-I'd like to say hi.
Oops. Here you are, Captain.
Thank you, Admiral.
I haven't seen her
since she was a baby.
It's amazing how fast you've all grown.
How's Tuvok?
Not well.
I thought maybe
I'd go see him tomorrow.
Oh, that would be nice.
I'm sorry I missed the funeral.
I should have been there.
You were on a mission.
Everyone understood.
It's so good to see you, Harry.
-Doc.
-Mr. Paris!
Voyager's pilot, medic,
and occasional thorn in my side.
Where have you been
hiding yourself?
I've been busy.
New holo-novel?
I'll make sure to get your input
before I send it off to my publisher.
Aren't you going to introduce me
to your date?
Mr. Paris, meet Lana,
my blushing bride.
You're married?
Tomorrow is our two-week
anniversary.
Well, congratulations.
My invitation must have gotten
lost in subspace.
Oh, you should be flattered.
We took a page from your book
and eloped.
Joe has a real flair
for romantic gestures.
Joe?
I decided I couldn't
get married without a name.
It took you 33 years
to come up with Joe?
It was Lana's grandfather's name.
Oh. Oh, so you're not a...
A hologram? No.
Frankly, Mr. Paris,
I'm surprised you'd even ask.
I thought we were beyond
those sorts of distinctions.
Are you kidding?
I think it's great.
I'm in a mixed marriage myself,
remember?
Speaking of which,
where is that wife of yours?
The High Council
had a lot of questions.
What did you tell them?
The truth... with a Klingon twist.
I told them that my beloved
former captain,
who had saved my life
many times in glorious battle,
would be honored to submit
Korath's House for consideration.
Do you think it will work?
I'm just the Federation liaison,
but I'd like to think
I have some influence.
You still haven't told me
why you're trying to help Korath.
He's an old friend.
Would this old friend
have anything to do
with the mission
that you sent my daughter on?
Sorry, B'Elanna, but you know
I can't talk about that.
Couldn't you at least have
waited until after the reunion?
-She really wanted to be here.
-She'll be home soon, I promise.
[tapping on glass]
[Barclay] May I have
everyone's attention, please?
Ten years ago tonight,
this crew returned home
from the longest away mission
in Starfleet's history.
[laughter]
23 years together
made you a family,
one I'm proud
to have been adopted by.
So let's raise our glasses...
To the journey.
[all]
And to those who aren't here
to celebrate it with us.
Ladies and gentlemen,
meet the Borg.
Over the course of this term,
you're going to become intimately
familiar with the Collective.
You'll learn
about the assimilation process,
the Borg hierarchy,
and the psychology of the Hive mind.
And when it comes
to your performance in this class,
my expectations are
going to be no different
than the Borg queen herself--
perfection.
[all laugh]
This semester,
we are very fortunate
to have a special guest lecturer--
the woman who literally
wrote the book on the Borg--
Admiral Kathryn Janeway.
-[applause]
-Thank you, Commander.
I'm glad to be here.
A question already, Cadet?
I suppose it could wait
until after class, Admiral.
As they say in the Temporal
Mechanics Department,
there's no time like the present.
In the year 2377, you aided
the Borg resistance movement
known as Unimatrix Zero.
Sounds like someone's
been reading ahead.
I thought you had a question, Cadet.
Yes, ma'am.
When you informed the Queen
that you were going to liberate
thousands of her drones,
could you describe
the look on her face?
[group chuckles]
[female cadet]
Admiral?
Some of us were talking before class,
and we were curious.
How extensive was Seven of Nine's
involvement with Unimatrix Zero?
I'd, uh...
prefer not to discuss Seven of Nine.
Yes, ma'am.
Sorry.
[indistinct whispering]
Excuse me.
Okay. Uh, who can tell me
a little about nanotechnology?
I'm sorry to pull you
out of class, Admiral.
-Did you see it?
-Yes, ma'am.
-And?
-It works.
Korath has agreed to the exchange?
Yes.
But?
He's insisting on handing it
over to you personally.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Good work, Ensign Paris.
Hello, Tuvok.
-The light.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-I know you.
-That's right. I'm your friend.
Kathryn Janeway, remember?
You're an impostor.
No, Tuvok. It's me.
Admiral Janeway visits on Sunday.
Today is Thursday.
Logic dictates that you are not
who you claim to be.
How are you?
I am close to completing my work.
I'm glad to hear it.
It is difficult
with so many interruptions.
I'm sorry.
Would you like me to leave?
You may stay.
[quietly]
Tuvok.
There's something I need to tell you.
It's very important.
I'm going away...
and I may not see you again.
Commander Barclay and the Doctor
will continue to visit you.
They'll bring you anything you need.
The Doctor comes on Wednesdays.
Commander Barclay's visits are...
e-erratic.
Goodbye, Tuvok.
You must be the only doctor
who still makes house calls.
What are your symptoms?
I'm perfectly fine.
For 33 years you fought me
every time you were due
for a physical.
Now you ask me to give you one
ahead of schedule.
I'm taking a trip. I just wanted
to get our appointment
out of the way before I left.
-That's all?
-That's all.
Hmm. The good news is
you're as healthy as you were
the first day I examined you.
Well, now that's out of the way,
have a seat.
We didn't get to talk much
at the party.
No. I don't suppose we did.
So, how's married life?
Wonderful. You should try it.
Oh, I think
it's a little late for that.
Marriage is for the young,
like your wife.
I can only hope she ages
as gracefully as you have.
I, of course, will be the same
handsome hologram
20 years from now as I am today.
I've been meaning to ask you.
Are you familiar
with a drug called chronexaline?
We've been testing it
at Starfleet Medical
to determine if it can protect
biomatter from tachyon radiation.
And?
It's very promising.
Why do you ask?
I need 2,000 milligrams
by tomorrow afternoon.
-Why?
-That's classified.
Will you get it for me?
[sighs]
Of course, Admiral.
You'll have it by 0900.
Thank you.
Download complete.
This should be everything you need.
The shuttle?
Waiting for you
at the Oakland shipyard.
-I wish you'd let me come with you.
-Sorry, Reg, but this is my mission.
Besides, if you leave,
there won't anyone
to teach those eager young
cadets about the Borg.
Oh.
I made you some fresh tea for the trip,
not that replicated stuff.
Thank you. For everything.
I wouldn't have been able
to do this without you.
Oh, don't remind me.
Any final words of advice
for your old captain?
Wait. Don't tell me.
I'm being impulsive.
I haven't considered
all the consequences.
It's too risky.
Thanks for the input,
but I've got to do
what I think is right.
I know it wasn't easy
living all these years
without her, Chakotay.
But when I'm through,
things might be better for all of us.
Trust me.
Tom?
[sleepy mumbling]
Tom.
I'm sleeping.
It's time.
For what?
I'll give you one guess.
Ohh.
Paris to...
Paris to Sick Bay. It's time.
[Doctor]
Remain calm, Mr. Paris. Can she stand?
Affirmative.
Then I suggest
you report to Sick Bay.
Right.
What about B'Elanna?
Her, too.
Right, of course.
Maybe we should take
the transporter.
Hey, wait for me!
Hmm...
What do you mean by "hmm"?
You're going to have
a very healthy baby,
but not tonight.
Tell me you're joking.
You're experiencing false labor,
Lieutenant.
-Again?
-As I explained the last time,
it's a common occurrence,
especially among Klingons.
I want this thing out of me now!
Misdirected rage--
another common occurrence
among Klingons.
-Can't you induce?
-I wouldn't recommend it.
If this keeps happening,
we'll never get any sleep.
You think it's bad now?
-When?
-0400.
How many false alarms
does that make?
Three that we know of.
That baby is as stubborn
as her mother.
Harry's starting a pool
to see who can guess
the actual date and time of birth.
Tell him to put me down
for next Friday, 2300 hours.
-Anything else?
-Crewman Chell's asked
about taking over
in the mess hall full-time.
Neelix left some pretty big pots
and pans to fill.
Does Mr. Chell feel
he's up to the challenge?
Apparently so.
He's prepared a sample menu.
"Plasma Leek Soup."
"Chicken Warp Core-don Bleu"?
[both laughing]
If his cooking's as bad as his puns,
we're in trouble.
Oh, I don't know. I wouldn't mind
giving his "Red Alert Chili" a try.
Feel like having lunch?
I'd love to,
but I've already made plans.
-Rain check?
-Absolutely.
What's all this?
A picnic.
According to my research,
this is an appropriate third date.
You didn't have to go
to this much trouble.
If this makes you uncomfortable,
I could prepare a less elaborate meal.
No, no, don't change a thing.
This is perfection.
[Kim coughing]
In the interest of fair play,
I should inform you
that Mr. Kim has never
defeated me at Kal-toh.
You should've listened to me.
Kal-toh is as much a game
of patience as it is of logic.
An experienced player will
sometimes take several hours
to decide his next move,
and in some cases, even days
may be necessary to...
Kal-toh.
You beat him.
Congratulations.
I'm sure it was
just beginner's luck, sir.
I'd offer you a rematch,
but I'm due in Astrometrics.
Another time, perhaps.
He may have to go,
but I'm free and feeling lucky.
If you'll excuse me, Ensign.
It's just a game, Tuvok.
Icheb's an exceptionally
bright young man.
Did it occur to you that he might
simply be a better player?
My loss was the result of another
lapse in concentration.
I am detecting
lower neuro-peptide levels.
As I suspected.
My condition is deteriorating.
It's a minor change.
We knew it would happen.
I simply have to increase
your medication.
[sighs]
Thank you, Doctor.
Commander, I understand
your desire for privacy,
but maybe it's time
we informed the Captain.
I will inform her
if and when the disorder
begins to affect the performance
of my duties.
Of course.
Your move.
Green, grid 1210.
Red, grid 313.
Tricky.
How's Brax?
Wonderful. Thanks for asking.
I know I can never replace
his father, but...
I have no doubt
the boy looks up to you.
Orange, grid 1012.
I haven't told anyone,
but I'm thinking of asking Dexa
to marry me.
She'd be wise to accept.
That's enough of my love life.
How about yours?
I don't have a love life.
Oh? What about your relationship
with Commander Chakotay?
It's your turn.
Actually, it's yours.
At least tell me
how he liked the picnic.
It was an enjoyable activity
for both of us.
Thank you for suggesting it.
Any time.
[alarm beeping]
What is it?
Long-range sensors are detecting
extremely high neutrino emissions,
accompanied
by intermittent graviton flux
approximately three light-years away.
A wormhole.
I'm not sure.
I'll need to conduct more scans.
We can finish our game tomorrow.
I'll contact you at the usual time.
The emissions are occurring
at the center of the nebula.
There appear to be hundreds
of distinct sources.
Which could translate
to hundreds of wormholes.
The radiation is interfering
with our sensors,
but if Ensign Kim's enthusiasm
turns out to be justified,
it would be the most
concentrated occurrence
of wormholes ever recorded.
Any idea where they lead?
Not yet, but if just one of them
leads to the Alpha Quadrant...
Who knows, Harry?
It might take us right into
your parents' living room.
Alter course, Mr. Paris.
Ensign, when you speak
to your mother,
tell her we may need her
to move the sofa.
7153...5331...7153...
5331...7153...
I'm sorry if I pulled you away
from something important, sir,
but he won't let anyone near him,
and I thought you might...
You did the right thing.
His condition's never been
associated with violent behavior.
He seems more frustrated
than violent.
Long-range sensors
have detected no trace.
Her disappearance
remains a mystery.
I am deeply concerned.
What are you concerned
about, Tuvok?
-Her disappearance.
-Whose?
5331...7153.
He's been repeating those same
numbers over and over again--
533171.
It might be a stardate.
Stardate 53317...
If my memory files are accurate,
that was the day Captain Janeway
was abducted by the Kellidians.
Is that who you're talking about,
Tuvok? Captain Janeway?
Her disappearance
remains a mystery.
No, you solved that mystery, Tuvok.
You rescued the Captain
and brought her back to Voyager
safe and sound, remember?
I am deeply concerned,
deeply concerned.
Maybe if the Admiral paid him a visit,
showed him that she was all right?
Unfortunately,
she's out of town right now.
I'm not sure when she'll be back.
She's never coming back!
Her disappearance
remains a mystery.
I'm deeply concerned...
deeply concerned.
[Doctor]
Voyager to Pathfinder.
Come in, Pathfinder.
Doctor, what a pleasant sur...
Oh! I've forgotten about
our golf game again, haven't I?
Relax, Reg. It's not until next week.
I'm here because I need to get
in touch with Admiral Janeway.
Oh, she's out of town.
I know. Did she tell you
where she was going?
Uh, I'm afraid it--it never came up.
I mean, is something wrong?
I'm not sure.
I paid a visit to Tuvok this morning.
He seemed to think that she
was in some sort of danger.
Well, you know better than anyone
how confused Tuvok can get.
Yes, but I've been worried
about the Admiral, too.
-Why?
-Two days ago, she asked me
for a large quantity
of an experimental medication.
When I asked her why she needed it,
she said it was classified.
Then you shouldn't be telling me
about it, should you? [laughs]
I spoke to Director Okaro
at Starfleet Intelligence.
He assured me that the Admiral
hasn't been involved
in any classified work since she
began teaching at the Academy.
You know how sneaky
these intelligence people can be.
Maybe he was just trying
to throw you off.
Maybe, but still,
she's been talking for months
about how excited she is
to be teaching with you.
Then, just as the semester begins,
she goes away
without even telling you where.
Don't you find that...a little strange?
I...I'm...
sure that there is a perfectly
reasonable explanation.
Doctor, I'm sorry.
I have some...
papers to grade.
-You're stammering, Reg.
-So?
I haven't heard you do that in years.
I think you do know where she is.
She is one of the most
decorated officers
in all of Starfleet history.
I'm...I'm...
sure she can take care of herself.
You wouldn't be saying that
unless she was doing
something dangerous.
You are putting words in my mouth.
Tell me where she is, Reg.
Welcome to the House of Korath,
Admiral.
I love what he's done with the place.
[speaking Klingon]
[growling]
What was that about?
He says your demeanor
was disrespectful.
I hope you told him
I didn't mean to be rude.
I told him if he didn't show you more
respect, I would break his arm.
You are your mother's daughter.
Korath is waiting. We should go in.
Sorry, but this is
where we part ways.
-Excuse me?
-You're dismissed, Ensign.
But, Admiral, I really think that...
I can take care of myself.
With all due respect,
I've been working on this
for six months, and...
And you've done an exemplary job,
but it's over. Understood?
Yes, ma'am.
I happen to know
your parents are anxious
to spend some time with you.
Take a few days' leave.
Go and see them.
A Cardassian disruptor.
I've modified it
to emit a nadion pulse.
Impressive, but that's not
what I've come for.
No.
You've come for something
far more dangerous.
Where is it?
Somewhere safe.
I went to a great deal of trouble
to get you your seat
on the High Council.
Now give me what you promised.
[beeping]
I've scanned your shuttle.
It appears you've made some...
interesting modifications.
Your shields generator
is of particular interest.
It's not for sale.
Then what you want
isn't available, either.
We had an agreement.
Show the Admiral out.
[door opens, closes]
Maybe Chell should add
"Nebula Soup" to his menu.
[rumbling]
-Shields.
-[Tuvok] Holding.
-Bridge to Astrometrics.
-[Seven] Go ahead.
Any more data on those
neutrino emissions?
Negative, Captain.
I still can't get a clear scan.
Distance to the center?
Six million kilometers.
[rumbling]
What is it?
I'm detecting a tritanium signature,
bearing 342, mark 55.
Whatever it is, it's too close.
Evasive maneuvers.
Was it a ship?
Possibly.
[rumbling]
Another tritanium signature
right on top of us.
Tom!
Get us out of here now.
[Borg]
Vessel identified: USS Voyager.
We will pursue and assimilate.
No, they haven't compromised
our security.
Let the vessel continue...for now.
I'll keep an eye on them.
There's no evidence
that the Cube detected us.
[Chakotay]
Where is it now?
Approximately
three light-years away.
How could they not have seen us?
We came within ten meters
of their hull.
The Borg wouldn't
knowingly risk a collision.
The radiation must have interfered
with their sensors as well.
If they can't detect us,
we should go back.
I wouldn't recommend it.
My analysis
of the tritanium signature
suggests there were at least
47 Borg vessels inside the nebula.
We can't just give up
on those wormholes.
Oh, yes, we can.
-What if we try to modify...
-I'm sorry, Mr. Kim.
You may be the Captain someday,
but not today.
Tom.
What are you doing
when your shift ends?
No plans. Why?
I've been thinking.
You and I should have some fun.
One last adventure before you get
too busy being a father.
Did you reserve
some holodeck time?
I've got a better idea.
This is your idea of fun?
It'll work. We just need to make
a few modifications to the Flyer.
We might as well just
hand it over to the Borg.
How could that happen
with the best pilot in the quadrant
at the helm?
Nice try.
If we go to the Captain together,
she'll be much more likely
to approve my plan.
I don't want her to approve it.
Where's your sense
of adventure?
I left it in that nebula,
and I'm not going back for it.
-Don't you want to find a way home?
-I am home, Harry.
Captain Proton would never
walk away from a mission like this.
Captain Proton doesn't have a wife
and a baby on the way.
If you're here for my daily report,
it's not complete.
Actually, I'm here
in an unofficial capacity.
I was wondering if you'd like
to get together again.
To do what?
Well, that all depends
on your research.
Would a quiet dinner
be an appropriate fourth date?
Hmm, I believe it would be
a more suitable fifth date.
I'm willing to skip ahead if you are.
You're fine...
aside from some
minor inflammation
around your biradial clamp.
Let me know if it starts
to bother you.
Is there something else?
Do you remember
three months ago
when my cortical node
shut down?
How could I forget?
You said it might be possible
to remove the fail-safe device
that was causing the problem.
Has it been giving you
trouble again?
No, but I've reconsidered
your offer to extract it.
I've been hoping you would.
You said it would require
several surgeries.
Actually, in anticipation
of your change of heart,
I've been studying the problem
in more detail.
I now believe I can reconfigure
the microcircuitry
with a single procedure.
You'll be free to experience
the full ranges of emotions--
everything from a hearty belly laugh
to a good cry.
How soon can you do it?
Today, if you'd like.
My shift ends at 1800 hours.
It's a date.
Speaking of dates...
once the fail-safe is gone,
you'll be free to pursue
more intimate relationships.
I'm aware of that.
If you decide you need help
with that aspect of your humanity,
I'm always at your disposal.
I appreciate that.
Really?
Yes.
But I already have all the help I need.
Ah.
Of course.
You'll undoubtedly be running
more simulations
with the Chakotay hologram.
No, actually.
I'll see you at 1800 hours.
Mak-tah hoon...
Janeway, ghuy'cha.
I've reconsidered your offer.
I thought you might.
I'll give you the shield emitter,
but not until I've inspected
the device you're offering,
to make sure it's genuine.
You question my honor?
If you were honorable,
you wouldn't have changed
the terms of our agreement.
Show it to me, or I'm leaving.
This will do just fine.
Stop her!
Computer, deploy armor.
Lay in a course
for these coordinates.
[communications beep]
[sighs]
What do you want?
You'll pay for your deceit, ghuy'cha!
And the house of Korath won't rest
until you've drowned in your own blood!
I'd love to stay and chat,
but I'm on a tight schedule.
Computer, warp six.
[computer]
Approaching designated coordinates.
All stop.
Warning: vessel approaching,
vector 1-2-1, mark six.
[communications beep]
Harry! And people are always
saying that space is so big.
Lower your shields, Admiral.
Prepare for transport.
I'm taking you into custody.
You have no grounds
to take me into custody, Captain.
Reg told the Doctor everything,
and the Doctor told me.
Now please, Admiral, stand down.
On one condition: you let me
explain why I'm doing this.
You have no idea
what the consequences would be.
I know what the consequences
are if we do nothing.
So do you.
I have a chance to change all that.
If Starfleet Command knew
what you were trying to do...
You haven't told them.
The Doctor and I decided
to keep things in the family.
What about your crew?
I told them I needed to take you
back to Starfleet Medical
because you'd contracted
a rare disease.
I hope it isn't terminal.
No, but it has been known
to affect judgment.
I know what I'm doing, Harry.
Do you?
Can you say with absolute
certainty that it'll work?
Because if you can't...
Even if it weren't a violation
of every rule in the book,
it would still be far too risky.
What?
I'm remembering a young Ensign
who wanted to fly
into a Borg-infested nebula,
just to explore the remote possibility
that we might find a way home.
If I remember correctly,
you stopped me.
We didn't know then
what we know now.
Our technology
may have advanced, but...
I'm not talking about technology.
I'm talking about people--
people who aren't as lucky
as you and me.
You said you and the Doctor wanted
to keep things in the family.
But our family's
not complete anymore, is it?
I'm asking you
to trust my judgment, Harry...
one last time.
Am I early?
No, you're right on time.
Something wrong with the door?
I didn't think it would be discreet
to be seen carrying flowers
to the First Officer's quarters.
Your research?
I should put these in water.
I've been told that anticipation of
the first kiss is often uncomfortable.
I wanted to alleviate the tension.
That was very considerate of you.
What about the second kiss?
I'd have to check the database.
It may indicate...
[Janeway]
Senior officers report to the Bridge.
Next time we deactivate
the com system.
[door opens]
What is it?
Judging from the tachyon emissions,
some sort of temporal rift.
How's it being generated?
That's what we're trying to figure out.
If Starfleet Command finds out
I had anything to do with this,
they'll demote me back to Ensign.
You worry too much, Harry.
It's turning you gray.
Propulsion's online,
plasma flow stable.
This device of Korath's,
it produces too much
tachyo-kinetic energy.
It could burn itself out by the time
you get where you're going.
You wouldn't be able to get back.
I always assumed
it was a one-way trip.
You're sure I can't talk you
out of this?
Right. Stupid question.
Kim to the Rhode Island.
One to beam back.
Computer,
activate the chronodeflector.
-Deploy armor.
-Unable to comply.
Ablative generator is offline.
Evasive pattern, beta six.
Open a channel to the Rhode Island.
Harry, I'm under attack.
How fast can you get back here?
I'm detecting nadion discharges
on the other side of the rift.
Weapons fire?
It's possible. The signature
appears to be Klingon.
Red alert.
[Kim]
Stand by for transport, Admiral.
You know where I'm going, Harry,
and it's not to your ship.
Your structural integrity is failing.
Just get these Klingons off my tail!
Computer, activate the tachyon pulse
and direct it to these spatial
and temporal coordinates.
There's a vessel
coming through the rift.
Klingon?
No.
Federation.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Recalibrate your deflector
to emit an anti-tachyon pulse.
You have to seal that rift.
It's usually considered polite
to introduce yourself
before you start giving orders.
Captain, a Klingon vessel
is coming through.
Close the rift!
In case you didn't notice,
I outrank you, Captain.
Now do it.
I did what you asked.
Now tell me what the hell
is going on.
I've come to bring Voyager home.
Welcome aboard.
It's good to be back.
-Fresh coffee.
-Would you like a cup?
No, I gave it up years ago.
I only drink tea now.
I told the curator at the museum
that if he wanted to make
the ready room more authentic,
he should always keep a steaming
pot of coffee on the desk.
Voyager's in a museum?
Voyager is a museum,
on the grounds of the Presidio.
On a clear morning,
you can see Alcatraz from here.
You made it back to Earth.
Unfortunately, our favorite cup took
a bit of a beating along the way.
It was damaged during a battle
with the Fen Domar.
-Who?
-You'll run into them in a few years.
You know what? I shouldn't be
listening to details about the future.
Oh, the almighty
Temporal Prime Directive.
Take my advice. It's less of
a headache if you just ignore it.
You've obviously decided to,
or you wouldn't be here.
A lot's happened to me
since I was you.
Well, I'm still me,
and this is still my ship,
so no more talk about
what's going to happen
until I decide otherwise.
Understood?
All right.
Let's talk about the past.
Three days ago, you detected
elevated neutrino emissions
in a nebula in Grid 986.
You thought it might
be a way home.
You were right.
I've come to tell you to take
Voyager back to that nebula.
It was crawling with Borg.
I've brought technology
that'll get us past them.
Oh, I don't blame you
for being skeptical,
but if you can't trust yourself,
who can you trust?
For the sake of argument,
let's say I believe
everything you're telling me.
The future you come from
sounds pretty good.
Voyager's home. I'm an admiral.
There are ways
to defend against the Borg.
My ready room even gets
preserved for posterity.
So why would you want to tamper
with such a rosy timeline?
To answer that,
I'd have to tell you more
than you want to know.
But suffice it to say...
if you don't do what I'm suggesting,
it's going to take you
another 16 years
to get this ship home.
And there are going to be
casualties along the way.
I know exactly what you're thinking.
You've also become a telepath?
I used to be you, remember?
You're asking yourself,
"Is she really who she says she is,
or is this some sort of deception?"
For all you know, I could be a member
of species 8472 in disguise.
Have your people examine my shuttle.
Tell them to take a close look
at the weapons systems
and the armor technology.
In the meantime, the Doctor
can confirm my identity.
My scans of the Admiral's
cerebral cortex
turned up something interesting.
-What is it?
-I'm not sure.
I've never seen this kind
of implant before.
Alien technology?
The microcircuitry
has a Starfleet signature.
Of course it does.
[clears throat]
Admiral?
You invented it--12 years ago,
from my perspective.
I'm sorry, Admiral, I didn't realize...
What? That I was eavesdropping?
I may be old,
but my hearing's still excellent,
thanks to your exemplary care
over the years.
So, this...
implant I'm going to invent--
what does it do?
It's a synaptic transceiver.
It allows me to pilot a vessel
equipped with a neural interface.
Fascinating.
Tell me, what other extraordinary
breakthroughs am I going to make?
Doctor.
Sorry, Captain, but you can't
blame a hologram for being curious.
Just finish your report.
Yes, ma'am.
My scans indicate the two of you
are genetically identical.
The Admiral is you,
approximately 26 years from now.
[door opens]
Hello, Seven.
The technology aboard
the Admiral's ship is impressive.
Much of it appears
to have been designed
to defend against the Borg.
Could we install these systems
on Voyager?
The stealth technology
is incompatible,
but I believe we can adapt
the armor and weapons.
Well, Captain?
Do it.
[Janeway] Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 54973.4.
We've begun outfitting Voyager
with Admiral Janeway's upgrades.
As soon as the major modifications
are complete,
we'll reverse course
and head back to the nebula.
Though I've certainly had some
strange experiences in my career,
nothing quite compares
to the sight of my future self
briefing my officers on technology
that hasn't been invented yet.
Computer, begin regeneration cycle.
[Borg Queen]
Seven of Nine,
tertiary adjunct
of Unimatrix Zero One.
It's been too long.
What do you want?
Do I need a reason to visit a friend?
We're not friends.
No. We're more than that.
We're family.
While we're on the subject
of old friends,
I see that Voyager
has just got a visitor
and she's come from the future.
Tell me why.
You may be able to communicate
with me while I'm regenerating,
but I'm no longer a drone.
I don't answer to you.
I've extrapolated Voyager's trajectory.
I know that you're
returning to the nebula.
I suggest you alter course.
Why should we comply?
You've always been
my favorite, Seven.
In spite of their obvious
imperfections,
I know how much you care
for the Voyager crew...
so I've left them alone.
Imagine how you'd feel
if I were forced to assimilate them.
Voyager is no threat to the collective.
We simply want to return
to the Alpha Quadrant.
I've no objection to that.
But if you try to enter
my nebula again...
I'll destroy you.
[computer] Warning.
Regeneration cycle incomplete.
Her cortical node was exposed
to a low-energy EM surge.
It could have been much worse.
It was the Borg Queen.
She wanted to make sure
I'd be able to deliver a message.
She said she'd assimilate Voyager
if we attempted to reenter the nebula.
Why is it so important to her?
That doesn't matter.
She's not going to be able
to make good on her threat.
I wish I shared your confidence.
You would if you'd had as much
experience with the Queen as I've had.
It was one thing to attempt this
when we thought it was a secret,
but if the Borg are monitoring us...
There's no guarantee
they won't try to assimilate Voyager,
even if we don't go
back into the nebula.
Is that supposed to be reassuring?
I'm not saying
the Borg aren't dangerous,
but from my perspective,
they're 30 years behind the times.
We shouldn't push our luck.
Luck's not going to have
anything to do with it.
I know, you don't want to hear
too much about the future,
but let's just say I ran into the Borg
a few more times
before I made it home.
If I hadn't developed
technology and tactics
that could defeat them,
I wouldn't be standing here today.
We'll maintain course
for the nebula,
but we'll stay at red alert.
And I want continuous scans
for Borg activity.
I heard what happened.
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine.
Because if you need time to rest...
I am in charge of the duty roster.
It would be inappropriate
to allow our personal relationship
to affect your command decisions.
You're right.
This is a time
to keep things professional.
Report.
There's no sign of Borg activity
within a ten-light-year radius.
That's good news, crewman.
Yes, sir.
But we shouldn't
underestimate the collective.
The Admiral seems confident
we can make it past them.
Captain Janeway is more cautious.
Our chances would be good
with one Kathryn Janeway
on the bridge,
but with two?
I'd bet on this ship any day.
If we do make it back to Earth...
what are your plans?
I assume Starfleet
will want to debrief me.
And then, I suppose, I'll attempt
to find a useful position somewhere.
You?
I don't know yet, either.
But wherever I end up,
I'm going to make sure
it's in transporter range of you.
[Torres] I don't want
this whole system crashing
because of one faulty relay.
-Install new ones.
-Yes, ma'am.
And I need an update
on the inductor capacitance.
-B'Elanna.
-Yes, Lieutenant.
Shouldn't you be on the Bridge?
Is there something wrong with a pilot
requesting a systems report
from the Chief Engineer?
The last report I got said the com
system was working perfectly.
[chuckles]
Okay, you caught me.
-I'm checking up on you.
-I'm fine.
-Your back?
-I'm ignoring it.
Well, I would offer
to give you a massage,
but then everybody would want one.
You know, for a Starfleet flyboy,
you're pretty sweet.
[chuckles] So how's it going?
This armor technology
that the Admiral brought--
it's incredible.
I hate to sound like Harry, but we
might actually make it this time.
Well, you don't seem
too happy about that.
Oh, I'm happy.
It's just that I'd actually gotten
used to the idea
of raising our daughter on Voyager,
and now I might end up
delivering her
at Starfleet Medical
instead of Sick Bay.
Well, that wouldn't be
so bad, would it?
Not as long as you're with me.
And I want the Doctor.
I don't want some stranger.
You would have to take him offline
to keep him away.
If we do make it home,
where do you think we'll live?
Well, we could always
stay with my parents for a while.
You're right. Bad idea.
Of course, it probably doesn't
matter to you anyway.
You flyboys are all the same.
You'll probably take the first piloting
assignment that comes along
and leave me home
to change the diapers.
Not a chance.
Bridge to Engineering.
[Torres]
Go ahead, Captain.
-Deploy armor.
-Yes, ma'am.
Armor integrity at 97 percent.
Tuvok?
Integrity holding at 90 percent.
Maintain course.
They're looking for ways to adapt.
[alarm sounds]
Port armor integrity
down to 50 percent.
40 percent.
Mr. Paris, attack pattern Alpha One.
Target the lead cube
and fire transphasic torpedoes.
Target the second cube.
Distance to the center?
Less than 100,000 kilometers.
What the hell is it?
Mr. Paris, alter course
to enter the aperture
at coordinates 346 by 42.
Belay that. I asked you a question.
What is it?
The road home.
[Seven]
It's more than that.
It's a transwarp hub.
You once told me there were
only six of them in the galaxy.
That's correct.
You knew this was here,
but you didn't tell me about it.
-Why?
-I'll answer all your questions
once we're back
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Take us out of the nebula.
-Captain?
-You heard me.
I gave you an order, Lieutenant.
Proceed to the aperture.
This is my Bridge, Admiral,
and I'll have you removed
if necessary. Take us out.
Aye, Captain.
[Seven] This Hub connects with
thousands of transwarp conduits
with end points
in all four quadrants.
It allows The Collective
to deploy vessels
almost anywhere in the galaxy
within minutes.
Of all the Borg's tactical advantages,
this could be the most significant.
It's no wonder the Queen
didn't want us in that nebula.
So how do we destroy it?
The structure is supported
by a series of interspatial manifolds.
If we could disable enough of them,
theoretically, the Hub would collapse.
This is a waste of time.
The shielding for those manifolds
is regulated from the central plexus
by the Queen herself.
You might be able
to damage one of them, maybe two,
but by the time you moved
on to the third, she'd adapt.
There may be a way to bring them
down simultaneously.
From where, inside the Hub?
Voyager would be crushed like a bug.
What about taking the conduit
back to the Alpha Quadrant
and then destroying the structure
from the other side?
This Hub is here.
There's nothing in the Alpha
Quadrant but exit apertures.
While you're all standing around
dreaming up fantasy tactical scenarios,
the Queen is studying her scans
of our armor and weapons.
And she's probably got
the entire collective
working on a way to counter them.
So take the ship back into that nebula
and go home before it's too late.
Find a way to destroy that Hub.
Let's take a walk.
I want to know why you didn't
tell me about this.
Because I remember how stubborn
and self-righteous I used to be.
I figured you might try
to do something stupid.
We have an opportunity
to deal a crippling blow to the Borg.
It could save millions of lives.
I didn't spend the last ten years
looking for a way to get
this crew home earlier
so you could throw it all away on some
intergalactic goodwill mission.
Maybe we should go
back to Sick Bay.
Why, so you can have me sedated?
So I can have the Doctor
reconfirm your identity.
I refuse to believe
I'll ever become as cynical as you.
Am I the only one
experiencing dj vu here?
-What are you talking about?
-Seven years ago,
you had the chance
to use the Caretaker's array
to get Voyager home.
Instead, you destroyed it.
I did what I knew was right.
You chose to put the lives of strangers
ahead of the lives of your crew.
You can't make
the same mistake again.
You got Voyager home,
which means I will, too.
If it takes a few more years,
then that's...
Seven of Nine is going to die.
What?
Three years from now.
She'll be injured on an away mission.
She'll make it back to Voyager
and die in the arms of her husband.
-Husband?
-Chakotay.
He'll never be the same
after Seven's death,
and neither will you.
If I know what's going to happen...
I can avoid it.
Seven isn't the only one.
Between this day and the day
I got Voyager home,
I lost 22 crew members.
And then, of course, there's Tuvok.
What about him?
You're forgetting the Temporal
Prime Directive, Captain.
The hell with it.
Fine.
Tuvok has a degenerative
neurological condition
that he hasn't told you about.
There's a cure in the Alpha Quadrant,
but if he doesn't get it in time...
Even if you alter Voyager's route,
limit your contact with alien species,
you're going to lose people,
but I'm offering you a chance
to get all of them home
safe and sound today.
Are you really going
to walk away from that?
Your concern is appreciated,
Captain, but premature.
It will be several years before
the symptoms become serious.
Until then, the Doctor can manage
my condition with medication.
Is it true what the Admiral said--
that there's a cure
in the Alpha Quadrant?
It is called a fal-tor-voh,
and it requires a mind meld
with another Vulcan.
What about the other Vulcans
on Voyager?
None of them are compatible.
But members of your family are.
If you knew that returning
to the Alpha Quadrant
was your only chance for recovery...
why didn't you object
when I asked you
to help find a way
to destroy the Hub?
My sense of logic isn't impaired yet.
If we succeed,
millions of lives will be saved.
What about your life?
To quote Ambassador Spock,
the needs of the many
outweigh the needs of the few.
I appreciate your candor, Admiral.
But Captain Janeway
is my commanding officer.
-I won't disobey her.
-I'm not asking you to.
I simply want you to tell her
that, in your opinion,
destroying the Hub is too risky,
the cost too high.
I can't do that.
Even if it means avoiding
the consequences I mentioned?
Now that I know
about those consequences,
they're no longer a certainty.
But even if they were, my death
would be a small price to pay
for the destruction
of the transwarp network.
I have known you
for a long time, Seven,
longer than you've known yourself.
You're thinking
that collapsing the network
is an opportunity
to atone for atrocities
you participated in
while you were a drone.
It's time to let go of the past
and start thinking about your future.
My future is insignificant
compared to the lives
of the people we'd be saving.
You're being selfish.
Selfish?
I'm talking about helping others.
Strangers
in a hypothetical scenario.
I'm talking about real life--
your colleagues, your friends...
people who love you.
Imagine the impact
your death would have on them.
Excuse me, Admiral.
I have work to complete.
[sighs]
[Tuvok] Once inside, we'd fire
a spread of transphasic torpedoes.
They'd be programmed
to detonate simultaneously.
If the torpedoes
penetrate the shielding,
the conduits should
begin to collapse
in a cascade reaction.
In order to avoid the shock wave,
we'd have less than ten seconds
to exit the hub.
A long time ago, I made a decision
that stranded this crew
in the Delta Quadrant.
I don't regret that decision.
But I didn't know all of you then,
and Voyager was just a starship.
It's much more than that now.
It's become our home.
I know I could order you
to carry out this plan,
and none of you would hesitate
for a second,
but I'm not going to do that.
You know the crewmen
who work under you,
and you know what your own
hearts are telling you.
So we're not going to attempt this
unless everyone in this room agrees.
No one will think less
of you if you don't.
Captain.
Go ahead, Harry.
I think it's safe to say
that no one on this crew
has been more...
obsessed with getting home
than I have.
But...
when I think about everything
we've been through together...
...maybe it's not
the destination that matters.
Maybe it's the journey.
If that journey takes a little longer
so we can do something
we all believe in,
I can't think of anyplace
I'd rather be
or any people I'd rather be with.
To the journey.
Hear, hear.
[all]
To the journey.
[Admiral]
Coffee. Black.
I thought you'd gave it up.
I've decided to revive
a few of my old habits.
Oh?
What else besides the coffee?
Oh, well...
I used to be much more idealistic.
I took a lot of risks.
I'd been so determined
to get this crew home
for so many years...
that I think I forgot how much
they loved being together...
and how loyal they were to you.
It's taken me a few days
to realize it.
This is your ship...
your crew, not mine.
I was wrong to lie to you,
to think I could talk you out of
something you'd set your mind to.
You were only trying to do what you
thought was right for all of us.
Well, you've changed
my mind about that.
And I'd like to help you
carry out your mission.
Maybe together
we can increase our odds.
Maybe we can do more than that.
There's got to be a way
to have our cake and eat it, too.
We can't destroy the hub
and get Voyager home.
Are you absolutely sure
about that?
There might be a way.
I considered it once,
but it seemed too risky.
That was before you decided
to revive your old habits.
I don't know why I ever gave this up.
It's about time. I'm not getting
any younger, you know.
You're sure you want to do this?
No.
But Voyager isn't big enough
for both of us.
Good luck, Admiral.
You, too.
Captain.
I'm glad I got to know you again.
Any word from the Admiral?
We lost contact as soon
as she entered the hub.
Did the Borg give her any trouble?
Her vessel was scanned
by several Cubes,
but none approached her, sir.
Are we keeping things
professional again today?
Yes, Commander.
You're not joking, are you?
No.
-What's wrong?
-Nothing. I'm just...busy.
I think I've gotten to know you
a little better than that.
I'd prefer it if you didn't speak to me
as though we're on intimate terms.
We are on intimate terms.
Not anymore.
What the hell is going on?
I've decided to alter the parameters
of our relationship.
You mind telling me why?
We both have dangerous
occupations.
It's possible one of us could be
seriously injured or worse.
I believe it's best to avoid
emotional attachments.
Maybe you can just
flip some Borg switch
and shut down your emotions,
but I can't.
I suggest you try.
It will make things
less difficult for you
if any harm should come to me.
Why are you suddenly
so concerned about that?
Is there something I should know?
The Admiral suggested...
that your feelings for me will
cause you pain in the future.
I can't allow that to happen.
Seven.
Any relationship involves risk,
and nobody can guarantee
what's going to happen tomorrow,
not even an Admiral from the future.
The only certainty is how we feel
about each other here and now.
If you think I'm going
to let you end this
because of what might happen...
then you need to get
to know me a little better.
-[groans loudly]
-Try to relax, Lieutenant.
Oh, if you tell me
to relax one more time,
I'm going to rip your
holographic head off!
I hope you don't intend
to kiss your baby with that mouth.
-[yells]
-Tell me this isn't another false alarm.
This isn't another false alarm.
-I can't believe it.
-Oh, believe it!
I might actually win.
-What?
-The baby pool.
I picked today, 1500 hours.
I'm so glad I could
accommodate you.
Don't celebrate yet.
Klingon labor sometimes
lasts several days.
[yells loudly]
Of course I'm sure
that won't be the case here.
[Janeway]
Bridge to Lieutenant Paris.
We're ready to get underway.
-Captain, I'm afraid...
-Go.
-But...
-No buts, flyboy.
If this mission is going to succeed,
we need our best pilot at the helm.
Don't worry.
The Doctor will be here with me.
[Janeway]
Is there a problem, Mr. Paris?
On my way, Captain.
Let's get this show on the road.
Voyager has altered course.
Current position: spatial grid 362.
Trajectory, 112 mark five.
[Admiral]
I don't know how you do it.
All those voices talking at once.
You must get terrible headaches.
If you're calling drones
to assimilate me, don't bother.
I don't need drones
to assimilate you.
I'm not actually here, Your Majesty.
I'm in your mind.
I'm using a synaptic interface.
If I were you, I wouldn't waste
my time trying to trace the signal.
For the moment,
it's beyond your abilities.
What do you want?
To make a deal.
Captain Janeway thinks I'm here
to help her destroy
your transwarp network.
-That's beyond your abilities.
-Oh, I know that,
and I tried to explain it
to my naive younger self,
but she wouldn't listen.
She's determined
to bring down that hub.
She'll fail.
Yes.
But she has weapons
that I brought from the future.
I believe you're familiar with them.
Transphasic torpedoes.
We will adapt.
Eventually,
but not before Voyager
does a great deal of damage.
I'm willing to tell you how
to adapt to those weapons now.
In exchange...for what?
To send a Cube to tractor Voyager...
and drag them back
to the Alpha Quadrant.
You're asking me to believe
that the incorruptible
Kathryn Janeway
would betray her own crew?
Not betray them.
Save them from themselves.
I brought technology
to help Voyager get home.
But the Captain's arrogant,
self-righteous.
And her officers
are so blinded by loyalty
that they're prepared
to sacrifice their lives
just to deal a crippling blow
to the Borg.
But you'd never try to harm us.
I've become a pragmatist
in my old age.
All I want is to get that crew
back to their families.
You wish to ensure
the well-being of your collective.
I can appreciate that.
I'll help you.
But it'll cost more
than you're offering.
What do you want?
Your vessel and its database.
I told you, I'll show you
how to adapt to their torpedoes.
Insufficient.
If I let you assimilate technology
from the future,
there's no telling
how events would be altered.
You're willing to alter the future
by getting Voyager home now.
Oh, yes, but there's a difference.
Do what all good pragmatists
do, Admiral--
compromise.
All right.
I'll give you the shuttle...
after Voyager arrives safely
in the Alpha Quadrant.
You've already lied
to your younger self.
How do I know
you're not lying to me?
I guess you'll just have to trust me.
That won't be necessary.
You underestimate me, Admiral.
While we've been talking, my drones
have triangulated your signal.
Computer, deactivate the interface.
Deploy armor.
[Borg Queen]
Very clever.
Hiding right at my doorstep.
Were you planning to attack us
from inside the Unicomplex?
Not feeling talkative?
[moans]
You and I don't need words
to understand each other.
Take us in.
Aye, Captain.
Voyager has entered aperture 823.
Access transwarp corridor
zero-nine.
Redirect vessels to intercept at...
[garbled] corridor nine.
[garbled communications]
...zero...nine...
transwarp facility...
[groans]
Must be something you assimilated.
What have you done?
I thought we didn't need words
to understand each other.
You've infected us...
with a neurolytic pathogen.
Just enough...
to bring chaos to order.
The Admiral succeeded, Captain.
The conduit's shielding
is destabilizing.
Now, Mr. Tuvok.
Voyager will be destroyed.
[Admiral]
They're ahead of the shock wave.
They'll survive.
Captain Janeway and I
made sure of that.
It's you who underestimated us.
[groans]
Sphere six-three-four.
They can still hear my thoughts.
I may have assimilated
your pathogen...
but I also assimilated
your armor technology.
[groans]
Captain Janeway is about to die.
If she has no future,
you will never exist,
and nothing that you've done here
today will happen.
[Admiral Paris]
What the hell is it?
A transwarp aperture.
It's less than a light-year from Earth.
How many Borg vessels?
We can't get a clear reading,
but the graviton emissions
are off the scale.
I want every ship in range to converge
on those coordinates now.
Yes, Admiral.
Aft armor is down to six percent.
Hull breaches
on Decks Six through 12.
I can't stay ahead of them,
Captain.
The armor is failing.
Where's the nearest aperture?
Approximately 30 seconds ahead,
but it leads back
to the Delta Quadrant.
Mr. Paris,
prepare to adjust your heading.
Yes, ma'am.
We've got 18 ships in position,
nine more on the way.
Open a channel.
Open, sir.
This is Admiral Paris.
Use all necessary force.
I repeat, all necessary force.
Sir, there's a vessel
coming through.
Mr. Paris, what's our position?
Right where we expect it to be.
The transwarp network
has been obliterated, Captain.
We'll celebrate later. Mr. Tuvok.
Cease fire!
We did it.
[beep]
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Sorry to surprise you.
Next time, we'll call ahead.
Welcome back.
-It's good to be here.
-How did you...
It'll all be in my report, sir.
I look forward to it.
Thanks for your help,
Admiral Janeway.
[Doctor]
Sick Bay to the Bridge.
[baby gurgling and crying]
Doctor to Lieutenant Paris.
There's someone here
who'd like to say hello.
You'd better get down there,
Tom.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Chakotay.
The helm.
Aye, Captain.
[beeping]
Set a course...
for home.