[BoJack] Who wants
chocolate chip pancakes?
I do! I do!
Ethan, didn't you already eat
your pancakes?
As Oliver North would say,
"I do not recall."
[canned laughter]
Hey, where's Sabrina?
Not hiding under the table,
that's for sure.
[audience] Aww...
Why don't you guys
leave this one to me?
Why aren't you dressed
for school, prickly muffin?
I'm scared.
Olivia told me
sometimes, at school
they have pop quizzes.
I don't want to pop!
That's too much, man.
[canned laughter and applause]
[laughs] Sabrina,
nobody's popping on my watch.
You stick with me,
and I promise you,
everything's gonna be
just fine.
- Cut, boom in the shot.
- What? I'll be in my trailer.
[canned laughter]
Nah, I'm just horsin' around.
[canned laughter and applause]
[laughs]
You folks enjoying the show?
[crowd cheering]
And how about Sara Lynn
as Sabrina? Isn't she wonderful?
- [cheers and applause]
- Oh. [chuckles] Thank you.
Sarah Lynn.
You remember that name.
Back to one, everybody.
- Hey, you see those people?
- Yeah.
Well, those boobs
and jerk wads
are the best friends
you'll ever have.
Without them, you're nothing.
Remember that.
Let's take it back
to "prickly muffin."
Your family will never
understand you,
your lovers will leave you
or try to change you,
but your fans,
you be good to them,
and they'll be good to you.
We are rolling.
Sound speed.
The most important thing is,
you got to give the people
what they want,
even if it kills you,
even if it empties you out until
there's nothing left to empty.
No matter what happens,
no matter how much it hurts,
you don't stop dancing,
and you don't stop smiling,
and you give those people
what they want.
And action.
Why aren't you dressed
for school, prickly muffin?
You might remember her
as adorable Sabrina
from Horsin' Around,
but on her new dance pop album,
Sarah Lynn wants you to know
that she is hot to trot.
♪ Why don't you touch
My prickly muffin? ♪
♪ My prickly muffin ♪
♪ Ooh, prickly
And it's muffin, and it's-- ♪
[gasps]
♪ It's ready
For your stuffing ♪
What is the message
behind your music?
America needs to know that I'm
not that little girl anymore.
I'm a grown up, sophisticated
woman now, and I have sex,
and I do sexy things.
People like sex, okay,
and since I'm sexy right now,
they like me.
Are you at all worried
that audiences will grow bored
and abandon you
for the next sexy thing?
[chuckles] Are you kidding?
I'm Sarah freaking Lynn.
I'm gonna be sexy forever!
Pop star and child actress,
Sarah Lynn,
celebrates her 30th birthday
this month,
raising the question,
"does anyone care
about Sarah Lynn anymore?"
After all, she is 30.
Here to answer that question,
sexy, 14-year-old dubstep
wunderkind, Sextina Aquafina.
Hey!
[applause]
Sextina,
what's your take?
I love Sarah Lynn.
I grew up on her music, okay,
and she's, like, an inspiration,
but now, she is old,
and shriveled, and gross, and
nobody want her no more, okay?
They want Sextina Aquafina,
baby!
Ha ha!
You're delightful.
So where does Sarah Lynn
go from here?
Oh, you know where
she should go?
She should go
wherever famous people go
when they're done being famous,
and nobody cares
if they live or die.
[horse whinnying doorbell ringing]
Who could that be?
[funky electronic music]
♪ ♪
Who-o-o wants
chocolate chip pancakes?
I do! I do!
Why are you talking to me?
I thought maybe
if I said that,
you'd make me
chocolate chip pancakes.
- [grumbles]
- Oh, come on, buddy.
It's a beautiful morning,
the sun is shining,
- birds are chirping--
- Hey, BoJack,
-any plans for the weekend?
- Still hate the troops, Boj?
Why don't you refill
your bird feeder, huh?
Yeah, who's a bird
got to blow
- to get some seed around here?
- [chuckles] Good one.
Let's do something fun
today.
- Like what?
- Like a cannonball!
Like a
"buying you a new bed"?
Wow, everything in this store
is made
out of old train tracks
and a reclaimed pier.
Oh, great, for ten grand,
I can sleep like a hobo.
Do we need letter openers
made out of Confederate
bayonets?
It says they're stained
with authentic Yankee blood.
O-M-G. O-M-G!
O-M-M-F-C-S-D-V-R-Q-Q-P-Q-F-G!
- I know.
- Ugh.
Yeah, it's me,
straight off your TV screens
and into your shitty lives.
It's Sarah Lynn
and Andrew Garfield.
[screams]
Huh? What the--?
And what's your name,
darling?
I-- mm--
I'll just make it out
to "Evelyn."
Uh--
Um, hi.
Sarah Lynn, hi.
BoJack? Hey. Andrew,
this is BoJack, my TV dad.
Oh, hello,
I'm Andrew Garfield.
Andrew's my boyfriend.
We're a celebrity power couple.
It's no big deal.
[whispering]
It's a really big deal.
Sarah Lynn, I actually wanted
to talk to you about that.
When we started dating,
you were the biggest star
in the world,
but your last few albums tanked,
so now, I don't even know
what you are anymore.
Are you-- Are you breaking up
with me?
Oh, bother.
Um, are those candy pills,
'cause if so,
that is a lot of sugar.
Why are you doing this to me?
Do you like seeing me suffer?
Because you know
I'll bleed for you.
Ugh!
[all gasp]
- Oh!
- Damn!
- Oh, dear.
- Whoa-oh-oh. Um--
Darling, please, I wanted
to do this in a public place
so you wouldn't make a scene.
You think I won't make
a scene, you limey bastard?
Then you really
don't know me at all.
Hey, everyone!
Who wants to see me take a dump
on that sofa?
And then she took a dump
on a sofa
made out of a reclaimed
propeller.
Where's Sarah Lynn now?
I checked her into Promises.
28 days, she'll be good as new.
How did it feel
to check the girl
you raised on television
into rehab?
It was tough.
I would have liked
to reconnect with her.
At least we got to bond a little
on the drive to Malibu.
I can see my organs.
Oh, whoa! She is losing
a lot of blood, BoJack.
Beautiful day for a drive,
though, huh?
Well, maybe the two of you
can catch up some more
when she gets out of rehab.
People don't usually want to
hang out with me after rehab.
I'm really more
of a before-rehab friend.
I think it's gonna be
a long time
before I see Sarah Lynn again.
[horse whinnying doorbell ringing]
Who could that be?
Look, BoJack, I appreciate
what you were trying to do,
but I don't need rehab.
Look, good as new, huh?
Oh, great,
well, that's a relief.
Uh, should you be taking
all those pills?
It's
dexitriathylphenolbarbatol.
- I got it from a doctor.
- Your doctor or just a doctor?
I don't know,
some doctor, okay?
I met him at Adam Levine's
Halloween party.
I think he said
his name was Dr. Who.
Yeah, I don't think
that was--
Ohh, God damn.
Uh, are you supposed to be
snorting it like that?
Ugh!
What are you, the paramedic
who restarted my heart at
Adam Levine's Halloween party?
Okay, so before we
put to bed the whole
- you going to rehab thing--
- BoJack, all my life,
I've never been forced
to confront my problems head on.
No one has ever said "no" to me,
ever, so is it cool
if instead of confronting
my problems head on,
I just hide out here
for a little bit?
Sarah Lynn,
I hear what you're saying,
and I think I know
what you need.
You just need
a strong, responsible adult
to say, "Yes.
Yes, you can move in with me."
This is gonna be fun.
Hey, everyone,
the old gang's getting
back together.
♪ Three little orphans
One, two, three ♪
Who-o-o wants
chocolate chip pancakes?
I do! I do!
Uh, what's going on
in here?
Morning, sleepy-pooh,
you want pancakes?
Yeah,
that sounds great.
Ooh, tough break, champ.
I just gave the last one
to Sarah Lynn.
Early bird gets the worm.
More like early turd
gets the sperm.
Wha-- "Early turd gets the sperm,"
nice one, Sarah Lynn.
You should do
a Shouts and Murmurs.
Help yourself
to some cold wheat bran, sport.
Ugh.
Thanks for letting me
crash here, BoJack.
The guest room is yours
as long as you want.
You have a guest room?
Why have I been sleeping
on the couch for five years?
You'll get the guest room when
you've earned the guest room.
These pancakes are so good.
All Andrew ever wanted to eat
was stupid lasagna.
Andrew Garfield
loves lasagna?
I don't want to talk
about him!
BoJack, can you drive me
to the mall today?
I really want to go shopping,
but I'm not allowed to drive
because somebody got a DUI.
Uh, that somebody was you,
right?
I don't have to answer
your questions!
What are you,
the cop that pulled me over
after Adam Levine's
Halloween party?
Honey, do you really think
going to the mall's a good idea?
I seem to recall another time
you went shopping
when things got
pretty out of control.
Oh, that's too much, man!
[cheering and theme music]
Really? Not the time
when she gored herself
with a bayonet
and shat on a floor model?
Hey,
I'm not the crazy one.
Andrew's the one
who flies off the handle
whenever his agent sets up
an audition on a Monday.
Andrew Garfield hates Mondays
and loves lasagna?
I said I don't want
to talk about it!
- She said drop it, Todd!
- Whatever,
I don't want to go
to the stupid mall.
I'll just tell my friends
to come here.
Muffin, I've got to work
on my book today,
and I can't have
a bunch of folks over
making a lot of noise.
Oh, I see.
I'm a burden to you.
No, no, no, no, no.
Sweetheart. Sweetheart.
I'm no longer cute, so I have
nothing to offer this world.
Honey, of course your friends
are always welcome here.
Cool. Bye.
- Can I invite a frien--
- No.
You let that basket case
into your house?
That girl is a PR hurricane
that you don't need right now.
She has nowhere else to turn.
She broke up with her boyfriend.
She stabbed herself and
closed the wound with duct tape.
- She fired her agent.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Back it up, horsey.
Did you say Sarah Lynn
doesn't have an agent?
Laura, hold my calls,
cancel everything!
Ahab's got a white whale
to catch, baby!
[vase smashes on the ground]
[footsteps]
Uh, hello?
Still there?
[house music]
♪ ♪
Oh, th-- that's--
That's fragile.
Uh, no, oh, no, wait.
[glass breaking]
Careful. Careful. Careful.
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey!
Ah! Lemur!
♪ ♪
[grunts]
- Great party, Sarah Lynn.
- [blows raspberry]
Hi, what it is,
banana bread?
I'm not looking
for a new agent right now.
Oh, whoa, whoa. Who says
I'm looking for a new client?
Slow your roll,
Speed Racer.
We're just two single ladies
having a no-presh rap sesh.
I'm not one of those agents
who can't turn it off.
Your Ari Emanuels and Vanessa
Geckos and what have you.
Vanessa Gecko is actually
Andrew's agent,
and she's really great.
Is she?
I've heard that.
I didn't realize you were
so into house music.
Look, I asked her
to turn it down, but apparently,
this volume was prescribed
by Dr. Who
to treat something called
"uptight dickhead disease."
What do you-- What do you think
about Sarah Lynn?
Oh, I don't really think
about her all that much.
I mean, obviously,
I'm a fan of her early work
which both satirized
and celebrated
youth culture's obsession
with sex,
but I do wonder
as a third-wave feminist
if it's even possible for women
to reclaim their sexuality
in this deeply entrenched
patriarchal society,
or if claiming to do so
is just a lie we tell ourselves
so we can more comfortably cater
to the male gaze.
- Uh, what?
- But you know,
on the other hand, I worry
that conversations like this one
often dismiss her as a mere
puppet of the industry...
- That's my same worry.
- ...incapable of engaging
- in these discussions herself...
- Obviously.
...and infantilization,
which is itself a product
- of the deeply misogynistic...
- So deep.
...society we live in.
But like I said,
I don't really think about her
all that much.
Okay, well,
that is very interesting,
but I was more asking,
like, what do you think
about her living here?
Oh, right.
Well, what was
your relationship like
with her when you were working
on the show?
It was very good,
very professional.
BoJack,
where did you go to college?
- Don't bother him, honey.
- Oh, it's no problem.
Honey, college is for
ugly people who can't tap dance.
- I want to be an architect.
- [laughing] Sweetheart,
Mommy didn't do what Mommy did
to that Star Search producer
so that you could be
an architect.
- Aw.
- All right,
- take it sleazy, everybody.
- Wait, BoJack,
um, what are you doing
this weekend?
I don't know.
I'll probably just go
to the amusement park,
maybe the circus,
fly a kite on the beach,
watch the sunset,
then I'll head
back to my place
to watch any number
of Disney princess movies
while eating ice cream
straight from the tub.
Whoa, that sounds like
so much fun.
Can I come?
[laughing] Yeah,
like I want to spend my weekend
hanging out with a little girl.
[laughing] Good one!
You should write
for the Shouts and Murmurs.
See you Monday!
So the makeup
they were putting on you
was not for the show,
it was just for the weekend?
Why does that matter?
I'm just trying
to understand the story.
Do you think it's possible
that you inviting Sarah Lynn
into your house now is your way
of compensating for not--
No, Diane,
I'm just helping out a friend.
I'm not trying to play out
some weird, sick dad fantasy,
or resolve a deep guilt
for past neglect,
or even try to retroactively fix
my own childhood
by recreating someone else's,
and I'm especially not doing
all those things at once!
Okay.
- [loud crash]
- What happened?
Did somebody hurt
my precious baby?
Sarah Lynn! Ah!
What the--?
Oh, hey, BoJack.
I told my friends they could
tear this wall out to build
a sweet cocaine booth/sex
closet.
- Is that cool?
- No, that's not cool.
Oof. Way to harsh the vibe,
Kissinger.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't realize.
I thought this was a place
where Sarah Lynn
could finally be Sarah Lynn,
but I guess...
that's too much, man.
I always loved
that catch phrase.
Can your friends at least take
the artwork off the wall first?
Ooh.
I want to say yes, but no.
- Okay, good talk.
- Wha-- Are you serious?
The reason I have called
this house meeting is--
Todd, how many times
have we been over this?
You don't have the authority
to call house meetings.
Only I can call a house meeting.
You can propose a house meeting.
All right, fine, fine, fine,
but the reason I propose
- this house meeting--
- Your proposal has been
submitted and
is under board review.
- Proposal denied.
- BoJack, this Sarah Lynn thing
is getting out of control, okay?
She's taking advantage of you.
What? No she's not.
We have a special relationship.
You couldn't possibly
understand.
Oh, my God. Look at what
she's done to your house.
All right, look, I mean,
I stepped on a needle earlier.
I think I'm addicted
to heroin now,
so now, that's probably
gonna be a whole thing.
I have to say,
I agree with Todd.
You're not this girl's father,
and you're not doing her
any favors by refusing
to set boundaries.
Look, I played a dad
for nine years on TV,
so I think I know a little bit
more about parenting
than you two jokers.
The kids on Horsin' Around
didn't need boundaries.
All they needed was
some good, old-fashioned love.
BoJack!
This is not a TV show, okay?
This is real life.
Ah! Lemur on fire!
Lemur on fire!
Some good, old-fashioned love,
and I'm gonna give it to her.
I'm gonna give it to her
so... hard.
You know, I feel like
we don't ever hang out.
Here you are, milady,
a gin and nutmeg
just like you asked.
Ugh.
Too much nutmeg.
Well, you know what
would taste even better?
An endorsement
for a Slovakian yogurt.
Could Vanessa Gecko
get you that?
Vanessa Gecko got Andrew
The Social Network,
and she has skybox seats
at the Staples Center.
- What do you have?
- Well, I've got a table
at the Comedy Central roast
of Gloria Stein--
Hey, Sarah Lynn, what say
we spend the day together,
just you and me,
away from all the haters?
- I want to say yes, but--
- Great, let's go.
♪ It really seems like
Some things are forever ♪
♪ in this world ♪
♪ Don't you know
I'm feeling fine ♪
♪ Together with my girl ♪
♪ Daddy's girl
She's daddy's girl ♪
You know, Sarah Lynn,
I got a feeling
- everything's gonna be okay.
- Uh-huh.
Hey, did you hear
Kazaz got cancer?
What?
Herb Kazaz has cancer?
Yeah, in the butt. He's got,
like, six months I think.
Well, that's horrible.
Why would you tell me that now?
I don't know. The sun setting
over those two hills
made me think of a big ass,
and that made me think
of ass cancer,
of Herb Kazaz's ass cancer.
You really didn't know?
No, Herb and I aren't
on the best--
Look, I'm trying to have
a moment here. I can't--
Hey, I want to give you
something.
Is this
your TV Guide award?
It's the most prestigious
award I ever won.
I always thought if I ever
had kids of my own,
I'd give it to them one day.
I want you to have it.
Oh, wow. BoJack, thanks.
You're sweet.
[sighs]
♪ Na-na-na-na La-la-la-la ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na
La-la-la-la ♪
- What are you doing?
- Shh.
Just let the credits roll,
let the credits roll.
♪ Sha-na-na-na-na-na
Special moment ♪
♪ Exec Producer Garry Marshall ♪
♪ Na-na-na
Such a happy day ♪
"Sit, Ubu, sit."
"Good dog." "Arf."
- Can we go home now?
- Yeah, okay, we're done.
♪ Hey now, boy, come and try
My clitoris is ginormous ♪
[phone buzzing]
- Hello?
- BoJack Horseman.
Did you get rid
of your old TV Guide award?
This pawnshop on La Cienega
was selling one
- with your name on it.
- What?
Wait, why were you
at a pawnshop?
Oh, I just have a guy there
who calls me
whenever TV awards come in
so I can buy 'em.
I put my name on,
it's like I won it myself!
I have two Golden Globes
and a People's Choice
forTemple Grandin.
Sarah Lynn!
Hello?
You still there?
♪ My clitoris is ginor-- ♪
[record scratch]
Okay, party's over.
Everybody out.
- [all] Aw!
- Not you.
You are in big trouble,
young lady.
I can't believe
you pawned my award.
It wasn't personal. I just
thought your award was stupid,
and I already have
a billion other awards,
and I wanted to get money
for drugs.
Look, things have been tough
for you, and I understand that.
I know what you're
going through right now.
[chuckling] Oh, you know
what I'm going through? Why?
Because you were on some dumb
kids show a million years ago?
- Hey, now.
- I had my own fashion line
when I was ten.
By 20, I was packing stadiums.
I get letters every day
from boys telling me
that I was the first girl
they masturbated to.
Literally, someone
tells me that every day.
- That is gross.
- Oh-ho, I know!
You sit up here
in your little house
and feel sorry for yourself?
Oh, guess what, Bo-j,
in order to be a has-been,
you have to have actually,
- you know, been.
- You are way out of line!
You're not my dad.
You're just a rugged, older man
who provided me with a strong,
masculine presence
during my formative years.
I'm not your dad,
and you're not my child.
We're just a man and a lady
living in a house together,
and we're both adults,
and we're both a little drunk.
[both groaning]
Who-o-o lit my ottoman
on fire?
Seriously,
you seriously don't know?
I'm a bad "widdle" girl.
Yeah, you are bad,
very bad!
You want me to put it out
with my boob?
- Uh, what?
- Your boob
is a very impractical way
to put out a fire.
What is happening?
I think you have
a serious drug problem.
The only drug I need
is horse.
Guys, guys,
what are you doing?
Please don't do this.
[both moaning]
No, no. Why are you--
- [whinnies]
- This is a very bad idea.
[both moaning]
Can I at least get my blanket--
Let me get my blanket
out from under--
Oh G-- Oh, my God, my arm.
- You got my arm.
- [laughs] Ow! Ow!
I'm in it now.
Oh, God, no! I'm a part of it.
[both moaning]
I still haven't regained
the feeling in my fingers.
That was the longest two minutes
of my life.
Um, I think it was a little
longer than two minutes.
It was longer
than two minutes.
How do you not get
that this is terrible?
Oh, you mean
from a P.R. standpoint?
Yeah, 'cause if this got out,
oh, I would get flayed!
Oh, I'm done being
the voice of reason.
It's exhausting.
I got to take an angry nap.
Ugh. Ugh. Ugh.
I know. I know.
She's taking advantage of me.
Actually, it kind of feels
like you're the one
taking advantage of her.
She's the one
with substance abuse problems
and daddy issues.
Hey, we both have
substance abuse problems
- and daddy issues.
- Yeah, but she came to you
- for help.
- [sighs]
Hey, notice how
I've been ignoring you,
playing hard to get?
Only makes you want me more.
Ugh. Go stand
on the other side of the room.
- Okay.
- Sarah Lynn, get your coat.
- I'm taking you to rehab.
- Nah,
I was gonna keep hanging out
here if that's all right.
- No, it's not all right.
- What?
This place isn't good
for you.
You need to go where you can
get help, real help.
But I thought you were always
gonna be there for me
like you said.
I will always
be there for you.
Cut, let's take ten.
That's ten, everyone.
Let's make it a tight ten.
- These pages are shit.
- [coughs]
you understand?
Shit.
I wouldn't wipe my ass
with these pages.
It would defeat the whole
purpose of wiping my ass.
- Phone for you.
- Uh-huh.
You get me points
on the back end?
- [coughs]
- Well, I told you
I'm not gonna do it
unless I get points.
Oh, they can't find any?
Well, maybe they could
suck some out of my dick!
- [coughs]
- I'm on the phone.
- You're being very rude.
- [laughs]
You promised me you would
always be there.
Sarah Lynn,
this is for your own good.
You can't stay here anymore.
Okie-doke.
I guess I'll just move out
and find
one of the billion people
who will let me party
at their house.
Uh, well,
you should not do that.
Oh, I know. I know,
but I can, so I will.
I'm at a place right now
where I never need
to grow as a person
or rise to an occasion
because I can constantly
just surround myself
with sycophants and enablers
until I die tragically young.
- Wh-What?
- Yeah,
it's pretty much
too late for me.
Well, them's the breaks.
Take it sleazy, everybody.
Oh, by the way,
I called Vanessa Gecko,
and I'm meeting with her
tomorrow.
- Thanks for the suggestion.
- No! No, no, no, no, no!
Hey, you guys want to hear
my new catchphrase?
Suck a dick, dumb shits!
[blows raspberry]
[grunting]
Laura, the dummy took the bait.
Now for phase two.
Is she gone?
Is it safe to come out?
Leak to the trades
that Andrew Garfield's agent
is taking meetings with his ex,
get it all over town,
wait an hour,
then get me lunch with Andrew
on the books for this weekend,
someplace Italian.
I really blew it,
didn't I?
I mean, maybe you could
have been a better role model
when she was young, but also,
she never really had a chance.
This is what our celebrity
culture does to people.
So what you're saying is,
Everything is society's fault,
and we as individuals
never need
to take responsibility
for anything?
Uh, no. Not exactly.
I was just saying that--
Yeah. I like that.
I didn't do anything wrong
because I can't do
anything wrong
because we're all just products
of our environment,
bouncing around like marbles
in the game
of Hungry Hungry Hippos
that is our random
and cruel universe.
Wait, no, that's not even
what I'm saying--
Yeah, It's not my fault.
It's society.
Everything is
because of society!
- BoJack, that--
- Dude, just let him have this.
Hooray!
Everything is meaningless!
Nothing I do
has consequence!
So what'd you get,
anything good?
Oh, I got everything.
[both laugh]
[both chuckle]
♪ Back in the '90s ♪
♪ I was in a very famous TV show ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ I'm BoJack the horse ♪
- ♪ BoJack ♪
♪ BoJack the horse ♪
♪ Don't act like you don't know ♪
♪ ♪
♪ And I'm trying to hold on to my past ♪
♪ It's been so long ♪
♪ I don't think I'm gonna last ♪
♪ I guess I'll just try ♪
♪ And make you understand ♪
♪ That I'm more horse than a man ♪
♪ Or I'm more man than a horse ♪
♪ BoJack ♪
Boxer versus raptor.
♪ Na na na na na na na na ♪