You got to get your shit
together.
So you took some licks,
but you're gonna bounce back,
because you're talented,
you're smart,
and damn it,
you're good.
You are a goddamn American
treasure, you know that?
You are BoJack goddamn
Horseman.
So get the hell off my lawn.
Oh.
Here I thought I was at the
drive-through at Carl's Jr.
How much did I have to drink
last night?
Last night?
Oh, you've been on a bender
for the last two weeks, ever
since you found out Diane
got engaged
to Mr. Peanutbutter.
Diane got engaged
to Mr. Peanutbutter?
- I need a drink.
- No. No more drinking.
You've been out of control.
Princess Carolyn, look.
I met John Stamos.
That is not John Stamos.
Hey, Princess Carolyn,
John Stamos and I
got our ears pierced.
That is not your ear.
Princess Carolyn,
John Stamos died.
Why?
Why, God?
Why did you take John Stamos?
That doesn't sound so bad.
Oh, I forgot to mention you
were naked for a lot of that.
Stamos!
Also, it wasn't here.
It was at my office.
We thought night swimming
would be fun,
but the current
was too strong.
Oh, God, I wasn't
driving around, was I?
No. You made Todd
your designated driver,
but then you also made him
drink with you.
Yeah, I'll have
a western bacon cheeseburger.
BoJack, we are going
to get you back on your feet.
All you need to do
is get off Diane
and get on to something else.
- [line rings]
- Hello?
Tony, hi.
I'm calling in that favor.
Get your crew
to BoJack Horseman's house.
Can you be there in an hour?
- Yeah.
- Great.
What just happened?
You're the new face
of Guten Bourbon.
What is Guten Bourbon?
It's an urban German
bourbon.
Am I just hungover, or are
you talking like a Muppet?
They're looking
for American celebrities
to talk about how much
they like to drink.
It's the part
you were born to play.
All you have to do is smile
and stay upright.
I don't know.
It sounds like a lot of work.
You take up 80% of my time
with your drama
and make me 0% of my money.
Do the damn commercial.
[cell phone vibrates]
7:00 a.m. Breakfast
with Lenny Turteltaub.
Okay, I got to go.
You're in charge, Todd.
Keep this dummy
out of trouble.
Hooray, responsibility.
- [vomits]
- Hey.
Do you really believe all that
stuff you said to me earlier
about me being smart
and talented and good?
BoJack, I'm an agent.
I believe everything I say.
Ah.
Hey, where the hell
is that cheeseburger?
I ordered it,
like, an hour ago.
[funky electronic music]
♪ ♪
Lenny Turteltaub,
you skinny bitch.
How the hell are you?
I'm in a hurry,
so I'll make this... snappy.
I got some great news about
the picture
we're putting together.
- [cell phone rings]
- Sorry. Hello?
Hey, I just wanted to thank
you for getting me this job
and pulling me out of that
oh-so-predictably BoJack
spiral of self-loathing
and substance abuse.
- You really are the best.
- I know. Talk to you later.
I feel like you see things
in me that nobody else sees.
Yep, I'm pretty great.
Got to go.
All this time,
I never even--
BoJack, I'm in a very
important breakfast right now.
- Okay. I got to go, too.
- Sorry.
What's the great news?
- We got Braff.
- You beautiful dickhead.
You finally got Zach Braff?
Ah, no other director
has enough weight
to handle a movie about
the last days of Eva Braun.
No shit, toots.
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
There you go.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Everything's coming
together.
With Braff directing,
my client Cate Blanchett
starring,
and the great
Lenny Turteltaub producing,
this movie is a done deal.
Look, honey, I been in this
business a long time, okay?
Long time.
And as I once said
to a young Ed Begley Sr.,
"It ain't a done deal
till the deals are all done."
I'm the best agent
in the biz.
I can seal these deals
with my paws in my pants.
Well, then I'll say to you
what I once said
to a young Buster Keaton,
"What?"
[jazzy music]
[overlapping shouting]
Laura!
What's happening?
- We're merging.
- No shit. With what?
FME. A bunch of people
got laid off,
and some of the FMEers
are already moving in.
It's all so sudden
and unexpected.
- It was not handled well.
- [laughter]
Oh, shit. Don't tell me
one of the new agents is...
Vanessa Gekko.
That slippery, slimy,
cold-blooded, bug-eyed--
What's new, pussycat?
- Gekko.
- In the flesh.
Ha ha. How are you?
What a morning, huh?
I was in the middle
of my second soul cycle class
when I got the news.
- Can you imagine?
- No.
I was so excited,
I rushed home,
made love
to my husband of 15 years,
made a hot breakfast
for my three wonderful girls,
read to them, dropped them off
at their elite private school,
and then got my ass here
as quick as I could.
- Um, how old are your kids now?
- I don't have any children.
Oh, well, it'll happen.
You're still...
- Anyway--
- Princess Carolyn.
I see you've already met
a new member of the team.
- Vanessa Gekko, sir.
- I know that.
This merger is very exciting.
- I'm pumped.
- I'm beyond pumped.
You should be, or at least
I think you should be.
It's hard to keep track
of who's getting promoted
- and who's getting fired.
- Oh.
You're probably fine or not.
Who knows?
[cell phone rings]
Ugh.
What do you want, Todd?
Well, good news, bad news.
The bad news is that there
actually is no good news,
and the other bad news
is BoJack's gone.
What? Where did he go?
The shoot is at his house.
He just disappeared. I don't
even know why he'd leave.
This charcoal mellowed bourbon
is so smooth,
every time I take a sip,
pure happiness.
- That was amazing.
- Really?
Can I get you to say that
in a tuxedo?
Hey, I got to go.
I think this is my big break.
Don't worry. I won't let it
get to my head or anything.
Hey, who told that asshole
he could sit in my chair?
Don't forget I'm your agent, too!
I want 10%.
Hello, beautiful.
What the hell
are you doing here?
You're supposed to be
shooting a commercial.
I know, but I was sitting
there drinking bourbon and--
They didn't give you
fake bourbon on set?
Oh, they did, and then
I just mixed it with bourbon.
And it hit me.
Why was I so upset
about Diane getting engaged?
You're the one who's always
been there for me,
so I drank a lot more bourbon
and drove over to tell you
how I feel.
Oh, I see what this is.
Princess Carolyn,
what are we doing?
Clearly we're in love
with each other.
You're not in love with me.
You're in love with Diane.
And you're not even
really in love with her.
You just think you are
because you pay her
to listen to you
talk about yourself.
Diane getting engaged
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
It made me realize you're
the one I need to be with.
Ha! You say that every time
something bad happens.
Not getting nominated
for a People's Choice Award
is the best thing
that ever happened to me.
It made me realize--
Getting caught
with that pound of cocaine
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
That hooker getting pregnant
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Sneezing on Marisa Tomei
was the best--
Every time
something bad happens,
you come running to me
for comfort.
Well, it's not gonna happen
this time.
I can't be your agent
and your girlfriend.
- It just doesn't work.
- [knock on door]
I have Lenny Turteltaub
for you.
- I have to take this.
- Okay.
But remember,
I'm coming for you,
and I'm gonna make you love me.
Please don't.
Hey.
Bad news, P.C.
Braff used your merger as
an opportunity to jump ship.
Aw, fish.
Now his new agent's
asking for twice the money.
As I once said
to a young Lionel Barrymore,
"Eh, shut up."
Without a director, Eva Braun
is as dead as Eva Braun.
Yep.
You got to get someone big.
- What about those brothers--
- Hello? Hello?
Lady, you work too hard.
That was
an important phone call.
Important phone call
beep boop blorp.
Don't you robot-voice me.
Princess Carolyn,
what are we doing?
Well, I'm working,
and you are leaving.
Before I go, I got you
a little sexy something
to remember me by.
Since we can't be together
every second,
which would be my preference,
I give you cardboard BoJack.
It's got
a light-sensitive sound chip,
so every time you walk by it,
it quotes a line
from Jerry Maguire,
your favorite movie.
You complete me.
What do you think?
Pretty sweet, huh?
You had me at "hello."
I don't have time for you
or cardboard you.
I need to find
a new director.
Or you could find
my nude erector--
She's gone.
[jazzy music]
[elevator bell dings]
Blech.
Word to the wise, Laura--
Do not pitch a Nazi romance
to Steven Spielberg.
Just thought you should know
there's been some
reorganization
- vis-a-vis resource management.
- What are you saying?
You and Vanessa Gekko
are sharing an office
until they can find her
a permanent one.
- The hell we are.
- Also...
Good news, Princess Carolyn.
Vanessa's my agent now.
What?
You said you couldn't be
my girlfriend and my agent,
so I'm firing you.
Now we can be in love.
- Hope you like money, BoJack.
- This is so great.
Now I can date you
and have a better agent.
- Everybody wins.
- Oh.
I'm a sporting agent.
Are you still
searching for happiness?
Make your own happiness.
Mmm, that's some Guten
Bourbon.
Cut.
That was great.
Was it? You know, I'm trying
to do good work here,
really find the character,
but it's pretty distracting
to have all these robots
staring at me
with their blinking red eyes.
Those are cameras, Todd.
We're making a commercial.
Oh, well,
you want to make a good one?
Then get them
the hell out of here!
I'm the face of this brand,
I'm the man behind the thing,
and I'm determined
to get the jargon
of this German bourbon blurbin'.
Is it just me,
or does this fake booze
taste a lot like real booze?
You want BoJack,
you can have him.
Here's a list of directors
who won't work with him,
studios that won't hire him,
former assistants
with restraining orders.
This is great.
You know,
it gets kind of boring
when all your clients
are in such demand,
they practically
find their own jobs.
Well, then BoJack should be
a lot of fun for you.
- No one wants to hire him.
- [knock on door]
Hello. We're looking
for BoJack Horseman's agent.
We'd like to discuss
a very lucrative business
opportunity.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- I'm BoJack's agent.
The opportunity
is we're blackmailing you.
Ha. All yours.
Needless to say,
it would be a shame
if these pictures got out.
Fortunately, that can
easily be avoided
by simply paying me
and my partner here $150.
Each.
Let me just get my
checkbook.
Huh?
- Whoa.
- [chuckles]
Oh, except California law
prohibits taking photos
on private property
without a permit,
but you had a permit, right?
- Uh...
- What's that?
Oh, also, extortion can be
prosecuted
as a class E felony.
That's four years
in prison, easy,
and when you throw in
the murder of Tupac Shakur...
- We didn't do that.
- Yeah, yeah.
You can't pin that on us.
Well, someone's got
to take the fall.
- [both gulp]
- Sorry to bother you.
Forget we were ever here.
That was fun.
Hey, Laura, send those guys
a nice fruit-and-nut basket.
You got it, boss.
Who said you could use
my assistant?
- I did.
- Oh, hello, Mr. Witherspoon.
Did you know the human head
weighs 8 pounds?
Fascinating.
So sorry we have
to double up on everything
while we work out who goes
where and who gets fired,
but in the meantime,
help yourself to an intern,
one of the rising stars
at our company--
- Charlie Witherspoon.
- Hello. I-- Oh.
Sorry, my-- My hands
are really sticky.
[groans]
Oh, God, am I blowing this?
[glass shatters]
Charlie was the editor
of The Harvard Lampoon.
He can be Princess Carolyn's
new assistant
while I use Laura.
- Ugh.
- Good thinking, boss.
[phone rings]
Ah, ah, phone is ringing.
Phone is ringing.
What do I do?
I'll take it in here,
Charlie. Hello.
Princess Carolyn,
your client is out of control.
BoJack is not
my client anymore.
Not BoJack.
Todd.
I think someone mixed alcohol
into his prop drink.
Oh, you pretenders.
Bourbon is the name
of a county.
You can't just make bourbon
in Germany.
That would be like
making Rice-A-Roni
- anywhere but San Francisco.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- Ugh. I'll be right there.
- Ow.
You got to get
your shit together.
You are a winner, okay?
You are Todd-- Hold on.
4:30 p.m.
Meeting with Eva Braun team.
Fish.
Okay, you are Todd goddamn--
- What's your last name?
- Chavez.
- Your last name is Chavez?
- Yeah. Why?
I don't know,
I just never thought of you
as a Chavez.
Look, I got to go.
I feel like you didn't
really finish the pep talk.
I know, but I got a movie
to put together.
Best of luck.
Ready for the tagline?
Here's the tagline.
What the heck is going on?
"The woman who loved the man
who hated everyone."
- That writes itself.
- You got to be kidding me.
Hey, where were you?
We looked everywhere.
You're having the Eva Braun
meeting without me?
I'm so sorry,
but I didn't know what
the protocol was around here,
and these guys were just
champing at the bit.
- We're just wrapping up.
- But Cate is my client.
Okay, why don't I come
find you when it's over,
and I'll bring you up to speed?
Is that Quentin Tarantulino?
Yeah.
I brought him on board.
You know he's always wanted
to direct a romantic comedy?
Eva Braun
is not a romantic comedy.
[sing-song] Bye.
[dramatic music]
We live in a cynical world,
a cynical world.
He's right, you know.
Oh, ooh, oh, oh, over-rotate.
Hey.
I just missed
an important meeting
because I was babysitting
Todd, who's too drunk to work,
because you switched out
the prop bourbon
with the real bourbon.
You are ruining my life.
- Have dinner with me tonight.
- No way.
Come on, just me, you,
and a bottle of Pinot.
Probably more than one bottle
and some entrees.
And I'll probably get
an appetizer.
I own the restaurant,
so we can go crazy.
- I have to work.
- You don't have to work.
- You choose to work.
- Hmm.
Why not choose to be happy
for once?
Mm.
[soft piano music]
When you're writing a memoir,
you spend a lot of time
reflecting on the past.
I regret not being
a better friend to you
and lover.
Thank you.
Lover's kind of a weird word,
but thanks.
You want to get out
of this stuffy old restaurant,
get some gelato, and maybe
drive out to the ocean
- and put our feet in the water?
- That sounds great.
Let me just freshen up
my whiskers.
Great. I'll get the car
and meet you outside.
You scamper right back,
pussycat.
You look at your reflection
too long,
you might fall in love.
She's gone.
[cell phone rings]
What do you want, Gekko?
Well, I was hoping
to talk to you face-to-face,
but I guess you had
to leave work early.
I left at 8:30.
What is it?
Well, Cate and I
had a really good talk today.
We have so much in common,
and especially since I'm doing
so much for Eva Braun,
it almost seemed weird
that I wasn't repping her.
No. No. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
She and I are both
high-powered working mothers,
so I understand her
priorities,
so she's switching to Gekko.
Wow, being a mom
helped my career?
I really can have it all.
This isn't fair.
I know everything about Cate.
Her favorite color is red.
Her favorite book
is Suffragette City.
Her favorite Spice Girl is Baby.
I know all I need to know,
which is that she's beautiful,
she's British,
and she's gonna make me
a lot of money.
She's Australian, you moron.
If you need me,
I'll be at work.
[sing-song] Bye.
Ugh.
[phone rings]
Uh, telephone.
Charlie,
get me Cate Blanchett.
Um, who is--
Okay, I don't--
Uh, uh, sorry, I can't--
Oh, sticky.
You know what?
Never mind.
If Vanessa Gekko wants Cate
that bad, she can have her.
I'm gonna be okay.
I'm gonna be happy.
Tonight, I choose to be happy.
Hello? I think
I put you on mute.
Good night, Charlie.
[ringtone jingles]
Holy shit.
Herb! How the hell
are you, buddy?
Ruin any lives lately?
- Excuse me?
- I got your message, asshole.
[coughs]
You got something to say
to me,
you come out to Malibu
and say it to my face.
I'll be alive tomorrow.
After that, who knows?
[beeps off]
[sighs]
Sorry that took me so long.
Just wanted to look my best
for you, lover.
Hey, um, I just got kind of
a weird phone call.
You and me both.
Hey, screw 'em all, right?
Yeah.
Are we going to gelato?
Princess Carolyn,
what are we doing?
Getting gelato?
[sighs]
This was a mistake.
I've been acting crazy.
That phone call just
pulled me back to reality.
You were right.
I don't love you.
You don't love me.
We're just two lonely people
trying to hate ourselves
a little less.
Maybe that's all
we're ever gonna be.
Maybe that's all we ever were.
Well, this night took
a turn.
You know the worst part?
I knew this was gonna happen
and I let myself
get excited anyway.
So we agree that this is
on you, then?
I guess I'll see you around.
You're not even
gonna give me a ride home?
Sorry, I think I just
need to be alone right now.
[tires squealing]
[sighs]
Of course, of course.
That's what you get
when you fall for a horse.
Taxi.
You got to get your shit
together.
So yesterday, you let yourself
fall in love a little bit,
and you got your heart broken.
Serves you right
for having feelings.
Starting now, you are
a hard, heartless career gal.
Go to work, be awesome at it,
and don't waste time
on foolish flights of fancy.
From now on, you are a robot.
Beep bop boop blurp bleep.
[cell phone vibrates]
- Hello.
- I just want you to know I'm fine.
Uh-oh. People only say they're fine
when they're not fine.
Did I hurt your feelings
last night?
I'm an agent.
I don't have feelings.
Well, I'm glad you called.
I think that you had
the right idea yesterday.
I should be
getting back to work.
Can you get me another job?
Yeah, well, I'm not
your agent anymore, so, no.
Oh, right. Well, just tell
whoever, then.
- Haah!
- [tires screech]
Whoa.
[honks horn]
Asshole!
Anyway, I'm off to Malibu
to see Herb Kazzaz.
He has cancer, which,
as you know, is a whole thing.
Plus, he hates me, so I could
really use some good news
at the end of the day.
Oh, my God,
you're going to see Herb?
You must be really--
Nope, don't care.
Not interested.
[phone beeps]
Hope you like kicking ass,
Charlie,
because that's all
we're gonna do today.
My tie got stuck in the
copier this morning.
That's great, Charlie.
If you flip them real quick,
it looks like
the tie is running.
Hey, Vanessa, your client,
BoJack Horseman, wants a job.
- Good luck.
- Oh, yeah, about that.
Gwyneth came in this morning,
and I wanted to show her
that she was a top priority,
so I shredded BoJack's
contract
right in front of her.
Heh heh
What? You just signed BoJack
yesterday.
I say good riddance
to Mr. Houseman
or whatever
that horse's name is.
It's not like he makes
this company any money,
and he does seem to take up
an awful lot of your time.
I'm from Arizona, Jerry.
I went to Arizona State.
Todd, how do I
turn this thing off?
Todd.
[Todd] What? I'm busy.
[BoJack] Never mind.
Think I've figured it out.
Now that I've got the room
to myself,
time to practice the trombone.
[trombone plays]
He's kind of in
a bad place right now.
You can't just drop him.
The best agent
in this building
couldn't get that guy a job.
The best agent
in this building
got him a job yesterday,
and I could get him a feature
by the end of today.
If you want to get him
a movie
by the end of the day,
great, do that.
Otherwise, we are washing
our hands of him.
Charlie, I hear NBC picked up
your running tie show.
Congratulations.
[Charlie] Thank you, Dad.
Hey, Marty,
Princess Carolyn here.
How'd you like to work with
the BoJack Horseman?
What's that?
You hate his guts?
He's a talentless boob?
What's that? You'll never
work with BoJack again?
What's that?
You want him to die in
an ass factory warehouse fire,
smothering to death
under a pile of burning asses?
Well, if you change your mind,
give me a call.
Oh, BoJack, what am I
gonna do with you?
I don't understand
why you're going through
all this trouble for him.
That guy's dead weight,
Princess Carolyn.
If you don't cut him loose,
you're never gonna be happy.
Help me help you.
That's it.
Of course.
Cameron Crow,
you skinny bitch.
You know Jerry Maguire's
my favorite movie of all time?
All your films are so human,
which is super impressive
since you're a crow.
Well, my name is
Cameron Crow,
but I'm actually a raven,
so common misconception.
- Well, whatever you are--
- A raven.
- I brought you this
- Suffragette City...
"a coming of age story
about rock music,
being a teenager in the '80s
and buying zoos"?
How have I not
heard of this book?
You'd be the perfect
director
to make a movie out of it,
and I happen to know this is
Cate Blanchett's
favorite book.
I'll bet she'll drop
everything to play the part.
You should give her a caw.
Okay, I see-- Yeah.
Caw is what crows say.
Again, I am not a crow.
[jazzy music]
Cate, listen to me,
you're making a big mistake.
Eva Braun
is your dream, remember?
Cate? Hello?
Cate!
Oh, no. What happened?
Did Cate drop out of
your little Holocaust movie
so she could make
my little Cameron Crow movie?
Why don't you go home
and cry about it
to your loving husband
and children?
Say, which one of you
is overseeing
the Eva Braun package?
That would be me, sir.
Vanessa, you really
shat the bed on this one.
Now, are you fired?
Not exactly.
Can you still work here? No.
Lenny Turteltaub
here to see you.
Thanks, Laura.
So, one minute I'm making
a movie with Cate Blanchett.
Next, I hear she's doing
a picture with Cameron Crow
about mix tapes.
As I said to Ed Porter
at the premiere of
The Great Train Robbery,
"Aah, the train's
coming right at me."
- What the hell is going on?
- I don't know, Lenny.
Eva Braun
was Vanessa's project.
All that work for nothing.
Now Quentin Tarantulino's
got four arms up my ass
'cause he got all excited
about making a rom-com.
You know what would be
a great romantic comedy?
Remember when that guy stole
the D from the Hollywood sign
so he could propose
to his girlfriend?
That would make
a great movie,
but who would play the lead?
Preferably someone
kind of washed up.
You know how much Quentin
loves to revitalize
dead careers.
It's kind of his thing.
Well, in that case,
you know who'd be great?
Show me the money.
[cell phone vibrates]
- Yeah.
- Good news.
You're back in my stable,
and I got you the lead
in a romantic comedy.
Who's the best agent
in the world?
What?
I went through hell and back
today, but it was worth it
because I got you a job.
Aren't you excited?
No. I don't know.
I don't care about that.
You... You said
you wanted a job.
It doesn't matter.
Nothing matters.
- Wow. What happened in Malibu?
- I got to go.
[beep]
Need anything else?
No, thanks, Laura. Go home.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Are you gonna head out soon?
Where else would I go?
[upbeat music]
[cell phone vibrates]
Happy birthday,
Princess Carolyn.
[sighs] Thanks, phone.
You are 40.
[soft music]
♪ We were young ♪
♪ We had our heads down ♪
♪ Oh and I ♪
♪ I was all
of a landslide ♪
♪ Didn't know ♪
♪ It was something
to hold onto ♪
♪ Never meant us
to fall in ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ ♪
Boxer versus raptor.
♪ Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na ♪