[seatbelt clicks]
[clears throat]
[engine turns]
So... should we talk about
how you just tried to kiss me?
No, I don't think
we need to talk about that.
Yeah, you're right.
What's to talk about, right?
We're f-friends, right?
- Oh, yeah, totally.
- Yeah, friends.
And I think it's important
that we stay friends.
Yeah, I agree.
And be friends
with each other.
- Yeah, friends.
- And also to each other.
Plus, hey,
you're getting married.
That's right.
Next summer.
Nantucket is great
in the summer.
Not like L.A.,
which is so hot and dry.
- [laughs]
- It is arid.
[brakes squeak]
Well... see you later!
We're still a few miles--
I'll walk.
It's a beautiful night.
- [horn honks, tires screech]
- Ah! Sorry, sorry!
Shit.
Todd, we gotta stop
this wedding.
Todd?
Aw, crap.
I left him in Malibu.
- [tires squeal]
- [car horn honking]
[funky electronic music]
♪ ♪
But wait, doesn't Diane want
to marry Mr. Peanutbutter?
No, see, she thinks she does,
but she actually doesn't.
That's why we need to be
good friends right now,
and put our own feelings aside
and sabotage
our friend's engagement.
Oh...
- Wait? What?
- Oh.
I got here as soon as I could.
What's the emergency?
We got to figure out a way
to stop Diane's wedding.
[clears throat]
Okay.
So when you woke me up
in the middle of the night
and told me to rush over here
because of an "emergency,"
the emergency
you were referring to
was Diane getting married
a year from now?
- Yeah, you got any ideas?
- I'm done.
I'm not going to waste
another thought on you.
I am at a bar.
It's the weekend.
I'm gonna enjoy myself.
Look, if you don't have
any ideas,
just say you don't have
any ideas.
Yoo-hoo!
Buy me a drink.
Uh, okay.
What's your name, stud?
Vincent.
Adult... man.
Vincent Adultman.
Ya hear that, BoJack?
Vincent is an adult,
and I'll bet he knows
how to treat a lady.
He very clearly
isn't and doesn't.
Would you like alcohol?
I certainly would,
you sophisticated
smooth talker.
Mmm!
Tell me all about you.
Mm...
I like business...
transactions.
[laughs]
Are you seriously trying
to make me jealous
by flirting with
what is very obviously
just three kids
stacked on top
of each other
under a trench coat?
Vinnie, what does a guy
like you do for fun?
I don't have time
for these shenanigans.
I got a wedding
to shanghai.
Good luck with
your business transactions.
- Thanks.
- [grunts] Ugh!
[laughs]
Officer.
The mail truck pulled up
right next to me.
I got a bad vibe.
What was I supposed to do?
Not chase the mail truck?
Mr. Peanutbutter,
I'm a big fan,
so I'm gonna let you off
with a warning this time.
[rap music]
♪ Dangerous ♪
- ♪ Come on ♪
- ♪ Dangerous ♪
- Aah!
- Mr. Peanutbutter!
[siren wails]
[Mr. Peanutbutter barking]
[sips]
[table rattles]
Hey, honeysuckle.
Great news.
I got to ride
in a police car.
Bad news--
I lost my driver's license.
Let me guess.
Were you chasing
the mailman again?
Yeah, why?
Did you see him out there too?
[lowers voice]
Nothing stops them.
Not rain, not sleet,
not dead of night,
not gates!
[dramatic music]
Anyway,
I need a little favor.
Can you... drive me
everywhere I need to go
for the next three months?
I really can't, sweetheart.
I'm super busy.
Oh, you're working
on our wedding registry.
- I'm writing my book.
- Right.
But don't forget
about the registry.
Mr. Peanutbutter,
you know I love you.
And you know I am really excited
about getting married,
but right now I'm working,
and I have a lot of thoughts
in my head,
and I can't really think
about our wedding
or the future
or me being married to you.
Okay.
What's going on?
Talk to me like
I'm Michelle Pfeiffer
in the Coolio video.
Just-- Well, um...
with the leg--
Hmm, all right.
And Coolio.
Nothing's going on.
It's just that this wedding
is kind of
starting to feel like
a lot.
Honey, relax.
Getting married is easy.
I mean,
I've already done it twice.
It's fine.
I'm sorry.
I just... need to focus
on the book right now.
So that's still a no
on driving me around?
- Why don't you hire a driver?
- Eh-eh-eh-deh--
Is there a light bulb
above my head?
Because while you were talking,
I just got an amazing idea.
I should hire a driver!
Oh, this will be a romp.
[laughs] If I know me,
this will be a romp.
I'm not sure how I feel
about breaking and entering,
BoJack.
Well, that's the beauty part.
The B&amp;E is really
the least illegal piece
of this 12-point master plan.
- Have you got your tool kit?
- Check.
- Burner phone?
- Cyanide capsule?
- Check.
Wait, why do we need--
Okay, let's get started.
Step one: Enter the study.
[glass shatters]
Step two: Plant incriminating--
- Hello? Todd?
- Uh...
- Hi, Mr. Peanutbutter.
- Take the cyanide, Todd.
Take the cyanide!
[panting]
And hup. Hup.
And hup-- No.
Are you here to interview
to be my driver?
Um... yes, I am.
Brilliant.
I didn't even post
the ad yet.
Here's me thinking
destiny over here.
And hup. Yeah!
Hu-aah!
[crash]
[car alarm blares]
[car alarm chirps]
Thank you for your interest
in the role of driver.
I know you don't have
your resume with you,
so I've taken the liberty
of letting you use mine.
Yeah, thanks.
Here, business boss.
Let's just have a look here.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, ho,
with a resume like this,
you should be the one
hiring a driver.
[laughs]
Just kidding.
I know it's my resume.
But I see you went
to Northwestern.
You know,
I'm an N.U. man myself.
Go, fighting Westerns.
And it says here you do
a great Rodney Dangerfield
impression.
Give us a taste.
Uh, okay.
"I'm Roger Dangerfield."
[laughs]
No respect, indeed.
Todd, you got the job.
Oh.
Can you believe this weather
we're having?
No, I cannot believe
this weather we're having!
[laughs]
Oh, wow.
We make a great pair.
It's like I'm Miss Daisy,
and you're Minnie Driver.
[lawn mower rattling]
- [phone beeps]
- Hey, I'm bored.
And I think Todd swallowed
a cyanide pill
and might be dead.
Wanna come over
and bang it out?
Appealing as that sounds,
I have lunch plans
with Vincent.
I know that might be hard
for you to hear.
Wait, that guy from the bar
who is actually three boys
stacked on top of each other
under a trench coat?
Well, don't fly into
a jealous rage about it.
Not jealous.
Just reminding you that
you are trying
to have a relationship
with someone who is--
and again, it's bizarre
I should have to point
this out-- three young boys
stacked on top of each other
under a trench coat.
He listens to me.
Okay, okay, but can
you just acknowledge that--
- That you are being jealous?
- Oh, oh!
- [glass shatters]
- Already acknowledged.
- Toodles.
- [phone beeps]
- Look who's not dead.
- Better than not dead.
You are looking at
Mr. Peanutbutter's new driver.
You're his driver?
That's perfect.
Now you can infiltrate
Mr. Peanutbutter's inner circle.
I don't know, BoJack.
Sure, you'll act
all friendly,
gain his trust,
chauffer him around
on his little errands
to the groomer and whatnot,
but all the while,
you'll be studying him,
scouring out his weaknesses,
biding your time
till we're ready to strike.
And once you zero in
on his Achilles' heel,
we will take... him... down.
Hooray. Betrayal.
[warbling]
Oh, man. Oh, man.
- Keep it cool, Todd.
- Hey, pal.
If you're making
small talk up there,
how about sending
a little my way?
Um... can you believe
this weather we're having?
No, I cannot believe
this weather we're having!
[doorbell rings, horse neighs]
Hey, weren't you supposed
to be here
like a half hour ago?
Yeah, I've just been
sitting in my car.
[chuckles]
Listen, I was looking
over my notes,
and I think I have enough
to go write the book,
so...
I'm just going to do that.
You don't want
to interview me anymore?
But don't you want to know
what my Rosebud is?
You told me repeatedly
it was the nudie magazine
your uncle showed you
with the three-nippled woman.
- Who was she?
- I got it all.
Oh, okay.
Well, I'll see you
around though, right?
Yeah.
I, um--
Why did you have to make
things weird, BoJack?
[car door opens, closes]
I made things weird?
[Mr. Peanutbutter] So if you see anything
you know we need,
like this biscuit warmer,
you just run the laser
over the barcode,
- and kablamsky!
- [beep]
It goes in the registry.
And that way, everybody knows
what I want.
- And I know what I want.
- Uh...
Which is what everyone wants.
And it's really clear,
and nobody's confused
about anything.
Am I crazy,
or are you not into this?
No, I am. It's just--
[sighs]
The big wedding in Nantucket,
all these presents--
I'm so overwhelmed,
I can barely consider
whether I want or need
a biscuit warmer,
which I think is how people
end up with biscuit warmers.
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Close your eyes.
Come on.
Okay, picture
our lives together.
It's a cold Sunday morning
a bunch of years from now.
Maybe robots have taken over,
maybe they haven't.
I don't know.
It's the future.
This story isn't about that.
The important thing is
it's Sunday morning.
I brought you the paper,
fetched your slippers.
You come into the kitchen--
Can you smell biscuits?
- Yes.
- So can I.
- Are they warm?
- Yeah.
Well, that's all
a biscuit warmer's for.
Look, if marriage
stresses you out,
we don't have to get married.
It's not the marriage.
It's the wedding
and the year of build-up.
So forget all that.
I've done
the whole big wedding thing.
I don't need to do it again.
Let's do something
small and casual
right here in town
next month.
Honestly,
that would be amazing.
But we'd have to cancel
the doves,
and we wouldn't be able
to send out
those fancy invitations
you liked.
Those doves were being
jerks anyway.
And invitations--
They're just a scam
made up by the Post Office
to keep tabs on us.
Post Office.
- [growls]
- Settle down, boy.
[Todd] And then we talked about
his favorite Smash Mouth CDs.
[crunching]
And-- Oh, oh.
And then that led to a whole
conversations about sticks.
Oh, and let me tell you,
Mr. Peanutbutter has got some
serious opinions about sticks.
Why are you telling me this?
What? You said
you wanted every detail.
Did I mention
he got a new bandana?
Give me something
I can use
to make them call off
their wedding.
Oh, yeah.
Did I not tell you?
They called off their wedding.
What? Thank God!
Oh, the universe makes sense.
They decided against
a big destination wedding,
so they're doing it here
- sometime next month.
- What?
I guess saying
they called it off
is probably not right.
[groans]
[ominous music]
Hey, what's this?
Oh, yes,
I got jury duty,
but I can't worry
about that right now.
That is a problem for
Friday BoJack.
Now think, Todd.
Gotta have something I can use
sloshing around in that
pot-infused Jell-O shot
- you call a brain.
- Let's see.
Mr. Peanutbutter likes having
his tummy scratched,
and Diane's family
is from Vietnam,
which is where Vietnamese food
comes from,
and since that goes
in your tummy--
Okay, stop thinking.
Just give me raw data.
What's happening this week?
Well, the circus
is in town.
Congress is going to vote
on the new Education Bill--
With Mr. Peanutbutter!
What's happening
with Mr. Peanutbutter?
Well, I'm taking
Diane and him
to the bank on Thursday.
I can use that.
I can actually use that.
I don't know if I'm up
for staging
a bank robbery, BoJack.
Oh, come on, character
actress Margo Martindale.
They say that there are
no good parts
for women over 50.
I want to stick an AK-47
in your hand
and prove them wrong.
I do tire of the limitations
of stage, film,
and television.
You might as well perform
in a cage, am I right?
This is guerilla theater--
No stage, no script, no net.
It's the kind of work
we talked about
doing that night
in the desert.
Don't tell me we left
those dreams in the sweat lodge.
- Hell, I'll do it.
- [dishes clatter]
And that little boy
never found his mother.
Hey, guys.
BoJack Horseman?
Oh. Hi.
What a weird coincidence.
I did not know
you would be here today.
How are... things?
Things are good.
You?
Things good with you?
Hands behind your head,
everybody.
Nobody moves,
nobody gets shot.
- [gasps]
- What an unfortunate surprise.
Well, well,
isn't that a pretty ring?
- [gasps]
- [coughs] This one.
Well, well,
isn't that a pretty ring?
I'll take it.
But it's
my engagement ring.
Give it to her, Diane.
- It's just a ring.
- Just a ring?
That ring is a symbol
of your love.
If you don't care
about the ring,
it really makes me wonder
if you care about
the woman wearing it.
That terrifying bank robber
is making
some very cogent points.
No, Mr. Peanutbutter's right.
If the ring is
just a symbol for love,
why would I need a symbol
when I have the real thing
right here?
Yeah, we don't need rings,
we have each other.
Hey, why are we even waiting
a month to get married?
If anything, this bank robbery
is reminding me
that life is short.
We should get married
even sooner!
[softly]
No...
What do you mean sooner?
Why not this weekend?
We could get married Saturday.
Am I crazy?
[softly]
Yes. Don't do it.
- Oh, keep the damn thing.
- Aw.
[applause]
Okay.
Saturday it is.
What the hell
just happened?
Something truly beauti--
Aah!
- Oh.
- Get your hands off me!
- [Taser crackles]
- Uh-oh.
[landing blows]
[laughs]
Long story short,
Erica did have to lose
the foot,
but she gained a friend.
Sorry, kind of went off
on a tangent there.
Diane and I
wanna thank you all
for coming to our
impromptu rehearsal dinner,
even though
we did not actually have time
- to organize a rehearsal.
- Or a dinner.
But there is an open bar...
[cheers and applause]
which you are
all welcome to partake in
as soon as I finish
this toast,
which I will be doing right...
after one more quick anecdote.
- [guests groan]
- It was winter in Prague,
and the consumption hung low
in the air.
Well, the bank thing
was a dud.
Thanks a lot, Todd.
Well, you win some,
you lose some.
It's like Vincent always says--
- "Oopsy."
- Vincent?
Yeah,
Princess Carolyn's boyfriend.
We've hung out
a couple times.
- What are you ta--
- That dude is funny.
You know he's not
a person, right?
Look, I don't want to get
in the middle
of your whole thing
with Princess Carolyn.
It's not about that.
I just don't understand
why nobody else
seems to notice
that she is dating a man
who is clearly
three little boys
doing the thing
from The Little Rascals.
Oh, that reminds me
of another funny story.
[clinks glass]
If I could say a few words?
BoJack Horseman.
Take the mic.
Spin us a yarn.
Mr. Peanutbutter, Diane.
Since I am friends
with both of you
- and have no ulterior motives...
- Mm-hmm.
I would like to offer
my restaurant
as a venue for your wedding.
Wow! Really?
I don't know.
That's too generous.
Hey, don't look a horse's gift
in the mouth, right?
[laughter]
I get it.
Like the song.
That's not a song.
All right, everyone.
That's it for the toasts.
Enjoy yourselves
and each other.
[dance music plays]
This is perfect.
Now that the wedding's
at my restaurant,
we have
the home field advantage.
Perfect for sabotage.
BoJack,
I need to thank you.
You calling me to the bar
the other night
turned out to be
the best thing
that ever happened to me.
- I think I'm in love.
- Okay.
This "person"
you're in love with--
Have you seen him
without his trench coat on?
I don't understand why
you can't be happy for me.
He's a good boyfriend.
I actually think
you and Vincent
would really hit it off
if you gave him a chance.
You should spend some
one-on-one time with him.
You mean one-on-three time?
Because
there are three of him.
We get it.
You don't like him.
I'm actually not sure
you do get it.
- [unzips]
- I know what's been going on.
Ah!
I wasn't gonna pee.
I was just taking
my penis out.
You've been driving me around,
but there was something else
happening the whole time.
I see it now.
What are you
talking about?
You weren't just working
as my driver, Todd.
You were becoming my friend.
Oh, yeah.
That was happening.
Well, I could use a friend
right about now.
There's something I really
gotta get off my chest,
and if it got out, it could
destroy the whole wedding.
No, I'm not great
with sensitive information.
I don't know if I'm ready
to get married again.
Don't get me wrong.
I love Diane so much.
I didn't have any doubts
until I realized
she had doubts.
Then I figured
she's smarter than I am.
Maybe she knows things
I don't.
You are kind of unloading
a lot of sensitive information here.
Sure, I think I'm ready
to commit to Diane,
but I can't even commit
to my favorite type of stick.
Yes, today, it's short
and knobby, but tomorrow?
Well, sure, Diane is short,
but I don't know about knobby.
The last thing I want to do
is hurt Diane,
but I keep having this dream
where she's gone.
There's no break-up,
no tragedy.
She's just gone, and my life
continues without her.
And it terrifies me
to say this,
but in the dream I feel...
relief.
Hey, thanks for listening
to all this.
You're
a really good friend, Todd.
[groans]
Since you weren't able
to give me any useful intel,
I had to offer up
my restaurant,
but now, we're on my turf.
Time for operation "I don't."
Yeah, sounds good.
You know, with my knack
for coming up with plans
and your ability
to hear them
without contributing
more than three words
at a time,
we make a pretty good team,
don't we, Todd?
- You said it.
- See?
[news theme playing]
[newsman] Beloved character actress
Margo Martindale
is in police custody tonight
for her role in
a failed bank robbery.
Margo Martindale?
But first,
pizza for breakfast?
The answer might surprise you.
I know her, but how?
Wait.
She was
at the convenience store
the night I bought
that video game
and ruined my rock opera.
She's the one who asked me
to hand her that tape
from the 10¢ bin.
[gasps] That means
Margo Martindale likes tapes!
And a tape is something
you listen to,
but tape is also
a sticky thing
you can use to seal boxes.
Boxes is
what cereal comes in.
What does it all mean?
Am I just grasping
at straws?
Wait.
Straws-- That's it.
Straws are used
to drink soda or water,
and plants need water.
And BoJack used Margo Martindale
as a plant
at the bank
and the convenience store,
which means--
Ugh!
BoJack hired Margo Martindale
to make me find
that video game
so he could kill
my rock opera!
Aw, dude.
- Rise and shine, Todd.
- I didn't sleep.
Well, we're down to the wire,
but we still got
one more day to figure out
how to stop this wedding,
and I can't afford to waste
one second, so let's get--
Oh, shit.
Forgot about jury duty.
Damn you, Tuesday BoJack.
- And so, you saw the defendant.
- Yes.
That man, the defendant--
You saw him?
Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up.
- That's correct.
- The defendant was seen by you.
Sweet Jesus.
Some of us have weddings
to ruin.
Yes.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
I'm sorry. I misspoke.
A lot of further questions.
[groans]
The jury finds the defendant
not guilty on all charges.
[murmuring]
We did the right thing today,
BoJack.
But you know who
the real winner is?
- Justice.
- Mr. Peanutbutter.
[sighs]
BoJack.
There's my superstar.
- How are you?
- Amazing!
This has been
the role of a lifetime.
I think they're gonna
send me up to Lompoc,
and when I get there,
I'm gonna find
the meanest, hardest queen bitch
of the yard,
and I'm going to bite
her finger off.
[laughs] That'll show everyone
I'm crazy,
and you don't mess
with crazy.
Plus, free finger.
Oh, here I am blabbering
on about my plans.
Did you ever stop
that wedding?
It's actually happening
right now.
I ran out of time.
I never understood why
it was so important to keep
those two apart.
I was just trying to be
a good friend
in my own
shitty, ass-backwards way.
Diane deserves the best.
She's smart
and kind and beautiful,
and it's gonna be
mostly synonyms from here on
if I keep going,
and I'm in love with her.
Tell her that, BoJack.
You don't need kooky schemes
or nutty capers.
Just go to her
and speak from your heart.
Then find the biggest person
at the wedding
and bite his finger off!
You're right, partly.
I've gotta tell her
how I feel.
Okay, I'm gonna do it.
Good luck with
your finger thing.
[tires screech]
[car alarm chirps]
Todd, thank God you're here!
Did I miss it?
Is it too late?
Dude. I'm done with this.
No. No.
Mr. Peanutbutter's
been nice to me.
Mr. Peanutbutter
is nice to everybody.
That's what makes him
so stupid.
No, I'm stupid.
But even I know
that the only reason
you're doing this is because
you're in love with Diane.
Yes, that's right.
And I'm here to finally
tell her how I feel.
BoJack,
she knows how you feel.
How?
I barely just realized--
Hey, man,
she made her choice.
Look around.
This day is not about you, okay?
So maybe you should
just stop trying
to mess
with other people's lives.
[Diane] I never thought I wanted
to get married.
It's so weird,
this idea of dedicating
yourself to something
for the rest of your life.
Like, how could you know,
right?
But then I realized it's okay
to not know everything.
And some things take
a leap of faith.
Mr. Peanutbutter, I want
to take that leap with you.
By the power vested in me
by one of those dumb websites,
I now pronounce you married.
Go ahead.
Kiss, you lovesick dummies.
[kissing]
[cheers and applause]
♪ Ow! ♪
♪♪
♪ Mmm-yeah ♪
♪ I used to think maybe-- ♪
Hey, Todd. Todd.
Thanks for hearing me out
the other night.
I'm really glad I went
through with this.
This is the happiest day
of my life.
Always happy
to be of service.
Oh, and, um,
I got you something.
Todd Chavez?
Hey.
That name's my name.
What's "PB Livin'"?
My film production company.
Read your title.
"Executive Vice President
of West Coast Operations."
Whoa! Does that mean
I control the waves?
No, it means
you're my assistant.
You've got a big future
ahead of you,
and I don't want you
to waste any time looking back.
So I got all my cars' mirrors
taken off.
Isn't that kind of dangerous?
What do I care?
I'm not driving.
Hey, BoJack.
Thanks for coming.
I wasn't sure
you were gonna make it.
Wouldn't have missed it
for the world.
You're a good friend.
I'm really glad to know you.
- Mwah.
- Sorry that I--
If I made things weird.
They weren't that weird.
- Oh.
- [Mr. Peanutbutter] Diane, honey?
Oh, I gotta go
dance with my husband.
[squeals]
I'm married!
[giggles]
Hi.
So you're the quote-unquote
person, singular,
that everyone's so crazy about.
What have you got figured out
that I don't?
Um, adult stuff.
Yeah, I'm not seeing it.
But that doesn't matter.
Not everything's about me.
And maybe I am
a little jealous.
Not because I actually want to
date Princess Carolyn anymore,
but just because I don't like
the idea that I can't.
I guess I just assumed
I always could.
But I made
a lot of bad decisions.
Not just with her.
With... [sighs]
with everyone, really.
You know,
Princess Carolyn was right.
- You are a good listener.
- Thanks.
You know, sometimes I feel
like I was born with a leak,
and any goodness I started
with just slowly
spilled out of me,
and now it's all gone.
And I'll never get it
back in me.
It's too late.
Life is a series of
closing doors, isn't it?
Don't be sad.
Good horsey.
♪ ♪
That actually feels
kind of nice.
♪ Back in the '90s ♪
♪ I was in a very famous TV show ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ I'm BoJack the horse ♪
- ♪ BoJack ♪
♪ BoJack the horse ♪
♪ Don't act like you don't know ♪
♪ ♪
♪ And I'm trying to hold on to my past ♪
♪ It's been so long ♪
♪ I don't think I'm gonna last ♪
♪ I guess I'll just try ♪
♪ And make you understand ♪
♪ That I'm more horse than a man ♪
♪ Or I'm more man than a horse ♪
♪ BoJack ♪
Boxer versus raptor.
♪ Na na na na na na na na ♪