We're very different,
but I think that we bring out
the best in each other.
It's like you're chocolate
and I'm Mr. Peanutbutter.
Shut up and kiss me,
you silly goof.
- Cut!
- [buzzer sounds]
Welcome back
to Excess Hollywoo.
I'm A Ryan Seacrest Type,
and I'm visiting the set
of Mr. Peanutbutter's Hollywoo Heist.
I'm thrilled to be talking
to the star of the film,
BoJack Horseman, and his
real life inspiration,
Mr. Peanutbutter.
Am I an inspiration?
Well, that depends
on how you define--
- Wait a minute. Yes, I am.
- Ugh.
You know, I'm just over
the moon to be producing
this movie
about my daring exploit.
- Yes, your daring exploit.
- Yes.
It's such a treat to be
shooting in my very own casa.
And it's an even sweeter treat
to be played by my good amigo--
dare I say best amigo?
- You "daren't."
- We're so in tune.
We even finish each other's...
sentences.
Sometimes it doesn't happen.
- It never--
- Happens.
Ah, see?
I'm inside him.
BoJack, you haven't worked
in quite some time.
In fact,
I thought you were dead.
You must be so grateful to be
working again and also alive,
which, again,
I thought you were not.
How did you get involved
with this?
Well--
You want me to play
Mr. Peanutbutter
in the story he stole from me?
I stole the D,
and then he stole
my stealing of it.
That makes him an idea thief,
which is much less cool
than a thief thief,
which is what I am
and what he also is.
You know what might help?
If you think about this
like a professional
instead of a big titty baby.
This movie is
a huge opportunity.
Quentin Tarantulino is known
for revitalizing dead careers.
This could do for you
what Reservoir Dogs
did for Rin Tin Tin.
But isn't there
any other part?
I could play myself.
No, BoJack's already being
played by Wallace Shawn.
What? The short guy
from The Princess Bride
who says "inconceivable"?
- Why Wallace Shawn?
- BoJack Horseman?
I don't want to play
that boob.
I'm trying to help
you out, Wally.
You're the one who keeps
buying expensive Rothkos.
I have a disease.
Would you tell an alcoholic
to stop buying alcohol?
You know,
Black and Blue Number 7's
going up for auction next week.
Fine.
I'll do the dumb movie.
But if you find me in a bathtub
with open wrists tomorrow
and the words "I hate my agent"
smeared across the walls
in blood, you'll know why.
So obviously I'm thrilled
to be here, just thrilled.
[funky electronic music]
♪ ♪
Cast and crew only.
I know you're
just doing your job,
but I live here, and the crew
has been here since 3:00 a.m.,
so I'm a little tired.
Cast and crew only.
Hey, stranger.
Haven't really seen you
since the wedding.
Kind of feels like we're
coming back to school
- after summer vacation.
- Yeah.
I'll see you at the pep rally.
Hope we don't get Mrs. Kirkman
for trig this year.
Yeah, well, I hope
the cheerleaders don't stuff me
in a locker and write
"virgin slut" on my forehead,
and then when I ask how
I could be both a virgin
and a slut,
they make me eat a lipstick.
Uh...
So what have you been up to
these last couple months?
Well, I've been pretty busy.
Met a girl at Soho House.
- Was she your waitress?
- Yes.
Then I met a girl at Mastro's.
- Was she also your waitress?
- Yes.
Then I met a girl
at P.F. Chang's.
Let me guess.
She was your--
A hooker, yes,
but what she really wants to do
- is wait tables.
- [laughs]
Well, I, for one,
would love to meet
the aspiring food-service worker
who finally gets you
to settle down.
What?
Why would I want to settle down?
I'm 50.
- Yeah, anyway...
- So I'm sending the first draft
of the book to Pinky
this afternoon.
- What? It's done?
- Not yet. Almost.
I'm excited for you to read it,
but I'm also
cripplingly nervous.
I actually kind of feel
like throwing up,
but I can't throw up because
I haven't had anything to eat
because this lady won't let me
in my own kitchen.
Cast and crew only.
Listen, if reading a book
you wrote is anywhere near
as great as it is
to actually spend time with you,
I'm sure
it's gonna be wonderful.
Having said that,
what do I know about books?
I'm just a dumb actor.
I'm here with Hollywoo darling
Naomi Watts.
Tell me, what attracted you
to the role of Diane?
I just keep getting
pigeonholed
as these complex characters
in highly acclaimed movies.
For once, I would just love
to phone it in
and play a two-dimensional girl
in a rom com
with no inner life of her own.
That's kind of the reason
I got into this business.
Ha ha!
You said words.
Now, is it true you stay
in character between takes?
Oh, we all do.
The director insists upon it.
He even has everyone
calling me Diane
to help me get
in the headspace.
It's been great.
Diane, looking good.
- Um, thanks.
- Ugh, not you.
I was talking to Diane.
Oh, thank you.
Now, where's my peanut butter?
Right over here, Q.
No, I'm looking
for peanut butter.
Oh, you mean BoJack?
If I wanted BoJack,
I would call BoJack.
Did someone call for BoJack?
It really cuts
down on confusion.
Ah, show business,
the great equalizer.
Is that what it is?
Todd, spritz me.
- Spritzing.
- Mm, mm, mm.
Well spritzed.
Have you ever been
on a movie set before?
No, sir, Mr. Peanutbutter.
Please, Mr. Peanutbutter
was my father's name.
- Uh--
- And it's also my name!
[buzzer sounds]
Ooh, speaking
of Mr. Peanutbutter,
I'll be back
in a jiff, skippy.
Keep that air spritzed for me.
Aloha, kemosabe.
Hey, allow me to put
on my producer hat
and produce you
just for one second here.
I have a few notes
on how you're playing me.
Let's see.
[humming]
Problems, problems, problems,
ah, here we go.
I find it really troubling
that my movie self
is wearing a crew neck T-shirt.
[laughs]
I only wear V-necks.
You see the problem.
- I do not.
- I just think if we're telling
the story, we should tell it
how it really happened.
Yeah, this whole story
isn't how it really happened.
Right...
because of the shirts.
Because I'm the one
who stole the D.
I'm the real hero here.
My life is full
of exciting adventures.
I should write a book.
Oh, wait.
I did.
Suck on that, society.
Hey, you're in a mood.
Perhaps the tightness
of that crew neck
is cutting off circulation
to the brain?
Let me talk to Donna
in wardrobe.
We're gonna fix this, buddy.
Donna!
What are you doing?
I'm just trying to get inside
my character, which is you.
Is this how we move our arms?
We're so weird.
Is this really necessary?
That's not what I sound like.
That's not mut
mi sound mike.
Hey, what's it been like
since we got married?
Is it everything we dreamed
of since we were little?
When I was little,
I dreamed of getting
a MacArthur grant for my 'zine
about how all the girls
at school were bitches.
- Oh.
- Look, the wedding was great.
But that's not real life.
I mean,
I guess I got a happy ending,
but every happy ending
has the day after
the happy ending, right?
And the day after that.
So the wedding was so much fun.
It was the happiest day
of my life.
But, you know,
what does that say
about all the days
I have left?
Whoa.
We're such a Zoe.
Oh, Todd, glad you're here.
Hold this.
Todd, my jacket
is on the floor.
You're supposed to hold
the jacket
so it doesn't go on the floor.
Hey, sorry, BoJack--
I mean, uh, Mr. Peanutbutter.
But I work
for Mr. Peanutbutter now.
- I mean, uh, Mr. Peanutbutter.
- Ugh.
I can't believe
I'm on a movie set, you know?
I mean, this is my first chance
to work on something big
since my rock opera
fell apart.
Man, I really messed up
that huge career opportunity
all on my own, didn't I?
Uh...
Nothing sabotaged me one bit.
Yep.
You said it.
Well, see you later.
[indistinct chatter]
Where can I grab a nosh?
Oh, craft services
is in the kitchen.
Up the driveway, through
the living room, make a left.
- Can't miss it.
- I'm gonna grab a quick bite.
Don't do anything stupid
while I'm gone.
Okay, fellas, here's the thing
about the story.
I don't buy it.
It's like something's missing,
but I can't put
any of my fingers on it.
Um, maybe once
we add the music--
The music?
Are you kidding me?
Music?
You're fired.
What dumb shit brought
this dumb shit?
Okay, you're fired too.
Oh, okay.
Anyone else
got any bright ideas?
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Hey, maybe it make it
more Diane-y?
- Um, excuse me?
- I don't know.
This is probably stupid,
but the whole story's
about how this guy's
in love with this lady, right?
But we don't even know
who she is or what she wants.
I mean, maybe give her
more lines or words
or, I don't know,
feelings or whatever?
What?
He's new.
He doesn't know the rules.
Forgive him, mighty Caesar.
Yes. Yeah.
I love you.
Who is this kid?
You're a genius.
- I'm gonna kiss your face.
- What?
Oh!
[laughs]
Come back to my web.
Let's talk
about Diane's feelings
and make this baby sing.
Hey, Todd, talk to him
about the wardrobe,
specifically the top half
of the wardrobe,
specifically the shirt part
of the top half of the wardrobe,
specifically the neck part of
the shirt part of the wardrobe.
[cell phone rings]
Ugh.
What now?
I'm sick
of this dog and pony show.
The movie is dumb.
Mr. Peanutbutter is annoying
the shit out of me,
and there's too much honeydew
in the fruit bowl.
Blech. Honeydew
is garbage fruit.
Also, why is BoJack
being played by an old, nebbishy
five-foot-tall bald guy?
Is that how the world sees me?
Oh, I see.
So I can play
Vanya on 42nd Street,
but I'm not a deft-enough talent
to capture the essence
of the elusive
BoJack Horseman.
So sorry to offend you, sir.
I'm just glad my book's
coming out soon
so people will get
an opportunity to see
the real BoJack Horseman.
Oh, are you coming out
with a book?
You never mentioned it.
Plus,
Todd's being super weird.
I think he's onto me.
Onto you in regards to what?
Oh, right, I didn't tell you.
I sabotaged his rock opera
by getting him readdicted
to a video game because
I didn't want him to move out.
Jesus Christ, BoJack.
Anyway, I think he knows
and might be plotting
to sabotage me back.
Why is it that 90%
of our conversations
these days revolve around
plotting sabotages?
Are you saying I should
plot a countersabotage?
No, no more plotting.
Just be a good soldier
and do your job.
Nobody is out to get you.
[cell phone beeps]
Have you seen the new draft?
They took it all off you
and put it on me.
What?
Apparently some dickweed
named Todd
decided I should be
three-dimensional
and you should have no lines.
Ugh. Isn't this town sick
of creating
three-dimensional roles
for women?
This happens to me
all the time!
A.O. Scott is sick of talking
about how brilliant I am.
Todd.
I guess
what I've been saying
for the last
seven uninterrupted minutes is,
how can I forgive my father
if I can't forgive myself?
True dat.
But none of that matters,
because we bring out
the best in each other.
I'm the chocolate,
and you're Mr. Peanutbutter!
- True dat.
- Mwah!
Cut!
Amazing.
This is the movie
that I wanted to make.
This is gonna be great.
- Oh, my God, I'm so--
- Ugh, what kind of idiot
puts food on top of a hill?
Hey, so I guess now that
the movie's all about Diane,
I really need to dig deep
and get to know the real you.
So let's talk and talk
and talk until I am you
and you are nothing
but a hollowed-out husk
of your former self and every
thought and every feeling
you ever had belongs to me
and me alone.
So do we like Sprite,
or are we more of a 7-Up girl?
Uh, that all sounds great.
But, you know, the person
you should really be talking to
is that guy.
- Yeah, okay, I'm done.
- Diane loves talking to him.
They have great rapport.
In fact, Diane could spend
all day talking to him
and never talk to me again.
Oh, I get it, because Diane
doesn't talk to Diane.
- Diane talks to--
- Anybody else.
Hey, Todd,
remember that time
when you wouldn't clean
up your shit?
That was hilarious.
- We've had some good times.
- Oh. Hi.
So I was thinking,
I have some...
[sighs] pretty sloppy seconds
left over from P.F. Chang's
in the fridge, and I don't think
that I want it anymore.
Maybe tonight you could eat it.
Friendly gesture
because we're friends.
- Uh...
- Oh-oh, there's my guy.
I heard you had a few more
thoughts about the script.
I do.
I was just thinking, what if
we made the BoJack character
into a real shithead?
- Is that really necessary?
- I don't think it's necessary.
Yeah, let's-- Let's make him
be a real selfish asshole
so the audience has someone
to root against.
You're probably right.
Let's take another swing
at the script
and give BoJack more to do.
Now, when you say,
"Give BoJack more to do"--
Not now, Mr. Peanutbutter.
And also,
now that I'm thinking about it,
why does the movie
have to take place on Earth?
You are blowing my head.
- I hope you like Oscars.
- Honeydew?
More like,
"Honey, do I enjoy eating it?
Yes, I do." Right?
Not right, and I would love to
go through all the reasons why,
but I've got bigger concerns
right now.
- Honeydew, go on.
- Did you notice
that the Mr. Peanutbutter part
has been cut in half?
- What is happening to our movie?
- I thought you hated the movie.
Yeah, I do, but if I'm
gonna be in a dumb movie
I hate that makes no sense,
I should at least
be the star of it.
Look, I agree that this movie
has really lost its way.
I mean, first of all,
why would Mr. Peanutbutter
wear a crew neck T-shirt?
And second of all, uh...
It's just the shirt,
isn't it?
It doesn't make sense.
I'm a V-neck man.
A V you can put
your sunglasses in.
Can you do
that with a crew neck?
Because I'd like
to see you tr--
Whoa.
[groaning]
Bagel.
Thanks so much for running
this scene with me.
I have so many lines to learn.
Yeah, well, most of my lines
are, "True dat,"
but I guess it never hurts
to practice.
The citizens of Planet D
want their king back.
But I'm more concerned
with getting my self-esteem back
after being in the shadow
of powerful men for so long.
True dat.
Is it just me,
or is this movie
kind of flying off the rails?
Well, I don't want to overuse
my catchphrase here,
but true dat.
This is so typical.
I just wanted to do something
light and fun
to distract me from the deep
well of sadness that is my life.
You probably
wouldn't understand.
Oh, puh-lease.
I'm so deep down
a well of sadness
that Baby Jessica
is like, "Damn."
Shut up and kiss me,
you miserable goof.
What?
Oh. Okay. Mwah.
Pop this in a drawer.
Huh?
- [glass shatters]
- This is good, baby.
Oh, this is amazing.
Naomi, I haven't felt
like this since--
No, no, shh, shh, shh!
Call me Diane.
Okay, got my bagel.
Now back to work.
Hey, guys.
Hey, guys!
Wow, wow.
So you guys
really hit it off, huh?
That's awesome.
Want to do some hand stuff
in the bathroom
before we go down to set?
You read my mind.
Now, kiss me some sour cream.
Hey, so I finished the book
and sent the draft
to the publishers.
What?
My book is ready?
Let me read it.
Can I read it?
Call Pinky.
He'll probably send you a copy
as soon as he's done with it.
All right!
You hang tight, baby.
I got an instant classic
to read.
Keep the engine running, though,
because if I know me,
this book is gonna give me
a pretty big erection.
Okay, enjoy!
Keep an open mind.
You'll love it.
It's a work in progress.
[telephone rings]
Hello.
Penguin Publishing.
Unless this is that loan shark,
in which case,
Johnny's House of Noodles.
May I interest you
in our bento lunch box?
Pinky, it's me.
Let me read the book.
Give me, give me, give me.
Okay, okay, now,
I should warn you,
it's not quite what we expected,
but it is good.
I'm telling you,
this could really sell.
I might actually get
to see my kids again.
Great.
Send it over.
I'll read it right now.
All right, I sent it,
but just remember--
To set my expectations
sky-high?
- Way ahead of you.
- [cell phone beeps]
All right, book,
let's see what you got.
BoJack, this is you.
One Trick Pony?
"The first time
I met BoJack Horseman,
he was puking cotton candy
off the deck
of his lavish house
in the Hills,
the lights of the city
twinkling below us.
The Make-A-Wish kids
will not soon forget
the time the great
BoJack Horseman
referred to their parents
as 'a bunch of used jizz bags.'
He filled the air with words,
terrified of silence,
as one often is who is smart
enough to recognize
his many personal failings
but unwilling or unable
to take the steps required
to fix them.
Got out of the car,
stepped out toward the coast,
and looked across the water,
and for a moment,
he said nothing."
What the shit was that?
What the shit is this?
It's a phone.
Well, a tiny computer, really.
I mean, amazing
what technology can--
You were supposed
to ghostwrite my memoir,
but instead you wrote
a story about how you spent
six months with me and saw
what a big, dumb loser I am.
Well, I realized
that the best way
to fully capture you,
warts and all--
This isn't warts and all.
It's just warts.
Where's the all?
I come off like a total asshole.
You come off
as complex and deeply troubled
but ultimately sympathetic.
You might be too close
to see that.
There's an entire chapter
about me eating apple fritters.
You did go through
that fritter phase.
Is this book how you see me?
That day we ran errands
together,
I thought that we had
a really good time,
but you just wrote
about how I cried
because the dry cleaner
took my head shot down.
You were very emotional.
They didn't even
replace me with anyone.
Now it's just a faded spot
where my face used to be.
This will actually do wonders
for your career.
Trust me.
I mean, you're just
a dumb actor
who doesn't know anything
about books, right?
- [laughs]
- What?
Remember?
From before?
Oh, I don't think you
understand
what's happening here.
This is not a casual
conversation between friends.
This is your boss
telling his employee
that she did a bad job.
- Try again.
- What?
Start over, but do it right
this time.
Nobody is ever gonna see this.
- Ugh!
- [cell phone dialing]
- [cell phone vibrating]
- Diane?
Hey, Wayne,
you still work for BuzzFeed?
Um, yes.
'Cause I got something
that's gonna get you
a shit-ton of hearts or digs
or smileys
or whatever the hell you measure
your journalism with.
Curses!
My evil plan has been defeated,
but I'll be back.
You haven't heard the last
of Evil Emperor
BoJackitron Horsemaniac.
Oh, no!
You shot a laser at me!
I'm dying.
Oh, no, I'm dead.
And so now
that we've escaped
the evil clutches
of the emperor,
I'm free to assume
my natural form,
an all-knowing floating orb
of light?
True dat.
- Cut, cut.
- [buzzer sounds]
Come on, guys,
this is ridiculous.
Is this even a movie anymore?
Oh, maybe it isn't a movie.
Yeah, maybe it's
an immersive smartphone app
or a 21st-century approach
to 360-degree media envelopment.
Yeah, or maybe it's just,
like, a feeling, you know?
- We've got work to do.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Oh, my God, this is so good.
- Oh, this is gonna be awesome.
Yes!
Go, Todd.
Hello?
Are you just gonna leave me
like this?
Anyone?
Ah!
Oh, good.
You're here.
Oh, hi, BoJack.
This whole day's
been a shit show.
The book turned out
to be a total hatchet job.
The movie's a disaster.
But thank God I have one
good thing in my life,
and that's you.
BoJack, I--
Please let me say this
before I lose my nerve.
I spent 50 years roaming
the countryside
as a wild stallion,
but I am tired of the rodeo,
and I'm finally ready
to saddle up.
BoJack--
I guess what I'm trying
to say is,
this mustang wants to rest
his head in the comforts
of your spacious barn.
Uh, what?
I'm in love with you, Naomi.
BoJack, they fired me
and replaced me
with a ball on a stick.
I'm so sorry.
But look at the bright side.
Now you and I can just hang out
and talk about feelings.
No, but you're not getting it.
Boys never get it.
BoJack, I was in character
as Diane,
and as Diane,
we had a real connection.
But now that I'm off the movie,
I'm Naomi again,
and Naomi is not interested
in BoJack Horseman.
In fact,
she thinks he's kind of gross.
So I didn't fall in love
with Naomi Watts?
No.
You fell in love with Diane.
Naomi what?
Good-bye, BoJack.
Ugh.
See?
Nothing.
What's going on?
Why are they packing up?
Oh, glad you're here.
This is exciting.
Since we last talked,
this film has gone through
- so many permutations.
- So many.
First, we reimagined
the whole film
as an interactive
social-media experience.
Those are the dumbest words
I've ever heard.
I know.
So we realized it was actually
more of a floating
art installation,
but that
didn't feel right either.
We thought,
is it a high-end perfume?
A series of interrelated
fortune cookies?
A hat that if you turn it
upside down, it's a boat?
- No, it's none of those things.
- Exactly.
That's why we finally
settled on this.
Voilà!
What am I looking at?
[Todd] It is a bimonthly curated
box of snacks.
I don't know what that means.
I know.
It's confusing.
Not the bimonthly
that means twice a month,
the bimonthly that
means every other month,
and each time
it's a different box of snacks.
This is the future of cinema.
You guys, finally,
my story has been told.
Okay, that's a wrap, everyone.
[claps hands]
Thanks for making
this box of snacks a reality.
Let's go home.
What the hell happened
to the movie?
Shit, there were snacks here
the whole time?
Not bad.
- Whoa!
- Look, I get it.
You destroyed my big chance
at a comeback
as revenge for what I did
to your rock opera.
Revenge? Oh, that would have
been such a good idea.
Damn it, Todd!
Look, I figured out
what you did,
but I've been trying to put it
behind me and do my job.
So cutting my part down
was not about revenge?
No.
And making BoJack the villain
of your movie
was not a coded statement
of your feelings about me?
No.
Oh, okay, great.
Well, I'm-- I'm glad
we buried the hatchet
and everything's cool.
Uh, actually, you know,
everything is not cool.
You ruined my rock opera
by using character actress
Margo Martindale to trick me
into playing
an addictive video game.
And saying it all together
like that,
it all sounds
kind of ludicrous.
But still, it was something
I cared about,
and what you did
really hurt me.
Oh.
Well, this feels shitty.
You sure you don't want to just
get some revenge real quick--
thump me once in the stones
and then we'll be even?
I got to go.
I've got some artisanal popcorns
to gauge the mouthfeel of.
- Hey, BoJack.
- Yeah?
You want an apple fritter?
Uh, sure.
- Yeah, I bet you would.
- [laughter]
I bet you'd like
an apple fritter.
Yeah, an apple fritter
would be great.
Why? What-- What--
What's happening here?
"Five Shocking Facts
From New BoJack Book"?
No.
No!
Um, everyone,
please turn off your Internet.
It has gone bad.
I repeat,
the Internet has gone foul.
- What a loser.
- I'm glad I'm not that guy.
Give me your phones.
I'm a celebrity.
You have to listen to me.
Look at his deep well
of sadness.
It's hilarious.
Don't look at me.
I'm well-adjusted.
- You all want my life.
- [laughter]
Uh, what the hell?
I know, I know.
But if you just listen for--
You posted your dumb little
book on the Internet.
No, I just leaked
the first couple chapters,
and people are already talking
about it.
This is wildly unprofessional.
Who do you think you are?
I know you're mad,
and you have every right to be,
but you got to read
some of these comments.
People love you.
And they're gonna love you
even more
when they read the rest
of my book.
- Your book?
- Our book.
Nobody is gonna read
that book.
How do you still not get that?
It is never going
to be published.
BoJack, I stand by my work.
This is a really good book.
And if you just give it time,
you'll see.
[sighs]
Maybe you're right.
Really?
No.
You're fired.
♪ Back in the '90s ♪
♪ I was in a very famous TV show ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ I'm BoJack the horse ♪
- ♪ BoJack ♪
♪ BoJack the horse ♪
♪ Don't act like you don't know ♪
♪ ♪
♪ And I'm trying to hold on to my past ♪
♪ It's been so long
I don't think I'm gonna last ♪
♪ I guess I'll just try
And make you understand ♪
♪ That I'm more horse than a man ♪
♪ Or I'm more man than a horse ♪
♪ BoJack ♪
Boxer versus raptor.
♪ Na na na na na na na na ♪