[polite applause]
[male TV host] When we booked you
for this show,
you'd just won the Triple Crown,
but then just this week,
I open up the newspaper,
and look at this...
"Secretariat
Under Investigation."
What am I supposed to do
with that?
Maybe it's
a different Secretariat.
Ha ha ha ha. No,
but seriously, folks,
there is no truth
to these allegations.
I have never bet on
horse racing,
and I certainly did not bet on
my own races.
Although I did bet the network's
gonna give your show
back to Joey Bishop.
O-- ho ho-- kay.
We get letters here on the show,
and one particular letter,
for you, actually, struck
a chord with our producers.
This is from BoJack H.
BoJack is nine years old.
BoJack writes,
"Dear Secretariat,
I am a horse just like you.
I like to watch racing,
and you are my favorite racer."
Smart kid.
"When I grow up,
I want to be just like you,
and I think
I'm on the right track.
Get it? Track,
because horses run on tracks,
and you are a horse,
and I am a horse.
Do you get it? Do you
get my joke about the track?"
Okay, there's
a whole page of this.
Should I write him back
and tell him I get it?
He goes on,
"My question for you is,
I am a good kid,
and I like to play,
and I like to go to school,
but sometimes I get sad.
What do you do
when you get sad?
How do you not be sad?
Sincerely, BoJack."
That's a great letter.
BoJack, when I was your age,
I got sad.
A lot.
I didn't come from
such a great home,
but one day, I started running,
and that seemed to make sense,
so then I just kept running.
BoJack, when you get sad,
you run straight ahead
and you keep running forward,
no matter what.
There are people in your life
who are gonna try to
hold you back, slow you down,
but you don't let them.
Don't you stop running and
don't you ever look behind you.
There's nothing for you
behind you.
All that exists is what's ahead.
[man 1] Good morning, Louisville.
It's August 22nd, 1973.
[man 2] A sad day
for the sport of horse racing.
Secretariat banned for life
from competition.
[man 1] It's a disgrace is what it is.
This is the '70s.
You can't cheat in sports
and get away with it.
[man 2] You know, I think it
just goes to show you,
you can be the fastest runner
in the world,
but you can't outrun the truth.
[wind whooshes]
[man 3] And traffic is jammed today
coming into Louisville.
Looks like some idiot
parked his car on the bridge.
[funky electronic music]
♪ ♪
And the Golden Globe
for Best Comedy or Musical
goes to BoJack Horseman,
my friend,
for his book One Trick Pony.
[woman] This is a first win
for BoJack Horseman
and his first appearance
at the Globe ceremony
since his forced removal
in 1992
after he exchanged blows
with Sir Paul McCartney.
Wow, what an honor.
I have to thank
the Hollywoo Foreign Press.
I feel like I should mention
that my book
was not a comedy or a musical.
Do you guys actually watch
the movies you give awards to?
'Cause I kind of
get the sense that--
Also, my book was not a movie.
You do know that, right?
We're friends.
Anyway, the response to this
book has been incredible.
These last three months
have been really amazing.
You know, a lot of people
said to me,
"You sure you want to
publish this book?
It's pretty personal."
And I said, "If I can make
just one person out there
feel a little less alone,
then it's all worth it."
And they said,
"That's really brave."
And I said, "Well, I'm not one
to call myself brave,
but since you said it,
yeah, I am."
- After-party at my restaurant!
- [cheering, applause]
Why did I say after-party
at my restaurant?
I do not want to throw a party.
It did seem unlike you. I'm
gonna go get some cotton candy.
- You want some?
- No.
- Yes.
- There he is, man of the hour.
- Hello, other grown up.
- Ugh.
Oh, cheer up, dummy.
Your book is a huge success.
Everybody loves you.
You just won a Golden Globe.
If you can't be happy tonight,
maybe you'll
never be happy again.
I'm sorry, is that
supposed to be encouraging?
- Because it's super-bleak.
- Vincent Adultman...
how are things
at the old nine to five?
Good. I went to
the stock market today.
I did a business.
I keep telling him
he works too hard.
Come on, Vincent, let's get away
from the rat race.
Take a cruise someplace
wet and Latin.
I mean, can you imagine
this body in a swimsuit?
- I literally cannot.
- Vincent, let's do a lap.
Have you met Brendan Fraser?
I feel like you two
would love each other.
Whoa. Easy, easy.
I got to hand it to Diane.
This book has been everything
she said it would be.
Yeah, she knows
what she's doing.
How is Diane? I haven't
seen her since...
Well, I haven't seen her
in a while.
Oh, well, the book's
been huge for her, too.
She's practically as famous
as I am now.
- We're like the Brangelinas.
- Well, I'm happy she's happy.
- And how are you?
- Well, it's been really hard--
Erica, is that you? Who
let you out of the burn ward?
- Get over here, you.
- Uhh.
Excuse me. I just have to tell
you how much I love your book.
It's so naked and honest
and revealing.
It is? Uh-oh.
I love the part about
how you became famous
so you could be constantly
surrounded by distraction
and wouldn't have to be
alone with yourself.
I thought that was
a really profound observation.
Oh, yeah, definitely.
So profound.
- Do you want to get out of here?
- What?
Come back to my place,
maybe get a little more naked,
- honest and revealing?
- Oh, no. No, thanks.
- What about you?
- Yeah, okay.
[woman moaning and panting]
[BoJack groans]
- Oh-- Whoa.
- [screams]
Huh.
- Hey, Diane.
- You still friends with BoJack?
Heard you two
were on the outs.
You gonna write another book
about it?
Oh, you looking at
some oranges?
You gonna write a book
about those oranges, huh?
[cell phone vibrates]
- Hello.
- Diane.
Sebastian St. Claire here,
famed billionaire
philanthropist/adventurer.
Please, hold your applause.
- Okay.
- You can applaud a little.
Okay.
I got your number
from Pinky Penguin.
I'm looking for a journalist
to follow me around
for a few months
and document my daring exploits
aiding ravaged communities
and displaced people.
- Ssss.
- Wow, that sounds amazing.
But that's not usually
the kind of thing I write about.
Diane, if you can make people
care about BoJack Horseman,
surely you can make them
care about emaciated orphans
with missing limbs.
We need to wake people up.
Well, I am a morning person.
I hope you mean mourning
with a "u,"
because, Diane,
this is deadly serious.
Oh, yes, of course.
You want to spend
three months in Sudan?
Not just there. We're also
going to Haiti and Thailand
and Uganda and Chechnya.
Can't you do all that in L.A.?
I want to do something
important.
I want to help people
and do good work
and sleep on the ground
and poop in a bucket.
Honey, nobody wants to
poop in a bucket.
Maybe I do. Maybe
I want to poop in a bucket.
If you want to poop in a
bucket, we can get you a bucket.
You don't have to go all the way
the Chechnylavakia.
Am I saying that right?
It's not just
the pooping in a bucket.
I think it might be good for me
to get out of L.A.
for a little bit.
Sweetie, you know I support
you, whatever you want to do,
but you're not gonna find
what you're looking for
in these awful made-up places.
The universe
is a cruel, uncaring void.
The key to being happy
isn't a search for meaning.
It's to just keep yourself busy
with unimportant nonsense,
and eventually, you'll be dead.
Well, I guess
I can keep my options open.
Great.
[whistles gleefully]
Hey, can I ask you something?
Did Vincent seem extra weird
to you last night?
Well, he's still three kids
in a trench coat, so, no.
We're going through a rough
patch. It's hard, you know.
He's works a full time job
at the business factory,
so when he gets home,
he just wants to unwind
by watching R-rated movies.
Ahh, I thought I was ready
for a real adult relationship,
- but--
- [snores]
Enough about me.
BoJack, you are on fire.
Oh, are we talking
about me again?
We have an offer on the table
for you to play the bad guy
in the new James Bond.
- Ehh.
- I agree. Total garbage.
But this, it's a new drama
from the Coen Brothers.
A western about a one-horse town
and you're the horse.
Hello, Oscar. What do you think?
I think now's the time
to finally make "Secretariat."
Really? Now? Aren't you
a little, um, very too old?
You asked me what I wanted
to do. That's what I want.
That's all I've ever wanted,
and if I can't get it now,
then all of this
has been for nothing.
Oh, fish. Of course!
Why would you ever
make things easy for me
when instead you could make
things incredibly difficult?
Laura, clear out
the rest of my day.
I have to push a boulder
up a hill,
and then have it roll over me
time and time again
with no regard
for my well-being.
Attagirl.
All right, Todd. PB Livin'
needs a new project.
Bi-Monthly Curated Box of Snacks
has been an enormous success,
but I got into this game
to make movies,
so let's make a movie.
Well, I got a stack
of great scripts here.
Any one of them
would make a wonderful movie.
Fantastic.
But I also have this other
non-movie-related idea.
Ooh, let's hear
the other idea.
Okay. I was
heading down Wilshire,
and I saw this empty
store front, and I thought,
"You know what
this world needs?"
Edge of my seat over here.
A store where people can buy
Halloween stuff.
Halloween store.
Feel like that's been done.
Yeah, in October,
but how come your never see
a Halloween store in January?
- It's an untapped market.
- Yeah.
A Halloween store
that's open year-round.
- No, no. Just January.
- Brilliant.
That's the kind of idea
that wins Golden Globes.
I actually think the time
is right for "Secretariat,"
so what do you want to play,
like, Secretariat's dad
or his grandfather, maybe like
an elderly witch doctor
who puts a curse on him
or something?
Lenny, look, I know
I'm a little long in the tooth,
but I think that you
more than anyone
would know
not to count out an old pro.
Don't play the ageism card
with me, kid.
I've laid farts that lasted
longer than your entire career.
But Secretariat was dead at 27,
so who we kidding here?
Just set the project up
and give me an audition.
- That's all I ask.
- All right.
You got yourself
a "go" picture, kid.
And by you, I mean me.
And by "go" picture,
I mean I'll make some phone
calls, we'll see what I can do.
And by kid,
I mean middle-aged adult.
[whispers] Shh. No, no, no.
Put it here. Put it here.
- [whispers] Okay, I'll do it.
- Ahem.
- Has this ever happened to you?
- Has what ever happened to me?
- Todd?
- Yes, Mr. Peanutbutter?
What's going on?
Why are you talking like that?
Todd, I just got
a phenomenal idea
for a Halloween costume.
Why don't you and I dash over
to the store right quick
and spend some hard-earned
American money?
Oh, but, Mr. Peanutbutter,
didn't you hear?
It's January, and
the Halloween store won't open
for another nine months.
But I want satisfaction now.
Has this ever happened to you?
Not to anyone ever
at any time.
Ahem. We give you
Halloween in January,
a truly immersive
Halloween experience
for the rest of us.
Halloween in January?
Please elaborate.
Okay, but before I do,
tell the audience.
- Have we ever met before?
- Never.
Well, according to facts,
there's more suicides in January
- than any other month.
- I'm getting pretty close over here.
Also, there's less
Halloween stores. Coincidence?
Wow, I'm convinced.
This store could save lives.
Unbelievable.
When your powers combine...
you are somehow even more stupid
than the sum of your stupids.
- Thank you.
- Go on.
You stop encouraging him
and you stop encouraging him.
The two of you
are playing with fire.
A fire called
Having a Good Idea.
Or maybe
a fire called Friendship.
- Fires aren't called things.
- What about the Chicago fire?
Or Fire Island.
- Or Gabe.
- Who's Gabe?
Just a fire I met once.
Named him Gabe.
- He sounds delightful.
- He was. Good guy.
[groans]
Business, business, business.
Is that all you ever think about?
I don't know.
What's under that coat,
Vincent?
- You need to let me in.
- Not right now.
I have to call
the guy at the office
and take the car to the place.
It's always guys in places
with you.
You know, I thought
I wanted to date a real adult,
but I'm actually
young at heart.
I need to feel the grass
between my toes.
I want to wear jeans.
I want to dance.
- That's baby stuff.
- No, Vincent.
There's more to being an adult
than just work and business
and the tall-person rides at
Disneyland. I want to have fun.
There has to be a difference
between monogamy and monotony.
What's mahumanunny?
Well, clearly we had
a different understanding
of what this was.
I'd like to be an adult about
this, but frankly, I'm hurt.
I think you should just go,
just git. Get out of my life.
Okay.
Could I have another soda?
BoJack, you know
Kelsey Jannings, our director.
I really appreciate you
giving me this opportunity.
Yeah.
Secretariat
was kind of my hero as a kid.
Yeah, he was
a lot of people's hero.
Well, you know, here was a guy
who had everything--
Yeah, I know the story.
I'm the director.
Kelsey, be nice.
She's just cranky because
she's already seen 30 people
read for this today,
and we are all so goddamn sick
of seeing auditions,
so whenever you're ready.
Just jump right in.
Great. Let's get to it.
[stilted] Hey,
ain't you that horse
- that won all them races?
- Not today, ma'am.
Today I'm just a customer
who wants a warm slice of pie.
Can I ask you a question?
When you're out there
on that there racetrack,
- what are you running from?
- You want to know the truth?
Nothing.
Everyone's running
from something, sugar.
No, I'm running from nothing.
I'm terrified of nothing.
People come up to me,
they want my autograph,
they want my picture.
They think they recognize
something in me,
and I want to be that person
they think I am, but I'm not.
They see a greatness in me, and
they mistake it for goodness,
but I... I know
there's nothing there.
As fast as I run,
I can't get way from that.
- Oh.
- Wow.
BoJack, I think I speak
for everyone when I say--
Oh, my God,
Andrew Garfield said yes.
- We have our Secretariat.
- We got Andrew Garfield?
Oh, my God,
it's the best day of my life.
[Lenny] You don't say no
to Spider-Man.
[Kelsey] This movie
is gonna be amazing.
Andrew...
Garfield!
Now, the pills
will give you nightmares--
I mean, just horrifying--
but the malaria
will give you death,
so you're going to want to
take the pills, Diane.
- Uh-huh.
- Hold on.
A mosquito got into my tent.
What do you want?
- [cell phone vibrates]
- Hello?
Diane, it's Princess Carolyn,
BoJack's agent.
Yeah, I know who you are.
I'm the pink cat, the one
who used to date BoJack.
We've met a lot of times.
You came to my wedding.
Listen,
the Turteltaub Company
is making a movie
about Secretariat.
And since you're such an expert,
they want to bring you on board
as a character consultant.
What does that mean?
Oh, it's the cushiest job
in the world.
You sit in a fancy chair
and eat pastries all day.
And then once a week, you say,
"Secretariat wouldn't do that."
I don't know. I've already
been offered this other thing.
And did you know
there are orphans in Sudan--
You take this job, you can buy
all the orphans you want.
No, I don't want to buy them.
Look, if you really
want to help people,
it doesn't hurt to have
a little money in your pocket.
Take the job now,
help the orphans later.
- There's always later.
- Hmm.
Okay, talk it over
with your husband.
I got to go
get my whiskers trimmed.
I run into walls for days,
but I look hot.
- How's the pie here?
- Not good.
Well, I'll take all you got.
Screw it. Throw it in a bowl
with some bourbon
- and bring me a ladle.
- Mm-hmm.
BoJack, we notice you've been
pretty down in the dumps lately,
but we have something that we
think is going to cheer you up.
It's an exciting
new business venture
that's equal parts
new and exciting.
Another one? What happened
to your Halloween store?
- What now?
- Oh, right.
The Halloween store.
We took the floor out
because Mr. Peanutbutter
kept scratching up the hardwood,
and then-- Did we ever get
the new floor installed?
Uh...
Halloween? In January?
What a great ide-- Aah!
[thud]
Anyway, now we're
all about smoodies.
- What?
- Smoodies.
You're saying smoothies,
right? Smoothies.
No. Smoodies.
It's a mood that you drink
like a smoothie.
I don't understand it.
How do you drink a mood?
- Like a smoothie.
- So it is a smoothie.
No, it's a smoodie--
A mood that you drink.
- How do you drink a mood?
- Like a smoothie.
But do you buy it in a store?
What're the physical attributes?
We haven't worked out
all the kinks yet,
but the important thing is
we've gone public,
and we want you to get in on
the ground floor.
See, that's the problem
with all your ideas--
they don't have ground floors.
Finally, a Halloween store
for the rest of-- Aah!
[thud]
[man] Hello.
Anyway,
our launch party's tonight,
- and we'd love it if you came.
- We spared no expense...
that's how confident we are
in our product.
- Your product-- Smoodies.
- Yes.
Wait, did you say smoodies
or smoothies?
Because we only make--
Which one do we make?
I'd like to think
the smoodies make us.
Ahh, I can tell by your tone
that that was something smart.
[hip-hop music]
- Smoodie keychain?
- Smoodie cozy?
-Smoodie bottle opener?
It's a mood that you drink
like a smoothie.
Todd, it is all happening.
Hooray. And you know I don't
throw that word around lightly.
All right. Now we just got to
make sure we focus
and actually follow through
on this.
I'd feel awful
if this great idea fell apart
because we got distracted
by something else,
as we are often wont to do.
Wait, did you say
you feel awful or falafel?
I said, "Feel awful,"
but tell me more
about this falafel idea.
Falafel or fawaffle?
What?
[dance music]
BoJack, isn't this exciting?
Smoodies, right?
Do you even know
what a smoodie is?
I think it's some kind of
an adult onesie.
Whatever it is,
I'm trying new things.
I'm single again,
and I'm loving it.
- Let me repeat--
- Princess Carolyn.
Vincent. Well, you've got
some nerve showing your face.
- I've got half a mind to--
- No, let me talk.
I had a attitude problem,
but then I took a timeout,
and I thought about what I did.
I wanted to be a big man.
But sometimes the biggest thing
a man can do is tell the truth.
And the truth about me is,
I... I--
- Okay, here we go.
- I love you.
- What?
- Oh, Vincent.
Let's go feel grass
between our toes.
- What?
- All right.
You're a better man
than I could ever be.
I wish my boyfriend
was that mature.
- [groans]
- [cell phone vibrates]
- Hello?
- BoJack, it's Kelsey Jannings.
I got some news
about "Secretariat."
- What's up?
- Garfield's out.
He got into
some sort of accident.
An All Hallows' Eve store
in January?
How fiendishly droll.
Aah!
[thud]
Oh, bother.
The clumsy bastard
broke every bone in his body,
and now we got to find
a new lead.
Studio wants to go young,
but I was thinking we'd get
someone a little more
BoJack Horseman.
What? Are you serious?
You're the only one with
enough grit to play the part,
and we can age you down in post,
but I'm gonna tell you now,
not gonna put up with
any woe-is-me bullshit
or diva histrionics.
I get enough of that
from my ex-wife
along with newspaper clippings
about gluten.
God, we get it, Marla.
Gluten.
But if you want to make a movie,
and you're ready to work...
I am. I will.
I can. I do.
Great. You got one month
to get in shape.
You need to lose 50 pounds
and then gain back 20.
- And, BoJack...
- Yeah?
Don't ever call this number.
If I want to talk,
I'll call you.
[cell phone beeps]
- Hey.
Not big on parties, huh?
Nah. I never know what to do
with my hands.
I think I just got cast
in Secretariat.
- That's amazing.
- It's everything I ever wanted.
- Yeah, you seem super-jazzed.
- What do I do now?
Well, that's the problem
with life, right?
Either you know what you want,
and you don't get what you want,
or get what you want, and then
you don't know what you want.
- Well, that's stupid.
- Yeah.
I don't know if this makes you
more or less excited,
but I actually decided to take
a job on the Secretariat movie
as a character consultant.
Wow, so we're gonna be
working together again.
Yeah. I hope
you don't get sick of me.
I don't think
that's gonna happen.
- Is it weird I took this job?
- Why would it be weird?
You literally wrote the book
on Secretariat.
Yeah, I know. I just--
When I first moved to L.A...
I thought I was gonna be doing
really important work.
You know, writing stuff
that makes a difference.
But then you kind of fall into
one thing and then another...
Well, you've got time.
There's always later, right?
Yeah, I guess
there's always later.
Do you remember
the last time I saw you?
You asked me if I thought you
were a good person deep down?
Do I remember that?
Yeah, vaguely.
You caught me off guard.
I didn't know what to say.
Well, do you think
I'm a good person... deep down?
That's the thing. I don't
think I believe in deep down.
I kind of think all you are
is just the things that you do.
- Well, that's depressing.
- [laughs]
For what it's worth,
I think your writing
does make a difference.
Thanks.
I really wanted you
to like me, Diane.
I know.
♪ I know I've dreamed you ♪
♪ A sin and a lie ♪
♪ I have my freedom ♪
♪ But I don't have much time ♪
♪ Let's do some living ♪
♪ After we die ♪
♪ Wild horses ♪
♪ We'll ride them someday ♪
[girl on TV] Sorry we didn't
get you a birthday present.
I got so distracted
by trying to get tickets
to the New Kids On The Block
concert,
I completely lost sight
of what's important.
And I got so swept up in
my campaign for class president,
I forgot why I was running
in the first place.
And I was boy crazy.
Kids, kids,
I don't need a present.
I got everything I need
right here.
[audience] Aww.
- Macaroni.
- Sabrina.
Come here, you goofball.
[applause]
[closing theme music]
[overlapping chatter]
[laughter]
- Aha.
- Whoa.
- Can you make it out to Blake?
- Uh-huh.
Thanks, man.
You're, like, my hero.
Really?
Huh.
♪ All I want to know is ♪
♪ Can you come
A little closer? ♪
♪ The doors are open
The wind is really blowing ♪
♪ The night sky
Is changing overhead ♪
♪ It's not just all physical ♪
♪ I'm the type who won't get
Oh, so critical ♪
♪ So let's
Make things physical ♪
♪ I won't treat you like
You're oh, so typical ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ I won't treat you like
You're typical ♪
♪ I want you close
I want you ♪
♪ I won't treat you like
You're typical ♪
♪ All I wanna get is ♪
♪ A little bit closer ♪
♪ All I wanna know is ♪
♪ Can you come a little closer? ♪
Boxer versus raptor.
♪ Na na na na na na na na na ♪