So I send in the form,
and if my mom wants to meet me too,
-then we meet?
-Yeah.
And if she doesn't want to meet me,
then I get to feel that hot sting
of rejection all over again.
What a fun adventure this all is.
You know what is fun? You coming with me
to my first day on my new show.
"BoJack Horseman
in F.H.B.A. Los Angeles,
starring BoJack Horseman
as 'the Judge.'"
What is F.H.B.A.?
I think it's one of those shows
about Navy sex crimes that have gone cold?
And there may be numbers or something?
Then, they call "the Judge."
I'm just excited to get out of the house.
I've been getting really fidgety
cooped up on that hill.
Like I got tiny little bumps
crawling around
on the inside of my skin, you know?
Totally. Look at this guy,
texting in the middle of the intersection.
You have been judged
to be a shitty driver.
I'm the Judge.
I sentence you to kiss my ass.
Boom!
You got "judged."
It feels good
to be a dramatic actor again.
To make someone laugh
is a craft, to be sure,
but to make someone cry, on purpose,
that is a precious gift.
Hey, I'm Miles, the production intern.
Can I get you anything? Water?
That's so sweet of you.
Actually, that's so his job of him.
-Hey, PA, whose name I already forgot.
-It's Miles, and I'm an intern.
Still not interested. Can you take
my daughter to "video village"?
I wanna make sure she sees me
at my most awesome,
which is with a slightly high angle
to avoid appearance of a double chin.
Note to director.
-Right this way.
-Okay.
-[bell rings]
-[assistant director] Quiet!
-[grunts]
-Rolling!
[announcer]
Previously on F.H.B.A. Los Angeles...
I may be a human rights lawyer,
but those skanks are human wrongs.
I'll tell you the same thing
I tell kids in the cancer ward.
I'm not here to make friends.
I'm here to win and/or cure cancer.
[announcer] Tonight, the girls
return from Booty Boot Camp
and face new judge, BoJack Horseman.
Will BoJack turn the other cheek,
or is this the week
the booties hit the floor?
This is Felicity Huffman's
Booty Academy: Los Angeles!
Um... what's all this then?
[theme music playing]
[gavel raps]
On Booty Academy,
we're here to find out
who's got the right behind
and who's going to be left behind.
BoJack, do you have anything
you'd like to say to the contestants
before we give our verdict?
No, I'm good.
Very well.
Calliope, you are "ready for this jelly."
You can stay another week.
Tasha, our 'anaconda don't want none."
Cover up your bottom and go.
No!
Your booty's been adjudicated!
-[assistant director] Cut!
-[bell rings]
This is bullshit!
-Callin' my manager!
-Remind me what this show is?
-I know, remind me?
-[Tasha] ...my publicist!
Felicity Huffman's Booty Academy.
It was supposed to be
Felicity Huffman's
Future Leaders of America,
but it got retooled a little
by the network.
So are we judging who has the best booty?
Whoa, BoJack, no.
That is so degrading.
So if it's not about their butts,
then why is the other judge Sir Mix-A-Lot?
Because I'm an honest and impartial judge.
And if there's one thing I'm famous for,
it's that I cannot lie.
Yeah, I guess that would be the one thing.
Hey, can we go home now?
Being around all these skinny L.A. ladies
makes me feel like a blob.
Well, I gotta shoot
for, like, ten more hours.
Are you serious?
Apparently, it takes three hours to set up
the "badonka-donka-dobstacle course."
So making TV is like a full-time job?
Then why is it so bad?
I just assumed people weren't trying.
Uh, I don't mean to butt in here,
but shouldn't your daughter be in school?
Shouldn't you be
"Sir Minding-Your-Own-Business-A-Lot"?
I graduated early and took a gap year.
My friend Maryssa is backpacking
through Europe,
but lucky me, I get to hang out
in this butt-infested warehouse.
Oh. All right.
Someone better be checking
the pH levels of that Jacuzzi
because these bitches are basic.
Hey, you wanna explore the back lot?
They got a whole area that was built
to look like downtown Toronto.
That's where they shoot the stuff
set in New York.
Are you allowed to just leave the set?
What are they gonna do? Dock my pay?
I'm an intern. They don't pay me.
I got all the power!
[laughing]
Princess Carolyn,
you are going to love Stilton Acres.
We have a sauna and a tennis court
and a giant hedge maze.
And if you make it all the way through
the maze, you get some sugar water.
And you're gonna love
the Feast of Saint Squeaky.
It's the holiest of all mouse holidays.
We prepare a feast of Swiss--
Because it's the holiest of all cheeses?
Because it was all our ancestors
could carry
when they were trying to escape
for their lives.
Oh-- because it has holes!
-That's very funny.
-Thanks.
I really want you and my parents
to get along.
They can be kind of a lot,
especially around the holidays.
I'm sure I'm going to love them.
And they're gonna love me.
I'm Princess Carolyn!
I'm sure they will too.
But let's wait
until after they love you
to tell them about, you know, Philbert.
Of course. But what about her?
Don't worry. She's on her phone.
Unless Ralph and Princess Carolyn's
secret baby starts to trend,
she won't notice anything we do or say.
-Stefani? Stefani?
-[phone clicking]
-[squishes]
-Whoa.
Katrina!
Just the person I wanted to talk to!
-How's hotel life?
-Marvelous!
Room service, tiny ketchup bottles,
handy list of cable channels.
Now I know why so many people
like being homeless.
-Mr. Peanutbutter, that's not--
-On the phone, darling.
Well, I just found you
the perfect new campaign headquarters.
I'm gonna sign the lease now,
unless you think of a reason
I shouldn't.
Nothing comes to mind.
Great! It's done.
Now, what did you wanna talk to me about?
-I'm dropping out of the race.
-What?!
Woodchuck's a better leader
than I'll ever be.
This election is about bigger things
than just you and Woodchuck.
What is it about then?
It's about hope, and freedom,
and powerful lobbyists
who pay me to elect
a governor I can control
so we can get legislation passed
that allows them to build private prisons
on what are now protected wetlands.
Well, hopefully those evil lobbyists
can find some other puppet
to do their bidding.
Why would you hope that?
I'm done running for governor,
so you're fired.
No hard feelings, right?
You idiot. I will end you!
-Bye, Cruella!
-[Katrina screams]
-[mother] Hello.
-[father] Stefani!
-Hello.
-Oh, darling, you're home.
-Nice to meet you.
-Princess Carolyn!
-Hello.
-I'm Poppy! This is my wife, Mimi.
And this is our son, Sissy.
And this is my wife, Missy.
And the boys,
Tweeds, Nantucket, and Loophole!
Ugh.
It's so wonderful to meet you all!
-Can I get you a cocktail?
-Oh. No, thank you.
-Wine?
-That's all right.
I will consider it a personal affront
if you won't at least have a beer.
-I shouldn't.
-What about a very caffeinated coffee?
-No.
-Raw shellfish?
-Not tonight.
-Cigarette?
-I don't smoke.
-That's okay.
You can just stand around me
while I smoke.
No, I don't want to.
Cocaine, then?
I so appreciate that,
and I hate to be rude,
but I really don't think it's a good idea.
Would you like me to punch you
in the belly real quick
so you remember
what it's like to be alive?
That's a rich person thing.
Oh, I know.
I grew up around rich people.
But I'm actually good,
as far as belly-punchings go.
Well, can I at least offer you a ride
on our private rollercoaster?
Surely, there's no reason
you wouldn't want to do that.
-So if you decline, I will be offended.
-Oh.
Also, not that it's relevant,
but the rollercoaster
is specifically discouraged
for children under five
and pregnant women.
But since you are neither of those,
obviously, there's no reason
you will not want to ride
on our family's really fun rollercoaster.
-Okay, look, the truth is--
-Hey, Dad!
Why don't you tell Princess Carolyn
one of your great golf stories?
-Say, there's an idea.
-Yes!
So here I am with a mashie
when what I need is a niblick.
[all laughing]
Wow, golf. Fore! Am I right?
Yes, that's exactly right. Golf.
[camera shutters clicking]
Californians, this is an endorsement!
My message is simple.
If you want to vote Peanutbutter,
vote Coodchuck-Berkowitz
because a vote for Coodchuck-Berkowitz
is a vote for Peanutbutter.
Uh--
Since Peanutbutter
likes Coodchuck-Berkowitz.
So if you like Coodchuck-Berkowitz,
vote like Mr. Peanutbutter...
-Excuse me--
-...for Woodchuck Coodchuck-Berkowitz.
So if we want to vote for Woodchuck,
we should vote for you?
-No.
-Yes.
-By voting for Woodchuck.
-Thank you, Mr. Peanutbutter.
I look forward to moving past
the political divisiveness
of this campaign
and finally focusing on the issues.
What's with the gorilla feet?
[sighs]
As I've explained before,
my hands were crushed
during the fracking incident.
There were no hand transplants
readily available,
but gorilla feet are somewhat hand-like.
So I am using them temporarily
while my doctors
find me more suitable replacements.
[laughs]
They sure made a monkey out of you, huh?
-[reporters laugh]
-They did no such thing.
Gorillas are apes.
I feel that went pretty well.
Yes, well, thank you
for dropping out of the race.
Rest assured, under my stewardship,
the state will be in good--
-You were gonna say "hands," weren't you?
-Ugh.
So, what's next for us two amigos?
Mr. Peanutbutter,
we don't need your help on the campaign.
We are running virtually unopposed.
I think our team can handle it from here.
Wha-wha-wha-what?
The best way you can help us
is to go back to your regular life
and stay out of politics forever.
So this chapter of my life is over?
Doggy, doggy. What now?
Coochy-coochy-coochy...
Hey, Mom.
You got something in the mail.
Have I received
any gentleman callers today?
I'm expecting a visit
from Corbin Creamerman.
You know what? I'll check.
You could learn a thing or two
from him, Henrietta!
Mm-hmm.
-Hey, where have you been?
-I'll make coffee.
Oh, uh...
well, Miles actually took me
to check out UCLA.
He took me to a party,
and I got to sleep in a dorm room, and...
Wow, look at the time.
That's enough questioning of me,
and where I've been,
and what I've been doing. See ya later!
Hold up.
Did you and that PA hook up last night?
BoJack! We didn't just hook up.
Miles is a really interesting soul,
-and I feel like we connected.
-Oh, boy. Okay. Sit down.
Hollyhock, you are never gonna hear
from that guy again.
Okay, actually, I am,
because when I left his dorm
he said he would,
and I quote, "Definitely text me."
Oh, wow, I didn't realize.
Should we plan the wedding for you
and teenage-boy-you-slept-with
who-said-he-would-definitely-text-you"?
Very funny.
Believe me, I take no pleasure
in telling you this,
-but that kid is never, ever, ever--
-[phone chimes]
-Ooh! BoJack--
-Hollyhock, it is very rude to interrupt.
Now, where was I?
Right. You'll never ever
hear from this guy again.
-But, I--
-Ba-ba-ba!
In fact, if he texts you,
I will do a hundred pushups.
That's how sure I am,
since there is no possible way--
"Had a great time last night. Kilometers."
"Kilometers"?
It's an inside joke between me and Miles.
Not inside enough.
I figured it out and it's dumb.
-[phone chimes]
-He wants to take me to a party tonight.
-Shouldn't you be doing pushups?
-[sighs]
Nope, can't. Impossible.
Anyone who says
they did a pushup is lying.
-[phone chimes]
-That him canceling? Classic move.
No, he wants to spend the day together.
Oh. Well, you wanna
have breakfast first?
I got a box of crullers,
of which one remains.
Nah, I'm good with this coffee.
I'll be home for dinner, though. Bye!
Okay.
Forty-six, 47...
-Ah! I could do this all day.
-[groans]
-[horn honking]
-[gasps, whimpers]
We have gathered in Todd's new apartment
to discuss the future of PB Livin'.
You told me this was an intervention
to get Todd to stop coming up
with awful ideas.
That was a pretense
to get you to show up.
-What?
-It was Todd's idea.
What else you got, Todd?
Well, I got this one thing.
I don't know. It might be pretty dumb.
-You bite your tongue.
-Yes, bite it all the way off!
All your ideas are beyond terrible.
Well, in that case, I guess I must have
"terrible" business instincts.
-You do!
-Because I wanna hear it.
They say "the devil's in the details,"
so let's summon the devil!
Okay, so you know how hard it is
-to get your kids to go to the dentist?
-I don't.
But what if dentists
had a friendlier face?
Ooh!
What if you could take your kids
to a dentist's office
where all the dentists were clowns?
-What?!
-Kids love clowns!
-Do kids love clowns?
-Actually--
Don't they?
Who else would clowns be for?
Because adults don't love clowns.
That is true.
Adults find clowns creepy and off-putting.
So kids must love clowns,
because otherwise,
why would there be clowns?
That is sound logic. Okay.
I want these clown dentists
laughing maniacally
as they drill into the teeth
of America's children, starting yesterday!
As someone who does have children,
I have to say,
a lot of kids
are actually terrified of clowns!
Are they? Hm.
That would have been helpful information
before I committed.
But my word is my bond
and I already said yes, didn't I?
Okay, so do we find dentists
and train them to be clowns,
or do we get clowns
and train them to be dentists?
Why don't we get clowns and dentists
and they can train each other?
Oh, somebody call the police department,
because you are on fire!
[groans] Aw, jeez.
[all chuckling]
And without missing a beat, I say,
"Well, when life gives you lemons,
make an Arnold Palmer."
[all laughing]
It's been so wonderful getting
to know you all these last few days.
We're so happy to have you.
Now, let the festivities begin.
-Sissy, hand out those cat ears.
-Cat ears?
-And this is for you.
-I want those.
See, the feast is about remembering
the ancient tale of a heroic mouse
named Squeaky.
And we always start by wearing cat ears
and singing the song of Squeaky's enemy,
the cat tyrant, King Pusspuss.
Looks like Princess Carolyn
won't need any cat ears to look evil.
-[family laughing]
-[sighs]
[piano music playing]
♪ Look at me, I'm a dumb cat king ♪
♪ I'm an ugly, mean, fat thing ♪
♪ Innocent mice will feel my wrath ♪
♪ I'm a stinky cat
Who never takes a bath ♪
Okay, that's actually a stereotype.
Cats do take baths.
Darling, licking yourself
does not qualify.
[family laughing]
-Aw, come on, it was funny.
-[grunts]
♪ I'm positively evil
I'm nasty and I'm smelly ♪
♪ So I'll take my sword
And stab you in the belly ♪
[Poppy]
Oh! Right in the cat gut!
Hooray!
Sorry, it gets a little graphic.
I really wish you'd told me
your family's holiday was so anti-cat.
It's just an old story about one bad cat.
It's not about every cat.
-Death to all cats!
-Whoo-hoo!
-[Stefani] All right!
-I forgot about that part.
It's kinda like church.
You say the words so many times,
you forget what they mean.
Oh-hh...
-[yelps] Agh!
-Hello, Hollyhock.
[clicks]
Oh, come on. Wait there.
There's a spare bulb in the kitchen.
I've been sitting in that chair
for five hours waiting to do this.
-[crashing]
-Agh, damn it! Son-of-a--! What?
[huffing]
[clicks]
-Hello, Hollyhock.
-What are you trying to do?
I'm trying to keep you out of trouble
with a showman's flair for the dramatic.
I texted you I was gonna be home late.
You don't tell me when
you're home late.
This is my house.
You need to ask permission.
-What? You're not my dads.
-I'm just looking out for you.
You spent four days
with this kid, I'm worried--
There's nothing to worry about!
We like each other.
Yeah, now. But come on, Hollyhock.
[stammers, sighs]
He's a teenage boy
whose job is to be around hot women
in skimpy outfits all day.
You think he's gonna want--
What?
No, I just mean that...
What, you think
I'm not attractive enough for him?
Well, you're the one
who said you were a blob.
-Do you think I'm a blob?
-No.
What kind of person
calls his own daughter a blob?
-You said "blob."
-I said I "felt" like a blob.
Do you think I'm a blob?
I just-- [sighs]
I just think L.A. is a superficial town
and you need to be careful.
Well, Miles likes me just the way I am.
And that's the kind of person
that I want to spend my time with.
Hollyhock, wait. Wait. Wait!
I get it! It's my weight!
Yeah... I'm sorry about all that.
Why didn't you tell me they hate cats?
They don't hate cats.
Now I get why you didn't want
to tell your family about the baby.
Okay, I was a little nervous.
But they'll come around.
Besides, what am I supposed to do?
They're my family.
-And what are me and Philbert?
-[sighs] Oh...
Can't believe she's still pissed.
You shouldn't have called her a "blob."
I'm a blob too! We're both blobs!
How about just as a general rule,
don't ever call a woman a blob?
Never! What if I meet a woman
whose name is Barbara Lob?
And I call her "B" for short. "B. Lob."
Maybe instead of figuring out
the woman blob workaround,
you should just tell Hollyhock
you're sorry.
I still think Miles is up to something.
Why is it so hard for you to believe
someone could genuinely
like your daughter?
Because she's like me!
Okay. Do you think maybe this could be
more about you than it is about her?
Yes, obviously, I have a lot of work
to do on myself. Everyone knows that.
But the important thing right now
is how I can fix things with Hollyhock.
Try to stay on topic, Diane.
Well, an open conversation
about your concerns with--
No, that's too Diane-y.
She'd never buy it was coming from me.
Then why do you want my advice?
I got it. If I can somehow prove to her
what a jerk Miles is,
then she'll have to like me more
by default.
That's the BoJack way.
BoJack, no--!
Oh-- oh...
Ooh, that's... that's nice.
Goldie, how would you like
to advance to the final round?
I would do anything, and I mean, anything.
-So I did it. I had sex with the PA.
-You had sex with him?
That's what you wanted, right?
I just said "seduce" the PA.
Doesn't that mean have sex with him?
No, I just wanted you to,
like, get him all hot and bothered.
-Eh...?
-And ready to sleep with you.
Then once you get him on audiotape
-saying that he would sleep with you...
-What?
...come up with some excuse to get
out of there with virtue intact.
That's a lot of specifics
you just assumed I would know.
Okay, well, the important thing is,
we got him now.
Tell Miles what you told me.
-I had sex with the PA.
-What PA?
I think his name was "Eggberg"?
-What? Not him?
-That's the intern.
-You said "PA."
-Did you think I was a PA? Nice!
Why'd you want her to sleep with me?
Not sleep with.
You told a contestant
you would advance her to the final round
if she slept with a PA?
I said "seduce." There is a distinction.
We make a show about empowering women
and lifting them up,
and you cheapen it
with this coarse vulgarity.
I cannot lie. You disgust me.
This was all a big misunderstanding.
Cover up your bottom and go, BoJack.
You're not fit to judge
anyone's character, or their booties.
So it is about judging booties.
[groans]
-Hey, BoJack.
-Miles.
Don't want me dating your daughter,
you could have told me.
I'm sorry.
Maybe we could've worked out
some sort of deal.
What do you mean?
All right, so I got this screenplay,
and I think it's a really fresh area.
It's about a production intern
who wants to be a writer.
Oh, wow.
I think it could go somewhere
if it got in front of the right person.
So if you have like an agent
or a manager you could give it to,
that would be awesome,
and I would never talk to Hollyhock again.
I promise.
So you were right. He was a dirtbag.
Yeah. I was kinda hoping
I was wrong for once.
If it makes you feel any better,
you were wrong
about all the other parts of this.
Diane, you are so bad
at making people feel better.
Are you gonna tell Hollyhock?
She's a smart girl.
She'll figure it out eventually.
But for now, if she believes someone
can love her for who she really is,
then why would I take that
away from her?
BoJack, you gotta get
one of these massages.
-Oh-hh!
-Okay.
-[Mimi] Goodbye, darling.
-[Sissy] It was good seeing you.
-It was so much fun seeing you both.
-Thank you for hosting us.
It was so nice to get away for the week
and learn all about
your charming little traditions
that didn't freak me out at all. Bye-bye!
Did our little city mouse
have a nice time in the country?
Everything was wonderful.
And your little companion was darling--
for a week.
But I do hope the next one you bring home
knows how to appreciate
a good Feast of Saint Squeaky.
Well, for your information,
there's not gonna be a "next one,"
because...
I love Princess Carolyn and we're having
a baby and I couldn't be happier!
[Mimi] Oh, my God.
Oh, Mr. Peanutbutter, I am so relaxed.
I didn't realize
how much tension I'd built up in my--
Oh, my God! Um...
Mr. Peanutbutter, why is our hotel room
filled with dentist clowns?
Don't be ridiculous, Diane.
They're not all dentist clowns.
Half of them are clown dentists.
Just try to ignore them
and go about your business.
-Okay.
-So, this is the incisor.
Doc, if this is what's incisor,
I'd hate to see what's outsides 'er.
Hyuk, hyuk, hyuk!
-Please try to focus, Dr. Boing-Boing.
-[squirts]
Ugh!
[Tom Jumbo-Grumbo] With former rival
Mr. Peanutbutter's support,
just yesterday,
Woodchuck Coodchuck-Berkowitz
seemed to be unbeatable,
but as a new candidate enters the race,
is Woodchuck also "unbeata-Biel"?
"UnbeataBiel"?
Randy, you wily son of a--
I've missed you, buddy! Bring it in!
"UnbeataBiel"?
[gasps]
I'm tired of these politicians
who are all talk.
California needs a leader
who excels in both comedy and drama
and who is beautiful
in an approachable girl-next-door way,
and who will get all the criminals
off the street
while simultaneously finding a use
for our wetlands.
That's why I'm running for governor.
A candidate you can Jessica-lieve in.
What the--?!
Let's do it together! I'm with me!
Oh-hh! Katrina.
-Gadzooks!
-Not now, Professor Flim-Flam!
Of course,
Katrina would latch onto Jessica
as the beautiful face
of her dangerous agenda.
Well, there's no way
they could beat Woodchuck, right?
No? Because I almost beat him
and I don't even know
what a governor does.
That's true.
Mr. Peanutbutter, you've got to help.
Woodchuck has no idea
what he's up against.
You're right! But are we sure
this is the right thing for us?
If I jump right back into politics,
that's not gonna give me a lot of time
to focus on our burgeoning
clown dentistry business.
[nose beeps]
Then it is definitely
the right thing for us.
[Woodchuck]
This is an abomination.
[aide] It's only till the doctors
find better ones.
They're not even hands!
Well, they're better than feet,
aren't they?
-[beeping]
-What the--?!
-[yelps]
-I'm Dr. Boing-Boing!
And I am Dr. Jennifer Picarello, D.D.S.
We come with a message
from Mr. Peanutbutter.
You can tell Mr. Peanutbutter I don't--
-Ha! Woodchuck!
-What do you want?
You need me, Woodchuck!
You've got brain smarts,
but your sober-minded policy speeches
are no match for the glitz and pizzazz
of a Hollywoo starlet.
Even a relatively low-wattage one
like Jessica Biel.
He's right. California loves making
movie stars governors.
I was married to both Jessica and Katrina.
I know them inside and out.
And I'm not speaking in a sexual way,
although it is also true in a sexual way.
-You gotta let me join the campaign!
-[groans, sighs]
-All right.
-Great! There's no time to lose.
Quick! Get in Dr. Boing-Boing's
dream-powered smile-mobile!
It's been four seconds
and I already deeply regret this.
[beeping]
[changing channels on TV]
-Hey.
-Hey, yourself.
-I'm sorry I was an asshole.
-Mm-hmm.
-What are you doing?
-Seeing how fast I can change channels.
Also, I found all the loose change
in the house
and I put it in alphabetical order
by year.
Do you really think a guy like Miles
couldn't ever really like a girl like me?
No.
I was just jealous because you were
spending a lot of time with him.
He hasn't texted me all day today.
I've been trying to distract myself.
Forget him. You're gonna meet lots of guys
who will fall madly in love with you.
I might have scared him off. I don't know.
Do you ever get that feeling that like,
to know you more is to love you less?
Hollyhock, you are an amazing woman
and you should never settle for someone
who only loves the idea of you.
You are funny, and you're kind,
and you're clever.
Am I also pretty?
I-- come on.
What do you want me to say?
Obviously, I think you're beautiful.
Well, you don't have to go overboard.
Hey, I got an idea.
Why don't we go get some Cold Stone?
That'll take your mind off Miles.
Plus, I'll let you drive the Tesla!
Thanks, but I'm not really in the mood
for ice cream.
Well, then, forget that.
Let's get a pizza.
-I'm actually not hungry.
-Oh.
[TV audio switches rapidly]
♪ Back in the 90's
I was in a very famous TV show ♪
-♪ I'm BoJack the horseman ♪
-♪ BoJack ♪
♪ BoJack the horseman
Don't act like you don't know ♪
♪ And I'm trying to hold on to my past ♪
♪ It's been so long
I don't think I'm gonna last ♪
♪ I guess I'll just try
And make you understand ♪
♪ That I'm more horse than a man ♪
♪ Or I'm more man than a horse ♪
♪ BoJack! ♪
[man] Boxer vs. Raptor,
♪ Na-na, na-na, na-na, na-na ♪