[CHOKING]
[WHEEZING AND COUGHING]
[PANTING]
[CHOKES]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
Good evening.
[PIG SQUEALS]
[PIANO PLAYING]
Hello again,
and welcome to the show.
Tonight, we continue to look
at some famous deaths.
Tonight, we start
with the wonderful death
of Genghis Khan,
conqueror of India.
Take it away, Genghis.
[♪]
[SHOUTS]
ANNOUNCER:
Nine-point-one, 9.3, 9.7.
That's 28.1 for
Genghis Khan.
Bad luck, Genghis.
Nice to have you on the show.
And now, here are the scores.
Well, there you can see
the scores, now.
St. Stephen in the lead there,
with his stoning.
Uh, then comes, uh,
King Richard III
at Bosworth Field.
A grand death, that.
Then the very lovely
Jean d'Arc.
Uh, then Marat
in his bath.
Uh, best of friends
with Charlotte
in the showers afterwards.
Uh, then A. Lincoln
of the U.S. of A.
A grand little chap, that.
And at number six,
Genghis Khan.
And the back marker,
King Edward VII.
Back to you, Wolfgang.
Thank you, Eddie.
And now, time for this week's
request death.
For Mr. and Mrs.
Violet Stebbings
of 23 Wolverston Road, Hull,
the death of Mr. Bruce Foster
of Guildford.
[WHISTLING]
Strewth!
[GRUNTS]
Oh, blimey, how time flies.
Sadly, we are reaching the end
of yet another program
and so, it is finale time.
We are proud
to be bringing to you
one of the evergreen
bucket-kickers.
Yes, the wonderful death
of the famous English
Admiral Nelson.
Kiss me, Hardy!
[GRUNTS, THEN SQUEALS]
Well, good evening, everyone,
and welcome to the second
of our Italian language
classes,
in which we'll be helping you
brush up your Italian. Hm.
Now, last week we started
at the beginning,
and we learned the Italian
for "a spoon".
Now, I wonder how many of you
can remember what it was.
-ALL: Si.
-Not all at once.
Sit down, Mario. Giuseppe.
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
Oh, well done, Giuseppe.
Or, as the Italians would say:
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
Yes. Yes.
Well, now, this week, uh,
we're going to learn
some useful phrases
to help us open a conversation
with an Italian.
-[ALL MURMURING]
-Now, first of all,
try telling him
where you come from.
For example, I would say:
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
I am an Englishman
from Gerrard's Cross.
Shall we all try
that together?
-MAN 1: Yeah.
-MAN 2: Si. Si.
[ALL SPEAKING ITALIAN]
Not too bad.
Now let's try it
with somebody else.
Uh, Mr...?
-Uh, Mariolini, signor.
-Ah, Mr. Mariolini.
-And where are you from?
-Napoli, signor.
-Ah, you're Italian?
-Si, si, si.
Well, in that case,
you would say:
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
Yes?
[ALL SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Uh, signor, my friend,
he say, why--?
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Oh, Helmut, you want
the German classes.
Oh. Danke schoen.
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
My friend, he say--
He say, why must I say,
"I am Italian from Napoli,"
when he lives in Milan?
Oh, well, tell your friend
if he lives in Milan,
he must say:
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
-[ALL ARGUING IN ITALIAN]
-What's going on?
He say, "Milan is better
than Napoli."
Well, he shouldn't be saying
that, we haven't done
comparatives yet.
[ALL SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
[PLAYING GUITAR]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[ALL SHOUTING IN ITALIAN]
[PIG SQUEALS]
[SQUEALS]
[MAN GRUNTS]
[POP]
MAN:
Yes, mothers, new,
improved Whizzo butter
containing 10 percent
more or less
is indistinguishable
from a dead crab.
Remember, buy Whizzo butter
and go to heaven.
♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah ♪
I can't tell the difference
between Whizzo butter
and this dead crab.
Yes, you know, we find
that nine out of 10 British
housewives
can't tell the difference
between Whizzo butter
and a dead crab.
ALL:
It's true, we can't.
-No.
-Here.
You're on television,
aren't you?
Yes, yes.
ALL:
Ooh, yes. Yes.
He does that thing
with those silly women
who can't tell the difference
between Whizzo butter
-and a dead crab.
ALL: Ooh, yes.
You try that around here,
young man,
and we'll slit your face.
ALL:
Yeah.
Pull a razor
from there to there.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello, good evening,
and welcome
to another edition
of It's the Arts.
And we kick off tonight
with the cinema.
Good evening. One of
the most prolific of
film producers of this age,
or indeed any age,
is Sir Edward Ross,
back in this country for
the first time for five years
to open a season of his works
at the National Film Theatre.
And we are very fortunate
to have him with us here,
in the studio, this evening.
-Good evening.
-Edward, um--
You don't mind
if I call you Edward?
-No, not at all.
-It does worry some people.
I don't know why.
Perhaps they're sensitive.
So, I do take the precaution
of asking on these occasions.
No, no, no. That's fine.
So Edward's all right.
Splendid. Splendid.
Sorry to have brought it up,
only, uh...
No, no. Edward it is.
Well, thank you very much
indeed for--
for being so helpful.
Only it's more
than my job's worth to...
Quite. Yes.
Makes it difficult
to establish a rapport,
-to put the other
person at ease.
-Quite.
Silly little point,
but it does seem to matter.
Still, less said, the better.
Um, Ted,
when you first
started in the--
You don't mind
if I call you Ted?
No, no, no. No, no.
Everyone calls me Ted.
Good, good.
Well, it's shorter, isn't it?
-Yes, it is.
-Yes, and much less formal.
-Yes, Ted, Edward, anything.
-Splendid, splendid.
Incidentally,
do call me Tom.
I don't want you playing around
with any of this
"Thomas" nonsense.
[CHUCKLES]
Now, um, where were we?
Oh, yes.
Eddie-baby, when you first--
I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
I don't like being called
"Eddie-baby."
-I'm sorry?
-I don't like being
called "Eddie-baby."
-Did I call you "Eddie-baby"?
-Yes, you did.
Now, get on with it.
Don't think I did call
you "Eddie-baby."
You did call me
"Eddie-baby".
Did I call him "Eddie-baby?"
-AUDIENCE: Yes. Yes.
-MAN: No.
I didn't really call you
"Eddie-baby," did I, sweetie?
Don't call me "sweetie"!
-Can I call you "sugar plum"?
-No!
-Pussycat? Angel drawers?
No, you may not.
Now get on with it.
-Frank?
-What?
-Can I call you "Frank"?
-Why Frank?
It's a nice name.
Robin Day's got a hedgehog
called Frank.
Now, Frank--
What's going on?
Frannie, Frannie Knickers.
No. I'm leaving.
I'm leaving. I'm off.
Um, tell us about your latest
film, Sir Edward.
What?
Tell us about your latest film,
if you'll be so kind,
Sir Edward.
None of this "pussycat"
nonsense?
Promise.
Please, Sir Edward.
My latest film?
Yes, Sir Edward.
Well, the idea,
funnily enough,
came from an idea I had
when I first joined
the industry in 1919.
Of course, in those days
I was only a tea boy.
Oh, shut up.
Sir Edward Ross.
Now, later in the program,
we will bring you
a unique event in
the world of modern art.
Pablo Picasso will be doing
a special painting for us,
on this program, live,
on a bicycle.
This is the first time
that Picasso
has painted while cycling.
But right now,
it's time to look at a man
-whose meteoric rise to fame--
-[PIG SQUEALS]
[GUNSHOT]
[ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Last week,
the Royal Festival Hall
saw the first performance
of a new symphony
by one of the world's leading
modern composers:
Arthur "Two Sheds" Jackson.
Mr. Jackson--
Good evening.
May I just, uh, sidetrack you
for one moment, Mr. Jackson?
This-- Uh, what shall I call it,
nickname of yours.
-Oh, yes. Ahem.
-"Two Sheds."
-Yes.
-How did you come by it?
Well, I-I don't
use it myself.
It's just a few of my friends
call me "Two Sheds."
I see. And do you,
in fact, have two sheds?
No. No, I have only one shed.
I've had one for some time.
But a few years ago,
I said I was thinking
of getting another one,
and since then, some people
have called me "Two Sheds."
In spite of the fact
that you have only one?
-Yes. Ahem.
-I see.
And are you thinking
of purchasing a second shed?
No.
To bring you in line
with your epithet?
-No.
-I see, I see.
Well, let's return
to your symphony. Uh...
Now then, did you write
this symphony in the shed?
No.
Have you written
any of your
recent works in this
shed of yours?
No. It's just a perfectly
ordinary garden shed.
I see.
And you're thinking of buying
this second shed to write in.
No, no. Look.
This shed business,
it doesn't really matter
at all.
The sheds aren't important.
It's just a few friends
call me "Two Sheds,"
and that's all
there is to it.
I wish you'd ask me about
me music. I'm a composer.
People are always asking
about the sheds.
They've got it out
of proportion.
I'm fed up with the shed.
I wish I'd never got it.
I expect you're probably
thinking of selling one.
I will sell one.
Then you'd be
Arthur "No Sheds" Jackson.
Look, forget about the sheds.
They don't matter.
Mr. Jackson,
I think, with respect,
we ought to talk
about your symphony.
What?
Apparently,
your symphony
was written
for organ and tympani.
-What's that?
-What's what?
It's a shed. Get it off.
All right. Right.
Uh, now then, Mr. Jackson,
your symphony.
I understand that you--
that you used to be interested
in trainspotting.
What?
I understand, uh,
that about 30 years ago,
you were extremely interested
in trainspotting.
What's that got to do
with my bloody music?
-Are you having
any trouble from him?
-Yes, a little.
Well, we interviewers
are more than a match
for the likes of you, Two Sheds.
Yes, make yourself scarce,
Two Sheds.
This studio isn't big enough
for the three of us.
[CRASHING]
Get your own arts program,
you fairy.
Arthur "Two Sheds" Jackson.
MAN 1:
Never mind, Timmy.
MAN 2:
Oh, Michael,
you're such a comfort.
Arthur "Two Sheds"...
Jackson.
And now for more news
of the momentous
artistic event
when Pablo Picasso
is doing a specially
commissioned painting for us
whilst riding a bicycle.
Pablo Picasso,
the founder of modern art,
without doubt, the greatest
abstract painter ever,
for the first time,
painting in motion.
But first, let's have a look
at the route he'll be taking.
Well, uh, Picasso will
be starting, David,
at Chichester here.
He'll then cycle
on the A29 to Fontwell.
He'll then take the A272,
which will bring him
onto the A3,
just north of Hindhead here.
From then on, Pablo has
a straight run on the A3
until he meets the South
Circular at Battersea here.
Well, this is
a truly remarkable occasion,
as it is the first time
that a modern artist
of such stature
has taken the A272.
And it'll be very interesting
to see how he copes
with the heavy traffic
round Wisborough Green. Vicky.
Well, Picasso will be riding
his Viking Super Roadster,
with the drop handlebars
and the dual-thread wheel rims.
And with his Wiley-Prat
20-1 synchro-mesh,
he should experience
difficulties
on the sort of road surfaces
they just don't get
abroad. Mitzie.
And now for the latest report
on Picasso's progress,
over to Reg Moss
on the Guildford bypass.
Well, there's no
sign of Picasso at
the moment, David,
but he should be through
here at any moment.
However, I do have with me
Mr. Ron Geppo,
British cycling
sprint champion
and this year's winner
of the Derby-Doncaster rally.
Uh, well, Reg, I think
Pablo should be all right,
provided he doesn't
attempt anything
on the monumental scale
of some of
his earlier paintings,
like, uh, Guernica
or Les Demoiselles d'Avignon,
or even his later War and Peace
mural for the Temple of Peace
chapel at Vallauris.
Because with this
strong head-wind
I don't think even
Doug Timpson of
Manchester Harriers
could paint anything
on that kind of scale.
Well,
thank you, Ron.
Well, there still seems to be
no sign of Picasso
so I'll hand you back
to the studio.
Well, we've just heard
that Picasso is approaching
the Tolworth roundabout
on the A3,
so come in,
Sam Trench at Tolworth.
Well, something certainly
is happening here at
Tolworth roundabout.
David, I can now see Picasso.
He's cycling down towards
the roundabout,
he's about 75, 50 yards away
and I can now see his painting.
It's an abstract.
I can see some blue,
some purple.
Uh, some little,
black oval shapes.
I think I can see--
That's not Picasso,
that's Kandinsky.
Good Lord, you're right.
It's Kandinsky.
Wassily Kandinsky.
And who's this here with him?
It's Braque.
Georges Braque, the cubist,
painting a bird in flight
over a cornfield
and going very fast
down the hill
towards Kingston.
And Piet Mondrian just behind.
Piet Mondrian,
the neoplasticist.
Then a gap, then
the main bunch.
Here they come.
Chagall, Max Ernst, Miró,
Dufy, uh, Ben Nicholson,
Jackson Pollock,
and Bernard Buffet making
a break on the outside here.
Brancusi's going with him.
So is Géricault,
Ferdinand Léger, Delaunay,
de Kooning.
Kokoschka's dropping back here
by a little bit,
and so is Paul Klee
dropping back a bit.
And right at the back
of this group,
our very own
Kurt Schwitters.
-He's German.
-But as yet,
absolutely no sign
of Pablo Picasso.
And so,
from Tolworth roundabout,
back to the studio.
Well, I think
I can help you there, Sam.
We're getting reports in
from the AA that Picasso--
Picasso has fallen off.
He's fallen off his bicycle
on the B2127,
just outside Ewhurst,
trying to get a shortcut
to Dorking
via Gomslake and Peashall.
Well, Picasso is reported
to be unhurt,
but the pig has
a slight headache.
And on that note,
we must say good night to you.
Picasso has failed
in his first bid for
international cycling fame.
So from all of us here
at the It's the Arts studio,
it's good night.
Good night.
[SQUEALING]
[♪]
MAN:
Hold it.
Sit up.
[GROANING]
Sit up!
[GRUNTING]
[GLASS SMASHING]
Sit up.
[GRUNTS]
[MEN CHATTERING]
Ooh!
[WOMAN AND MEN CHATTERING]
WOMAN:
Shh!
There's somebody out there.
MAN:
Huh?
[GIBBERING]
Help, help me.
I'm trapped in his body.
Oh, please, help me out.
[SCREAMS]
[THUDS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[POTS AND PANS RATTLING]
Help me. Oh, please,
help me out. Oh, help.
[GIBBERING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[SAW BUZZING]
I'm free!
I'm free. I'm free.
[MUFFLED SPEECH]
[GONG RESOUNDS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[BOTH HUMMING]
MAN:
Just checking.
WOMAN:
Oh, no, you don't!
[MAN GRUNTING]
[CLANGING]
[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMEN:
Ooh!
[CROWD GRUMBLING]
WOMAN:
Shh! Shh! Shh!
There's somebody out there.
[GUNSHOT]
MAN: Ooh!
[WOMEN GIGGLING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[PIG GRUNTS]
Ugh!
Thompson's bought it,
sir.
Porker, eh?
The swine.
[♪]
NARRATOR: This man is
Ernest Scribbler,
writer of jokes.
In a few moments, he will
have written the funniest joke
in the world.
And, as a consequence,
he will die laughing.
[GASPS]
NARRATOR:
It was obvious
that this joke was lethal.
No one could read it
and live.
[GASPS]
[LAUGHING]
This morning,
shortly after 11:00,
comedy struck this
little house in Dibley Road.
Sudden, violent comedy.
Police have sealed off
the area,
and Scotland Yard's crack
inspector is with me now.
I shall enter the house
and attempt to
remove the joke.
[MAN LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
I shall be aided
by the sound of somber music,
played on gramophone records,
and also by the chanting
of laments
by the men of Q Division.
The atmosphere thus created
should protect me
in the eventuality
of me reading the joke.
[ALL MOANING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKER]
Well, there goes
a brave man.
Whether he comes out
alive or not,
this will
surely be remembered
as one
of the most courageous
and gallant acts
in police history.
[LAUGHING]
[MOANING STOPS]
NARRATOR:
It was not long before
the army became interested
in the military potential
of the killer joke.
Under top security,
the joke was hurried
to a meeting
of Allied commanders
at the Ministry of War.
[MEN LAUGHING]
[THUDDING]
NARRATOR:
Top brass were impressed.
Tests on Salisbury Plain
confirmed
the joke's devastating
effectiveness
at a range of up
to 50 yards.
[MOUTHING WORDS]
[LAUGHING]
-Fantastic.
All through the winter of '43
we had translators working
in joke-proof conditions
to try and produce
a German version of the joke.
They worked on one word each,
for greater safety.
One of them saw two words
of the joke
and spent several weeks
in hospital.
But apart from that,
things went pretty quickly.
And we soon had the joke,
by January,
in a form which our troops
couldn't understand
but which the Germans could.
[GUNFIRE]
NARRATOR:
So on July 8th, 1944,
the joke was first told
to the enemy
in the Ardennes.
[GUNFIRE]
Squad, get the joke.
Squad, tell the joke.
[ALL SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[GERMANS CHATTERING]
MAN:
Ooh!
[GERMANS LAUGHING]
NARRATOR:
It was a fantastic success.
Over 60,000
times as powerful
as Britain's
great pre-war joke
and one which Hitler
just couldn't match.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
NARRATOR:
In action, it was deadly.
[GUNFIRE]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[LAUGHING]
[MEN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[ALL LAUGHING]
NARRATOR:
German casualties
were appalling.
[LAUGHING]
What is the big joke?
I can only give you
name, rank,
and "Why did the chicken
cross the road?"
That's not funny!
-Ugh!
-I want to know the joke.
All right.
How do you make
a Nazi cross?
I don't know.
How do you make a Nazi cross?
Tread on his corns.
[SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
That's not funny!
Aah!
Now, if you don't tell me
the joke,
I shall hit you properly.
I can stand physical pain,
you know.
Ah, you're no fun.
All right, Otto.
Oh, no.
No, anything but that.
Please, no.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[LAUGHING]
All right. I'll tell you.
Quick, Otto,
the typewriter.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[LAUGHING]
That's not funny!
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[LAUGHING]
Ugh!
NARRATOR:
But at Peenemunde,
in autumn of '44,
the Germans were working
on a joke of their own.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
We let you know.
NARRATOR:
But by December,
their joke was ready.
And Hitler gave the order
for the German V-Joke
to be broadcast in English.
GERMAN MAN [ON RADIO]:
There were zwei peanuts
walking down the Strasse
and one was a salted peanut.
[LAUGHING]
["DAS LIED DER DEUTSCHEN"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKER]
In 1945, peace broke out.
It was the end of the joke.
Joke warfare was banned
at a special session
of the Geneva Convention,
and in 1950, the last
remaining copy of the joke
was laid to rest here,
in the Berkshire countryside,
never to be told again.
["RULE BRITANNIA" PLAYING]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[SNORTS]
[♪]
NARRATOR:
And here is the final score:
Pigs, 9, British bipeds, 4.
The pigs go on to meet
Vikki Carr in the final.