[PANTING]
[FOOTSTEPS ON ROCK SURFACE]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PANTING]
[POTS AND PANS RATTLING]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
[SHEEP BLEATING]
Ah. Good afternoon.
Afternoon.
Ah. Lovely day,
isn't it?
Ah. 'Tis that.
Are you, uh,
here on holiday or...?
No, no. I live here.
Oh, heh. Jolly good.
Heh, heh.
I-I say, uh, those--
Those are sheep,
aren't they?
Ah.
Yes, yes, of course,
I thought so. Heh-heh.
Only, uh, why are they
up in the trees?
A fair question. And one
that, in recent weeks,
has been much on my mind.
It's my considered opinion
that they're nestin'.
Nesting?
-What?
-Arr.
-L-like birds?
Exactly. Birds is the key
to the whole problem.
It's my belief that
these sheep are laboring
under the misapprehension
that they're birds.
Observe their behavior.
Take for a start
the sheep's tendency
to hop about the field
on their back legs.
[SHEEP BLEATING]
Now witness their attempts
to fly from tree to tree.
Notice they do not
so much fly as plummet.
[LEGS FLAPPING,
SHEEP THUDDING]
Observe, for example,
that ewe in that oak tree.
She is clearly trying
to teach her lamb to fly.
[LAMB BLEATS]
[THUDS]
Talk about the blind
leading the blind.
But-- But why do
they think they're birds?
Another fair question.
One thing is for sure:
a sheep is not
a creature of the air.
-It has enormous difficulty...
-[THUD]
...in the comparatively
simple act of perching.
-[SHEEP THUDDING]
-As you see.
As for flight, its body
is totally unadapted
to the problems
of aviation.
Trouble is,
sheep are very dim.
And once they get an idea
into their heads,
there's no shifting it.
But where did they get
the idea from?
From Harold. He's that sheep
over there under the elm.
He's that most dangerous
of animals, clever sheep.
He's the ringleader.
He's realized
that a sheep's life
consists of standing around
for a few months,
and then being eaten.
And that's a depressing
prospect for an ambitious sheep.
He's patently hit on
the idea of escape.
Well, why don't you
just get rid of Harold?
Because of the enormous
commercial possibilities
should he succeed.
MAN: And what exactly are
the commercial possibilities
of ovine aviation?
[speaking in French]
Good evening,
here is the diagram
of a French-English sheep.
It's not... I eat or baa...
Ah, pompom, ham or not.
Now, when its eyes are up over
there. Rrr, baa, like that...
...in our head,
we've got the cockpit!
Really?
Right here, where stands the
small English captaine,
Mr. Trubshaw!
Vive, Brian,
wherever you are.
Alright, OK.
Now, let me introduce you
to my colleague, Professor...
...Jean-Brian Zatapathique.
Here's the sheep. Wanted to book
it, the landing, during...
...les "wheels."
Bon!
Bon. Les "wheels" ici.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Well, ah!
Bere saloo et bahjin of the
machine the plane, baa.
Behind the sheep of...
well, good.
...chug, chug, chug.
Thanks a lot. Well, er,
follow the track.
-Come on, shut up.
-Er, sorry.
But...
Where is our luggage?
Where is the travelers?
-Gaspard.
-Please.
Merci.
Luggage!
Here it is!
First class, second, luggage.
And now, baa,
like that... baa.
Fantastic demo...
At three...
One, two, three, baa!
[both bleating]
We get a lot of French
people 'round here.
-Yes.
-Oh, yes. All over. Yes.
MAN:
And how do you get on
with these French people?
-Oh, very well.
-So do I, yeah.
-Me too.
-So does Mrs. Ape.
-Yes. Yes.
-Oh, yes, I like them.
I mean, they think well,
don't they?
I mean, be fair.
Pascal.
Blaise Pascal.
Jean-Paul Sartre.
Yes, Voltaire.
-Ooh!
-René Descartes.
Hmm. Hmm.
Mmm!
[POPS, HISSES]
And now for something
completely different.
A man with three buttocks.
Good evening.
I have with me
Mr. Arthur Frampton,
who has...
Mr. Frampton,
I understand, uh,
-that, uh, you, as it were...
-Mm.
...have...
Uh, well, let me
put it another way.
I believe, Mr. Frampton,
that, uh, whereas
most people have, uh, two...
Two. Uh, you...
-You.
-I'm sorry?
Ah. Yes. Yes, I see.
Um, are you quite
comfortable?
Yes, fine, thank you.
Uh, Mr. Frampton...
vis-a-vis your rump.
I beg your pardon?
-Uh, your rump.
-What?
Your, ahem, posterior.
Derrière.
[WHISPERS] Sit-upon.
-What's that?
-[WHISPERS] Buttocks.
-Oh, me bum!
-Shh!
Well, Mr. Frampton.
I understand, Mr. Frampton,
you have a, um,
50 percent bonus...
in the...
in the region
of, uh, what you said.
-I've got three cheeks.
-Yes. Splendid, splendid.
Well, we were wondering,
Mr. Frampton, if you could,
uh, see your way clear--
-Here, what's that camera doing?
-Uh, nothing.
-Hey!
-Nothing at all, sir.
We were wondering if
you could see your way clear
to giving us a quick...
A quick visual...
Mr. Frampton, will you
take your trousers down?
What? Here!
Here, get off!
I'm not taking me trousers off
on television.
Who do you think I am?
-Please take them down.
-No.
-Just a little bit.
Now, uh, ahem--
Now, look here, Mr. Frampton.
It's, uh, perfectly easy for
somebody just to come along here
to the BBC,
um, simply claiming
that they have a bit to spare
in the botty department.
The point is, Mr. Frampton,
our viewers need proof.
I've been on Persian Radio.
Get off!
Arthur Figgis knows
I've got three buttocks.
How?
We go cycling together.
Strewth!
And now for something
completely different.
A man with three buttocks.
Good evening.
I have with me,
Mr. Arthur Frampton, who...
Mr. Frampton...
I understand that you,
as it were, have, uh...
Well, uh, let me put it
another way.
I believe, Mr. Frampton,
that whereas most people...
-Didn't we do this just now?
-Well, yes.
Well, why didn't
you say so?
I thought it was
a continental version.
And now for something
completely the same.
A man with three buttocks.
[RINGS]
Hello?
Oh, did we?
And now for something
completely different.
A man with three noses.
MAN:
He's not here yet!
Two noses?
[APPLAUSE]
[BLOWING NOSE]
Ladies and gentlemen,
wasn't she just great?
Eh? Wasn't she
just great?
[LAUGHING]
And she can run
as fast as she can sing.
[LAUGHING]
And I'm telling ya
'cause I know.
[LAUGHING]
No, only kidding.
Ehh. Ugh.
Seriously now, ladies and
gentlemen, we have for you
one of the most unique acts
in the world today.
He's-- Well, I'll say no more,
just let you see for yourselves.
Ladies and gentlemen, my very
great privilege to introduce
Arthur Ewing
and his musical mice!
Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Uh, ladies and gentlemen,
I have in this box
23 white mice.
Mice which have been
painstakingly trained
over the past few years
to squeak at a selected pitch.
Uh, this is E sharp.
And, uh, this one is G.
Uh, you get the general idea.
Now, these mice are
so arranged upon this, uh, rack
that when played
in the correct order
they will squeak
"The Bells of St. Mary."
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you on the mouse organ
"The Bells of St. Mary".
Thank you.
[HUMS]
[MICE SQUEAKING
"BELLS OF ST. MARY'S"]
[HUMMING]
MAN:
Oh, my God!
Oh, stop him!
Stop him!
MAN 2: Oh, no!
Next.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[TAPS]
[SNAPS]
Are you the marriage
guidance counselor?
-Yes. Good morning.
-Morning, sir.
And good morning
to you, madam.
Name?
Mr. and Mrs. Arthur
Pewtey. Pewtey.
And what is
the name of your...
ravishing wife?
Wait. Don't tell me.
It's something to do
with moonlight.
It goes with
her eyes.
It's soft and gentle,
warm and yielding.
Deeply lyrical and yet
tender and frightened,
-like a tiny white rabbit.
-It's Deirdre.
Deirdre.
-What a beautiful name.
-ARTHUR: Heh.
What a beautiful...
beautiful name.
And what seems to be the trouble
with your marriage, Mr. Pewtey?
Well, it all started
about five years ago.
We started going on
holiday to Brighton.
Deirdre, my wife, has always
been a good companion to me,
and I never particularly
anticipated any marital strife.
Indeed, the very idea
of consulting a professional
marital adviser
has always been of
the greatest repugnance to me.
Although, far be it from me
to impugn the nature of
your trade or profession.
Do go on.
Well, we've always been good
friends, sharing interests.
Gardening, model airplanes,
the sixpenny bottle
for the holiday money.
And twice a month,
settling down at night to
do the accounts.
Something which,
uh, Deirdre,
Deirdre, that's my wife, uh,
particularly looked forward to
on account of her feet.
I should probably
have said at the outset
that I'm noted for having
a sense of humor,
although I've kept to myself
over the last two years,
notwithstanding as it were,
and it's only
comparatively recently
that I have begun
to realize, well--
Uh, perhaps "realize"
is not the correct word.
Uh, imagined.
Imagine that I was not
the only thing in her life.
You suspected
your wife?
Well, yes. Yes.
At first, frankly, yes.
Her behavior did seem
at the time to me,
who was after all,
there to see,
to be a little odd.
-Odd?
-Yes. Well, I mean, uh,
to a certain extent, yes.
I'm not by nature
a suspicious person.
Far from it.
I have a reputation as
an after-dinner speaker,
if you take my meaning.
-Yes, I certainly do.
-Yeah.
Anyway, in the area
where I'm known,
the people, in fact,
know me extremely well.
-Right.
-Heh.
Would you hold this?
Thank you.
Yes. Anyway,
as I said,
I must learn to
face up to the facts,
stop beating about the bush,
or I'd never look myself
in the bathroom mirror again.
Anyway. So--
Would you mind running along
for 10 minutes?
-No.
-Make it half an hour.
Right. Oh, fine.
Yes. I'll wait outside,
shall I?
Yes, well, that's perhaps
the best thing. Yes.
Certainly put
my mind at rest on--
on one or two points there.
Now, wait there,
stranger.
A man can run and run
for year after year...
until he realizes that what
he's running from is hisself.
Gosh.
Now, a man's gotta do
what a man's gotta do,
and there ain't
no sense in runnin'.
Now, you gotta turn,
and you gotta fight.
And you gotta hold
your head up high.
Yes.
Now, you go back in there,
my son, and be a man.
Walk tall.
Yes.
Oh, I will.
I will.
I've been pushed around
long enough.
This is it!
This is your moment,
Arthur Pewtey.
This is it, Arthur Pewtey.
At last... you're a man!
[DEIRDRE GIGGLING]
All right, Deirdre,
come out of there!
-COUNSELOR: Go away.
-Right, right.
DEIRDRE:
Oh. Oh. Oh.
[GIGGLES]
ANNOUNCER:
So much for pathos.
NARRATOR:
These historic pictures
of Queen Victoria,
taken in 1880 at Osborne,
show the Queen
with Gladstone.
This unique film
provides a rare glimpse
into the private world
of a woman who ruled
half the earth.
The commentary, recorded on
the earliest wax cylinders,
is spoken by
Alfred Lord Tennyson,
the poet laureate.
TENNYSON:
Well, hello,
it's the wacky queen again.
And who's the other fella?
It's Willie Gladstone.
And when these two way-out,
wacky characters get together,
there's fun aplenty.
And, uh-oh,
there's a hosepipe.
This means trouble
for somebody.
Uh-oh. Charlie Gardener's
fallen for that old trick.
Queenie's put him
in a heap of trouble.
Uh-oh! That's one
in the eye for Willie.
Here, you have a look.
[♪]
Well, doggone it,
where's that water?
Uh-oh! There it is,
all over his face.
Well, hello.
What's Britain's
wacky queen up to now?
Well, she's certainly not
sitting on the fence.
She's painting it.
Surely, nothing
can go wrong here.
Uh-oh. Here's the PM
coming back for more.
And he certainly gets it.
Well, that's one way to get
the housework done.
[♪]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Oh, Dad, look who's
come to see us.
It's our Ken.
[SPITS]
Aye, and about bloody time
if you ask me.
Aren't you pleased
to see me, Father?
Yes, of course he's
pleased to see you, Ken.
All right, woman. All right.
I've got a tongue in me head.
I'll do the talking.
Blimey.
I like your fancy suit.
Is that what they're wearing
up in Yorkshire now?
-It's just an ordinary suit,
Father.
-Ah.
It's all I've got
apart from the overalls.
How are you liking it
down the mine, Ken?
Oh, it's not
too bad, Mum.
We're using some new
tungsten carbide drills
for the preliminary coal-face
scouring operations.
Ooh, that sounds
nice, dear.
Tungsten carbide drills?
What in the bloody hell
is tungsten carbide drills?
It's something they use
in coal mining, Father.
"It's something they use
in coal mining, Father."
You're bloody fancy talk
since you left London.
Not that again.
Oh. He-- He's had
a hard day, dear.
His new play opens at
National Theatre tomorrow.
Oh. That's good.
Good? Good?
What do you know about it?
What do you know about
getting up at 5:00 in
the morning to fly to Paris,
back at the Old Vic
for drinks at 12,
sweating the day through
press interviews,
television interviews,
then getting back here at 10
to wrestle with the problem
of a homosexual nymphomaniac
drug addict
involved in the ritual murder
of a well-known Scottish
footballer?
That's a full working day, lad.
And don't you forget it!
-Oh, don't shout
at the boy, Father.
-Aye.
Hampstead wasn't
good enough for you, was it?
You had to go
poncing off to Barnsley.
You and your coal-mining
friends.
-[SPITS]
-Coal mining is
a wonderful thing, Father.
-Yeah.
-But it's something
you'll never understand.
-Just look at you!
-Oh, Ken, be careful.
You know what he's like
after a few novels.
What? What?
What?
Come on, lad.
Come on.
Out with it.
What's wrong with me?
You tit!
I'll tell you what's
wrong with you.
Your head's addled
with novels and poems.
You come home every evening
reeling of Château Latour.
-Don't, don't.
-Look what you've done
to Mother.
She's worn out with
meeting film stars,
attending premieres
and giving gala luncheons.
There's nowt wrong
with gala luncheons, lad!
I've had more gala luncheons
than you've had hot dinners.
-[CRYING] Oh, please, please.
-Ahh! Aahh!
-Oh! Oh, no!
-What is it?
Oh, it's his writer's cramp.
You never told me
about this.
No, we didn't
like to, Kenny.
I'm all right.
I'm all right, woman.
Just get him out of here.
Oh, Ken.
You'd better go.
All right.
I'm going.
After all we've
done for him.
One day you'll realize there's
more to life than culture.
There's dirt and smoke,
-and good honest sweat!
-Get out!
Get out, you laborer!
Hey. You know, Mother,
I think there's a play there.
Get agent on the phone.
Aye, I think
you're right, Frank.
-It could express--
-[KNOCKING ON FLOOR]
-It could express
a vital theme of our age.
-Ah.
Oh, shut up!
Shut up!
Well, that's better.
Now, for something
completely different.
A man with three buttocks.
DAD AND MOM:
We've done that!
Oh, all right! All right!
A man with... nine legs.
-MAN: He ran away.
-Oh, bloody hell.
Uh...
A-- A Scotsman
on a horse.
[BAGPIPE PLAYING LIVELY TUNE]
[HORSE SNORTS]
[APPLAUSE]
[BLOWING NOSE]
MAN 1:
Harold! Come back, Harold!
Harold!
Come back, Harold!
Oh, blast!
MAN 2:
Sir.
[RASPBERRY BLOWS]
[♪]
Good evening, and welcome
once again to The Epilogue.
On the program this evening
we have Monsignor Edward Gay,
visiting pastoral emissary
of the Somerset
Theological College
and author of a number
of books about belief,
the most recent of which
is the bestseller, My God.
Good evening.
And opposite him,
we have Dr. Tom Jack,
humanist,
broadcaster, lecturer,
and author of the book,
Hello Sailor.
Good evening.
Tonight... Tonight, instead of,
uh, discussing the existence
or nonexistence of God,
they have decided
to fight for it.
The existence,
or nonexistence
to be determined by two falls,
the two submissions
or a knockout.
All right, boys,
let's get to it.
Your master of ceremonies
for this evening,
Mr. Arthur Waring.
WARING:
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to a three-round
contest of The Epilogue.
Introducing on my right
in the blue corner,
appearing for Jehovah,
the ever-popular
Monsignor Eddie Gay.
And on my left
in the red corner,
author of the books
The Problems of Kierkegaard
and Hello Sailor,
and visiting professor of
Modern Theological Philosophy
at the University
of East Anglia,
from Wigan,
Dr. Tom Jack.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
EPILOGUE HOST:
Now Dr.-- Dr. Jack's got
the flying mare there.
A flying mare there.
Um, what's he doing?
And this is gonna be a full
body slam. A full body slam.
And he's going in to pin--
No, he's-- He's standing back.
Well, uh, there we, uh--
There we are leaving
The Epilogue
for the moment.
We'll be bringing you
the result of this discussion
later on in the program.
-[GUNSHOT]
-[MAN GRUNTS]
My God.
Ugh!
Oof!
[HUMMING]
Oh, isn't he an impressive
figure of a man?
Now, people of the country,
I want to say a word about
defacement of public property.
Anyway, this sort of thing
has got to be stopped.
Ebbing the destruction.
Defacement has got to be
put to an end.
This country is not
standing for vandals
and hooligans running about.
-[FOOTSTEPS RACING]
-But for the moment,
things will probably
be a little loud.
[SAW BUZZING]
WOMAN:
Oh, yes, that's much better.
[MUTTERING]
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little--?
[MUNCHING]
[BELCHES]
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little--?
[MUNCHING]
[BELCHES]
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little--?
MAN:
Wait a minute, buckaroos.
This has gone far enough.
Oh, no!
Take it away from me.
Take it away!
Oh, no. No. Get it away.
Get it away!
[DRUMROLL]
[FANFARE PLAYING]
[WHISTLE TOOTING]
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪]
Yes. The mouse problem.
This week, The World Around Us
looks at the growing social
phenomenon of mice and men.
What makes a man
want to be a mouse?
Well, uh...
it's not a question of
wanting to be a mouse.
It just sort of
happens to you.
Um...
all of a sudden
you realize...
that's what
you want to be.
And when did you first notice
these, shall we say, tendencies?
Well, I was about 17,
and some mates and me
went to a party.
And, uh...
Well, we had quite
a lot to drink, and then...
some of the fellows there...
started handing...
cheese around.
Well, just out of curiosity
I tried a bit and...
-Well, that was that.
-Yes.
And what else
did these fellows do?
Well, uh...
some of them started
dressing up as mice
a bit, um...
And then when they got
the costumes on, they...
started... squeaking.
-And was that all?
-That was all.
And what was
your reaction to this?
-Well, I was shocked.
-Yes.
But, uh...
Gradually I came to feel...
that I was more at ease
with other mice.
A typical case, whom we shall
refer to as "Mr. A".
Although his real
name is this:
ANNOUNCER:
Arthur Jackson,
32a Milton Avenue,
Hounslow, Middlesex.
What is it that attracts someone
like Mr. A to this way of life?
I have with me
a consultant psychiatrist.
Well, we've just heard
a typical case history.
I myself have
over 700 similar histories,
all fully documented.
Would you care to choose one?
Mr. Arthur Aldridge
of Lamington.
-Well, that's amazing.
-Thank you.
Amazing.
Thank you, Janet.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
Kargol, speaking as
a psychiatrist,
as opposed to a conjuror...
Oh.
...what makes certain men
want to be mice?
Well, we psychiatrists
have found
that over eight percent
of the population
will always be mice.
I mean, after all,
there's something of the mouse
in all of us.
I mean, how many of us
could honestly say
that at one time or another
he hasn't felt
sexually attracted to mice?
I know I have.
I mean, most
normal adolescents
go through a stage
of squeaking
two or three
times a day.
Most youngsters
on the other hand,
some youngsters,
are attracted to it
by its very illegality.
It's like murder.
Make a thing illegal,
and it acquires a mystique.
Look at arson.
I mean, how many of us
could honestly say
that at one time
or another
he hasn't set fire
to some great public building?
-I know I have.
-[RINGS]
The only way--
The only way to bring
the crime figures down
is to reduce
the number of offenses.
Get it out
in the open.
-I know I have.
-Hm.
The Amazing Kargol and Janet.
What a lot of people
don't realize is that a mouse,
once accepted,
can fulfill
a very useful role in society.
Indeed, there are examples
throughout history
of famous men now known
to have been mice.
Veni, vidi, vici.
[SQUEAKS]
And of course, Hilaire Belloc.
But what is the--
But what is the attitude...
Of the man in the street
towards...
This growing social problem?
Clamp down on 'em.
-MAN: How?
-I'd strangle them.
Well, speaking as a member
of the stock exchange,
I would suck their brains out
with a straw,
uh, sell the widows and orphans,
and go into South American zinc.
Yeah. I'd, uh, stuff sparrows
down their throats, uh,
until the beaks stuck out
through the, uh, stomach walls.
Oh, well,
I'm a chartered accountant,
and consequently
too boring to be of interest.
I feel that these poor,
unfortunate people
should be free
to live the lives
of their own choice.
I'd, uh, split
their nostrils open
with a boat hook,
uh, I think.
Oh, well, I mean, uh.
they can't help it, can they?
But, I mean, there's nothing
you can do about it,
so, uh, I'd kill 'em.
Clearly, the British public's
view is a hostile one.
Hostile.
WOMAN: Hostile.
But perhaps this is because
so little is generally known
of these mice men.
We have some film now taken at
one of the notorious weekend
mouse parties,
where these disgusting
little perverts meet.
Mr. A tells us what actually
goes on at these mouse parties.
Well, uh, first of all,
you get shown to
your own private hole
in the skirting board.
Uh, then you put
the mouse skin on, uh...
Then you...
scurry into the main room.
Oh, and perhaps, uh,
take a run in the wheel.
The remainder of this film
was taken secretly
at one of these mouse parties
by a BBC cameraman
posing as a vole.
As usual, we apologize for
the poor quality of the film.
MR. A:
Well, uh...
then you steal some cheese.
Uh, Brie or Camembert.
Or Cheddar or Gouda,
if you're on the harder stuff.
Um, you might go and see
one of the blue-cheese films.
Then... there's a big clock
in the middle of the room,
and about 12:50,
you climb up it.
And then...
eventually, it strikes one,
and you all run down.
INTERVIEWER:
And what-- What's that?
MR. A: That's the farmer's wife.
INTERVIEWER: Yes.
Perhaps we need to know
more of these mice men
before we can really judge them.
Perhaps not.
Anyway, our 30 minutes are up.
[SHEEP BLEATING]
Good night.
[PANTING]
[♪]
EPILOGUE HOST: And here is
the result of The Epilogue:
God exists, by two falls
to a submission.
[♪]