[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[LION ROARS]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER [READING]:
The larch.
Mr. Larch, you heard the case
for the prosecution.
Is there anything you wish
to say before I pass sentence?
Well, I'd just like to say,
my lord, that I've, uh--
I've got a family,
a wife and six kids,
and I hope very much
you don't have to take away
my freedom because--
Well, because, my lord,
freedom is a state much prized
within the realm
of civilized society.
It is a bond
wherewith the savage man
may charm the outward
hatchments of his soul
and soothe the troubled breast
into a magnitude of quiet.
It is most precious
as a blessed balm,
the savior of princes,
the harbinger of
happiness, yea,
the very stuff and pith
of all we hold most dear.
What frees the prisoner
in his lonely cell
chained within the bondage
of rude walls,
far from the owl of Thebes?
What fires and stirs
the woodcock in his springe,
or wakes the drowsy apricot
betide?
What goddess doth
the storm-tossed mariner
offer most tempestuous
prayers to?
Freedom!
Freedom.
It's only
a bloody parking offense.
I'm sorry I'm late, my lord. I
couldn't find a kosher car park.
Uh, don't bother to recap,
my lord.
I'll pick it up as we go along.
Call Mrs. Fiona Lewis.
CLERK:
I swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
So anyway, I said to--
I said to her-- I said,
"They can't afford that
on what he earns."
I mean, for a start,
the feathers get up your nose.
I ask you, four and six a pound,
and him with a wooden leg?
I don't know
how she puts up with it
after all the trouble she's had
with her you-know-what.
Anyway, it was a white wedding,
much to everyone's surprise.
'Course they bought everything
on-the-hire purchase.
I think they ought
to send them back
where they come from.
I mean, you've got to be cruel
to be kind.
So Mrs. Harris said-- So she
said-- She said-- She said,
"The dead crab," she said.
She said--
Well, her sister's
gone to Rhodesia,
what with her womb and all,
and her youngest--
Her youngest
as thin as a filing cabinet.
And the goldfish. The goldfish.
They've got whooping cough.
They keep spitting water.
Well, they do, don't they?
I mean, you can't, can you?
I mean, they're
not even married or anything,
they're not even divorced.
And he's in the KGB,
if you ask me.
He says he's a tree surgeon,
but I don't like the sound
of his liver.
All that squeakin' and banging
every night
till the small hours.
What is--?
Well,
his mother's been much better
since she had her head off.
Yes, she has. I said, "Don't you
talk to me about that--"
"Don't you talk to me
about bladders," I said.
Mr. Bartlett, I fail to see the
relevance of your last witness.
Uh, my next witness will explain
that if my lordship will allow.
I call the late
Arthur Aldridge.
The late
Arthur Aldridge?
Yes, my lord.
Mr. Bartlett, do you think
there is any real relevance
in questioning the deceased?
Uh, I beg your pardon,
my lord?
Well, I mean,
your witness is dead.
Uh, yes, my lord.
Uh, well, uh, virtually,
my lord.
He's not completely dead?
No, he's not completely dead,
my lord. No.
But he's not at all well.
But-- But if he's not dead,
what's he doing in a coffin?
Uh, it's purely a precaution,
my lord. If I may continue?
Uh, Mr. Aldridge,
uh, you were a--
You are a stockbroker
of 10 Savundra Close,
Wimbledon?
[KNOCKS ONCE]
-Mr. Aldridge--
-What was that knock?
Uh, it means yes, my lord.
One knock for yes,
and two knocks for no.
If I may continue?
Uh, Mr. Aldridge, would it be,
uh, fair to say that you
are not at all well?
[KNOCKS ONCE]
In fact, Mr. Aldridge, not to
put too fine a point on it,
would you be prepared to say
that you are, as it were,
what is generally known as,
in a manner of speaking, dead?
Mr. Aldridge, I put it to you
that you are dead.
A-ha!
Where is all this leading us?
Uh, that will become apparent
in one moment, my lord.
Mr. Aldridge, are you
considering the question,
or are you just dead?
I think I'd better
take a look, my lord.
No further questions,
my lord, ahem.
What do you mean,
"No further questions"?
You can't dump a dead body
in my court and say,
"No further questions."
I demand an explanation.
There are no easy answers
in this case, my lord.
I think you haven't got
the slightest idea
what this case is about.
My lord, uh, the-- the--
these strange, damnable,
almost diabolic threads
of this extraordinary,
tangled web of intrigue
will shortly, my lord,
reveal a plot so fiendish,
so infernal, so heinous--
Mr. Bartlett, your client
has already pleaded guilty
to the parking offense.
Parking offense,
"schmarking" offense, my lord.
We must leave no
stone unturned.
Call Cardinal Richelieu.
You're just trying
to string this case out.
Cardinal Richelieu?
A character witness, my lord.
[TRUMPETS PLAY]
Hello, everyone.
It's wonderful to be here,
you know.
I just love your country.
London is so beautiful
at this time of year.
Uh, you are Cardinal Armand
du Plessis de Richelieu,
first minister of Louis XIII?
Oui.
Cardinal,
uh, would it be fair to say
that you not only built up
the centralized monarchy
in France
but also perpetuated
the religious schism in Europe?
That's what they say.
And did you persecute
the Huguenots?
Oui.
And did you take even sterner
measures against
the great Catholic nobles
who made common cause
with foreign foes
in defense
of their feudal independence?
I sure did that thing.
Cardinal, are you acquainted
with the defendant,
Harold Larch?
Since I was so high.
Speaking as a Cardinal
of the Roman Catholic Church,
as first minister of Louis XIII,
and as one of the architects
of the modern world already,
would you say
that Harold Larch was a
man of good character?
Listen, Harry is a very
wonderful human being.
My lord, in view of
the impeccable nature
of this character witness,
may I plead for clemency?
Look, it's only 30 shillings.
Not so fast.
Why not?
Uh-- Uh...
None of your smart answers.
You think you're so clever.
Well, I'm Dim.
ALL:
Dim. Consternation. Uproar.
Yes, and I've a few questions
I'd like to ask
Cardinal so-called Richelieu.
Bonjour,
Monsieur Dim.
So-called Cardinal,
I put it to you
that you died...
in December 1642.
That is correct.
A-ha!
He fell for my little trap.
[APPLAUSE]
Curse you, Inspector Dim.
You are too clever
for us naughty people.
And furthermore,
I suggest that you are none
other than Ron Higgins,
professional Cardinal Richelieu
impersonator.
It's a fair cop.
My life, you're clever, Dim.
He'd certainly taken me in.
It's all in a day's work.
Oh, with a brilliant mind
like yours, Dim,
you could be something
other than a policeman.
-Yes.
-What?
[PIANO PLAYS]
♪ If I were not in the CID ♪
♪ Something else
I'd like to be ♪
♪ If I were not in the CID ♪
♪ A window cleaner, me ♪
♪ With a rub-a-dub-dub
And a scrub-a-dub-dub ♪
♪ And a rub-a-dub
all day long ♪
♪ With a rub-a-dub-dub
And a scrub-a-dub-dub ♪
♪ I'd sing this merry song ♪
ALL:
♪ If I were not in the CID ♪
♪ Something else
I'd like to be ♪
♪ If I were not in the CID ♪
♪ A window cleaner, me ♪
♪ With a rub-a-dub-dub
And a scrub-a-dub-dub ♪
♪ And a rub-a-dub
all day long ♪
♪ With a scrub-a-dub-dub
And a rub-a-dub-dub ♪
♪ I'd sing this merry song
Hey ♪
COUNSEL:
♪ If I were not
before the bar ♪
♪ Something else
I'd like to be ♪
♪ If I were not a barrister ♪
♪ An engine driver, me ♪
♪ With a chuff, chuff, chuff
And a chuff, chuff, chuff ♪
Chuff...
[CLEARS THROAT]
ANNOUNCER [READING]:
The larch.
ANNOUNCER:
This man is no ordinary man.
This is Mr. F. G. Superman.
To all appearances,
no different from any other
law-abiding citizen.
But Mr. F. G. Superman
has a secret identity.
When trouble strikes
at any time, at any place,
he is ready to become...
Bicycle Repairman.
[WHISTLING]
Whoa!
BOY:
Hey!
There's a bicycle broken.
Up the road.
BICYCLE REPAIRMAN:
Hm. Thinks.
This sounds like a job
for Bicycle Repairman.
But how to change without
revealing my secret identity?
If only Bicycle Repairman
were here.
Oh, yes.
Wait.
I think I know
where I can find him.
Look.
Over there.
BOTH:
Bicycle Repairman?
But how?
L-look.
Is it a stockbroker?
Is it a quantity surveyor?
Is it a church warden?
ALL:
No! It's Bicycle Repairman!
Why, Bicycle Repairman.
Thank goodness you've come.
Look.
[♪]
Why, he's mending it
with his own hands.
See how he uses a spanner
to tighten that nut?
ALL:
Whoa!
Bicycle Repairman,
how can I ever repay you?
Well, you don't need to, guv.
It's all right.
It's all in a day's work
for Bicycle Repairman.
[SNORTS, COUGHS]
ALL:
Our hero.
ANNOUNCER:
Yes, wherever bicycles
are broken
or menaced
by international Communism,
Bicycle Repairman is ready.
Ready to smash
the Communists,
wipe them up...
...and shove them off
the face of the Earth.
Mash that dirty, red scum!
Kick 'em in the teeth,
where it hurts!
Kill!
Kill! Kill!
Filthy, bastard commies.
I hate 'em, I hate 'em!
[SCREAMS]
[YELLS]
WOMAN:
Norman, tea's ready.
CALMLY: Coming, dear.
[♪]
Hello, children, hello.
Here is this morning's story.
Are you ready?
Then we'll begin.
"One day, Ricky the magic pixy
went to visit Daisy Bumble
in her tumbledown cottage.
He found her in the bedroom.
Roughly, he grabbed
her heavy shoulders,
pulling her down onto the bed
and ripping off her..."
"Old Nick the sea captain
was a rough, tough,
jolly sort of fellow.
He loved the life of the sea,
and he loved to hang out
down by the pier
where the men
dressed as ladies..."?
Uh--! Uh...
"Rumpletweezer
ran the Dinky Tinky shop
in the foot
of the magic oak tree
by the wobbly dumdum bush
in the shade of the magic glade
down in Dingly Dell.
Here he sold contraceptives
and--"
[MUMBLES INDISTINCTLY]
"Discipline"?
"Naked"?
With a melon?
[♪]
[HUMS WAGNER'S
"RIDE OF THE VALKYRIES"]
[PRAYS IN FOREIGN DIALECT]
[CONTINUES HUMMING]
Woo-hoo!
Hello, again.
Now, here's a little sketch
by two boys from London town.
They've been writing
for three years,
and they've come up
with a number.
Here it is.
It's called "restaurant sketch".
[APPLAUSE]
It's nice here,
isn't it?
A very good restaurant.
Three stars, you know.
-Really?
-Good evening, sir.
-Good evening, madam.
-Good evening.
And may I say what a pleasure it
is to see you here again, sir?
Oh, thank you.
Hmm, well,
there you are, dear.
Have a look there.
Anything you like?
The, uh, boeuf en croûte
is fantastic.
Oh, if I may suggest, sir,
the faisan à la reine.
The sauce is one of the chef's
most famous creations.
Ooh.
Mm, that sounds good.
Anyway, just have a look.
Take your time, all right?
Oh, uh, by the way,
I got a bit of a dirty fork.
Could you, uh,
get me another one?
I beg your pardon?
Uh, well, it's nothing.
I-- I've got a fork.
Little bit dirty.
Could you get me another one?
-Thank you.
-Oh, sir, I do apologize.
Oh, no need to apologize.
It doesn't worry me.
Oh, no, no, no.
I do apologize.
I will fetch the headwaiter
imédiatement.
No, there's no
need to do that.
Oh, no, no.
I am sure the headwaiter
he will want to apologize
to you himself.
I will fetch him at once.
Well, you certainly get
good service here.
They really
look after you, yes.
Excuse me,
monsieur and madam.
It's filthy!
Gaston, find out who
washed this up,
and give them
their cards immediately.
No, better still, can't afford
to take any chances.
Sack the entire
washing-up staff.
Look, I don't want
to make any trouble.
Oh, no.
Please, it's no trouble.
It's right that you
should point these
kind of things out.
Gaston! Tell the manager
what has happened,
immediately.
Oh-- No.
Ple-- Please.
I-I-I don't want
to cause any fuss.
Please, it's no fuss.
We simply wish to ensure
that nothing interferes
with your complete enjoyment
of the meal.
Oh, I'm sure it won't.
It was only a dirty fork.
I know.
And I'm sorry.
Bitterly sorry.
But I know that no apologies
I can make
can alter the fact
that in our restaurant
you have been given
a dirty, filthy,
smelly piece of cutlery.
-It wasn't smelly.
-It was smelly!
And obscene and disgusting!
And I hate it!
I hate it! I hate it!
Nasty, grubby, dirty, mangy,
scrubby little fork!
Goodbye.
Ooh!
Good evening, sir.
Good evening, madam.
I am the manager.
I've only just heard.
-Uh, may I sit down?
-Yes, of course.
I want to apologize humbly,
deeply and sincerely
about the fork.
Uh, oh, please, I was--
It's only a tiny bit dirty.
I was-- Just--
Couldn't see it.
Oh, you're good, kind,
fine people for saying that,
but I can see it.
To me it's like a mountain.
A vast bowl of pus.
-Oh, it's not as bad as that.
-No! It gets me here.
I can't give you any excuses
for it.
There are no excuses.
I've been meaning to spend
more time
in the restaurant recently,
but I haven't been too well
and--
And things aren't going
very well back there.
The poor cook's son
has been put away again,
and poor old Mrs. Dalrymple,
who does the washing up
can hardly move her--
Her poor fingers.
And then there's Gilberto's
war wound.
But they're good people.
And they're kind people.
And together,
we were beginning to get
over this dark patch.
There was light
at the end of the tunnel.
Now this!
Now this! I wanna die!
[SOBS]
Could I get you
some water?
It's the end of the road.
You bastards!
You vicious,
heartless bastards!
[LAUGHS]
Look what you've done to him!
He's worked his fingers
to the bone
to make this place what it is,
and you come in
with your petty,
feeble quibbling,
and you grind
him into the dirt!
This fine, honorable man
whose boots
you are not worthy to kiss.
Oh, it makes me mad.
Mad.
Easy, Mungo, easy.
Mungo-- Ah!
The war wound.
The wound!
It's the end.
Oh,
they've destroyed him!
The end!
[SCREAMS]
He's dead!
They killed him.
Revenge!
No-- No, don't, Mungo.
Never kill a customer.
Oh, the wound!
The wound.
[SCREAMS]
[CRIES]
-Rev--!
[SCREAMS]
Lucky we didn't say anything
about the dirty knife.
[AUDIENCE BOOS]
Oh, no, come on. No.
Shut up. No. No.
There we are, then.
That was restaurant sketch.
Nice little number,
a bit vicious in parts,
but a lot of fun.
But how about
that punch line, eh?
Oh, you know what I mean.
Oh-ho-ho, really.
ANNOUNCER:
Tired of that drab,
boring life you lead?
Then purchase a past.
Yes,
thousands of people
have led
far more interesting lives
than you will ever lead...
[DRUMROLL]
[JACQUES OFFENBACH'S
"INFERNAL GALLOP" PLAYS]
[SNORTS]
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[WHISTLES]
-[SNORTS]
-[WHISTLES]
[TINKLING MUSIC]
[SPLASH]
...and undoubtedly continue
to lead interesting lives
whereas you,
just as assuredly, will not.
ANNOUNCER [READING]:
...bits of their lives
are being made available
for purchase.
For only 15 shillings,
dullards like yourself
can obtain beautifully
framed photographs
of other people's lives.
Hang them in your den.
Stand them on your desk
or next to your bed.
Pretend they are pictures
from your past.
[♪]
[KNOCK]
Hello,
I'm Uncle Frank and family.
Mind if we stay
a couple of nights?
Or a month?
Or three years? So--
Hello. George and Agnes.
Could we live in
the guestroom?
Where's the bathroom?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
MAN:
Shut up. Shut up!
ALL:
Oh, sorry.
MAN:
Not good enough.
[WHISTLING]
[♪]
Ahem. Good evening.
Here is the 6:00 news
read by Michael Queen.
It's been a quiet day
over most of the country
as people went back to work
after the warmest July weekend
for nearly a year.
The only high spot
of the weekend was the meeting
between officials
of the NEDC and the ODCN
in Bradford today.
[LOUD BANGING]
Mr. Ted Johnson of the NEDC
moved...
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[GUNSHOTS]
In Geneva, officials
of the central clearing banks,
met with Herr Voleschtadt
of Poland
to discuss
non-returnable loans on
a 12-year trust basis
for the construction
of a new zinc-treating works
in the Omsk area of Cracow,
near the Gulistan border.
The board of trade
has ratified a trade agreement
with the Soviet Union
for the sale of 600 low-gear,
electric sewing machines.
The president
of the board of trade
said he hoped this would mark
a new era of expansion
in world trade
and a new spirit of
cooperation between
East and West.
There has been a substantial
drop in gold reserves
during the last 12 months.
This follows a statement
by the Treasury
to the effect that
the balance-of-imports
situation
had not changed dramatically
over the same period.
Still no news
of the national savings book
lost by Mr. Charles Griffiths
of Porthcawl
during a field expedition
to the nature reserves
of Swansea last July.
Mr. Griffiths' wife
said that her husband
was refusing to talk
to the press
until the savings certificate
had been found.
In Cornwall, the death
has been announced today
of the former
Minister without Portfolio,
General Sir Hugh
Marksby-Smith.
Sir Hugh was vice president
of the Rotarian movement.
In the match between
Glamorgan and Yorkshire,
the Yorkshire bowler Nicholson
took eight wickets
for three runs.
Glamorgan were all out for 36,
and therefore won the match
by an inning and seven runs.
Weather for tomorrow
will be cloudy
with occasional outbreaks
of rain.
And that is the end
of the news.
ANNOUNCER [READING]:
The larch.
The horse chestnut.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
Eric, do you think you could,
uh, recognize a larch tree?
I don't know.
What's your name?
Michael.
Michael, do you think, uh,
you know what a larch tree
looks like?
I want to go home.
Bottom.
Are there any other trees
that any of you, uh,
think you could recognize
from quite a long way away?
I want--
I want to see a sketch
of Eric's, please.
What?
I-- I want to see a sketch
of Eric's.
Nudge, nudge.
A what? A sketch?
-Eric's written--
-I've written a sketch.
Nudge, nudge.
E-Eric's written a sketch.
-Nudge, nudge.
Is your wife a--?
A goer, eh?
Know what I mean?
Nudge, nudge. Nudge, nudge.
Know what I mean? Say no more.
-Know what I mean?
-I beg your pardon?
Your wife. Does she, uh--?
Does she go?
Eh? Eh? Eh? Know what I mean?
Know what I mean?
Nudge, nudge.
-Say no more.
-Well, she sometimes goes, yes.
I'll bet she does. I'll bet
she does. I'll bet she does.
Know what I mean?
Nudge, nudge.
I'm sorry, I-- I don't--
Don't quite follow you.
Oh, follow me? Follow me?
I like that. That's good.
A nod's as good as a wink
to a blind bat, eh? Eh?
Are you--? Are you trying
to sell something?
Selling, selling.
Very good. Very good.
Oh, wicked. Wicked.
You're wicked, eh?
Know what I mean?
Nudge, nudge.
Nudge, nudge. Nudge, nudge.
Say no more.
-Say no--?
-Ah! Oh! Strewth.
Your wife. Is she, uh...?
Is she a sport, eh?
Well, yes.
She likes sport, yes.
I'll bet she does.
She's very fond of cricket,
as a matter of fact.
Who isn't, eh?
Know what I mean?
Likes games, likes games.
Knew she would.
She's been around, eh?
Been around?
Yes, she's traveled.
She's from Purley.
Oh! Oh! Say no more.
Say no more. Say no more.
Purley? Say no more.
Purley, eh? Know what I mean?
Know what I mean?
Say no more.
Your wife interested
in, uh...?
[CLICKS]
...photographs, eh?
Know what I mean? Photographs?
He asked him knowingly.
-Photography?
-Yes.
Nudge, nudge. Snap, snap.
Grin, grin. Wink, wink.
Say no more.
Hol-- Holiday snaps?
Could be. Could be taken
on a holiday. Could be, yes.
Uh, swimming costumes.
You know what I mean?
Candid photography. You know
what I mean? Nudge, nudge.
No, no.
We don't have a camera.
Ah. Still...
Wagh! Eh?
Wagh-ha-ha-ha.
Eh?
Look, are you insinuating
something?
[CHUCKLING]
Oh.
-Oh, yes.
-Well?
Well, I mean, uh--
I mean, you're a man
of the world, aren't you?
I mean, uh, you've, uh--
You've been there,
haven't you?
I mean,
you've been around, eh?
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, like,
you've, uh, I--
You've--
You've done it.
I mean, you-- I mean, like,
you know, you've--
You've slept...
with a lady.
-Yes.
-What's it like?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[♪]
-[LION ROARS]
-[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMS]
[YELPS]
ANNOUNCER:
The larch.