[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
[PANTING]
It's...
NARRATOR:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
♪ And did those teeth
In ancient time ♪
♪ Walk upon England's
Mountains green? ♪
Well, hello there again,
ladies and gentlemen.
At this time, we'd like
to up the tempo a little,
change the mood.
We've got a number requested
by Pip, Pauline,
Nigel, Tarquin,
and old Spotty,
Tarquin's mother.
It's a little number
specially written
for the pubescence
of ex-king Zog of Albania.
And it's entitled
"Art Gallery."
Hope you like it.
Hello, Marge.
Oh, hello, Janet.
How are you, love?
Fancy seeing you.
How's little Ralph?
Oh, don't ask me.
He's been nothing
but trouble all morning.
Stop it, Ralph. Stop it.
[SLAPS]
Same as my Kevin.
Nothing but trouble.
Leave it alone.
[SLAPS]
He's just been in
the Florentine Room and
smeared tomato ketchup
all over
Raphael's Baby Jesus.
Oh, dear.
Put that Baroque masterpiece
down.
Well, we've just come
from the Courtauld,
and Ralph smashed
every exhibit but one
in the Danish contemporary-
sculpture exhibition.
Just like my Kevin.
-Show him an exhibition...
-Really.
...of early 18th-century
Dresden pottery
and he goes berserk.
No. I said no,
and I meant no.
[SLAPS]
This morning we were viewing
the early Flemish masters
of the Renaissance
and Mannerist schools,
when he takes out
his black aerosol
and squirts Vermeer's
Lady At A Window.
Still. Still, it's not as bad
as spitting, is it?
No. Well, Kevin knows--
[SLAPS]
--if he spits at a painting,
I'll never take him
to an exhibition again.
Ralph used to spit.
He could hit a van Gogh
at 30 yards. Yes.
But he knows now it's wrong,
don't you, Ralph?
Ralph. Stop it. Stop it.
Stop chewing that Turner.
You are.
You're a naughty, naughty,
vicious little boy.
[SLAPPING]
-[SLAPS]
-Oh, look at that.
The Fighting Temeraire
ruined. What shall I do?
Well, don't do
a thing with it, love.
Just put it in the bin
over there.
-Really?
-Yes. Take my word for it,
Marge.
Kevin's eaten most
of the early 19th-century
British landscape artists,
and I've learned not to worry.
As a matter of fact,
I feel a bit peckish myself.
Yes. I never--
I never used to like Turner.
No.
I don't know much about art,
but I know what I like.
Yes.
[MUMBLES]
I think Utrillo's brushwork
is fantastic.
But it doesn't always agree
with me.
[HICCUPS, GRUNTS]
Not after a Rubens, anyway.
Mm. All those cherries.
[GROANS, GRUNTING]
Got Vermeer all down me shirt.
[GROANS]
Watteau, dear?
What a terrible joke.
But it's my only line.
All right,
you didn't have to say it.
-You could've kept quiet
for a change.
-But it's my only line.
That's typical.
Talk, talk,
natter, natter.
♪ Bring me my arrows ♪
♪ Of desire ♪
♪ Bring me my spear ♪
♪ O clouds unfold ♪
♪ Bring me my chariot of fire ♪
COLONEL:
Right, cut to me.
As officer commanding
the regular army's
Advertising Division,
I object, in the strongest
possible terms,
to this obvious reference
to our own slogan,
"It's a dog's life--
Eh, man's life.
--in the modern army."
And I warn this program
that any recurrence
of this sloppy, long-haired,
civilian plagiarism
will be dealt with
most severely.
Right, now,
on the command, "cut,"
camera will cut to camera two.
All right, director.
COLONEL:
Wait for it.
Camera, cut.
This is my only line.
MAN 1: Pathetic.
MAN 2: Aw!
MAN 3: Aw!
Well, it's my only line.
-MAN 1: No good. It's pathetic.
-[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
[CHOIR SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
Hmm.
[SEA GULLS SQUAWKING]
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
[♪]
[BURLESQUE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKER]
[CROWD CHEERING]
WOMAN:
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
Now, quiet. Wait a minute.
I've already warned
this program
about infringing the army
copyright of our slogan:
"It's a pig's life--
Man's life.
--in the modern army."
And I'm warning you,
if it happens again,
I shall come down on this
program like a ton of bricks.
Right.
Carry on, sergeant major.
Sir.
-Good evening, class.
-ALL: Good evening.
-Where's all the others, then?
-ALL: Not here.
I can see that.
What's the matter with them?
ALL:
Don't know.
Perhaps they've got flu.
Flu? Flu?
They've been eating
too much fresh fruit.
Right. Now, self-defense.
Tonight, I shall be carrying on
from where I got to last week
when I was showing you
how to defend yourself
against anyone
who attacks you
armed with a piece
of fresh fruit.
[ALL GROAN]
You promised you wouldn't
do fruit this week.
-What do you mean?
-We done fresh fruit
the last nine weeks.
What's wrong with fruit?
Think you know it all, eh?
Can we do something else
for a change?
Like someone who attacks you
with a pointed stick?
Pointed sticks?
Oh, oh, oh. We want to learn
how to defend ourselves
against pointed sticks,
do we?
Getting all high-and-mighty,
eh?
Fresh fruit not good enough
for you, eh?
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Well, I'll tell you something,
my lad.
When you're walking home
tonight
and some homicidal maniac
comes after you
with a bunch of loganberries,
don't come crying to me.
Right, the passion fruit.
When your assailant
lunges at you
with a passion fruit, thus:
ALL:
We've done the passion fruit.
-What?
-We've done the passion fruit.
We done oranges,
apples, grapefruits--
Whole and segments.
--pomegranates,
greengages.
Grapes,
passion fruit.
-Lemons.
-Plums.
Yeah,
and mangoes in syrup.
How about cherries?
ALL:
We done them.
-Red and black?
-ALL: Yes.
All right, then.
Bananas.
[ALL GROAN]
-We haven't done them, have we?
-No.
Right. Bananas.
How to defend yourself against
a man armed with a banana.
Here, you, take this.
Now, it's quite simple
to defend yourself
against the banana fiend.
First of all, you force him
to drop the banana.
Next, you eat the banana,
thus disarming him.
You have now rendered him
helpless.
Suppose he's got a bunch?
Shut up.
Supposing he's got
a pointed stick.
Shut up.
Right, now, you, Mr. Apricot.
-Harrison.
-Oh, Mr. Harrison.
Come at me with that banana.
Come on, attack me with it.
As hard as you like. Come on.
No, no, no, no, no.
Put something into it
for God's sake.
Hold it like that:
Scream. Now, come on.
Come on, attack me.
Come on, come on.
-[SCREAMS]
-Come on.
Now...
Now I eat the banana.
He's dead.
You shot him.
-He's completely dead.
-Completely dead.
-You've shot him.
-Right, right.
I have now eaten the banana.
The deceased Mr. Apricot
is now disarmed.
You shot him.
You shot him dead.
Well, he was attacking me
with a banana.
Well, you told him to.
Look, I'm only doing me job.
I have to show you
how to defend yourself
against fresh fruit.
And pointed sticks.
Shut up.
Supposing someone come at you
with a banana
and you haven't got a gun.
Run for it.
Well, you could stand and--
Could stand and scream for help.
Yeah, yeah. You try that with
a pineapple down your windpipe.
-Pineapple?
-Where? Where? Where?
Nowhere.
I was just saying "pineapple".
Blimey, I thought my number
was on that one.
What, on the pineapple?
-Where? Where?
-No, no.
I was just repeating it.
Oh, I see. Right. Whoa. Uh,
that's the banana then.
Next, the raspberry.
Harmless-looking thing,
isn't it?
-Now, you, Mr. Tinned-Peach--
-Thompson.
Mr. Thompson, come at me
with that raspberry.
Come on, be as vicious
as you like with it.
-No.
-Why not?
-You'll shoot me.
-I won't.
You shot Mr. Harrison.
That was self-defense.
Come on.
I promise I won't shoot you.
You promised you'd tell us
about pointed sticks.
Shut up. Now, brandish that--
Brandish that raspberry.
Come on, be as vicious
as you like with it. Come on.
-No. Throw the gun away.
-I haven't got a gun.
-Oh, yes, you have.
-I haven't.
You have.
You shot Mr. Harrison with it.
Oh, that gun.
-Throw it away.
-All right.
How to defend yourself
against a raspberry,
without a gun.
-You were gonna shoot me!
-I wasn't, I wasn't, I wasn't.
-You were.
-No, I wasn't. Come on.
Come on, you worm.
You miserable little man.
Come at me, then. Come on,
do your worst, you worm.
[SCREAMS]
If anyone ever attacks you
with a raspberry,
simply pull the lever,
and the 16-ton weight
will drop on his head.
I learnt that in Malaya.
Suppose you haven't got
the 16-ton weight.
Well, that's planning,
isn't it? Forethought.
Well, how many 16-ton weights
are there?
Look. Look, smarty pants.
The 16-ton weight
is just one way--
Just one way.
--of killing
the raspberry killer.
There are millions
of others.
-Like what?
-Shoot him.
Well, supposing you
haven't got a gun or
a 16-ton weight.
All right, clever dick.
You two, come at me
with raspberries.
There you are,
a whole basket each.
Come on.
Come at me with them.
-No gun?
-No.
-No 16-ton weight?
-No pointed stick?
-Shut up.
-No rocks up in the ceiling?
-No.
You won't kill us?
-I won't kill you.
-Promise?
I promise I won't kill you.
Now, are you gonna attack me?
-All right.
Right, now,
don't rush me this time.
I'm gonna turn me back,
so you can stalk me, right?
Come up as quietly as you can,
right, close-up behind me.
Then in with the raspberries,
right?
Start moving.
Now, the first thing to do
when you're being stalked
by an ugly mob
with raspberries
is to release
the tiger.
-[GROWLS]
-[BOTH SCREAMING]
The great advantage
of the tiger in unarmed combat
is that it not only eats
the raspberry-laden foe
but also the raspberries.
The tiger, however,
does not relish the peach.
The peach assailant should be
attacked with a crocodile.
Right. Now, the rest of you,
I know you're there.
Lurking under the floorboards
with your damsons
and your prunes.
Hiding behind the wall bars
with your quinces.
Well, I'm ready for you.
I've wired myself up
to 200 tons of gelignite.
And if any of you so much
as tries anything,
we'll all go up together.
I warned you. I warned you.
Right, that's it.
[GRUNTS]
Say, have I shown you
my last operation?
Now, we've got to find
that tumor.
[MUMBLING]
A-ha!
Now, where does it go?
[MUTTERING]
Uh, no.
No, no.
[GLASS SHATTERING, RESONATING]
MAN:
Bloody hell.
[MAN HUMMING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
It's a lot of clothing, sir.
♪ And did those feet ♪
♪ In ancient times ♪
♪ Walk upon England's
Mountains green? ♪
Well, now we'd like to alter
the mood a little.
We'd like to bring
you something for Mum and Dad,
Annie and Roger,
Mazarin and Louis,
and all of Versailles.
It's a little number called
"England's Mountains Green."
Hope you like it.
♪ And did those feet ♪
♪ In ancient time-- ♪
[SHEEP BRAYING]
Yes, you know, it's
a man's life in England's
mountains green.
What? I heard that,
I heard that.
I'm going to stop
this sketch now.
And if there's any more
of this,
I'm going to stop
the whole program.
I thought it was supposed
to be about teeth.
Why can't you do something
about teeth? Go on.
What about my rustic
monologue?
I'm not sleeping
with that producer again.
ANNOUNCER:
Excitement.
Drama.
Action.
Violence.
Fresh fruit. Passion.
Thrills.
Spills.
Romance.
Adventure.
All the things you can
read about in a book.
Ah. Oh.
Good morning.
I'd like to buy a book,
please.
Well, I'm afraid
we don't have any.
-[CLEARS THROAT]
-I'm sorry?
Uh, we don't have any books.
We're fresh out of them.
Good morning.
What are all these?
All what?
Oh, all these... these...
[CHUCKLES]
You're referring to...
to these, um...
-books.
-Yes.
They're, um...
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
They're all sold.
Good morning.
What, all of them?
Every single one of them.
Not a single one of 'em
in an unsold state.
-Good morning.
-Who to?
-What?
-Who are they sold to?
Oh, various...
[SIGHS]
Good Lord, is that the time?
Oh, my goodness.
I must close for lunch.
-It's only half past 10.
-Ah, yes.
Well, I feel rather peckish.
Very peckish.
I don't suspect
I'll open again today.
I think I'll have
a really good feed.
Look at that lovely bookshop
just across the road.
They've got a much better
selection than we've got,
probably at ridiculously
low prices.
Just across the road there.
Good morning.
But I was told to come here.
Well...
Well, I see.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I hear the gooseberries
are doing well this year.
And so are the mangoes.
I'm sorry?
Oh, I was just saying,
thinking of the weather,
I hear the gooseberries
are doing well this year.
And so are the mangoes.
Hm. Mine aren't.
-Go on.
-What?
Go on. "Mine aren't, but..."
What?
Aren't you gonna say,
"Mine aren't,
but the Big Cheese gets his
-at low tide tonight"?
-No.
Oh, ah. Good morning.
Wait. Who sent you?
Uh, the little old lady
in the sweet shop.
She didn't have a dueling scar
here and a hook?
-No.
-No, of course not.
I was thinking of
somebody else. Good morning.
Wait a minute.
There's something
going on here.
What? Where? You didn't
see anything, did you?
No, but I think there's
something going on here.
No, no, well,
there's nothing going on here,
and he didn't see anything.
Good morning.
There is something going on.
No, there is nothing going on.
Please believe me,
there is absolu-lu-lu-lutely
nothing going on.
Is there anything going on?
No, there's nothing going on.
-See? There's nothing going on.
-Who was that?
[STAMMERING]
That-- My aunt.
What was this book you wanted?
Quickly. Quickly.
Oh. Uh, well, I'd like
to buy a copy
of An Illustrated History
of False Teeth.
My God, you've got guts.
What?
-Just how much do you know?
-What about?
Are you from the British
Dental Association?
No, I'm a tobacconist.
-Get away from that door.
-I'll just go over--
Stay where you are.
You'll never leave
this bookshop alive.
-Why not?
-You know too much,
my dental friend.
-I don't know anything.
-Come clean.
You're a dentist, aren't you?
No, I'm a tobacconist.
A tobacconist who just happens
to be buying a book on teeth?
-Yes.
-Ha-ha-ha.
Drop that gun,
Stapleton.
Lafarge.
-There is something going on.
-No, there isn't.
Okay, Stapleton, this is it.
Where's Mahoney hidden
the fillings?
Uh, what fillings?
You know which fillings,
Stapleton.
Upper right, two and four,
lower right, three,
lower left, one.
Come on. Remember
what happened to Nigel?
What happened to Nigel?
Orthodontic Jake gave him
a gelignite mouthwash.
-I knew there was something
going on.
-There isn't.
Come on, Stapleton.
The fillings.
They're at 22 Wimpole Street.
Don't play games
with me.
Ow!
All right, 22A Wimpole Street.
-That's better.
-But you'll need
an appointment.
Okay. Brian, make with
the appointment, baby. No gas.
Eh. Not so fast, Lafarge.
LAFARGE:
Van der Berg.
Yes. Now, drop the roscoe.
-There is something going on.
-No, there isn't.
Nurse, get the guns.
-Who's that?
-That's Van der Berg.
He's on our side.
All right, get up
against the wall, Lafarge.
-And you too, Stapleton.
-Me?
-Yes.
-You dirty, double-crossing rat.
What's happened?
-He's two-timed me.
-Bad luck.
All right.
Where are the fillings?
[PANTING]
Answer me.
Where are they?
This is quite exciting.
Not so fast.
ALL: Brian!
Ooh! What's that?
ALL:
It's a bazooka.
All right, get against the wall,
Van der Berg, and you, nurse.
And the first one
to try anything
moves to a practice
six-feet underground.
This is an anti-tank gun,
and it's loaded.
And you've just got
five seconds to tell me:
What ever happened
to Baby Jane?
ALL:
What?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
My mind's wandering.
I've had a terrible day,
I really have.
[CLEARS THROAT]
You've got five seconds
to tell me...
I've forgotten.
The five seconds haven't
started yet, have they?
Only we don't know
the question.
Was it about Vogler?
No, no, no. You've got five
seconds to tell me...
-About Nigel?
-No, no.
-Bronski?
-The fillings!
-Oh, yes, the fillings,
of course.
-How stupid of me.
Ha-ha-ha.
-[CHATTERING]
Right,
you've got five seconds.
Where are the fillings?
Five...
four...
three...
two, one...
zero.
Zero.
Oh, I've forgotten
to fire it.
[LAUGHS]
Sorry.
Silly day. All right.
Five, four,
three, two, one--
Drop the bazooka, Brian.
ALL:
The Big Cheese.
I'm glad you could all come
to my little party.
And Flopsy's glad too,
aren't you, Flopsy?
Aren't you, Flopsy?
That will teach you
to play hard-to-get.
There, poor Flopsy's dead,
and never called me mother.
And soon you will all be dead.
-[ALL HISSING]
-Dead, dead, dead.
And because I'm so evil,
you will all die the slow way:
under the drill.
Uh, it's 1:00.
So it is. Lunch break,
everyone. Back here at two.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Hello.
Give me the British
Dental Association
and fast.
You see, I knew there was
something going on.
Of course, the Big Cheese
made two mistakes.
First of all,
he didn't recognize me,
Lemming.
Arthur Lemming,
special investigator,
British Dental Association.
And second-- Spit.
--by the time I got back
from lunch,
I had every dental surgeon
in SW1
waiting for them all
in the broom cupboard.
Funny, isn't it,
how naughty dentists
always make
that one fatal mistake?
Bye, for now.
Keep your teeth clean.
♪ Lemming, Lemming
Lemming of the BDA ♪
♪ Lemming, Lemming ♪
♪ Lemming of the BD
Lemming of the BD, BD, BDA ♪
ANNOUNCER:
Right. No, I warned you.
No, I warned you
about the slogan.
Right. That's the end.
Stop the program. Stop it.
[WHISTLES]
[GROANING]
[GRUNTS]
[♪]
COLONEL:
Ah. Got you, me lad.
Still acting, eh?
Over you go.
[YELPS]