[BREATHING HEAVILY]
It's...
NARRATOR:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[THEME MUSIC]
[WHOOSHING]
[THUD]
Oh, good. That'll
be the vet, dear.
I'd better go
and let him in.
It's the vet, dear.
Oh. Very glad indeed
you could come around, sir.
Not at all. Now what
seems to be the problem?
You can tell me.
I'm a vet, you know.
See?
Tell him, dear.
Well--
It's our cat.
He doesn't do anything.
He just sits out all day
on the lawn.
Is he...
dead?
-Oh.
-Oh, no.
Thank God for that.
For one ghastly moment,
I thought I was...
too late.
If only more people would call
in the nick of time.
He just sits there,
all day and every day.
-And at night.
-Shh.
Almost motionless.
We have to take
his food out to him.
-And his milk.
-Shh.
He doesn't do anything.
He just sits there.
Are you at your wits' end?
Definitely, shh, yes.
Hmm. I see. Well, I think
I may be able to help you.
You see...
your cat is suffering
from what we vets
haven't found a word for.
His condition is typified
by total physical inertia,
absence of interest
in its ambiance.
What we vets
call "environment."
Oh.
Failure to respond
to the conventional
external stimuli.
A ball of string,
a nice... juicy mouse, a bird.
To be blunt,
your cat is in a rut.
It's the old
stockbroker syndrome.
The suburban
fin-de-siècle ennui.
Angst, Weltschmerz,
call it what you will.
Moping.
In a way, in a way. Hmm.
Moping, I must remember that.
Now... what's to be done?
Tell me, sir, have
you confused your
cat recently?
-Well, we--
-Shh. No.
Yes. Well, I think
I can definitely say
that your cat badly needs
to be confused.
-What?
-Shh. What?
Confused. To shake it out
of its state of complacency.
I'm afraid... I'm not personally
qualified to confuse cats,
but I can recommend
an extremely good service.
Here is their card.
Oh. "Confuse-a-Cat, Limited."
"Confuse-a-Cat, Limited."
-Oh.
-Mmm.
[♪]
[SHOUTING]
Squad! Eyes front!
Stand at ease!
Cat-confusers,
confusers-hut!
[BRAKES SCREECH]
Now, men, we've got a pretty
difficult cat to confuse today
so let's get straight onto it.
Jolly good.
-Thank you, sergeant.
-Sir.
Confusers, get into the van
and fetch out--!
Wait for it!
Fetch out
the funny things!
Move, move,
move, move.
One, two, one, two,
get those funny things off!
[HAMMERING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
Men, fall in!
Stage ready
for confusing, sir!
Very good.
Carry on, sergeant.
Left turn!
Double march!
ALL:
Tum-hum, tum-hum,
tum-hum, tum-hum.
Right, men.
Confuse the... cat.
[♪]
[GROWLING]
Arr!
Ladies and gentlemen...
[♪]
[DRUMROLL]
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
I hope to God
it works.
Anyway, we shall know
any minute now.
Oh! I can't
believe it.
Neither can I.
It's just like
the old days.
He's cured.
Oh, thank you, general.
What can we ever do
to repay you?
No need to, sir.
It's all in a day's work for:
Confuse-a-Cat.
[♪]
[HUMMING]
[MAN HUMMING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
-Have you read this, sir?
-Nope.
Oh, yes, yes. Yes.
Anything to declare?
Yes. No! No. No.
No, nothing to declare, no.
Nothing in my suitcase,
no, no.
No, uh, watches, cameras,
radio sets?
Oh, yes, four watches.
No! No, no.
No, one wa-- One watch.
No, no!
Not even one watch.
No, no watches at all.
No precision watches, no.
Which, uh, country
have you been visiting, sir?
Switzerland. Ah, no! No.
Not Switzerland. Ha.
Uh, not Switzerland,
began with an "S",
but wasn't Switzerland.
Oh, what could it be?
Terribly bad memory for names.
Oh. It was... Um...
What's the name of that
country where they don't make
watches at all?
-Spain?
-Spain, that's it. Spain, yep.
Mm-hm.
Label says "Zurich", sir.
Yes, well.
It was Spain, then.
Zurich's in Switzerland, sir.
Switzerland, yeah.
Hmm, hmm.
-Switzerland.
-Yeah.
Where they make
the watches.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, yeah.
[HUMMING]
♪ Da dum, da dee dee ♪
Oh, nice shed
you've got here. Hm.
You, uh, got any
Swiss currency, sir?
No, just the watches.
Ah! Just my watch.
Just my watch.
Uh, my watch
on the currency.
I've kept a watch
And I've watched it.
And I haven't got any.
That came out a bit glib,
didn't it?
-[CHUCKLES]
-[LOUD RINGING]
You got an alarm clock
in there, sir?
No, no, heavens no!
No, no.
Just vests. Heh.
[BANGS BAG,
RINGING STOPS]
Sounded a bit like
an alarm clock going off.
Well, it can't have been.
It must have been a vest.
Uh...go-- Going off.
Going off?
[CHIMING]
All right.
I confess, I'm a smuggler.
This whole case is crammed full
of Swiss watches and clocks.
I've been purposely trying
to deceive Her Majesty's
Customs and Excise.
I've been a bloody fool.
I don't believe you, sir.
It's true. I'm, uh,
guilty of smuggling.
Don't give me
that, sir.
You couldn't smuggle a piece
of grease-proof paper,
let alone a case
full of watches.
What do you mean?
I've smuggled watches
before, you know.
I've smuggled bombs, cameras,
microfilms,
aircraft components.
You name it,
I've smuggled it.
You're wasting our time.
Move along, please--
No, no, look at this.
Look at this.
Look, for all I know, sir,
you could've bought these
in London
before you ever went
to Switzerland.
What? I wouldn't buy
2000 clocks.
People do.
Now close your case.
Move along please, go on.
Don't waste our time.
We're out to catch
the real smugglers.
I am a real smuggler!
I'm a smuggler, everybody!
-Eric, take him out.
-Don't you understand?!
I'm a smuggler!
I'm a lawbreaker!
Poor fellow.
I think he needs help.
Right, cut
the wisecracks, vicar.
Get in the search room
and strip.
Well, to discuss
the implications
of that sketch,
and to consider
the moral problems
raised by the law-enforcement
methods involved,
we have a duck,
a cat and a lizard.
Now, first of all,
I'd like to put this question
to you please, lizard.
How effective do you consider
the legal weapons
employed by legal Customs
officers nowadays?
Oh, while you're thinking
about that, heh,
I'd like to bring the duck
in here and ask her,
if possible,
to clarify the whole question
of currency restrictions
and Custom regulations
in the world today.
Heh. Perhaps the cat
would rather answer that?
No? Lizard?
No. Ahem.
Well, um...
Let's ask the
man in the street
what he thinks.
I am not a man,
you silly-billy.
I'm not in the street,
you fairy.
Well, uh, speaking
as a man in the street--
Whaa!
What was the question again?
NEWSCASTER:
Just how relevant
are contemporary
Customs regulations
and currency restrictions
in a modern, expanding
industrial economy?
Oh, never mind.
Well, I think Customs men
should be armed
so they can kill people
carrying more than
200 cigarettes.
Well, I-I think that, uh,
nobody who has gone abroad
should be allowed
back in the country.
I mean, uh, blimey!
Blimey! If they're not
keen enough to stay here
when they're here,
why should we allow 'em back,
huh, at the taxpayers' expense?
I mean, be fair.
I mean, I don't
eat squirrels, do I?
I mean, well,
perhaps I do, one or two,
but there's no law
against that, is there?
It's a free country.
I mean, if I want to eat
a squirrel now and again,
that's me own business,
isn't it?
I mean, I'm no
racialist. I...
Oh. Oh.
[GROANING]
I think it's silly to ask
a lizard
what it thinks, anyway.
NEWSCASTER:
Why?
I mean, they should
have asked...
Margaret Drabble.
Well, I think, uh, Customs
people are quite necessary,
and I think they're doing
quite a good job, really.
Check.
[LOUD BANGING ON DOOR]
-Door's open.
-Oh, yes.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
My name's Police Constable
Henry Thatcher,
and this is a raid.
I have reason to believe
that there are certain
substances on the premises.
What sort of substances,
officer?
Uh, certain substances.
Well, what sort of
certain substances?
Uh, certain substances
of an illicit nature.
Uh, could you be
more specific?
I beg your pardon?
Uh, could you be
clearer?
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Uh, certain substances
on the premises
to be removed
for clinical tests.
Have you got anything
particular in mind?
-Well, what have you got?
-Nothing, officer.
You are Sandy Camp, the actor?
-Yes.
-I must warn you, sir,
that outside
I have police dog Josephine,
who is not only armed
and trained to sniff out
certain substances,
but is also a junkie.
What are you after?
Oh! Oh, oh! Oh!
Oh, oh, oh! Oh! Oh!
I've--
Here is a brown paper bag
I have found on the premises.
I must confiscate this, sir,
and take it with me
for clinical examination.
Wait a minute. You just
got that out of your pocket.
-What?
-Well, what's in it, anyway?
Sandwiches?
Blimey. Whatever did I
give the wife?
WOMAN:
"Dear BBC,
East Grinstead, Friday.
I feel I really must write
and protest about that sketch.
My husband, in common
with a lot of people
of his age, is 50.
For how long are we
to put up with these things?
Yours sincerely,
E.B. Debenham, Mrs."
MAN:
"Dear Freddy Grisewood,
Bagshot, Surrey.
As a prolific letter-writer,
I feel I must protest
about the previous letter.
I am nearly 60
and am quite mad,
but I do enjoy listening
to the BBC Home Service.
If this continues to go
on unabated, Dunkirk,
dark days of the war,
backs to the wall,
Alvar Liddell, Berlin airlift,
moral upheaval of Profumo case,
young hippies roaming
the streets, raping,
looting and killing.
Yours etc., Brigadier
Arthur Gormanstrop, Mrs."
Well, I think they should
attack things like that.
With satire.
I mean, Ned Sherrin.
Fair's fair.
I think people should
be able to make up
their own minds for me.
Well, I think they should attack
the fuddy-duddy attitudes
of the lower middle classes,
which permit
the establishment to survive
and keep the mores
of the whole country
back where they were
in the 19th century,
and the ghastly days
of the pre-sexual revolution.
Well, that's, uh,
very interesting,
because, uh, I am, in fact,
made entirely of wood.
Well, I think they should attack
the lower classes,
uh, first with bombs and
rockets, destroying their homes,
and then when they
run helpless into the streets,
uh, mowing them down
with machine guns.
Uh, and then, of course, uh,
releasing the vultures.
I know these views
aren't popular,
but I have never courted
popularity.
I think there should be
more race prejudice.
Less.
Less race prejudice.
...and several
butchers' aprons.
In Fulham this morning,
a jeweler's shop
was broken into,
and jewelry to the value
of £2000 stolen.
Police have issued
this picture of a man
they wish to interview.
The man is in his late 20s,
wearing a grey suit,
a white shirt and
a floral tie.
Would anyone who sees this man,
or can give any information
about his whereabouts,
contact their nearest
police station.
Ah. Oh, we've just heard that
police have detained the man
they wished to interview
in connection
with the jewel robbery.
Uh, but after questioning,
police have ruled him out
of their enquiries
and released him.
Sport.
Uh, they say, however,
that acting on
his information,
they now wish to interview
a newsreader
in the central London area.
Uh, police are concentrating
their enquiries
on the British Broadcasting
Assoc--
Excuse me a minute.
We understand a man
is now helping police
with their enquiries.
And that is the end
of the news.
And now, Match of the Day.
-[ENGINE REVS]
-[MOANS]
[KNOCKING]
Uh, I'm--
I'm terribly sorry.
It-- It's not, in fact,
Match of the Day,
it is, in fact,
edited highlights
of tonight's romantic movie.
Uh...sorry.
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
On BBC2, Joan Bakewell
will be talking
to Michael Dean
about what makes
exciting television.
[MOANING]
Uh, sorry about all that.
And now, uh,
back to the movie.
-Oh. Oh, Bevis.
-Oh, my darling.
-Oh, oh. Should we?
-Well, why not?
Oh. Be gentle
with me.
[♪]
Oh, Bevis. Are you going
to do anything
or are you just going to
show me films all evening?
-Just one more, dear.
-Oh!
[♪]
Wow, Charles Atlas,
with the world's
most perfectly developed body.
Tired of being pushed around?
Would you like to do
some pushing around instead?
Would you like a body
that can't fail to
attract women?
[SHRIEKING]
ATLAS:
A body that is
the envy of other men?
Oh, I must
get one of those.
Then let me have your skinny,
scrawny, little body
for just 15 minutes
a day.
Oh, I've heard that one
before, ducky. Ugh.
Let me slap 50 pounds
of he-man muscles on you.
ATLAS:
Thick, Herculean arms,
a deep, massive chest,
atomic-powered legs,
shoulders a yard wide,
and right in the privacy
of your own home.
What's my secret?
It's dynamo tension.
Muscles pulling against
muscles, the natural way.
Agh!
Here's living proof.
And there's no need
to stop there.
So don't delay.
Send today for my gigantic,
free, 78-page muscle-building
course.
[KNOCKING]
Postman.
And start building a body
you can be proud of.
[FLAPPING]
[♪]
[GIGGLING]
Hmm?
You know, I really enjoy
interviewing applicants
for this management
training course.
[BANGING AT DOOR]
Come in.
Ah, come and
sit down.
Uh. Thank you.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Would you mind
just standing up again
for one moment?
-Take a seat.
-I'm sorry?
Take a seat.
Ahh.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
Good morning.
Morning.
Tell me. Why do you say
"good morning"
when you know perfectly well
that it's afternoon?
Well-- Well--
Well, you said good morning.
[CHUCKLES]
Good afternoon.
Oh. Good afternoon.
Oh, dear.
Good evening.
Goodbye?
[LAUGHING]
No.
[BELL RINGING]
Aren't you going to ask me
why I rang the bell?
[STAMMERS]
Why did you ring the bell?
Why do you think
I rang the bell?
-Well--
-[SHOUTING] Five, four, three,
two, one, zero!
-Well, I-I--
-Too late.
[RINGING]
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
♪ Ah, good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
Um-- Uh, this isn't--
It is the interview
for the management training
course, is it?
-Yes. Yes, it is.
-Oh.
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
Oh, dear, I don't think
I'm doing very well.
-Why do you say that?
-Uh, well, I don't know.
Do you say it
because you didn't know?
Well, I-I-I--
I don't know.
[SHOUTING]
Five, four, three,
two, one, zero!
Right. Ahem.
[WAILS]
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Well, why do you think
I did that, then?
-Well, I don't know.
-Aren't you curious?
-Well, yes.
-Why don't you ask me?
-Well. I-- I'll--
-Name?
-What?
-Your name, please. Your name.
-Um-- Uh, David.
-David. Sure?
-Oh, yes.
-David Sure.
No, no, Thomas.
Thomas Sure.
No, no, David Thomas.
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
Oh, dear, we're back
to that again.
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
I don't know what to do
when you do that.
Well, do something.
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding ♪
[SHOUTING]
Five, four,
three, two, one!
[SHRIEKING]
-Good!
-Good?
Very good. Do it again.
[SHRIEKING]
Very good indeed.
Quite outstanding.
Uh, right. Ready now.
Right. Once more.
♪ Good night ♪
♪ A-ding-ding-ding
Ding-ding-ding-ding ♪
[SHRIEKING]
What-- What's going on?
What's going on?
You got very good marks.
Well, I don't care.
I want to know
what's going on.
I think you're deliberately
trying to humiliate people!
I'm going out to tell the police
exactly what you do to people.
And I'm going to make bloody
sure you never do this again.
There, what do you think
of that?! Huh?!
What do you
think of that?!
-Very good marks.
-Oh.
Oh. Well...
do I get the job?
Uh, well, I'm afraid not.
I'm afraid all the vacancies
were filled several weeks ago.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Hmm. Well, that was
all good fun,
and we all had
a jolly good laugh.
But I would like to assure you
that you'd never be
treated like that
if you had an interview here
at the Careers Advisory Board.
Perhaps I should
introduce myself.
I am the head of
the Careers Advisory Board.
I wanted to be a doctor,
but there we are.
I'm head of
the Careers Advisory Board.
Or a sculptor.
Something artistic.
Or an engineer,
with all those dams,
but there we are,
it's no use crying
over spilt milk.
The facts are there,
and that's that.
I'm the head of
this lousy board.
[SOBBING]
Never mind.
Now, I wonder if
you've ever considered
what a very profitable
line of work this man is in.
Burglar.
-Yes?
-Burglar, madam.
What do you want?
I want to come in
and steal a few things, madam.
Are you an encyclopedia
salesman?
No, madam, I'm a burglar.
I burgle people.
I think you're
an encyclopedia salesman.
Oh, I'm not. Open the door,
let me in, please.
If I let you in, you'll
sell me encyclopedias.
I won't, madam.
I just want to come in,
ransack the flat.
Honestly.
Promise? No encyclopedias?
None at all.
All right.
You can come in, then.
Mind you, I don't know
whether you've ever really
considered the advantages
of owning a fine set
of encyclopedias.
You know, they can do you
really wonders.
That man was a successful
encyclopedia salesman.
But not all encyclopedia
salesmen are successful.
Here is an unsuccessful
encyclopedia salesman.
Now, here are two unsuccessful
encyclopedia salesmen.
I think there's a lesson there
for all of us.
[THEME MUSIC]