[RINGING]
[PANTING]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
I thought you did that
so well, Mr. Figgis.
Could I have your autograph?
ARTHUR: Certainly, yes. Mm.
[CHIRPING]
[CLANKS]
[♪]
Beethoven, Mozart, Chopin,
Liszt, Brahms, panties--
I'm sorry.
Schumann, Schubert,
Mendelssohn and Bach.
Names that will live forever.
But there is one composer
whose name
is never included
with the greats.
Why is it the world
never remembered the name
of Johann Gambolputty de von
Ausfern Schplenden-Schlitter
Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle
Burstein von
Knackerthrasher-Applebanger
Horowitz Ticolensic
Grander-Knotty Spelltinkle
Grandlich Grumblemeyer
Spelterwasser Kurstlich
Himbleeisen-Bahnwagen
Gutenabend-Bitte
Ein Nurnburger-Bratwurstle
Gerspurten Mitz Weimache
Luber Hundsfut
Gumberaber-Schonedanker
Kalbsfleisch Mittler-Aucher
von Hautkopf of Ulm?
To do-- To do justice
to this man,
thought by many
to be the greatest name
in German Baroque music,
we present a profile
of Johann Gambolputty de von
Ausfern Schplenden-Schlitter
Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle
Burstein von
Knackerthrasher-Applebanger
Horowitz Ticolensic
Grander-Knotty Spelltinkle
Grandlich Grumblemeyer
Spelterwasser Kurstlich
Himbleeisen-Bahnwagen
Gutenabend-Bitte
Ein Nurnburger-Bratwurstle
Gerspurten Mitz Weimache
Luber Hundsfut
Gumberaber-Schonedanker
Kalbsfleisch Mittler-Aucher
von Hautkopf of Ulm.
We start with an interview
with his only surviving
relative,
Karl Gambolputty
de von Ausfern--
Yeah, I first met
Johann Gambolputty
de von Ausfern
Schplenden-Schlitter
Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle
Burstein von
Knackerthrasher-Applebanger
Horowitz Ticolensic
Grander-Knotty Spelltinkle
Grandlich Grumblemeyer
Spelterwasser Kurstlich
Himbleeisen-Bahnwagen
Gutenabend-Bitte
Ein Nurnburger-Bratwurstle
Gerspurten Mitz Weimache
Luber Hundsfut
[GURGLES]
Gumberaber-Schonedanker
Kalbsfleisch Mittler-Aucher
von Hautkopf of Ulm
when he was with his wife,
Sarah Gambolputty de von--
Yes, if-- If I may just, uh,
cut in on you there,
Herr Gambolputty de von
Ausfern Schplenden-Schlitter
Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle
Burstein von
Knackerthrasher-Applebanger
Ticolensic
Grander-Knotty Spelltinkle
Grandlich Grumblemeyer
Spelterwasser Kurstlich
Himbleeisen-Bahnwagen
Gutenabend-Bitte
Ein Nurnburger-Bratwurstle
Gerspurten Mitz Weimache
Luber Hundsfut
Gumberaber-Schonedanker
Kalbsfleisch Mittler-Aucher
von Hautkopf of Ulm,
and ask you just quickly
if there's any particular
thing that you remember
about, uh, Johann Gambolputty
de von Ausfern
Schplenden-Schlitter
Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle
Burstein von
Knackerthrasher-Apple--
[CROAKS]
--banger Ticolensic
Grander-Knotty Spelltinkle
Grandlich Grumblemeyer
Spelterwasser Kurstlich
Himbleeisen-Bahnwagen
Gutenabend-Bitte
Ein Nurnburger-Bratwurstle
Gerspurten Mitz Weimache
Luber Hundsfut
Gumberaber-Schonedanker
Kalbsfleisch Mittler-Aucher
von Hautkopf of Ulm?
[SIGHS]
A tribute
to Johann Gambolputty de von--
-Ausfern Schplenden-Schlitter--
-Crasscrenbon-Fried
Digger-Dangle-Dungle--
Dungle Burstein von
Knackerthrasher--
Applebanger Horowitz
Ticolensic--
-Grander Spelltinkle--
-Grandlich--
-Grumblemeyer--
-Spelterasser--
-Kurstlich Himbleeisen--
-Bahnwagen Gutenabend--
-Bitte--
-Nurnburger--
-Bratwurstle--
-Gerspurten--
-Mitz--
-Weimache Luber--
-Gumberaber-Schonedanker--
-Kalbsfleisch--
ALL:
Mittler-Aucher von Hautkopf--
Of Ulm.
[♪]
Ooh!
-[MUMBLING]
-Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
-[PANTING]
-[GRUNTING]
That's it.
We're not about
to allow this sort of smut
to be shown on-screen.
I must agree with the censor.
Smut and filth have no place
on the street.
Street-- On the street.
No. Smut and filth should--
[CASH REGISTER DINGS]
[♪]
All clear?
All clear, boss.
Right, this is the plan, then.
At 10:45, you, Reg,
collect me and Ken in the van
and take us round to
British jewelery center
in the High Street.
We arrive outside
the British jewelery center
at 10:50 a-of-m.
I shall then get out
of the car.
You, Reg, take it
and park it back here
in Denver Street, right?
At 10:51, I shall enter
the British jewellery center,
where you, Vic,
disguised as a customer,
will meet me
and hand me
£5.18 and 3 pence.
At 10:52, I shall
approach the counter
and purchase a watch
costing £5.18 and 3 pence.
I shall then
give the watch to you, Vic.
You will go to Norman's Garage
on East Street.
You lads come and pick me
back up here at 10:56
and we rendezvous in the back
at the Cow and Sickle, at 11:15.
All right, any questions?
We don't seem to be doing
anything illegal.
-What do you mean?
-Well, we're paying
for the watch.
Yeah.
Well, why are we paying
for the watch?
[SCOFFS]
They wouldn't give it to us
if we didn't pay for it,
would they?
-I don't like this outfit.
-Why not?
Well, we never break
the bloody law.
What do you mean?
Well, look at that
bank job last week.
What was wrong with that?
Having to go in there
with a mask on
and ask for £15
out of my deposit account,
that's what was wrong.
What are you trying to say,
Larry?
Couldn't we just steal
the watch, boss?
Oh, you dumb cluck!
We spent weeks
organizing this job.
Reg rented a room
across the road
and filmed people
going in and out every day.
Vic spent three weeks
looking at watch catalogs
till he knew the price
of each one backwards.
And I'm not going to risk
the whole raid
just for the sake
of breaking the law.
-Park on the
double-yellow line?
-No!
-Couldn't we get a dog to--?
-Here, boss.
-What's the matter with you?
I just thought, uh--
I left the car
on a meter and it's...
Overdue?
Yes, boss.
How much?
I don't know, boss. Maybe
two-- Maybe five minutes.
Five minutes overdue?!
You fool!
All right, no time to lose.
Ken, shave all your hair,
get your passport,
and meet me at this address
in Rio de Janeiro Tuesday.
Vic, go to Africa,
have plastic surgery
and meet me there.
Reg, go to Canada,
work your way south
to Nicaragua by July.
Larry, you stay here.
Give us 15 minutes,
then blow the building up.
All right? Make it fast!
-I can't blow the building up.
-Why not?
Well, it's illegal.
Oh, bloody hell.
Well, we better
give ourselves up, then.
-We can't, boss.
-Why not?
We haven't done anything
illegal.
-[GUNSHOTS]
-[ALARM RINGING]
MAN: Excuse me.
Uh, no, well,
I think, uh, being illegal
makes it more exciting.
Yeah, I agree. I mean, uh,
if you're gonna go straight,
you might as well be a--
A vicar or something.
What? What?
I agree.
If there were fewer robbers,
there wouldn't be so many
of them, numerically speaking.
I think sexual ecstasy
is overrated.
Well, how very interesting,
because I'm now made entirely
of tin.
After a few more
of these remarks,
I shall be appearing
in a sketch, so stay tuned.
It's the uniform
that puts 'em off.
That and my bad breath.
We like dressing up, yes.
Hello again. I am,
at present, still on film,
but in a few seconds, I shall
be appearing in the studio.
Thank you.
Hello.
Mr. Milton, you are
sole proprietor and owner
-of the Whizzo Chocolate
Company?
-I am.
Superintendent Parrot and I
are from the Hygiene Squad.
We want to have a word with you
about your box of chocolates
entitled the Whizzo
Quality Assortment.
Ah, yes. Heh.
If I may begin
at the beginning.
First, there is
the Cherry Fondue.
[GAGS]
This is extremely nasty,
but we can't prosecute
you for that.
-Agreed.
-Next, we have number four:
-"Crunchy Frog."
-Ah, yes.
Am I right in thinking
there's a real frog in here?
-Yes, a little one.
-What sort of frog?
A dead frog.
-Is it cooked?
-No.
What, a raw frog?
We use only the finest
baby frogs,
dew-picked
and flown from Iraq,
cleansed in the finest quality
spring water, lightly killed,
and then sealed in a succulent
Swiss, quintuple-smooth,
treble-cream,
milk-chocolate envelope
and lovingly frosted
with glucose.
That's as may be,
it's still a frog.
-What else?
-Don't you take the bones out?
If we took the bones out it
wouldn't be crunchy, would it?
Superintendent Parrot
ate one of those.
[DRY HEAVING]
Excuse me a moment.
[GRUNTS]
It says, "Crunchy Frog"
quite clearly.
Well, the superintendent thought
it was an almond whirl.
People won't expect there
to be a frog in there.
They're bound to think
it's some form of mock frog.
"Mock frog"? We use
no artificial preservatives
or additives of any kind.
Nevertheless, I must warn you
that in future,
you should delete the words
"Crunchy Frog"
and replace them
with the legend:
"Crunchy, raw, unboned, real,
dead frog" if you want
to avoid prosecution.
What about our sales?
I'm not interested
in your sales.
I have to protect
the general public.
Now, how about this one?
It was number five,
wasn't it?
Number five,
"Ram's Bladder Cup."
-[GAGS]
-Yes.
What kind of confection
is this?
We use choicest, juicy chunks
of fresh Cornish ram's bladder,
emptied, steamed,
flavored with sesame seeds,
whipped into a fondue and
garnished with lark's vomit.
"Lark's vomit"?
Correct.
Well, it don't say nothing
about that here.
Yes, it does,
on the bottom of the box,
after monosodium glutamate.
Well, I hardly think
this is good enough.
I think it would be more
appropriate if the box
bore a large red label
warning "lark's vomit."
Our sales would plummet.
Well, why don't you move
into more conventional
areas of confectionary
like praline or lime cream,
a very popular flavor,
I'm led to understand.
-I mean look at this one,
"Cockroach Cluster."
-[GAGS]
"Anthrax Ripple."
What's this one,
"Spring Surprise"?
Oh, now, that's our specialty.
Covered in darkest
creamy chocolate,
when you pop it in your mouth
steel bolts spring out
and plunge straight through
both cheeks.
Well, where's the pleasure
in that?
If people place a nice choccy
in their mouths, they don't want
their cheeks pierced.
In any case,
this is an inadequate
description of the sweetmeat.
I shall have to ask you
to accompany me to the station.
-It's a fair cop.
-Stop talking to the camera.
I'm sorry.
[COUGHS]
If only the general public
would take more care
when buying its sweeties,
it would reduce the number of
man-hours lost to the nation,
and they would spend less time
having their stomachs pumped
and sitting around
in public lavatories.
[GRUNTS]
The BBC would like
to apologize
for the extremely poor quality
of the next announcement,
only he's not at all well.
We present, "The Dull Life
of a City Stockbroker." [GAGS]
[♪]
[BOTH PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
Agh!
[EXPLOSIONS]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[GUNFIRE]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[♪]
Yes, sir, coming right up,
the theater sketch,
so don't move.
[♪]
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
Me heap want see play.
Me want play start heap soon.
Yes, well, I think
it begins in a minute.
Me heap-big fan
Cicely Courtneidge.
Yes, she's very good.
She fine actress.
She make interpretation
heap subtle.
She heap-good diction
and timing.
She make part really live
for Indian brave.
Yes. Yes, she's marvelous.
My father,
Chief Running Stag,
leader of mighty
Redfoot tribe,
him heap keen
on Michael Denison
and Dulcie Gray.
Um, do you go
to the theater a lot?
When moon high over prairie,
when wolf howl over mountain,
when mighty wind
roar through Yellow Valley,
we go Leatherhead rep,
block-booking, upper circle.
Whole tribe get in
on three and six each.
That's very good.
Stage manager, Stan Wilson,
heap-good friend
Redfoot tribe.
After show we go powwow.
Speakum with director,
Sandy Camp,
in snug bar
of Bell and Compasses.
Him mighty fine director.
Him heap famous.
Yes, well,
I-I don't know him myself.
Him say Leatherhead rep
like do play
with Redfoot tribe.
Oh, that's good.
We do Dial M for Murder.
Chief Running Elk, him kill
buffalo with bare hands,
run thousand paces
when the sun is high.
Him play
Chief Inspector Hardy.
Heap-good fine actor.
You, uh-- You do a lot
of acting, do you?
Yes, Redfoot tribe
live by acting and hunting.
-You don't fight anymore?
-Yes!
Redfoot make war.
When Chief Yellow Snake
was leader
and Mighty Eagle
was in land of forefather,
we fight Pawnee
at Oxbow Crossing.
When Pawnee steal
our rehearsal copies
of Reluctant Debutante,
we kill 50 Pawnee.
Houses heap full every night.
Heap good publicity.
I think he's about to start
now. Thank God for that.
Paleface like eat chocolate?
No, thank you very much.
Mm.
Crunchy Frog. Heap good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
before the play starts,
I would like to apologize
to you all.
But unfortunately,
Miss Cicely Courtneidge
is unable to appear,
owing to-- [GASPS]
[♪]
Oh, did you read that, Edgar?
What's that, dear?
There's been another
Indian massacre
at Dorking Civic Theatre.
About time, too, dear.
"Those who were
left alive at the end
got their money back."
Well, that's what live theater
needs, a few more massacres.
"The police are anxious to speak
to anyone who saw the crime,
ladies with large breasts,
or just anyone
who likes policemen."
Yes, policemen
make wonderful friends.
So if you are over six-feet tall
and would like a friend,
a pen friend
in the police force,
here is the address
to write to:
Mrs. Ena Frog,
8 Masonic Apron Street,
Cowdenbeath.
Remember, policemen
make wonderful friends.
So write today and take
advantage of our free officer.
Thank you.
And now for the next sketch.
[GIGGLES]
Oh. Oh, thank you.
Ooh! "A Scotsman on a Horse."
For Mrs. Emma Hamilton of
Nelson, "A Scotsman on a Horse."
[bagpipes playing]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[HARPSICHORD PLAYING]
Oh, I liked that.
I want to get one of those
for myself too, peachy-face.
[ENGINE HUMMING]
[YELPS]
[GRUNTS]
[YELLS]
MAN [ON MEGAPHONE]:
It's the police, Percy.
We know you're in there, so come
out with your hands up high
and there'll be no trouble.
[SISSY VOICE]
You'll never take me
alive, copper.
[MAN] Oh. All right.
[♪]
[SQUEAKS]
Morning, boys.
ALL:
Good morning, Mr. Saltzberg.
Sit down, sit down,
sit down, sit down.
Well, boys,
I want you to know
that I think you're the best
six writers in movies today.
And I want you to know
that I've had an idea
for the next movie
I'm gonna produce
and I want you boys
to write it.
[EXCITED CHATTER]
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, sit down, sit down,
sit down, sit down!
There'll be plenty of time
for that later on.
-Now, here's my idea--
-It's great!
You like it, huh?
-Yeah, yeah, great!
-Terrific.
Great.
Terrific.
Do you like it?
Oh, yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What do you like best
about it?
[CHUCKLES] Oh... Well, you
haven't told us what it is yet.
What?
Um... I like what he likes.
-What do you like?
-I like what he likes.
BOTH:
I like what he likes.
I'm just crazy about
what he likes.
What do you like
about it?
-I agree with them.
-Good.
Now we're getting somewhere.
Now, here's the start
of the movie:
I see snow.
-White snow.
-Think of the colors!
And in the snow,
I see a tree.
ALL:
Yes! Yes!
Wait, wait.
I haven't finished yet.
-There's more?
-By this tree, gentlemen,
I see a dog.
ALL:
Okay!
And gentlemen, this dog
goes up to the tree,
and he piddles on it.
ALL:
Hallelujah!
Have we got a movie!
He tells it the way it is!
-It's where it's at!
-This is something else!
It's out of sight!
I like it! I like it!
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah!
I promise I like it.
Sir, I don't know
how to say this,
but I've got to be
perfectly frank.
I really and truly believe
this story of yours
is the greatest story
in motion-picture history.
Get out! If there's one thing
I can't stand, it's a yes man!
Get out!
-[SOBBING]
-I'll see you never work again!
-What do you think?
-Well, I, uh--
Just because I have an idea
it doesn't mean it's great.
It could be lousy.
It could?
Yeah!
What do you think?
-It's lousy.
-There you are.
He spoke his mind.
He said my idea was lousy.
It just so happens
my idea isn't lousy,
so get out you goddamn
pinko subversive, get out!
[SOBBING]
You!
Well, I think
it's an excellent idea.
Are you a yes man?
No, no, no! I-I mean,
there may be things against it.
You think it's lousy, huh?
No, no. I-I mean,
i-it takes time.
Are you being indecisive?
[STAMMERING] Yo!
Nes! Perhaps.
Now, I hope you three gentlemen
aren't gonna be indecis--
What the hell are you doing
under that table?
-We dropped our pencils.
-Yeah.
Pencil droppers, eh?
ALL:
No, no, no!
Right.
Now, I want your opinion
of my idea.
-You!
-[MOANS]
-Has he had a heart attack?
-[BOTH STAMMERING]
If there's one thing
I can't stand, it's people
who have heart attacks!
I feel fine now.
Well, what do you think?
Uh, what? You didn't
ask me, you asked him.
-Oh, you didn't ask me,
you asked him.
-Uh, him.
-ALL: Him!
-I've changed my mind.
-I'm asking you,
the one in the middle.
-[GASPING]
The one in the middle?
-Yes, the one in the middle.
-[PHONE RINGS]
Hello? Yes, Dimitri.
No, no. Sorry. It doesn't
matter. Okay, just a second.
Go on. All right.
-What the hell are you doing?
-Uh, thinking.
Get back in those seats
immediately.
-Yeah, sure, sure, sure.
Right, you!
-[ALL GRUNTING]
The one in the middle,
what do you think?
[WHIMPERING]
-Come on!
-Splunge!
Did he say "splunge"?
-Yep.
What does "splunge" mean?
[STAMMERING] It means,
it's a great idea, but--
But possibly not.
-And I'm not being indecisive!
-Good. Right.
-What do you think?
-Uh, splunge?
-Okay.
-Yeah, splunge for me too.
So all three of you
think splunge?
-ALL: Yeah.
-Now we're getting somewhere.
No, wait! A new angle.
In the snow,
instead of the tree,
I see... Rock Hudson.
Oh, yeah! Yeah.
And instead of the dog,
I see... Doris Day.
-Oh, yes!
-And, gentlemen,
Doris Day goes up
to Rock Hudson,
and she kisses on him.
-I love it.
-It's a love story.
Intercourse Italian-style.
David Hemmings
as a hippie Gestapo officer.
Frontal nudity.
A family picture. A comedy.
And then, when Doris Day's
kissed Rock Hudson,
she says something funny...
Like...?
[STAMMERS]
"Good evening"?
Doris Day's a comedienne,
not a newsreader. Get out!
She says something funny like?
[WHIMPERS, STAMMERS]
"Splunge."
That's the stupidest idea
I ever heard! Get out!
Doris Dog kisses Rock Tree
and she says?
I can't take it anymore!
I like that! I like that,
"I can't take it anymore."
And then Rock Hudson says:
"I'm a very rich film producer
and I need a lobotomy."
And then Doris Dog says:
"I think you're very handsome
and I'm gonna
take all my clothes off."
And then Doris Dog
turns into a yak
and goes to the bathroom
on David Lemming.
No, wait, wait!
Hello? Hello?
[RINGING]
SALTZBERG:
Hello, who are you?
You're an out-of-work writer?
Well, you're fired!
Roll the credits!
Produced by
Irving C. Saltzberg, Junior,
in an Irving C. Saltzberg
Production, Ltd.
And Saltzberg Art Films,
Oil, Real Estate,
Banking
and Prostitution, Inc.
[♪]