[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Whoa!
MAN:
It's...
MEN:
It's...!
MAN:
No, no. It's...
MEN:
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
Good evening. Tonight we're
going to take a hard, tough,
abrasive look
at camel spotting.
-Hello.
-Hello, Peter.
Now, tell me,
what exactly are you doing?
Uh, well,
I'm camel spotting.
I'm spotting to see if there
are any camels that I can spot
and put them down
in my camel-spotting book.
Good. And, uh, how many camels
have you spotted so far?
Uh, well, so far, Peter,
up to the present moment,
I've spotted nearly...
ooh...
-nearly one.
-Nearly one?
-Uh, call it none.
-Fine.
-And, uh, how long
have you been here?
-Uh, three years.
So in, uh, three years
you've spotted no camels?
Yes, in only three years.
Uh, I tell a lie, four.
Be fair, five.
I've been camel spotting
for just the seven years.
Before that, of course,
I was a yeti spotter.
A yeti spotter. That must have
been extremely interesting.
Oh, it was extremely
interesting.
Very, very, uh, quite--
It was dull.
Dull, dull, dull--
Oh, God, it was dull.
Sitting in the Waterloo
waiting room.
Of course, once you've seen
one yeti, you've seen them all.
-And have you seen them all?
-Well, I've seen one.
Well, a little one. A picture
of a-- I've heard about them.
Well, now, tell me, what do
you do when you spot a camel?
Uh, I take its number.
Uh, camels don't have numbers.
Oh, well, you've got to know
where to look.
Uh, they're on the side of
the engine above the piston box.
What?
Uh, of course you've
got to make sure
it's not a dromedary,
because if it's a dromedary,
it goes in the dromedary book.
Well, how do you tell
if it's a dromedary?
Uh, well, a dromedary
has one hump,
and a camel has
a refreshment car,
buffet
and ticket collector.
Uh, Mr. Sopwith, aren't you
in fact a train spotter?
-What?
-Don't you in fact spot trains?
Oh, you're no fun anymore.
[♪]
SOLDIER:
Oh, no, Rasheed, we can't
go on meeting like this.
RASHEED:
Oh, you're no fun anymore.
LASHER:
Thirty-nine, forty.
All right, cut him down,
Mr. Fuller.
Oh, you're no fun anymore.
Now, look, if anybody else
pinches my phrase,
I'll throw them under a camel.
If you can spot one.
[SPITS, SNICKERS]
Aww.
Lady Chairman, sir,
shareholders,
ladies and gentlemen.
I have great pleasure
in announcing that
owing to a cutback
on surplus expenditure
of 12 million
Canadian dollars,
plus a refund of seven and
a half million Deutschmarks
from the Swiss branch,
and in addition adding
the debenture preference stock
of 3.75 million
to the director's reserve
currency account of 7.5 million,
plus an upward expenditure
margin of 11,500 lira
due to a rise
in capital investment
of 10 million pounds,
this firm last year made a
complete profit of a shilling.
A shilling, Wilkins?
Uh, roughly, yes, sir.
Wilkins, I am the chairman
of a multimillion-pound
corporation,
and you are a very new
chartered accountant.
Isn't it possible there may
have been some mistake?
That's very kind of you, but
I'm not ready to be chairman.
Wilkins. Wilkins, this shilling,
is it net or gross?
-It's British, sir.
-Yes.
Has tax been paid on it?
Yes, this is after tax.
Owing to the rigorous bite
of the income tax,
five pence of a further sixpence
was swallowed up in tax.
Five pence
of a further sixpence?
-Yes, sir.
-Five pence
of a further sixpence?
That's right, sir.
Then where is
the other penny?
Uh...
That makes you a penny short,
Wilkins. Where is it?
-Uh...
-Wilkins?
I embezzled it, sir.
What? All of it?
-Yes, all of it.
-You naughty person.
[CRYING]
It's my first.
Please be gentle with me.
I'm afraid it's
my unpleasant duty to
inform you that you're fired.
-Oh, please, please.
-No, out!
Yes, there's no place
for sentiment in big business.
Oh, you're no fun anymore.
I heard that.
Who said that?
-Uh, he did! He did!
-Oh, no, I didn't.
ALL:
Ooh!
Right.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
ANNOUNCER:
Here is the address
to complain to.
The Royal Frog
Trampling Institute,
16 Rayners Lane,
London, W.C. Fields.
I'll just repeat that.
Tristram
and Isolde Phillips,
7:30, Covent Garden,
Saturday, near Sunday,
and afterwards at the
Inigo Jones Fish Emporium.
They want to put
the license fee up?
And now here is a reminder
about leaving your radio on
during the night.
Leave your radio on
A little joke, a little jest.
Nothing to worry about,
ladies and gentlemen.
Now we've got some science
fiction for you, some sci-fi,
something to send
the shivers up your spine,
send the creepy crawlies
down your lager and limes.
All the lads
have contributed to it.
It's a little number entitled:
"Science Fiction Sketch."
[APPLAUDS]
NARRATOR:
The universe consists of
a billion, billion galaxies.
Seventy-seven billion miles
across.
And every galaxy is made up
of a billion, zillion stars.
And around these stars
circle a billion planets.
And of all of these planets,
the greenest
and the pleasantest
is the planet Earth,
in the system of Sol,
in the galaxy known
as the Milky Way.
And it was to this world
that creatures
of an alien planet came
to conquer and destroy
the very heart of civilization.
It was a day
like many another,
and Mr. and Mrs.
Samuel Brainsample
were a perfectly ordinary
couple,
leading perfectly ordinary
lives.
The sort of people to whom
nothing extraordinary
ever happened
and not the kind of people
to be the center
of one of the most
astounding incidents
in the history of mankind.
So let's forget about them
and follow instead
the destiny of this man.
Harold Potter, gardener
and tax official,
first victim of creatures
from another planet.
[♪]
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYING]
NEWS VENDOR:
Read all about it!
Man turns into Scotsman!
Mrs. Potter, you knew
Mr. Potter quite well,
I believe?
Oh, yes, quite well.
He was me husband.
Yeah, and, uh, he never showed
any inclination
towards being a Scotsman
before this happened?
No, no. Not at all. He was
not that sort of person.
He didn't, uh, wear a kilt
or play the bagpipes?
No, no, no, no.
He never got drunk at night or
brought home black puddings?
No, no. Not at all.
He didn't have an inadequate
brain capacity?
No, no. Not at all.
I see. So by your account,
Harold Potter was a perfectly
ordinary Englishman
without any tendency towards
being a Scotsman whatsoever?
Absolutely, yes.
Mind you, he did always
watch Doctor Finlay
on the television.
A-ha!
Well, that's it, you see.
That's how it starts.
-I beg your pardon?
-Well, you see,
"Scottishness" starts
with little things like that
and works up.
You see, people don't
just turn into a Scotsman
for no reason at all.
No further questions!
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYING]
[PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC]
Ho!
Left-hut!
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYING]
-Charles?
-Darling.
Charles?
Darling, darling.
Charles, there's something
I've got to tell you.
What is it, darling?
It's Daddy.
He's turned into a Scotsman.
What? Mr. Llewellyn?
Yes, Charles.
Help me, please help me.
But what can I do?
Well, surely, Charles,
you're the chief scientist
at the Anthropological Research
Institute at Butley Down.
An expert in
what makes people change
from one nationality
to another.
So I am.
This is right up my street.
Oh, good.
Now, first of all, why would
anyone turn into a Scotsman?
Um, for--
for business reasons?
No, no. Only because he has
no control over his own destiny.
Look, I'll show you.
-WOMAN: I see!
-Yes.
So this means that some person,
or persons unknown,
is turning all these people
into Scotsmen.
Oh, what kind of heartless
fiend could do that to a man?
I don't know.
All I know is that
these people are streaming
north of the border
at the rate of thousands
every hour.
If we don't act fast, Scotland
will be choked with Scotsmen.
Ooh!
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYING]
NARRATOR:
Soon Scotland
was full of Scotsmen.
The overcrowding
was pitiful.
Three men to a caber.
[INDISTINCT MUMBLING]
[DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE]
For the few who remained,
life was increasingly
difficult.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Charles! Thank goodness
I've found you. It's Mummy.
Hello, Mummy.
No, no. Mummy's turned
into a Scotsman.
Oh, how horrible.
Will they stop at nothing?
I don't know,
do you think they will?
I meant that rhetorically.
What does "rhetorically" mean?
It means I didn't expect
an answer.
Oh, I see.
Oh, you're so clever, Charles.
Did Mummy say anything
as she changed?
Yes. She did,
now you come to mention it.
Well, what was it?
Oh, she said: "Them."
[♪]
Is that someone at the door?
No, it's just the incidental
music for this scene.
Oh, I see.
"Them." Wait a minute.
A whole minute?
No, I meant that
metaphorically.
Them. Them. She was obviously
referring to the people
who turned her into
a Scotsman.
If only we knew
who "they" were
and why "they"
were doing it.
Who are "them"?
NARRATOR:
Then, suddenly,
a clue turned up in Scotland.
Mr. Angus Podgorny, owner
of a Dunbar menswear shop,
received an order
for 48 million kilts
from the planet Skyron
in the galaxy of Andromeda.
Angus, how are you going
to get 48 million kilts
into the van?
I'll have to do it
in two goes.
Uh, do you not ken that
the galaxy of Andromeda
is 2,200,000
light years away?
-Is that so?
-Aye.
And you've never been
further than Berwick-on-Tweed.
Aye.
But think of the money, dear.
18.10 a kilt. That's...
900,000,000,
and that's without sporrans.
Ah, I think you ought
not to go, Angus.
Ah, we would be able
to afford writing paper
with our names on it.
We would be able to buy
that extension to the toilet.
Yeah, but he hasn't signed
the order yet, has he?
-Who?
-Oh, the man from Andromeda.
Oh, well...
He wasn't, uh, really a man,
do you ken?
Not really a man?
He was as strange a thing
as ever I saw
or ever I to hope to see,
God willing.
He were a strange,
unearthly creature.
A quivering, glistening mass.
Angus Podgorny,
what do you mean?
He wasn't so much a man
as a blancmange.
-A blancmange, eh?
-WOMAN: Yes, that's right.
Uh, I was just having
a game of doubles
with Sandra and Jocasta,
Alec and David--
Hang on.
-What?
-There's five.
-Five people.
How do you play doubles
with five people?
Uh, well, we were--
Sounds a bit funny,
if you ask me,
playing doubles
with five people.
Oh, well, we often
play like that.
Jocasta plays on the side
receiving service.
-Oh, yes?
-Yes. It helps to speed
the game up
and make it a lot faster and it
means Jocasta isn't left out.
Look, are you asking me
to believe
that the five of you
was playing doubles
when on the very next court
there was a blancmange
playing by itself?
-That's right, yes.
-Well, answer me this then:
Why didn't Jocasta play
the blancmange at singles
while you and Sandra
and Alec and David
had a proper game of doubles
with four people?
Because Jocasta always
plays with us.
She's a friend of ours.
Call that friendship?
Messing up a perfectly
good game of doubles?
It's not messing it up,
officer.
We like to play with five.
Look, it's your affair if you
want to play with five people,
but don't go calling
it doubles.
-Well, no--
-Look at Wimbledon, right?
If Fred Stolle and Tony Roche
played Charlie Pasarell
and Cliff Drysdale
and Peaches Bartkowicz,
they wouldn't go
calling it doubles.
But what about the blancmange?
That could play Ann Haydon Jones
and her husband Pip.
Oh, a blancmange gave you
an order for 48 million kilts?
Aye.
And you believed it?
Aye, I did.
Oh, you're a stupid man,
Angus Podgorny.
Oh, look, woman, how many
kilts did we sell last year?
Nine and a half, that's all.
So when I get an order
for 48 million, I believe it.
You better believe it.
Even if it's from
a blancmange?
Oh, woman, if a blancmange
is prepared to come
2,200,000 light years
to purchase a kilt,
they must be fairly keen
on kilts.
So cease your prattling,
woman, and get sewing.
This could be the biggest
breakthrough in kilts
since the provost of Edinburgh
sat on a spike.
Mary, we'll be rich.
We'll be rich.
Oh, but Angus,
he hasn't given you
an earnest of his good faith.
Ah, maybe not,
but he had give me this.
Oh, what is it now?
An entry form for the British
Open Tennis Championships
at Wimbledon town,
signed and seconded.
Oh, but Angus,
you ken full well
that Scots folk don't know how
to play the tennis
to save their lives.
Aye, but I must
go though, dear.
I didn't want
to seem ungrateful.
Oh, Angus, I will not let you
make a fool of yourself.
-But I must.
-Oh, no, you'll not.
-Oh, Mary, Mary--
-[HINGES SQUEAK]
Oh, Mary, look out.
Look out!
Oh-- Ah! It's the blancmange!
[SCREAMS]
-[SQUISHY SOUNDS]
-[WET CHEWING]
Oh, uh, now this is where
Mr. Podgorny
could have saved
his wife's life.
If he had gone to the police
and told them
that he'd been approached
by unearthly beings
from the galaxy of Andromeda,
we'd have sent a man 'round
to investigate.
As it was, he did a deal
with a blancmange
and the blancmange
ate his wife.
So if you're going out,
or going on holiday,
or anything strange happens
involving other galaxies,
just nip 'round
to your local police station
and tell the sergeant on duty,
or his wife,
of your suspicions.
And the same goes for dogs.
So, I'm sorry to have
interrupted your exciting
science fiction story,
but then, crime's
our business, you know.
So carry on viewing,
and my thanks to the BBC
for allowing me to have
this little chat with you.
Good night. God bless.
Look after yourselves.
Do sit down, Mr. Podgorny.
I-- I think what's happened
is terribly,
terribly funny--
Tragic.
You must understand that
we have to catch the creature
that ate your wife
and if you could just help us
answer a few questions
we may be able to help
save a few lives.
I know this is the way your wife
would have wanted it.
Aye, I'll do my best,
sergeant.
"Detective inspector."
Detective inspector.
Now, then,
the facts are these:
You received an order
for 48 million kilts
from a blancmange
from the planet Skyron
in the galaxy of Andromeda.
You'd just shown your wife
an entry form for Wimbledon
which you'd filled in,
when you turned around
and saw her legs disappearing
into a blancmange.
-Is that correct?
-Yes, sir.
-Are you mad?
-No, sir.
Well, that's a relief,
because if you were,
your story would be
less plausible.
Now, then,
do you recognize this?
Oh, yes. That's the one
that ate my Mary.
-[SOBS]
-Good.
His name's Riley,
Jack Riley.
He's that most rare
of criminals:
a blancmange impersonator
and cannibal.
But what about
the 48 million kilts
and the galaxy of Andromeda?
I'm afraid that's just
one of his stories.
You must understand
that a blancmange
impersonator and cannibal
has to use some pretty clever
stories to allay suspicion.
-Then you mean--
-Yes.
-But-- Yes.
-How? Well--
-Not! Why?
-I'm afraid so.
-Who knows. Could be. I know.
-You think--? But--
-I know. Yes
-She was--
-Oh!
-[♪]
Good Lord, what's that?
Ah, Riley.
Come to give yourself up,
have you, Riley?
-Eh, Riley? Riley?
-[CHEWING, LIP-SMACKING]
Riley. It's not Riley!
It's an extraterrestrial being!
[SCREAMS]
So everyone in England
is being turned
into Scotsmen, right?
Yes.
Now, which is the worst
tennis-playing nation
in the world?
Um, Australia.
-No. Try again.
-Australia?
No, try again but say
a different place.
Oh, I thought you meant
I said it badly.
-Of course you didn't
say it badly. Now, hurry!
-Um... Uh...
-Czechoslovakia.
-No, Scotland.
-Of course.
-Now...
Now, these blancmanges,
apart from the one
that killed Mrs. Podgorny,
have all appeared
in which London suburb?
Finchley.
No, Wimbledon.
Now do you begin
to see the pattern?
With what sport is Wimbledon
commonly associated?
NARRATOR:
For viewers at home,
the answer is coming up
on your screens.
Those of you who wish
to play it the hard way,
stand upside down
with your head in a bucket
of piranha fish.
Here is the question
once again.
With what sport is Wimbledon
commonly associated?
-Cricket.
-No.
-Pelote?
Wimbledon is most commonly
associated with tennis.
Of course. Now I see.
Yes, it all falls into place.
The blancmanges
are really Australians
trying to get the rights
of the pelote rules
from the Czech publishers!
No, not quite.
But, uh, just look in here.
Oh...
Yes.
So these blancmanges--
Blancmange-shaped creatures
come from the planet Skyron
in the galaxy of Andromeda.
They order 48 million kilts
from a Scottish menswear shop,
turn the population of England
into Scotsmen,
well-known as the worst
tennis-playing nation on Earth,
thus leaving England empty
during Wimbledon fortnight.
Empty during
Wimbledon fortnight.
What's more, the papers
are full of reports
of blancmanges
appearing on tennis courts
up and down the country
practicing.
This can only mean one thing.
MAN (READING):
They mean to win Wimbledon!
[♪]
Well, here at Wimbledon,
it's been a most extraordinary
week's tennis.
The blancmanges have swept
the board,
winning match after match.
Here are a few of the results:
Billie Jean King
eaten in straight sets,
Laver smothered whole
after winning the first set,
and Pancho Gonzalez, serving
as well as I've ever seen him
with some superb volleys
and decisive return volleys
off the backhand,
was sucked through the net
at match point and swallowed
whole in under two minutes.
And so, here on the final day,
there seems to be
no players left
to challenge the blancmanges,
and this could be
their undoing, Dan,
as the rules of Wimbledon
state quite clearly
that there must be at least
one human being
concerned in the final.
Well, the blancmange is coming
out onto the pitch now and--
There's a human with it!
It's Angus Podgorny, the plucky
little Scottish tailor
upon whom everything depends.
And so it's Podgorny
versus blancmange
in this first ever
Intergalactic Wimbledon.
And it's blancmange
to serve.
And it's a good one!
15 - Love.
[GRUNTS, SNORTS]
And Podgorny fails
to even hit the ball,
but this is no surprise as he
hasn't hit the ball once
throughout this match.
So it's 72 match points
to the blancmange now.
Podgorny prepares
to serve again.
[BLANCMANGE SLURPS, GRUNTS]
This is indeed a grim day
for the human race, Dan.
But what's this?
Two spectators
have rushed onto the pitch
with spoons and forks.
What are they going to do?
They mean to eat
the blancmange.
Oh...
-[SLURPS]
-BOTH: Mm.
[GRUNTS]
And they're eating
the blancmange.
Yes. The blancmange
is leaving the court.
It's abandoning the game.
This is fantastic!
Mm! Mm!
NARRATOR:
Yes, it was Mr. and Mrs.
Samuel Brainsample who,
after only a brief and
misleading appearance
in the early part
of the film,
returned to save the Earth.
But why?
Oh, well you see,
we love blancmanges.
Uh, my wife makes them.
She makes blancmanges
that size?
Oh, yes, you see,
we're from the planet Skyron
in the galaxy of Andromeda,
and they're all
that size there.
We tried to tell you
at the beginning of the film,
but you just panned off us.
So the world was saved.
And Angus Podgorny
became the first Scotsman
to win Wimbledon...
fifteen years later.
[♪]