[BIRDS SINGING]
Mm.
[GLASSES CLINK]
Mm. Mm-mm.
[SIGHS]
Mm.
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
Speaking as
a public-opinion poll,
I've had enough
of the permissive society.
I haven't had enough
I would not appear
in a frontal nude scene
unless it was valid.
[GUNSHOTS]
ANNOUNCER:
In 1943,
British army officers,
working deep behind
enemy lines,
carried out one of the most
dangerous and heroic raids
in the history of warfare.
But that's as maybe.
And now...
-[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Come in.
[DOOR OPENS]
What do you want?
Uh, I'd like to leave
the army, please, sir.
Good heavens, man, why?
It's dangerous.
What?
There are people
with guns out there, sir.
-What?
-Real guns, sir.
Not toy ones, sir.
Proper ones, sir.
They've all got them.
All of them, sir.
And some of them have got tanks.
Watkins, they are on our side.
And grenades, sir.
And machine guns, sir.
So I'd like to leave, sir,
before I get killed, please.
Watkins, you've only been
in the army a day.
I know, sir,
but people get killed.
Properly dead, sir.
No barley cross fingers, sir.
Apparently, sir,
a bloke was telling me
if you're in the army,
and there's a war,
you have to go and fight.
That's true.
Well, I mean.
Blimey, I mean, if it was a big
war, somebody could be hurt.
Watkins,
why did you join the army?
For the water-skiing
and for the travel, sir.
And not for the killing, sir.
I asked them to put it
on my form, sir: "No killing."
Watkins, are you a pacifist?
No, sir.
I'm not a pacifist, sir.
I'm a coward.
That's a very silly line.
-Sit down.
-Yes, sir. Silly, sir.
Awfully bad.
[STOMPS FEET]
Two civilian gentlemen
to see you, sir.
Show them in,
please, sergeant.
Mr. Dino Vercotti
and Mr. Luigi Vercotti.
[STOMPS FEET]
Morning, colonel.
Morning, gentlemen.
Now, what can I do for you?
You've, uh...
You've got a nice army base
here, colonel.
Yes.
We wouldn't want anything
to happen to it.
-What?
-No, what my brother means is,
it would be a shame if, uh--
-Oh.
-Oh, sorry, colonel.
Well, don't worry about that.
Please sit do sit down.
No, we prefer to stand,
thank you, colonel.
All right, all right.
But what do you want?
-What do we want?
-[DINO &amp; LUIGI LAUGH]
Very good, colonel.
The colonel's a joker, Luigi.
Explain it to the colonel,
Dino.
How many tanks you got,
colonel?
About 500 altogether.
Five hundred, eh?
You ought to be careful,
colonel.
We are careful.
Extremely careful.
Because, uh, things break,
don't they?
Break?
Well, everything breaks,
don't it, colonel?
Oh, dear.
Oh, see, my brother's clumsy,
colonel.
And when he gets unhappy
he, uh, breaks things.
Like, say he don't feel
the army's playing fair by him,
uh, he may start
breaking things, colonel.
Well, what is all this about?
How many men
you got here, colonel?
Oh, uh, 7000 infantry,
600 artillery,
and, uh, two divisions
of paratroops.
Paratroops, Dino.
Oh, be a shame if someone
was to set fire to them.
-Yeah.
-Set fire to them?
Fires happen, colonel.
Things burn.
Look, what is all this about?
Uh, ahem, my brother
and I have got a little
proposition for you, colonel.
Could save you
a lot of bother.
I mean, you're doing
all right here, colonel.
But suppose some of your tanks
was to get broken,
and troops started
getting lost.
Uh, fights started breaking out
during general inspection, like.
Yeah, it wouldn't be good for
business, would it, colonel?
Are you threatening me?
Oh, no, no, no.
Whatever made you
think that, colonel?
The colonel doesn't think
we're nice people, Louie.
We're your buddies,
colonel.
We want to look after you.
Look after me?
We can guarantee you
that not a single armored
division will get done over
-for 15 bob a week.
-No.
-Twelve and six. Eight and six.
-No, no, no, no. No, no.
-Five bob.
-No, no, this is silly.
-What's silly?
-No, the whole premise is silly,
and it's very badly written.
I'm senior officer here and I
haven't had a funny line yet.
-So I'm stopping it.
-You can't do that.
I've done it.
The sketch is over.
Uh, I want to leave the army,
please, sir. It's dangerous.
Look, I stopped your sketch
five minutes ago,
so get out of shot.
Right. Director?
Close up.
Zoom in on me.
That's better.
LUIGI: It's only 'cause you
couldn't think of a punch line.
Not true. Not true.
It's time for the cartoon.
Cue telecine.
Ten, nine, eight...
DINO: General public's not gonna
understand this, are they?
GENERAL: Shut up, you Eyeties.
[MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[CHUCKLES]
Ooh.
Ooh, what the devil's
going on here? What--?
Hey. Hey, what's going--?
What's happening here? Hey.
Hey, wait a minute.
Whoa. Hey. Oh. Hey.
Stop that.
[♪]
Ladies and gents, here it is,
the show you've been waiting
for, you've heard so much about.
This is the show that
gives you what you want
the way you like it.
So move right up front
for Full Frontal Nudity.
[MAN CLAPS]
[♪]
MAN 1:
Sit down.
I'm sorry.
Strawberries
and whipped cream, sweetie?
[MAN 2 GRUNTS]
[BELL RINGS RINGS]
[USHER SPEAKER INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKER]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
FAT MAN:
Oh, my God.
[BRAKES SQUEALING,
HORNS BLARING]
FAT MAN:
Oh, no.
[♪]
Wasn't that just great,
ladies and gents?
Admittedly a few problems,
a few disappointments--
Shut up, you pansy.
I paid for full-frontal nudity,
and I'm gonna get some.
Tough luck, sailor.
Full-frontal nudity? Never.
What do you think, Barbara?
Oh, no, no, no. Unless it was
perfectly valid, of course.
Yeah.
Full-frontal nudity?
Yes, I'd do it,
if it was valid.
Uh, if the money was valid.
And if it were a small part.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Good evening.
I'd like to talk to you tonight
about the place of the nude
in my bed--
Um, in--
In the history of my bed--
Of art. Art. I'm sorry.
The place of the nude
in the history of tart--
Call girl-- I'm sorry.
I'll start again.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Bum. Oh, what a giveaway.
Oh--! Um--!
The place of the nude in a--
Ha! Hello there, Father--
Uh, confessor. Professor.
Your Honor. Your grace. Ha!
I'm not your Grace,
I'm your Elsie.
What a terrible joke.
[SOBBING]
But it's my only line!
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
But there, let us leave the art
critic to strangle his wife
and move on to pastures new.
[GROANS, THEN GASPING]
[PANTING]
[CONTINUES PANTING]
[CONTINUED PANTING]
We want to buy a bed,
please.
Oh, certainly. I'll-- I'll get
someone to attend to you.
-Mr. Verity.
-[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
-Can I help you, sir?
-Uh, yes, we'd like
to buy a bed.
A double bed, about 50 pounds.
Oh, no, I'm afraid not, sir.
Our cheapest bed
is 800 pounds, sir.
Eight hundred pounds?
Oh, uh, perhaps
I should have explained.
Mr. Verity does tend
to exaggerate,
so every figure he gives you
will be 10 times too high.
Otherwise,
he's perfectly all right.
-Perfectly. [CHUCKLES]
-Oh, I-- I see.
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
Uh, I see. So your cheapest
bed is 80 pounds?
-Eight hundred pounds, yes, sir.
-And, uh, how wide is it?
Uh, the width is,
uh, 60-feet wide.
Uh, six-foot wide, eh?
[CHUCKLES]
-And the length?
-The length is, um...
-Lambert?
-LAMBERT: Mm?
What is the length
of the Comfydown Majorette?
Uh, two-foot long.
Two foot long?
Uh, yes. You have
to remember, of course,
to multiply everything
Mr. Lambert says by three.
Uh, it's nothing he can help,
you understand.
Apart from that,
he's perfectly all right.
I see, I'm sorry.
But it does mean when he says
a bed is two-foot wide,
it is in fact 60-feet wide.
Uh, heh, yes, I see, heh.
And that's not counting
the mattress.
Oh, how much is that?
Uh, Lambert will be able
to help you there.
-Lambert?
-Mm?
Will you show
these 20 good people
-the, uh, dog kennel, please?
-Certainly.
Dog kennel? No, no, no,
mattresses. Mattresses.
Oh, no, no, you have to say
"dog kennel" to Mr. Lambert,
because if you say "mattress"
he puts a bag over his head.
I should have explained.
Apart from that,
he's really all right.
[GIGGLING]
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
Ah, um, uh, we'd like to see
the dog kennels, please.
-Dog kennels?
-Yes, we want to see
the dog kennels, heh.
Yes, well, that's the pets
department, second floor.
Uh, no, no, no, we want to see
the "dog kennels".
Yes, pets department,
second floor.
No, no, no, we--
We don't really want
to see dog kennels,
only your colleague
said we ought to--
Oh, dear, what's he been
telling you now?
Well, he said we should say
"dog kennel" to you
instead of "mattress."
He-he-he.
Uh, hello, hello?
-Did you say "mattress"?
-Well, a little, yes.
I did ask you not to say
"mattress," didn't I?
Now I've got to stand
in the tea chest.
♪ And did those feet
In ancient times ♪
Did somebody say "mattress"
to Mr. Lambert?
♪ Mountains green ♪
BOTH:
♪ And was the holy lamb
Of God ♪
♪ On England's pleasant ♪
He should be all right now,
but don't...
-You know, just don't.
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
[CHUCKLES FEVEROUSLY]
Uh...
[FORMALLY] We-- We'd like to see
the dog kennels, please.
-Yes, second floor.
-Ah, no, no, no. Now, look.
These dog kennels here, see?
Mattresses?
[HIGH VOICE]
Oh, yes.
If you meant "mattress,"
why didn't you say "mattress"?
It's very confusing for me
if you say "dog kennel"
when you mean "mattress."
Why not just say "mattress"?
[LAUGHS]
Well, I mean you put
a bag over your head
last time I said "mattress."
Heh. Uh-- Uh-- Uh--
♪ Bring me my bow ♪
♪ Of burning gold ♪
♪ Bring me my arrows ♪
BOTH:
♪ Of desire ♪
♪ Bring me my spear ♪
Did somebody say "mattress"
to Mr. Lambert?
Twice!
Hey, everybody,
somebody said "mattress"
to Mr. Lambert twice.
♪ I shall not cease ♪
ALL:
♪ From mental strife ♪
♪ Nor shall my sword ♪
-♪ Sleep in my hand ♪
-[SHOUTING] We need more.
♪ Till we...♪
CROWD:
♪ Have built Jerusalem ♪
♪ On England's green
And pleasant-- ♪
Now, uh, can I help you?
W-we want a mattress.
-Oh, why did you say that?
-What did you say that for?
[SOBBING]
But it's my only line!
ALL: Well, you didn't
have to say it.
-ALL: Oh!
-[WAILING]
Full-frontal nudity?
Heh, not in this part of Esher.
I would only perform a scene
in which there was
total frontal nudity.
Now, I've noticed a tendency
for this program
to get rather silly.
Now, I do my best
to keep things moving along,
but I'm not having things
getting silly.
Those last two sketches I did
got very silly indeed.
And that last one about
the bed was even sillier.
Now, nobody likes a good laugh
more than I do.
Except perhaps my wife
and some of her friends.
Oh, yes, and Captain Johnston.
Come to think of it,
most people like a good laugh
more than I do,
but that's beside the point.
Now, let's have a good, clean,
healthy, outdoor sketch.
Get some air into your lungs.
Ten, nine, eight,
and all that.
COLONEL:
Ah, yes, that's better.
Now, let's hope
this doesn't get silly.
Hello, are you a hermit
by any chance?
Yes, that's right.
Are you a hermit?
Yes, I certainly am.
-Well, I never.
-[LAUGHS]
What are you getting
away from?
Oh, you know,
the usual:
-People, chat, gossip,
you know.
-Oh, I certainly do.
It was the same with me.
I mean, there comes a time
when you realize there's no good
frittering your life away
in idleness
and trivial chitchat.
Where's your cave?
Oh, up the goat track,
first on the left.
Oh, they're very nice
up there, aren't they?
Yes, now they've
got the view, you see.
A bit drafty though, are they?
-No, we've had ours insulated.
-Oh, yes?
Yes, I used birds' nests,
moss, and oak leaves
around the outside.
Oh, sounds marvelous.
Oh, it's a treat,
it really is,
'cause otherwise those
stone caves can be so grim.
FRANK: Yes, they really can be,
can't they?
They really can. Yes.
-Morning, Frank.
-Uh, morning, Norman.
Uh, talking of moss,
uh, you know Mr. Robinson?
With the, uh,
green loincloth?
-Uh, no, that's Mr. Seagrave.
-Oh, yeah.
Mr. Robinson's the hermit
who lodges with Mr. Seagrave.
Oh, I see.
Yes, well, he's put me
onto wattles.
-Really?
-Yes.
Swears by them. Yes.
Morning, Frank.
Uh, morning, Lionel.
Well, he says that moss tends
to fall off the cave wall
during cold weather.
You know, you might get
a really bad spell,
and half the moss drops off
the cave wall, leaving you cold.
Oh, well, Mr. Robinson's
cave's never been
exactly nirvana, has it?
Well, quite,
that's what I mean.
Anyway, Mr. Rogers,
he's the, uh, hermit--
-On the end.
-Up at the top, yes.
Well, he tried wattles
and he came out in a rash.
-Really?
-Yes, and there's me
with half a wall wattled.
I mean, what'll I do?
Well, why don't
you try birds' nests,
like I've done?
Or else, dead bracken.
-Frank!
-Yes, Han?
Can I borrow your goat?
Uh, yes, that'll be all right.
Oh, leave me a pint
for breakfast, will you?
I couldn't see it.
Uh, you know, that's the trouble
with living halfway up a cliff.
You feel so cut off.
You know, it takes me
two hours every morning
to get out onto the moors,
collect my berries,
chastise myself,
and two hours back
in the evening.
Still is one thing
about being a hermit,
at least you meet people.
Oh, yes, I wouldn't go back
to public relations.
Well. Oh, well, bye for now,
Frank. Must toddle--
Right. You two hermits,
stop that sketch.
I think it's silly.
-What?
-Go on. It's silly.
What do you mean? You can't
stop it, it's on film.
That doesn't make any
difference to the viewer
at home.
Go on, get out. Out with you.
Come on, out, all of you.
Get off. Go on, all of you.
Get that bloody camera out--
Go on, move, move.
Get out!
MAN:
I'm doing an interview!
I don't wanna know anything
about your bloody interview.
[ARGUING INDISTINCTLY]
Go on, get out.
Get out. Come on,
get on. Move.
COLONEL:
You lot, sod off.
Move. Move.
[GRUMBLING &amp; ARGUING
INDISTINCTLY]
[♪]
[CLICK, THEN JAZZ PLAYING]
Hello, I wish to register
a complaint.
Hello, miss?
What do you mean, "miss"?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I have a cold.
I wish to make a complaint.
-Sorry, we're closing for lunch.
-Never mind that, my lad.
I wish to complain about this
parrot what I purchased
not half an hour ago
from this very boutique.
Oh, yes, the Norwegian Blue.
What's wrong with it?
I'll tell you
what's wrong with it.
It's dead,
that's what's wrong with it.
No, no, it's resting. Look.
Look, my lad, I know
a dead parrot when I see one,
and I'm looking at one
right now.
No, no, sir, it's not dead.
It's resting.
-Resting?
-Yeah.
Remarkable bird,
the Norwegian Blue.
Beautiful plumage, innit?
The plumage don't
enter into it.
It's stone dead.
No, no, it's resting.
All right then.
If it's resting,
I'll wake it up.
Hello, Polly.
I've got a nice cuttlefish
for you when you wake up,
Polly Parrot.
-There, it moved.
-No, it didn't.
-That was you pushing the cage.
-I did not.
Yes, you did.
Hello, Polly.
Polly!
Polly Parrot, wake up.
Polly.
Now, that's what I call
a dead parrot.
No, no. It's stunned.
Look, my lad, I've had
just about enough of this.
That parrot is definitely
deceased.
And when I bought it
not half an hour ago,
you assured me
that its lack of movement
was due to it being tired and
shagged out after a long squawk.
No, sir. I-- It's probably
pining for the fjords.
Pining for the fjords?
What kind of talk is that?
Look, why did it fall flat
on its back the moment
I got it home?
The Norwegian Blue
prefers kipping on its back.
It's a beautiful bird,
lovely plumage.
Look, I took the liberty
of examining that parrot.
And I discovered
that the only reason
that it had been sitting
on its perch in the first place
was that it had been
nailed there.
Of course
it was nailed there.
Otherwise it would muscle up
to those bars and, "Voom!"
Look, matey,
this parrot wouldn't "voom"
if I put 4000 volts
through it.
It's bleeding demised.
It's not!
It's-- It's pining.
It's not pining,
it's passed on.
This parrot is no more.
It has ceased to be.
It's expired
and gone to meet its maker.
This is a late parrot.
It's a stiff.
Bereft of life,
it rests in peace.
If you hadn't nailed it
to the perch, it would be
pushing up the daisies.
It's rung down the curtain and
joined the choir invisible.
This is an ex-parrot.
Well, I'd better
replace it, then.
If you want to get anything
done in this country,
you got to complain
till you're blue in the mouth.
Sorry, guv,
we're right out of parrots.
I see. I see.
I get the picture.
I've got a slug.
Does it talk?
Not really, no.
Well, it's scarcely
a replacement then, is it?
Listen, I'll tell you what.
Tell you what.
If you go to my brother's
pet shop in Bolton,
he'll replace your parrot
for you.
-Bolton, eh?
-Yeah.
All right.
[WHISTLING]
Uh, excuse me.
This is Bolton, is it?
No, no, it's, uh, Ipswich.
That's InterCity Rail for you.
[DOOR OPENS, BELL JINGLES,
THEN DOOR CLOSES]
[MAN WHISTLING]
I wish to make a complaint.
I don't have to do this,
you know.
-I beg your pardon.
-I'm a qualified brain surgeon.
I only do this 'cause I like
being me own boss.
Uh, excuse me,
this is irrelevant, isn't it?
Oh, yeah, it's not easy to pad
these out to 30 minutes.
Well, I wish
to make a complaint.
I got on the Bolton train
and found myself
deposited here in Ipswich.
[CHUCKLING]
No, this is Bolton.
The pet shop owner's
brother was lying.
Well, you can't blame
British Rail for that.
If this is Bolton, I shall
return to the pet shop.
I understand
that this is Bolton.
-Yeah.
-Well, you told me
it was Ipswich.
It was a pun.
-A pun?
-No, no, not a pun, no.
No, what's the other thing,
which reads the same
backwards as forwards?
-A palindrome?
-Yeah, yeah.
It's not a palindrome.
The palindrome of Bolton
would be Notlob.
-It don't work.
-Look, what do you want?
No, I'm sorry.
I'm not prepared to pursue my
line of inquiry any further,
as I think
this is getting too silly.
Quite agree. Quite agree.
Silly, silly, silly.
Right.
Get on with it.
Oh! Ahh.
Oh, I-I-I'm sorry.
Uh... and now, um,
uh, frontal nudity.
Oh. Oh, I'm-- I'm sorry.
I thought the film was longer.
Uh...
Uh, now, Notlob. Uh, Bolton.
REPORTER:
This is a frightened city.
Over these houses,
over these streets,
hangs a pall of fear.
Fear of a new kind
of violence,
which is terrorizing
the city.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Yes, gangs of old ladies
attacking defenseless,
fit young men.
[MEN GRUNTING]
[OLD LADIES LAUGHING]
[♪]
MAN 1:
Well, they-- They come up
to you, like, and push you.
You know, shove you off
the pavement, like.
There's usually
four or five of them.
MAN 2:
Yeah, thi-this used to be
a nice neighborhood
before the old ladies
started moving in.
Nowadays, some of us daren't
even go down to the shops.
Well, Mr. Johnson's son Kevin,
he don't go out anymore.
He comes back from wrestling
and locks himself in his room.
[OLD LADIES LAUGHING]
REPORTER:
What are they in it for,
these old hoodlums,
these layabouts in lace?
OLD LADY 1:
Well, it's-- It's something
to do, isn't it?
I-it's good fun.
OLD LADY 2:
It's-- It's like, uh,
you know, well, innit, eh?
REPORTER:
Favorite targets for the old
ladies are telephone kiosks.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Well, come on, come on.
Off with you.
Clear out.
Go on, what.
Get out of it.
We have a lot of trouble
with these oldies.
Pension day is the worst.
They go mad.
Soon as they get their hands
on their money,
they blow it all
on milk, bread,
tea, tin of meat for the cat.
Yes, well, of course,
come the 2:00 matinee,
uh, all hell breaks out
in there.
Especially if it's something
like The, uh, Sound of Music,
heh.
We get, uh, seats ripped up,
hearing aids broken,
all that sort of thing.
[OLD LADIES GRUNTING]
The whole problem
of these senile delinquents
lies in their
complete rejection
of the values
of contemporary society.
They've seen their children
grow up and become accountants,
stockbrokers
and even sociologists,
and they begin to wonder,
is it all really--
[REPORTER SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
Oh, well, we sometimes feel
we're to blame in some way
for what our gran's become.
I mean, she used to be
quite happy here until she--
She started on the, uh,
crochet.
-REPORTER: Crochet?
-Yeah.
Now she can't do without it.
Twenty balls of wool a day,
sometimes.
If she can't get the wool,
she gets violent.
What can we do about it?
[ENGINE REVVING]
REPORTER:
But this is not just
an old ladies' town.
There are other
equally dangerous gangs,
such as the Baby Snatchers.
[BABY SNATCHERS CRYING]
I just left my husband
outside here while I went in
to do some shopping,
and I came back
and he was gone.
[SOBBING]
He was only 47.
REPORTER:
And on the roads too,
vicious gangs
of "keep left" signs.
Right, right, stop it.
This film's got silly.
Started off
as a nice little idea
about grannies attacking
young men,
but now it's got silly. Humph.
That man's hair is too long
for a vicar too.
Those signs
are pretty badly made.
Right, now for a complete
change of mood.
I've heard of unisex
but I've never had it.
ANNOUNCER:
David Hemmings appeared
by permission
of the National
Forestry Commission.
[♪]
[TICKING]