[MAN PANTING]
It's...
NARRATOR:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
[SINGING AND PLAYING]
[CONTINUES IN SPANISH]
ALL:
Olé!
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
ALL:
[TRILLING]
BOTH:
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
ALL:
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
Olé!
[MAN COUGHS]
Fine.
Okay.
And now for something
completely different:
A man with a tape recorder
up his nose.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[TAPE REWINDING]
[MUSIC REPLAYS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
MAN'S VOICE:
And now for something
completely different:
The office
of Sir George Head...
O.B.E.
Next, please.
Uh, one at a time, please.
There is only me, sir.
So there is.
Uh, take a, um...
[SNAPPING FINGERS]
-Seat?
-Seat. Seat. Take a seat.
So, uh, you want to join
my mountaineering
expedition, do you?
-Me, sir?
-Yes.
Yes, I'd very much
like to, sir.
Jolly good. Jolly good.
And how about you?
There is only me, sir.
Well, bang goes
his application then.
Now, let me fill you in.
I'm leading this expedition
and we're going to climb
both peaks
of Mount Kilimanjaro.
I thought there was
only one peak, sir.
Well, that'll save
a bit of time.
Well done.
Now, the object
of this expedition
is to see if we can
find any traces of
last year's expedition.
Last year's expedition?
Yes, my brother
was leading that.
They were going to build
a bridge between the two peaks.
My idea, I'm afraid.
Now, I ought to, uh--
I ought to tell you
that I have practically
everyone that I need
for this expedition.
So, what special
qualifications do you have?
Uh, well, sir--
Yes, you first.
There is only me, sir.
I wasn't talking to you.
Carry on.
Well, I'm a fully
qualified mountaineer.
Mountaineer?
Mountaineer.
Where the devil are they?
"Mound... mount...
mountain...
A mountaineer:
Two men skilled
in climbing mountains."
My God,
that would be useful.
Jolly good.
Well, you're in.
Congratulations,
both of you.
Now, um,
what are your names?
Uh, Arthur Wilson.
Arthur Wilson. Right.
Well, look, I'll call you
"Arthur Wilson One"
and you "Arthur Wilson Two"
just to avoid confusion.
Are you actually leading
this expedition, sir?
Yes, we are leading
this expedition to Africa.
And what routes
will you both be taking?
Good questions.
Shall I? Fine.
Well, uh, we'll be leaving
on January the 22nd
and taking the following
routes.
Uh, the A23s through Purleys,
down onto the main roads
near Purbrights
avoiding Leatherheads
and then taking the A231s,
entering Rottingdeans
from the north.
Um, from Rottingdeans
we go through Africa
to Nairobis.
We take the south road out
of Nairobis for about 12 miles
and then ask.
Does anyone
speak Swahili, sir?
Oh, yes, I think most
of them do down there.
Does anyone in our party
speak Swahili, sir?
Well, Matron's got
a smattering.
Apart from the two Matrons.
Good God,
I'd forgotten about her.
Apart from them, who else
is coming on the expedition?
Uh, well, we've got
the Arthur Brown twins
uh, two botanists
called Machin,
the William Johnston
brothers--
-Two of them?
-No, four of them.
Pair of identical twins.
And a couple of
the Ken Spinoza quads.
The other two pulled out.
And of course, you two.
And none of these
are mountaineers?
Well, you two are.
And we've got a brace of guides
called Jimmy Blenkinsop.
Because Kilimanjaro is a pretty
tricky climb, you know.
Most of it's up,
till you reach
the very, very top
and then it tends to slope away
rather sharply.
But Jimmy's
put his heads together
and worked out a way up.
Jimmy?
-Ah. I don't believe you've met.
-Hello.
Jimmy Blenkinsop,
Arthur Wilson.
Arthur Wilson,
Jimmy Blenkinsop.
Arthur Wilson Two,
Jimmy Blenkinsop One.
Jimmy Blenkinsop One,
Arthur Wilson Two.
-Carry on Jimmies. Excuse me.
-Don't worry about the, uh...
We'll get him up somehow.
Now, the approach to Kilimanjaro
is quite simply
over the foothills
and then we go on after that
up to set a base camp
somewhere in the region
of the bottom of the glacier
when, after the glacier,
we'll find...
[TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
And, of course, we'll have
a rather difficult climb...
[TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CRASHING]
He'll be leading
the first assault.
I'm afraid I shan't be coming
on your expedition, sir.
I've absolutely no confidence
in anyone involved in it.
Oh, dear.
Well, how 'bout you?
Well, I'm game, sir.
So are we.
-Fine. Fine.
-Fine.
BOTH:
And now for something
completely different:
A man with a tape recorder
up his brother's nose.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[TAPE REWINDING]
MAN READS:
[MUSIC PLAYS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
Thank you. Thank you.
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
Have you ever considered
the advantages
of owning a really fine set
of encyclopedias?
[GIBBERISH]
-For only ten--
-George.
[QUIETLY] Louise, I told you
never to call me at the office.
-[GIBBERISH]
-George.
[SMOOCHING SOUNDS]
Okay, stop it.
[CLEARING THROAT]
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Congratulations, sir,
you've just won
this lovely Kewpie Doll.
MAN'S VOICE:
Get off!
[MAN HISSES]
And get a haircut,
ya pansy!
Good morning.
Ah! Morning, sir.
Morning. Morning.
I'll, um, uh,
be with you in a minute.
Oh, fine, fine.
-Ah.
-BOTH: [CHUCKLE]
[METAL CRASHES]
[CHUCKLES]
[HUMMING]
[WHISTLING]
[SNIFFLING]
Ah.
Um, how--?
How would you like it, sir?
Oh, just short back
and sides, please.
How do you do that?
Well, just ordinary
short back and sides.
It's not a, um...
a-a-a razor cut?
Razor, razor, razor, razor cut,
blood, spurt, artery, murder!
Oh, thank God. Thank God.
It's just, uh... scissors.
Yes, yes.
You wouldn't rather have it
just combed, would you, sir?
Beg your pardon?
You wouldn't rather forget
all about it?
No, no, no, I want it cut.
Cut, cut, cut, cut, cut!
Blood, spurt, artery, murder,
Hitchcock, Psycho, blood!
Damn it!
Right, sir. Well, I'll--
-I'll get e-everything ready.
-Good.
In the meantime,
perhaps you'd fill
in one of these.
Oh, right. Fine, yes.
-Excuse me?
-What?
Where it says "next of kin"
shall I put "Mother"?
Yes, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes!
All right, there we are.
Thank you.
Right.
[CHUCKLES]
[WHISTLING]
Ahh.
[CHUCKLES]
Mm.
[WHISTLING]
-There, I've finished.
-You've what?
I finished cutting, cutting,
cutting, cutting, cutting,
cutting, cutting your hair!
-It's all done.
-But you haven't
started cutting it.
I-I have. I did it
very quickly, Your Honor--
Sir, sir, sir! Sir.
Look here, old fellow,
I know when a chap's cut
my hair and when he hasn't.
So will you please
stop fooling around
and get on with it?
Yes. Yes, I will, sir.
I'm gonna cut
your hair, sir.
I'm gonna start cutting
Start cutting now.
[SOUND OF SCISSORS CUTTING
OVER TAPE PLAYER]
BARBER'S VOICE:
Nice day, sir.
Yes. Flowers could do
with a drop of rain though.
You see the match
last night, sir?
Yeah. Good game, I thought.
I thought Hurst
played well, sir.
-Beg your pardon?
-I thought Hurst played well,
sir.
Oh, yes. Only one
who did though.
-Can you put your head down
a little?
-Oh, sorry.
I prefer to watch Palace
nowadays.
Oh, sorry.
Was that your ear?
No, no. Didn't feel a thing.
Hey, what's going on? Look,
I came here for a haircut!
-Yes, it is a nice spot,
isn't it?
-It looks very nice.
It's exactly the same
as when I came in.
-That's the lot then.
-All right.
All right, I confess,
I haven't cut your hair.
I hate cutting hair.
I have this terrible,
un-un-uncontrollable fear
whenever I see hair.
When I was a kid,
I used to hate the sight
of hair being cut.
My mother said I was a fool.
She said the way to cure it
was to become a barber.
So I spent five ghastly years
at the Hairdressers'
Training Center at Totnes.
Can you imagine
what it's like
cutting the same head
for five years?
I didn't want to be
a barber anyway.
I wanted to be a lumberjack.
Leaping from tree to tree
as they float down the mighty
rivers of British Columbia.
The giant redwood,
the larch, the fir
the mighty Scots pine.
The smell of fresh-cut timber.
The crash of mighty trees.
With my best girlie by my side
we'd sing, sing, sing.
♪ I'm a lumberjack
And I'm okay ♪
♪ I sleep all night
I work all day ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
And he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
And he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees
I eat my lunch ♪
♪ I go to the lavatory ♪
♪ On Wednesdays
I go shopping ♪
♪ And have buttered scones
For tea ♪
♪ He cuts down trees
He eats his lunch ♪
♪ He goes to the lavatory ♪
♪ On Wednesdays
He goes shopping ♪
♪ And has buttered scones
For tea ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
And he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
And he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees
I skip and jump ♪
♪ I like to press wildflowers ♪
♪ I put on women's clothing ♪
♪ And hang around in bars ♪
♪ He cuts down trees
He skips and jumps ♪
♪ He likes to press
Wildflowers ♪
♪ He puts on women's clothing ♪
♪ And hangs around in bars? ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
And he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
And he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees
I wear high heels ♪
♪ Suspendies and a bra ♪
♪ I wish I'd been a girlie ♪
♪ Just like my dear mama ♪
♪ He cuts down trees
He wears high heels ♪
♪ Suspenders and a bra? ♪
-♪ I wish I'd been a girlie ♪
-[ALL GROANING]
♪ Just like my dear mama ♪
Oh, Bevis.
And I thought
you were so rugged.
MAN:
Dear sir, I wish to complain
in the strongest
possible terms
about the song which you
have just broadcast
about the lumberjack
who wears women's clothes.
Many of my best friends
are lumberjacks
and only a few of them
are transvestites.
Yours faithfully,
Brigadier Sir Charles
Arthur Strong, Mrs.
P.S. I have never kissed
the editor of The Radio Times.
Well, I object to all this sex
on the television.
I mean, I keep falling off.
[♪]
Well, I think television's
killed real entertainment.
In the old days,
we used to make our own fun
at Christmas parties.
I used to strike myself
on the head repeatedly
with blunt instruments
while crooning:
♪ Only make believe ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ That you love me ♪
Oh. Ow.
♪ Others find peace of mind ♪
[JAZZ PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen
and welcome to
the Refreshment Room
here at Bletchley.
My name is Kenny Lust,
and I'm your compere
for tonight.
You know, once in a while,
it is my pleasure
and my privilege
to welcome here
at the Refreshment Room
some of the truly great
international artists
of our time.
And tonight we have
one such artist.
Ladies and gentlemen,
someone whom I've always
personally admired,
perhaps more deeply,
more strongly,
more abjectly
than any other performer.
A man--
Well, more than a man, a god.
A great god whose personality
is so totally
and utterly wonderful
that my feeble words
of welcome sound wretchedly
and pathetically inadequate.
Someone whose boots
I would gladly lick clean
until holes wore through
my tongue.
A man who is so totally
and utterly wonderful
that I would rather be sealed
in a pit of my own filth
than dare tread
on the same stage with him.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the incomparably superior
human being...
-[APPLAUSE]
-Harry Fink.
[APPLAUSE STOPS]
MAN:
He can't come.
Never mind.
He's not all
he's cracked up to be.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we give you Ken Buddha
and his inflatable knees.
[POPPING SOUND]
Ken Buddha: A smile,
two bangs and a religion.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for your further
entertainment,
Brian Islam and Brucie.
[♪]
-So anyway, I became a barber.
-Oh, poor chap.
Yes, pity, really.
I always preferred
the outdoor life.
Hunting, shooting, fishing.
Getting out there with a gun,
slaughtering a few
of God's creatures.
That was the life.
Charging about the moorland,
blasting their heads off.
[♪]
-[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
-[GUNSHOTS]
MEN: [WHOOPING]
WOMEN: [YELPING]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
MAN: [GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
MAN: [SCREAMS]
I'm sorry,
we don't need you this week.
[SIGHS]
And now for something
completely different.
[♪]
Would you--?
Would you mind terribly if...
if I held your hand?
Oh!
Oh, no, not at all.
Oh, Iris, you're so
very beautiful.
Oh!
Oh, do you really
mean that?
I do, I do, I do.
I think I'm beginning
to fall in love with you.
Oh, Victor.
Silly, isn't it?
No.
No, not at all,
dear sweet Victor.
No, I-I didn't mean that.
Only, just us being so close
together for so many months
in the soft-toy department,
and yet never daring to--
Ohh...
-Oh, Victor.
-Oh, Iris.
-[DOORBELL RINGS]
-Oh!
Who can that be?
Oh, well, you try
and get rid of them.
Yes, I will. I will. Yes.
Won't be a moment.
-Hello!
-Hello.
-Remember me?
-Uh, no, I--
In the pub, the tall,
thin one with the mustache?
-Remember?
-No, I'm afraid--
-About three years ago?
-No, I don't, I'm afraid.
Blimey, it's dark in here.
That's better.
You said we must have a drink
together sometime.
So I thought I'd
take you up on it
as the film society meeting
was cancelled this evening.
-It is a little awkward
this evening.
-Hello. I'm Arthur.
Arthur Name. Name by name,
but not by nature.
[LAUGHS]
I always say that,
don't I, Vicky boy?
-Really?
-Is that your wife?
Um, no, actually, but--
Oh, I get the picture, eh?
Well, don't worry
about me, Vicky boy,
I know all about
one-night stands.
-I beg your pardon?
-Mind if I change the record?
No, no.
Look, we put that on.
Here's a good one.
I heard it in a pub.
What's brown--?
What's brown
and sounds like a bell?
I beg your pardon?
What's brown
and sounds like a bell?
"Dung."
[LAUGHING]
That is a good one.
I like that one.
Now, I won't keep you long.
[FANFARE PLAYING
OVER SPEAKER]
Ah, that's better.
Now, don't worry about me.
I'll wait here
till you're finished.
-What?
-[DOORBELL RINGS]
Who the hell is that?
I'll get it.
It'll be friends of mine.
I took the liberty
of inviting them along.
We were hoping to have
a quiet evening on our own.
They won't mind.
They're very broad-minded.
-Hello!
-Good evening.
Good evening.
My name is Equator,
Brian Equator,
like round the middle
of the Earth, only with an L.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
This is my wife, Audrey.
She smells a bit,
but she has a heart of gold.
[LAUGHS]
There must've been some
misunderstanding because--
-Who's that then?
-What?
-Who's the bird?
-Well, um--
Say, you got a nice pair
there, haven't you, love?
Go on, give us a kiss.
[SCREAMS]
Shut up, you silly bitch.
It was only a bit of fun.
Now, look here, I've--
Big gin, please. Big gin.
-I'll get it.
-No, leave those drinks alone.
And three cans
of beans for me, please.
I told you to lay off
the beans, you whore!
I only want three cans!
Button your lip, you ratbag!
BOTH: [LAUGHS]
Was rather witty, wasn't it?
Where's my gin?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Who the hell's that?!
Oh, I, uh-- I took the liberty
of inviting an old friend along,
as his wife
has just passed away.
He's somewhat distraught,
poor chap. Hope you don't mind.
-Come on in.
-[STAMMERS] Well--
Oh, my God,
what a simply ghastly place.
Yeah. It's not
too good, is it?
Uh, a pint of crème de menthe
for my friend.
Well, how are you,
you great poof?
Bit lumpy.
-[MEOWS]
-Oh, no wonder,
I was sitting on the cat.
[WAILS]
I brought along
a simply gorgeous little man
I picked up at the Odeon.
Is he sexy then?
[EXAGGERATED SNEEZE]
I had to bring the goat.
He's not well.
I only hope he don't go
on the carpet.
Come on, then, love.
Drop 'em.
[SCREAMS]
Blimey, she don't go much,
do she?
[LAUGHS OBNOXIOUSLY]
Oh, I wet 'em.
Ohh!
The goat's just done a bundle.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Now, look, get out,
all of you!
Go on, get out!
Get out! Get out!
I beg your pardon?
I'm turning you all out.
I'm not having my house
filled with filthy perverts.
I'm giving just half a minute,
then I'm gonna call the police,
so get out!
I don't much like the tone
of your voice.
Ah!
Right. Uh, let's have
a "Ding Dong."
ALL:
♪ Ding dong merrily on high ♪
♪ In heaven the bells
Are ringing ♪
[GUNSHOT]
♪ Ding dong verily the sky ♪
♪ It's riven
With angels singing ♪
♪ Glo-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oria ♪
♪ Hosanna in excelsis ♪
[MEN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[♪]