[♪]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
-[SIGHS]
-Well, where is he?
MAN:
Ooh.
-Mm.
-Oh, what is it, dear?
It's from the BBC.
They want to know if I want
to be on a sketch on telly.
Oh, that's nice.
Well, it's acting,
innit?
Yes.
Well, I'm a plumber.
I can't act.
Oh, you never know till you try.
Look at Mrs. Brando's son
next door.
He was mending the fridge when
they came and asked him to be
The Wild One.
What do they want you to do?
Well, they just want me
to stand at a counter,
and when the sketch starts,
I go out.
Oh, that sounds nice.
It's what they call "a walk-on".
Walk-on?
It's a walk-off,
that's what this is.
Where is he, George?
I don't know.
He should have
been here hours ago.
He bloody should have been.
What else does it say?
It just says, "We would like
you to be in a sketch.
You are standing
at a counter.
When the sketch starts,
you go off.
Yours faithfully,
Lord Hill."
Oh, well,
you better be off, then.
Well, what about the cat?
Oh, I'll look after the cat.
Goodness me,
Mrs. Newman's eldest
never worried about the cat
when he went off to do
the Sweet Bird of Youth.
All right then, all right.
Bye-bye, dear.
Bye-bye, and mind you
don't get seduced.
Well, it'll make a change
from plumbing.
Dad, Frank's got
a television part.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
You missed him.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Good morning.
I am a bank robber.
Uh, please don't panic.
Just hand over all your money.
This is a lingerie shop, sir.
Fine, fine, fine.
[SIGHS]
Adopt, adapt and improve.
Motto of the Round Table.
Well, um...
What have you got?
We've got corsets, stockings,
suspender belts, tights, bras,
slips, petticoats, knickers,
socks and garters, sir.
Fine, fine.
Um, ahem...
-No large piles of money
in safes?
-No, sir.
-No deposit accounts?
No piles of cash
in easy-to-carry bags?
None at all, sir.
-No luncheon vouchers?
-No, sir.
Fine, fine.
Well, um...
Adopt, adapt and improve.
Just a pair of knickers then,
please.
[CHUCKLING]
Well, that was a bit of fun,
wasn't it?
[CHUCKLES]
And a special
good evening to you.
Not just an ordinary good
evening, like you get
from all the other announcers,
but a special
good evening from me...
to you.
Well, what have we got next?
This is fun, isn't it?
[LAUGHS]
Look, I'm sorry if
I'm interrupting anything
that any of you
may be doing at home,
but I want you to think of me
as an old queen.
Friend.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Well, let's see
what we've got next.
In a few moments,
It's A Tree.
And in the chair,
as usual, is Arthur Tree.
And starring in the show
will be a host of star guests
as his star guests.
And then at 9:30,
we've got another
rollicking half-hour
of laughter-packed squalor
with Yes, it's the Sewage
Farm Attendants.
[CHUCKLES]
And this week, Dan falls
into a vat of human dung
with hilarious consequences.
[CHUCKLES]
But now it's the glittering
world of show business
with Arthur Tree.
[♪]
Hello. Hello, people,
and welcome to It's A Tree.
We have some really exiting
guests for you this evening.
A fabulous spruce,
back from a tour of Holland,
three gum trees,
making their first appearance
in this country,
Scot pine and the conifers,
and Elm Tree Bole.
There you go, can't be bad.
An exciting new American plank,
a rainforest
and a bucket of sawdust
giving their views
on teenage violence,
and an unusual guest
for this program,
a piece of laminated plastic.
Hi there. Heh, heh.
But first, will you please,
please welcome
a block of wood.
[APPLAUSE]
Well, Block. Nice to have you
on the show again.
Well, uh, thanks, Tree.
I've gotta pay the rent.
[AUDIENCE, TREES LAUGHING]
Super.
Well, uh, what have
you been doing, Block?
Well, I've just been starring
in several major
multi-million-dollar
international films
and, during breaks on the set,
I've been designing a cathedral,
doing wonderful,
unpublicized work for charity,
uh, finishing my history
of the world, of course,
-pulling the birds...
-Oh!
...uh, photographing royalty
on the loo,
averting--averting
World War III,
can't be bad,
and, uh, learning to read.
The full Renaissance bit,
really.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Heh-heh-heh. Super, super.
Well, I've got to stop you
there, Block, I'm afraid,
because we've got someone
who's been doing cabaret
in the new forest.
From America,
will you welcome please,
a Chippendale writing desk.
Thank you, Mr. Tree.
I'd now like to do
a few impersonations
of some of my favorite
Englishmen.
First off, Long John Sliver.
[DRUMROLL]
Arr, Jim Boy.
Arr, arr.
And now, Edward Heath.
[DRUMROLL]
Hello, sailor.
Now, a short scene from a play
by Harold Splinter.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
Wasn't that just great,
ladies and gentlemen?
But wait a minute,
we've got something else
I just know
you're going to love.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
Yes, sir,
coming right up,
the Vocational Guidance
Counselor sketch.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
♪ Vocational
Guidance counselor ♪
[SIGHS]
[WHISTLES]
Ah, Mr. Anchovy.
Do sit down.
Thank you. Take the weight
off the feet, eh?
-Yes, yes.
-Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Lovely weather for
the time of year, I must say.
Enough of this gay banter.
I understand, Mr. Anchovy,
you asked us to advise you
which job in life
you were best suited for.
That is correct, yes.
I now have the results here
of the interviews
and the aptitude tests
you took last week,
and from then we've built up
a pretty clear picture
of the sort of person
that you are.
And I think I can say,
without fear of contradiction,
that the ideal job for you
is chartered accountancy.
But I am
a chartered accountant.
Jolly good. Well, back to
the office with you then.
No, no, no.
You don't understand.
I've been a chartered accountant
for the last 20 years.
I want a new job.
Something exciting
that will let me live.
Well, chartered accountancy
is rather exciting, isn't it?
Exciting? No, it's not.
It's dull. Dull, dull.
My God, it's dull.
It's so desperately dull,
and tedious
and stuffy and boring
and desperately dull.
Well, uh, yes, Mr. Anchovy,
but you see, your report here
says that you are
an extremely dull person.
You see,
our experts describe you
as an appallingly
dull fellow.
"Unimaginative, timid,
lacking in initiative,
spineless, easily dominated,
no sense of humor,
tedious company
and irrepressibly
drab and awful."
And, uh, whereas
in most professions
these would be
considerable drawbacks,
in chartered accountancy
they're a positive boon.
But don't you see,
I came here to find a new job.
A new life.
A new meaning to my existence.
Can't you help me?
Well, do you have any idea
of what you want to do?
-Yes. Yes, I have.
-What?
Lion-taming.
Yes, yes.
Of course, it's a bit
of a jump, isn't it?
I mean, chartered accountancy
to lion-taming in one go.
You don't think
it might be better
if you worked your way
towards lion-taming,
say via banking, or--?
No! No, no, no!
I don't want to wait.
At 9:00 tomorrow,
I want to be in there, taming.
Fine, fine.
But, uh, do you--?
Do you have any
qualifications?
Yes, I've got a hat.
-A hat?
-Yes, a hat.
A lion-taming hat.
A hat, with "lion-tamer" on it.
I got it at Harrods and it
lights up, saying, "lion-tamer"
in great big neon letters,
so you can tame them after dark,
when they're less stroppy.
I see, I see.
You can switch it off
during the day time,
claim reasonable wear and tear
as allowable professional
expenses under--
Yes, yes, I do follow,
Mr. Anchovy, but you see,
the snag is,
if I now call Mr. Chipperfield
and say to him:
"Uh, look here,
I've got a 45-year-old
chartered accountant with me
who wants to become
a lion-tamer,"
his first question
is not going to be,
"Does he have his own hat?"
He's going to ask
what sort of experience
you've had with lions.
Well, I--
I've seen them at the zoo.
Good, good, good.
Yes, they're brown furry things
with short, stumpy legs
and great long noses.
I don't know what all the fuss
is about. I could tame one.
They look pretty tame
to start with.
Heh, heh. And these, um--
these lions, how high are they?
Well, they're about so high,
you know.
-Mm-hm.
-They don't frighten me at all.
Really?
And do these lions eat ants?
-Yes, that's right. Heh-heh.
-Mm-hm.
Uh, well,
Mr. Anchovy, I'm afraid
what you've got hold of there,
is an anteater.
-A what?
-An anteater. Not a lion.
You see, a lion
is a huge savage beast,
about five-feet high,
ten-feet long,
weighing about 400 pounds,
running 40-miles-an-hour,
with masses
of sharp pointed teeth,
and nasty, long,
razor-sharp claws that could
rip your belly open before
you could say Eric Robinson,
and they look like this:
-[ROARS]
-[SCREAMS]
Time enough, I think,
for a piece of wood.
MAN:
The larch.
Now, shall I call
Mr. Chipperfield?
Uh, no. No, no, no.
I think your idea of making
the transition to lion-taming
via easy stages,
say, via insurance or...
-Or banking.
-Or banking! Banking, yes.
Yes, banking.
That's a man's life, isn't it?
Banking.
Travel, excitement,
adventure, thrills.
Decisions affecting
people's lives.
Jolly good, well...
-shall I put you in touch
with a bank?
-Yes.
-Fine.
-No, no, no. Heh-heh.
Look, uh--
It's a big decision,
I'd like just a couple
of weeks to think about it.
Uh, you know, don't want
to jump into it too quickly.
Maybe three weeks.
I could let you know definitely
then. I just don't want
to make this decision...
Well, this is just one of the
all too many cases on our books
of chartered accountancy.
The only way that
we can fight this terrible,
debilitating social disease
is by informing the general
public of its consequences.
By showing young people...
For a bit, just for a bit.
...that it's just not worth it.
So please give generously
to this address:
[READING]
[♪]
Oh. [CHUCKLING]
Well, that was fun, wasn't it?
No, it wasn't, you fairy.
Oh, hello, sailor.
No, you wouldn't have got
on one of our voyages.
They were all dead butch.
Mm, that's not what I've heard.
[♪]
NARRATOR:
There is an epic quality
about the sea,
which has,
throughout history,
stirred the hearts and minds
of Englishmen of all nations.
Sir Francis Drake,
Captain Webb,
Nelson of Trafalgar
and Scott of the Antarctic,
all rose to the challenge
of the mighty ocean.
And today,
another Englishman
may add his name
to the golden roll of history.
Mr. Ron Obvious of Neaps End.
For today, Ron Obvious
hopes to be the first man
-to jump the Channel.
-[CROWD CHEERING]
Ron, now let's just
get this quite clear.
You're intending to jump across
the English Channel?
Oh, yes,
that is correct, yes.
And just how far is that?
Oh, well, it's 26 miles
from here to Calais.
That's to the beach at Calais?
Well, no, no. Provided
I get a good lift off,
and maybe a gust of breeze
over the French coast,
I shall be jumping into
the center of Calais itself.
[FRENCH ACCORDION MUSIC PLAYS]
Ron, are you using
any special techniques
to jump this great distance?
Oh, no, no. I shall be using
an ordinary two-footed jump
straight up in the air
and across the channel.
I see. Ron, what is
the furthest distance
that you've jumped so far?
Oh, 11-foot-6-inches
at Motspur Park
on July the 22nd.
Uh, but I have done nearly
12-feet, unofficially.
I see. Ron, Ron. Ron,
aren't you worried, Ron--?
Aren't you worried jumping
26 miles across the sea?
Oh, oh,
no, no, no, no.
It is, in fact, easier to jump
over sea than over dry land.
Well, how is that?
Well, my manager
explained it to me.
You see, if you're five miles
out over the English Channel,
with nothing but sea
underneath you,
there is a very great impetus
to stay in the air.
I see. Well...
thank you very much, Ron,
and the very best of luck.
Thank you. Thank you.
The man behind
Ron's cross-channel jump
is his manager,
Mr. Luigi Vercotti.
Mr. Vercotti.
Uh, Mr. Vercotti.
-Mr. Vercotti.
-What?
Uh, Mr. Vercotti.
I've never been-- I don't know
what you're talking about.
Uh, no, we're from the BBC,
Mr. Vercotti.
-Who?
-The BBC.
Oh!
Oh, I see. I thought--
I thought you were the, um,...
I like the police a lot.
I've got a lot of time for them.
Yes, well, Mr. Vercotti,
what is your chief task
as Ron's manager?
Well, my main task is to fix
a sponsor for the big jump.
And who is the sponsor?
The Chippenham Brick Company.
They pay all the bills,
in return for which Ron
will be carrying
half a hundredweight
of their bricks.
That was my idea.
I see. Well, it looks
as if Ron is ready now.
He's got the bricks.
He's had his passport checked
and he's all set to go.
And he's off, on the first-ever
cross-channel jump.
Will Ron be trying
the cross-channel jump
again soon?
No. No, I'm taking him
off the jumps.
Because I've got something
lined up for Ron next week
that I think is much more
up his street.
What's that?
Uh, Ron is going to eat
Chichester Cathedral.
Well, there he goes,
Ron Obvious of Neaps End,
in an attempt which could
make him the first man ever
to eat an entire
Anglican cathedral.
[CRUNCH]
[SCREAMING]
VERCOTTI:
I think, David,
this is something
which Ron and myself
are really keen on.
Ron is gonna tunnel
from Godalming, here,
to Java, here.
-Java.
-Yeah.
I personally think
this is gonna make Ron
a household name overnight.
-And how far has he got?
-Well, he's quite far now, Dave.
Well on the way.
Well on the way, yeah.
Well, where is he, exactly?
-Yeah.
-Where?
Oh, uh, well, um, you know,
it's difficult to say exactly.
He's, uh, you know,
in the area of, uh...
Ron, how far have you got?
Oh, about two-foot-six,
Mr. Vercotti.
Yeah, well, keep digging lad,
keep digging.
Mr. Vercotti, are you sure
there isn't a spade?
Mr. Vercotti,
what do you say to people
who accuse you of exploiting
Ron for your own purposes?
Well, it's totally untrue,
David.
Ever since I left Sicily,
I've been trying to do
the best for Ron.
I know what Ron wants to do.
I believe in him.
And I'm just trying to create
the opportunities for Ron
to do the kind of things
he wants to do.
And what's
he gonna do today?
He's gonna split a railway
carriage with his nose.
[RON SCREAMING]
The only difficult bit
for Ron
is getting out of
Earth's atmosphere.
Once he's in orbit,
he'll be able to run
straight to Mercury.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
[RON SCREAMING]
I am now extremely hopeful
that Ron will
break the world record
for remaining underground.
He's a wonderful boy this,
he's got this
really enormous talent,
this really huge talent.
WOMAN 1:
Oh, that's a bit sad,
isn't it?
WOMAN 2:
Shh. It's satire.
WOMAN 1:
No, it isn't.
This is zany, madcap humor.
WOMAN 2:
Oh, is it?
-Good morning.
-Morning.
I'd like to buy a cat.
Certainly, sir.
Got a lovely terrier.
-No, I want a cat, really.
-Oh, yeah.
How about that?
No, that's the terrier.
Well, it's as near as,
damn it.
Well, what do you mean?
I want a cat.
Listen, tell you what.
I'll file its legs down a bit,
take its snout off,
stick wires through
its cheeks.
There you are,
lovely pussycat.
-It's not a proper cat.
-What do you mean?
-Well, it wouldn't meow.
-Well, it'd howl a bit.
No. No, no, no.
Have you got a parrot?
Oh, I'm afraid not,
actually, guv,
we're fresh out of parrots.
Tell you what though.
I'll lop its back legs off,
make good.
Strip the fur,
stick a couple of wings on,
and staple on a beak
of your own choice.
[BEAKS RATTLING]
No problem. Lovely parrot.
How long would that take?
Oh, let me see.
Stripping the fur off,
no legs...
-Harry?
-HARRY: Yeah.
Can you do a parrot job
on this--?
on this terrier straight away?
HARRY:
No, I'm still putting
a tuck in the Airedale,
and then I got the frogs
to let out.
-Friday?
-No, I need it for tomorrow.
It's a present.
Oh, dear, it's a long job,
you see, parrot conversions.
Uh...
Tell you what, though,
for free,
terriers make lovely fish.
I mean, I would do that
for you straight away.
Legs off, fins on,
stick a pipe through
its neck so it can breathe,
bit of gold paint, make good.
You'd need
a very big tank.
It's a great
conversation piece.
-Yes, all right, all right.
-Ah.
But, uh...
only if I can watch.
Oh, I thought that
was a bit predictable.
It's been done before.
Yeah, we did it
for Caesar's Christmas show.
No, you didn't, you did
Jack and the Beanstalk.
Here, what was
that picture?
Shh. Next.
Good morning,
Mr. Phipps?
That's right, yes.
Um, do take a seat.
All right, sir.
Now, could you tell us,
roughly,
why you want
to become a librarian?
Uh, well, I've-- I've had
a certain amount of experience
-running a library at school.
-Yes, yes. Yes, yes.
What sort of experience?
Well, for a time, I ran
the upper science library.
Yes, yes.
Now, Mr. Phipps, of course
you do realize that the post
of librarian carries with it
certain very important
responsibilities.
I mean, there's the selection
of books,
the record library
and the art gallery.
Now, it seems to me that
your greatest disadvantage
is your lack
of professional experience,
coupled with the fact that,
being a gorilla,
you would tend
to frighten people.
-Is he a gorilla?
-Yes, he is.
Why didn't it say on his form
that he's a gorilla?
Well, you see,
applicants are not required
to fill in their species.
-What was that picture?
-Shh.
Mr. Phipps, what is your
attitude towards censorship
in a public library?
How do you mean, sir?
Well, I mean, for instance,
would you stock Last Exit
to Brooklyn or Groupie?
-Yes, I think so.
-Good.
Yes, well, that seems to be
very sensible, Mr. Phipps.
I can't pretend that
this library hasn't had
its difficulties.
Mr. Robertson,
your predecessor,
an excellent librarian,
savaged three people last week
and had to be destroyed.
-I'm sorry, sir.
-Oh, no, don't be sorry.
You see, I don't believe that
libraries should be drab places
where people sit in silence,
and that's the main reason
for our policy
of employing wild animals
as librarians.
-Also, they're more permissive.
-Yes, yes.
Pumas keep Hank Janson
on open shelves.
Yes, Mr. Phipps. Mr. Phipps,
I love seeing the customers
when they come to complain
about some book being damaged
ask to see
the chief librarian,
and then you should
see their faces
when the proud beast
leaps from his tiny office,
snatches the book
from their hands,
and sinks his fangs
into their soft...
Mr. Phipps. Kong.
-You can be our next librarian.
-Yes.
You're proud,
majestic and fierce enough.
Will you do it?
-I don't think I can, sir.
-Why not?
-I'm not really a gorilla.
-MAN: What?
I'm a librarian in a skin.
Why this deception?
Well, they said it was
the best way to get the job.
Get out, Mr. Librarian Phipps,
seeing as you're not a gorilla,
but only dressed up as one,
trying to deceive us
in order
to further your career.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Next.
Ah, Mr. Pattinson. Sit.
WOMAN:
Dear Mirror View, I would like
to be paid five guineas
for saying something stupid
about a television show.
Yours sincerely,
Mrs. Sybil Agro.
MAN:
Dear David Jenkins,
East Grinstead, Friday,
Why should I have to pay
64 guineas each year
for my television license
when I can buy one for six?
Yours sincerely,
Captain R.H. Pretty.
P.S. Support Rhodesia,
cut motor taxes,
save the Argylls,
running in, please pass.
MAN:
Dear old codgers,
some friends of mine and I
have formed a consortium
and, working with sophisticated
drilling equipment,
we have discovered
extensive nickel deposits
off Western Scotland.
The Cincinnati Mining Company.
MEN:
Good for you, ma'am.
MAN:
Dear old codgers,
I am President of
the United States of America.
Yours truly, R.M. Nixon.
MEN:
Phew! Bet that's
a job-and-a-half, ma'am.
MAN:
Dear sir,
I am over 3000 years old
and would like to see any
scene with two people in bed.
MEN:
Bet that's a link, ma'am.
[♪]
[SNORING]
[FRENCH ACCENT]
Vera. Vera, darling.
-Wake up, my little lemon.
-Ooh.
Come to my arms.
Oh, Maurice.
What are you doing here?
I could not keep away
from you. I must have you
all the time.
Oh,
this is most inconvenient.
Don't talk to me
about convenience.
Love consumes my naughty mind,
I'm delirious with desire.
[SNORTS]
What's that, Vera?
Oh, nothing, dear.
Just a trick of the light.
Right-o.
Phew. That was close.
Now then,
my little banana,
my little fruit salad,
I can wait for you no longer.
You must be mine, utterly.
Oh, Maurice.
-Vera. How dare you.
-Ooh!
-Roger!
-What's the meaning of this?
Oh, I can explain everything,
my darling.
Who's this?
This is Maurice Zatapathique,
Roger Thompson.
Roger Thompson,
Maurice Zatapathique.
-How do you do?
How could you do this to me,
Vera?
After all we've been through?
Damn it, I love you.
-Ooh, ooh, ooh.
-Vera.
Don't you understand,
it's me that loves you.
[SNORTS]
What's happening,
Vera?
Oh, nothing, dear.
Just a twig brushing
against the window.
Right-o.
Come to me, Vera.
Oh, not now, Roger.
Vera, my little hedgehog,
don't turn me away.
Oh, it cannot be,
Maurice.
Hands off, you filthy,
bally froggy!
Oh, Ken. Ken Biggles.
Yes,
Algy's here as well.
Algy Braithwaite?
That's right,
Vera.
Oh, God. You know
we both still bally love you.
Oh, Biggles. Algy.
Oh, but how wonderful.
[SNORTING]
What's happening,
Vera?
Oh, nothing, dear.
Just the toilet filling up.
Right-o.
Scusi, you tell me where
is Mrs. Vera Jackson, please?
Yes, right and right again.
-Ah. Muchas gracias.
-Right-o.
[ALL CHATTERING]
-[BAND PLAYING MARIACHI MUSIC]
-Oh, Vera.
Do you remember Acapulco
in the springtime?
Oh, the Herman Rodrigues Four.
[LAUGHING]
Vera.
I distinctly heard
a Mexican rhythm combo.
Oh, no, dear. It was just
the electric blanket
switching off.
Hm. Well,
I'm going for a tinkle.
No,
you can't do that.
Here, we haven't finished
the sketch yet.
Dash it all, there's only
another bally page.
I say. There's no one
to react to.
-Don't talk to the camera.
-Oh, sorry.
[GONG RESONATES]
It's no good you coming in.
He's gone and left the sketch.
Yes, he went for a tinkle.
Shh!
I think my wife is beginning
to suspect something.
I felt that ending
was a bit predictable.
[BELCHES]
Oh, yes, indeed,
there was a certain
lack of originality.
[SLURPING]
However, it's not necessarily
a good thing just to be
different.
No, quite, there is equal humor
in the conventional.
[PIGS SNORTING]
[BELCHES]
But on the other hand,
is it what the public wants?
I mean,
with the new permissiveness,
not to mention
the balance of payments.
It's an undeniable fact that--
[GULPING]
I agree with that completely.
[SLURPING]
[BELCHES]
That's it.
I'm getting out of this show,
before it's too late.
[GULPS] Too late.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
[♪]