-[TIRES SCREECHING]
-Ow! Ooh!
[HORNS HONKING]
[PANTING]
Ow! It's... Agh!
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
Have you finished
in there yet?
[♪]
MAN 1:
Dear Sir, I object strongly
to the obvious lavatorial turn
this show has already taken.
Why do we never hear about
the good things in Britain,
like Mary Bignall's
wonderful jump in 1964?
Yours et cetera, Ken Voyeur.
[CROWD CHEERING]
MAN 2:
Dear Sir, I object strongly
to the obvious athletic turn
this show has now taken.
Why can't we hear more about
the human body?
There is nothing embarrassing
or nasty about the human body
except for the intestines
and bits of the bottom.
MAN 3:
Dear Sir, I object
strongly to the letters
on your program.
They are clearly not written
by the general public
and are merely included
for a cheap laugh.
Yours et cetera,
William Knickers.
[ALL PLAYING]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
-MAN 1:
That was absolutely revolting.
-MAN 2: Appalling.
WOMAN 1:
Disgusting. Disgusting.
MAN 3:
Disgusting rubbish.
[♪]
I, too, take strong exception
to this resurgence
of cheap jokes about poo-poos.
Mr. Voyeur's letter
stated very--
Ooh. Oh, excuse me.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
As I was saying,
the letter previously read
made quite clear the view
of a great majority...
[♪]
1348. The Black Death,
typhus, cholera,
consumption, bubonic plague.
Oh, those were the days.
[ALL SIGHING]
-Now, I'm not-- I'm--
-[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
Now, I'm not prepared
to go on with this unless these
interruptions cease. All right?
Right.
The devastating effect
of these, um--
[TICKING]
[HORN HONKING]
[ENGINES REV]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CRASHING]
No, don't follow me.
And don't zoom in on me.
No, I'm off. I'm off.
That's it. That's all.
I'm off.
Are you nervy, irritable,
depressed, tired of life?
Keep it up.
This house is surrounded.
I'm afraid I must not ask
anyone to leave the room.
No, I must ask nobody.
No, I must ask everybody to--
I must not ask
anyone to leave the room--
No one must be asked by me...
to leave room.
No, no one must ask
the room to leave...
I ask the room
shall by someone be left. Not.
Ask no--
Ask nobody the room
somebody leave shall I.
Shall I leave the room?
Everyone must leave
the room as it is...
with them in it.
Understand?
You don't want anybody
to leave the room.
Now, alduce me
to introlow myself.
I'm sorry.
Alself me to myduce intro--
Intro me to lose mylow--
Alme to you introself my--
Excuse me a moment.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm afraid I must ask
that no one leave the room.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Inspector Tiger.
-ALL: Tiger?
-Where?! Where?!
[LAUGHS]
Oh.
Me Tiger.
You Jane.
[GROWLS]
Beg your pardon.
Um, allow me
to introduce myself.
I'm afraid I must ask that
no one leave the room.
-Why not?
-Elementary.
Since the body
was found in this room
and no one has left it.
Therefore, the murderer
must be somebody
in this room.
What body?
Somebody...
in this room
must the murderer be.
The murderer of the body
is somebody in this room
which nobody must leave.
Leave the body in the room
not to be left by anybody.
Nobody leaves anybody
or the body with somebody.
Anybody who is anybody
shall leave the body
in the room body.
Take the tablets, Tiger.
Anybody with a body
but not the body is nobody.
Nobody leaves the body
in the bo--
Albody me to introbody a--
[GRUNTS]
[METAL SCRAPING]
Now for Sir Gerald.
That's better.
Now, I'm Inspector Tiger
and I must ask
that nobody leave the room.
Now, someone
has committed a murder here
and that murderer
is someone in this room.
The question is... who?
Look, there hasn't been
a murder.
-No murder?
-ALL: No.
Oh.
I don't like it.
It's too simple,
too clear-cut.
I'd better wait.
No, too simple, too clear-cut.
[TIGER SCREAMS]
[GUNSHOT]
By Jove, he was right.
This house is surrounded.
I must ask that no one
leave the room.
I'm Chief Superintendent
Lookout.
-Lookout?
-What? Where?
Oh, me, Lookout.
Lookout of the Yard.
Why, what would we see?
I'm sorry?
Well, what would we see
if we look out of the yard?
I'm afraid I don't
follow that at all.
Ah-ha! The body.
So the murderer
must be somebody
in this room.
Unless he had very long arms.
Say, 30 or 40 feet.
I think we can discount
that one.
[LAUGHS]
Look out of the yard.
Very good.
Right. Now we'll reconstruct
the crime.
I'll sit down here.
Constable,
you turn off the lights.
Good. Now then,
there was a scream...
[LOOKOUT SCREAMS]
then just before the lights
went up, there was a shot.
[GUNSHOT]
All right, all right,
the house is surrounded,
and nobody leave the room
and all the rest of it.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Assistant Chief Constable
Theresamanbehindyou.
ALL:
Theresamanbehindyou?
You're not going to catch me
with an old one like that.
Heh-heh. Right,
let's reconstruct the crime.
Constable,
you be Inspector Tiger.
Right, sir.
Nobody leave the room
ask shall.
Somebody I leave nobody
in the room body shall.
Take the tablets, Tigerbody.
-Alself me to myduce introlow...
-[Theresamanbehindyou clapping]
-...left body in the roomself.
-Very good. Sit down there.
-Thank you, sir.
-Right.
Now we'll pretend
the lights have gone out.
Constable, you scream.
Aaaaagh!
Somebody shoots you.
And the door opens--
Nobody move.
I am Chief Constable Fire.
-ALL: Fire?
-Where? Where?
We're interrupting this sketch
but we'll be bringing you back
the moment
anything interesting happens.
Meanwhile, here are
some friends of mine.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
MAN:
Dear Sir,
I'm sorry this letter is late.
It should have come at
the beginning of the program.
Yours, Ivor Bigbottie, age two.
From the plastic arts,
we turn to football.
Last night in the
Stadium of Light, Jarrow,
we witnessed the resuscitation
of a great footballing
tradition
when Jarrow United came of age
in a European sense
with an almost Proustian
display
of modern existentialist
football,
virtually annihilating
by midfield moral argument,
the now surely obsolescent
catenaccio defensive
philosophy
of Signor Alberto Fanffino.
Bologna, indeed, were a sight
intellectually out-argued
by a Jarrow team
thrusting and bursting
with aggressive
Kantian positivism.
And outstanding
in this fine Jarrow team
was my man of the match,
the arch-thinker,
free-scheming,
scarcely-ever-to-be-curbed
midfield cognoscente,
Jimmy Buzzard.
Good evening, Brian.
Jimmy, at least one
ageing football commentator
was gladdened last night
by the sight of an English
footballer
breaking free
of the limpid tentacles
of packed Mediterranean
defense.
Good evening, Brian.
Uh, were you surprised
at the way the Italians
ceded midfield dominance
so early on in the game?
Well, Brian...
I'm opening a boutique.
Now, this is, of course,
symptomatic of a new breed
of footballer,
as it is indeed symptomatic
of your whole genre
of player, is it not?
Good evening, Brian.
What I'm getting at, Jimmy,
is you seem to have discovered
a new concept of the mode
of which you dissected
the Italian defense
last night.
I hit the ball first time,
and there it was
in the back of the net.
I know.
Uh, do you think Jarrow will
adopt a more defensive posture
for the first leg
of the next tie in Turkey?
I hit the ball first time,
and there it was
in the back of the net.
Uh, yes, yes, but have you
any plans for dealing with
the free-scoring Turkish
forwards?
Well, Brian...
I'm opening a boutique.
And now let's take a look
at the state of play
in the detective sketch.
Alself me to introlow mybody.
[GUNSHOT]
[SOMBER MUSIC]
[MUMBLING]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[♪]
Cheeky.
Oh, temper, temper.
Well, some of us
don't like having men
crawling over us
the whole time.
[GROWLING]
You need to take all the
opportunities you can get,
dear.
[SPLAT]
Unlike some people
I could mention,
I'm quite happily married,
thank you.
Yes, I've seen you often,
tethered up in the garden.
[♪]
[CANNON SHOTS]
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
[APPLAUSE STOPS ABRUPTLY]
Hello, good evening
and welcome
to yet another edition
of Interesting People.
And my first interesting
person tonight
is the highly interesting
Mr. Howard Stools
from Kendal in Westmorland.
[APPLAUSE]
[APPLAUSE STOPS]
Good evening, Mr. Stools.
[HIGH VOICE]
Hello, David.
Mr. Stools, what makes you
particularly interesting?
Well, I'm only
half an inch long.
Well, that's extremely
interesting.
Thank you for coming
on the show tonight,
Mr. Stools.
I don't think that was
interesting, David. In fact--
Ha. Mr. Howard Stools
from Kendal in Westmorland,
half an inch long.
[APPLAUSE]
[APPLAUSE STOPS]
Our next guest tonight has
come all the way from Egypt.
He's just flown into London
today. He's Mr. Ali Bayan.
He's with us
in the studio tonight
and he's stark raving mad.
[BABBLING]
[APPLAUSE]
[APPLAUSE STOPS]
Mr. Ali Bayan,
stark raving mad.
Now it's time for
our music spot and we
turn the spotlight tonight
on the Rachel Toovey
Bicycle Choir...
[APPLAUSE]
...with their fantastic
arrangement
of "Men of Harlech"
for bicycle bells only.
ALL:
♪ Sleep my babe ♪
♪ No ill betide thee ♪
♪ All through the night ♪
[BELLS DINGING]
[APPLAUSE]
The Rachel Toovey
Bicycle Choir.
Really interesting.
Remember,
if you're interesting
and want to appear
on this program,
write your name and address
on your telephone number
and send it to this address:
The BBC, care of E.F. Lutt,
18 Rupee Buildings, West 12.
-[APPLAUSE]
-Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
Now here's
an interesting person.
Apart from being
a full-time stapling machine,
he can also give a cat
influenza.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[COUGHING, RETCHING]
[CAT SNEEZING]
Well, you can't get much more
interesting than that,
or can you?
With me now--
Ah-ha.
With me now is Mr. Thomas
Walters of West Hartlepool,
who is totally invisible.
Good evening, Mr. Walters.
MAN:
Over here, Hughie.
Huh.
Mr. Walters, are--
Are you sure you're invisible?
Oh, yes, most certainly.
Well, Mr. Walters,
what's it like
being invisible?
Well, for a start,
at the office where I work,
I can be sitting at my desk
all day
and the others
totally ignore me.
At home, even though
we are in the same room,
my wife does not
speak to me for hours.
People pass me by
in the street
without a glance
in my direction
and I can walk into a room
without--
Well, last week
on Interesting People,
we met
Mr. Oliver Cavendish who--
Even now, you yourself
do hardly notice me--
Mr. Oliver Cavendish
of Leicester
who claims to be able
to recite the entire Bible
in one second
whilst being struck
on the head with a large axe.
[CHUCKLES]
Wow.
We've since discovered
that he was a fraud.
He did not--
Yes, a fraud.
He did not, in fact,
recite the entire Bible.
He merely recited
the first two words,
"In the", before his death.
[APPLAUSE]
HOST:
And now it's time for
Interesting Sport.
And this week
it's all-in cricket,
live from the Municipal Baths,
Croydon.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[APPLAUSE]
All-in cricket.
Great, great.
With me now is Mr. Ken Dove,
twice voted Most Interesting
Man in Dorking.
Ken, I believe
you're interested in shouting.
[SHOUTING]
Yes, I'm interested
in shouting, all right!
By Jove, you certainly
hit the nail on the head
with that particular
observation of yours, then!
What does your wife think
of this?
WOMAN [SHOUTS]:
I agree with him!
Shut up!
At parties, for instance,
people never come up to me.
I just sit there
and everybody totally--
Now, that is, uh,
Tiddles, I believe.
Um, yes, yes, this is--
This is Tiddles.
And what does she do?
Uh, she flies across
the studio
and lands in a bucket
of water.
-By herself?
-No, I fling her.
Well, that's extremely
interesting.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Don Savage and Tiddles.
[MEOWING]
[SPLASHES]
Oh, I'm more interesting
than a wet pussycat!
THOMAS:
--for hour after hour
after hour--
Yes, great. Now, for the first
time on television,
Interesting People
brings you a man
who claims he can send bricks
to sleep by hypnosis.
Mr. Keith Maniac
from Guatemala.
Good evening.
Keith, you claim you can
send bricks to sleep.
Yes, that is correct. I can.
Entirely by hypnosis.
Yes. I use no artificial
means, whatsoever.
-[HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM]
-Oh, oh.
You've injured
Mr. Stools!
I-I simply stare at the brick
and it goes to sleep.
Well, we have a brick here,
Keith.
Perhaps you can send it
to sleep for us.
Oh. Ah, heh.
Well, I am afraid
that is already asleep.
Ha. How do you know?
Well, it's not moving.
I see. Have we got
a moving brick?
Yes, we've got a moving brick,
Keith.
It's coming over now.
Now fast asleep.
-Very good. Very good, indeed.
-[APPLAUSE]
Yes, it's all done
with the eyes.
Yes, Mr. Keith Maniac
from Guatemala.
Mr. Stools!
Speak to me, Howard!
[CROWD CHEERING]
And now,
four tired undertakers.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[MOANS]
[BOTH GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
ANNOUNCER:
We're interrupting this
to take you back very quickly
to the Jimmy Buzzard
interview,
where we understand something
exciting's just happened.
I've fallen off my chair,
Brian.
[♪]
[DOG BARKS]
[WOMAN AND MAN GIGGLING]
MAN 1 [WHISPERS]:
Shh. I think my wife's
beginning to suspect.
MAN 2:
You, shut up, up there!
MAN 1:
What do you mean, shut up?
-You shut up! Be quiet!
-WOMAN 1: Shut up!
[ALL SHOUTING ANGRILY]
I apologize for that,
but I think you'll find this
a bit more interesting.
[♪]
TAYLOR:
Good evening.
Tonight I want to examine
the whole question
of 18th-century social
legislation:
Its relevance to
the hierarchical structure
of post-Renaissance society
and its impact on the future
of parochial organization
in an expanding agrarian
economy.
But first, a bit of fun.
[♪]
TAYLOR:
To put England's social
legislation
in a European context
is Professor
Gert Van Der Whoops
of the Rijksmuseum
in The Hague.
In Holland, in the early part
of the 15th century,
there were three things
important to social
legislation.
One, rise of merchant classes.
Two, urbanization
of craft guilds.
Three, declining moral values
in age of increasing
social betterment.
But first, a bit of fun.
[CHORUS SINGING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Oh. Ahem.
And now,
Professor R.J. Canning.
[CHOIR SINGING]
The cat sat on the mat.
And now,
the Battle of Trafalgar.
Tonight, we examine popular
views of this great battle.
Was the Battle of Trafalgar
fought in the Atlantic
off southern Spain?
Or was it fought on dry land
near Cudworth in Yorkshire?
Here is one man
who thinks it was.
And here is his friend.
CANNING: What makes you think
the Battle of Trafalgar
was fought near Cudworth?
Because Drake was too clever
for the German fleet.
CANNING:
I beg your pardon?
I've forgotten what
I said now.
CANNING: Mr. Gumby's
remarkable views
have sparked off a wave
of controversy
amongst his fellow historians.
Well, I---
I think we should, uh,
reappraise
our concept of
the Battle of Trafalgar.
Well, well!
I agree with everything
Mr. Gumby says.
Well, I-I think, uh,
cement is more interesting...
[SNIFFS]
...uh, than people think.
TAYLOR:
One subject,
four different views...
12 and six in a plain wrapper.
The stuff of history is indeed
woven in the woof.
Pearl Harbor.
There are pages
in history's book
which are written
on the grand scale.
Events so momentous,
that they dwarf
man and time alike.
And such is
the Battle of Pearl Harbor,
reenacted for us now
by the women of the Batley
Townswomen's Guild.
CANNING:
Miss Rita Fairbanks, you
organized this reconstruction
of the battle of Pearl Harbor.
Why?
Uh, well, we've always been
extremely interested
in modern drama.
We were, of course,
the first townswomen's guild
to perform
Camp on Blood Island.
And last year,
of course,
we did our extremely popular
reenactment
of Nazi war atrocities.
So this year, we thought
we'd like to do something
in a lighter vein.
CANNING: So you chose
the Battle of Pearl Harbor?
Yes, that's right, we did.
CANNING: Well, I can see
you're all ready to go,
so I'll just wish you good
luck in your latest venture.
Thank you very much,
young man.
CANNING: Ladies and gentlemen,
The World of History
is proud to present
the premiere
of the Batley
Townswomen's Guild
reenactment of
the Battle of Pearl Harbor.
[WHISTLE TOOTS]
[ALL SCREAMING, GRUNTING]
[GRUNTING]
The Battle of Pearl Harbor.
Incidentally, I'm sorry
if I got a little bit shirty
earlier on in the program
when I kept getting
interrupted
by all these films and things
that kept coming in, but I--
We shall--
[GUNSHOTS]
Heretofore shall this soul
be received unto thy mercy...
[SOMBER MUSIC]
-[UPBEAT MUSIC]
-[CHEERING]
And so I said
if it happened again,
I'd get very angry
and talk to Lord Hill and--
[MUMBLING]
CANNING:
Tell Lord Hill.
[♪]
Ugh!