[PINBALL MACHINE
CLATTERING AND RINGING]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
MAN:
Oh, no, you don't.
[BEAR GROWLING]
[MUFFLED CRIES]
[GRUNTING]
Hey, did you see that?
Hmm?
Did you see somebody
go past the window?
What?
Somebody just went past
the window.
That way.
Oh.
Another one.
Hmm?
Another one just went past,
downwards.
What?
Two people have just fallen
out of that window
to their almost certain death.
Fine, fine. Fine.
Look, two people--
Three people have just fallen
past that window.
Must be a board meeting.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, that was Wilkins
of Finance.
Ahem.
No, that was Robertson.
Wilkins.
Robertson.
-Wilkins.
-Robertson.
-That was Wilkins.
He was a good, uh,
good golfer, Wilkins.
Very good golfer.
Rotten at finance.
It'll be Parkinson next.
Bet you it won't.
How much?
What?
How much do you bet it won't?
Fiver?
-All right.
-Done.
-You're on.
-Fine.
-Come on, Parky.
-Don't do it, Parky.
-Come on, Parky. Come on, jump.
-Come on, now. Be sensible.
MAN:
Dear sir, I'm writing
to complain about that sketch
about people falling
out of a high building.
I have worked all my life
in such a building
and have never once--
[SCREAMING]
Parkinson!
Johnson!
[ALL SCREAM]
MAN 1:
My God, this is terrible.
Will somebody please stop it?
MAN 2:
I know, sir.
Let's try it this way:
[ALL SCREAM]
[GONG RESONATES]
Alakazam,
alacadabra, alakazam.
Alacadabra, alakazam,
alacadabra.
Alakazam, alacadabra.
[MAN HUMMING]
-[WOMAN GIGGLES]
-Hmm?
WOMAN:
Hello. [LAUGHING]
[♪]
Good evening. Tonight, Spectrum
looks at one of the major
problems in the world today.
The whole vexed question
of what is going on.
Is there still time to confront
it, let alone solve it,
or is it too late?
What are the figures?
What are the facts?
What do people mean
when they talk about things?
Alexander Hardacre of
the Economic Affairs Bureau.
In this graph,
this column represents
23 percent of the population,
28 percent of the population
and this column represents
43 percent of the population.
Telling figures, indeed.
But what do they mean to you?
What do they mean to me?
What do they mean to the
average man in the street?
With me now is Professor
Tiddles of Leeds University.
Professor, you've spent many
years researching into things.
-What do you think?
-I think it's too early to tell.
Too early to tell,
too early to say.
It means the same. The word
"say" is the same as "tell."
They're not spelt the same,
but they mean the same.
It's an identical situation
we have with "ship" and
"boat,"
but not "bow" and "bough."
They're spelt differently,
mean different things,
but sound the same.
But the real question remains
what is the solution to this?
What can we do?
What am I saying?
Why am I sitting in this chair?
Why am I on this program?
What am I going to say next?
Here to answer this
is a professional cricketer.
I can say nothing
at this point.
-You are wrong. Professor?
-Hello.
Hello. So where do we stand?
Where do we stand?
Where do we sit?
Where do we come?
Where do we go?
What do we do, what do we say?
What do we eat? What do we
drink? What do we think?
What do we do?
[CRASHING]
Sorry.
[GROWLING]
[GRUNTING]
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hello. Mr. and Mrs. Johnson,
isn't it?
-That's right. Yes.
-Well, come on in.
Excuse me
not shaking hands,
but I've just been putting a
bit of lard on the cat's boil.
Very nice.
Well, you must be tired.
It's a long drive from
Coventry, isn't it?
Yes, well, we usually reckon
on five and a half hours
and it took us six hours
and 53 minutes with
a 25-minute wait
in Frampton Cotterell
to stretch our legs.
We had to wait half an hour to
go on the M5 near Droitwich.
-Really?
-Then there was
a three-mile queue
just before Bridgewater,
on the A38.
I mean, normally,
we come around on the B3339
just before Bridgewater,
you see.
-Really?
-But we decided to risk it
because they're always saying
they're going to widen it.
-Are they?
-Just by the intersection
where the A372 joins up.
There's room to widen it there.
There's only the grass verges.
They could get another six-feet,
knock down that hospital.
Then we took the coast road
through Williton
and got all the Taunton
traffic on the A358
from Crowcombe and Stogumber.
Well, you must be dying
for a cup of tea.
Well, wouldn't say no.
-Well, good--
-Not if it's warm and wet.
[LAUGHS]
Well, come on in the lounge.
I'm just about to serve
afternoon tea.
Very nice.
Come on in,
Mr. and Mrs. Johnson.
Oh, this is
Mr. and Mrs. Phillips.
-Good afternoon.
-Pleased to meet you.
It's their third year with us.
We can't keep you away,
can we?
[CHUCKLES]
And over here is Mr. Hilter.
[GERMAN ACCENT] Ah. Ah.
Ah, good time.
Uh, good afternoon.
Planning a little excursion
are we, Mr. Hilter?
Uh, ja, ja, we make
a little, uh...
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
-Hike.
-Hiking.
We make a little hike
for--for Bideford.
Oh, well, you'll be wanting
the A39, then. You see--
No, no, no. You've got
the wrong map there.
This is Stalingrad.
You want the Ilfracombe
and Barnstaple section.
Ah. Ha, ha, ha.
Hein-- Uh, Reginald,
ha, ha, ha.
You have the wrong map here
you silly old,
leg-before-wicket
English person.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, mein Fuhrer.
I did not-- Oh!
Mein-- Mein Dickie,
old chum.
Lucky Mr. Johnson
pointed that out, eh?
You wouldn't have had much fun
in Stalingrad, would you?
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
I said, you wouldn't have had
much fun in Stalingrad,
would you?
Not much fun in Stalingrad,
no.
Oh, you know, I'm sorry.
I didn't introduce you.
This is Ron.
Ron Vibbentrop.
Oh, not von Ribbentrop, eh?
-[LAUGHS]
-Nein! Nein! Nein! Nein!
Oh, ha, ha. No,
he different, other chap. No.
I in Somerset am being born.
Von Ribbentrop is born
in Dusseldorf, West 8.
So they say.
Ha, ha, ha.
And this is the quiet one:
Mr. Bimmler.
Heinrich Bimmler.
How do you do there, squire?
Also, I am not Minehead lad
but I in Lincolnshire house
was given birth to.
But stay in Lincolnshire house
all during war,
owing to nasty running sores.
Uh, I was unable to go
in the streets,
play football, or go
to Nuremberg. Uh-- Ha!
I am a retired window cleaner
and pacifist
without doing war crimes.
Argh!
I am very glad England
win World Cup--
Bobby Charlton, Martin Peters.
And eating lots of chips
and fish and toad in the holes
and Dundee cake
on Piccadilly line.
Don't you know, old chap?
And was head of Gestapo
for 10 years.
No! Five years.
Ow! No, no. Nein. Ha!
Was not head of Gestapo
at all. [LAUGHS]
-I make joke.
-[ALL LAUGH]
-Oh, Mr. Bimmler,
you do have us on.
-[PHONE RINGS]
Oh, excuse me. I must
just go and answer that.
Uh, how long are you down here
for, Mr. Hilter?
Just the fortnight?
Why do you ask that?
Are you a spy or something?
Get over there against
the wall, Britischer pig!
You're going to die!
Take it easy, Dickie,
old chum.
I'm sorry, Mr. Johnson.
He's a bit on edge.
He hasn't slept
since 1945.
Shut your cake hole,
you Nazi.
-[LAUGHING]
-Cool it, Fuhrer cat.
Oh,
the fun we have.
Haven't I seen him
on the television?
Nicht! Nein! Nein!
Oh, uh, no. No.
-Television doctor?
-No, no.
Telephone, Mr. Hilter.
It's that nice Mr. McGohring
from the Bell and Compasses.
-Ah!
-He says he's found a place
where you can hire bombers
by the hour.
If he opens his big mouth
again, it's lampshade time.
VON RIBBENTROP:
Shut up!
Ha, ha, ha.
Hire bombers by the hour.
What a laugh he is,
that Scottish person.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
Good old Norman.
He's on the telephone
the whole time nowadays.
In business, is he?
Soon, baby.
Of course,
it's his big day, Thursday.
They've been planning it
for months.
What happens then?
Oh, it's the North Minehead
by-election.
Mr. Hilter's standing as a
National Bocialist candidate.
He's got wonderful plans
for Minehead.
-Like what?
-Well, for a start,
he wants to annex Poland.
Oh. North Minehead's
Conservative, isn't it?
Well, they get a lot of people
at their rallies.
-Rallies?
-Well, they're Bocialist
meetings
down at the Axis Café
on Rosedale Road.
[HILTER SPEAKING IN GERMAN
THROUGH MEGAPHONE]
["DAS LIED DER DEUTSCHEN"
PLAYING]
[SPEAKING GERMAN GIBBERISH]
I am not a racialist...
but--
und this is a big "but."
We in the National Bocialist
Party believe:
[SPEAKING GERMAN GIBBERISH]
[LIGHT APPLAUSE]
...Minehead.
Mr. Hitler--
Hilter. He says that,
historically,
Taunton is a part
of Minehead already.
He's right.
Do you know that?
[SPEAKING GERMAN GIBBERISH]
...in Somerset.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Sieg Heil! Sieg Heil!
[CHANTING]
INTERVIEWER:
What do you think
of Mr. Hilter's policies?
Well, I don't like the sound
of these here
"boncentration bamps."
Well, I gave him
my baby to kiss
and he bit it on the head.
Well, I think he'd do a lot
of good for the stock
exchange.
No, no.
Oh, yes, Britischer pals.
He is wunderbar-- ful. Uh...
I think he's right
about the coons,
but then,
I'm a bit mental.
I think he's got beautiful
legs.
Well, speaking as
Conservative candidate,
I just drone on and on
and on and on,
never letting anyone else
get a word in edgeways
until I start foaming
at the mouth
and falling over backwards.
Oh...
Is he foaming at the mouth
to fall over backwards,
or falling over backwards
to foam at the mouth?
Tonight, Spectrum examines
frothing and falling
coughing and calling,
screaming and bawling,
galling and mauling,
trawling and squalling
and "zalling." "Zalling."
Is there a word, "zalling"?
If there is, what's it mean?
If not, what's it mean?
Perhaps both. Maybe neither.
What do I mean by the word,
"mean"? By the word, "word"?
What do I mean by "do,"
and what do I do by "mean"?
What do I mean by wasting your
time like this? Good night.
Good night.
Uh, good evening.
I wish to report a burglary.
-[CLEARS THROAT]
-Speak up, please, sir.
I wish to report a burglary.
I can't hear you, sir.
I wish to report a burglary!
That's a little bit too loud,
sir.
Could you say it just a little
less loud than that?
I wish to report a burglary.
No, I'm still not
getting anything.
Uh, could you try it
in a higher register?
-What do you mean,
a higher register?
-What?
[IN SHRILL VOICE]
I wish to report a burglary.
Oh, that's it.
Hang on a moment.
Now, a little bit louder.
-I wish to report a burglary!
-Report a what?
-Burglary!
-That's it.
That's the exact frequency.
Now, keep it there.
-[SHRILLY] Hello, sarge!
-[DEEPLY] Good evening,
Charlie.
I was sitting at home
with a friend of mine
from Camber Sands
when we heard a noise
in the bedroom!
We went to investigate
and found £5000 stolen!
Well, I'm afraid
I'm going off duty now, sir.
Uh, could you tell
Sergeant Foster?
I was sitting at home
with a friend of mine
from Camber Sands--
[NORMAL VOICE]
Excuse me, sir, but, uh,
why the funny voice?
[NORMAL VOICE]
Oh, uh, I'm terribly sorry.
I just got used to talking like
that to the other sergeant.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I can't hear you.
Could you speak
in a lower register?
Uh... Oh.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Ahem, I wish to report
the loss of £5000.
Five thousand pounds?
That's serious!
You'd better speak
to the detective inspector.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
What seems to be the trouble,
sergeant?
[RAPIDLY] This man has come in
to report he was home, he heard
a noise, went to investigate,
and found that 5000
in savings was stolen.
I see. [NORMAL VOICE]
Where do you live, sir?
[NORMAL VOICE]
121 Halliwell Road,
Dulwich, SE21.
[RAPIDLY]
121 Halliwell Road,
Dulwich, SE21.
[SHRILLY]
Another Halliwell Road job,
eh?
[RAPIDLY]
I thought that bloke
was put inside last year.
[SHRILLY]
Yes, in Parkhurst.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
It must have been
somebody else.
[DEEPLY]
Thank you.
[NORMALLY] We'll get
things moving right away.
[SHRILLY]
You take over.
[NORMALLY]
Alert squad cars.
[SING-SONG]
Hello, darling. I'm afraid
I'll be late home.
♪ Calling all squad cars ♪
♪ In the area ♪
[IN DEEP, GRUFF VOICE]
I think that's in
very bad taste.
[MEOWS]
[BARKS]
[BLEATS]
Some people do talk
in the most extraordinary way.
ANNOUNCER:
Good afternoon, and welcome
to Hurlingham Park.
You join us
just as the competitors
are running out onto the field
on this lovely winter's
afternoon here
with the going firm underfoot
and very little sign of rain.
Well, it certainly looks
as though
we're in for a splendid
afternoon's sport in this,
the 127th Upper-class
Twit of the Year Show.
Now, the competitors
will be off any moment
so let me just identify them
for you.
Vivian Smith-Smythe-Smith
has O-level in chemo-hygiene.
Simon-Zinc-Trumpet-Harris
married to a very attractive
table lamp.
Nigel Incubator-Jones'
best friend is a tree,
and in his spare time,
he's a stockbroker.
Gervaise Brook-Hampster
is in the Guards
and his father uses him
as a wastepaper basket.
And finally,
Oliver St. John-Mollusc Harrow
and the Guards,
thought by many to be this
year's outstanding twit.
Now they're moving up
to the starting line.
There's a jolly good crowd
here today.
They're under
starter's orders.
And...
they're off!
Oh, no, they're not.
No, they didn't realize
they were supposed to start.
Never mind,
we'll soon sort that out.
The judge is explaining it
to them now.
I think Nigel and Gervaise
have got the idea.
All set to go.
Oh, and they're off!
And it's a fast start
this year.
Oliver St. John-Mollusc
running a bit wide there.
And now they're coming into
their first test:
the straight line.
They've got to walk along
this straight line
without falling over--
And Oliver's over
at the back there.
Simon's coming through
quite fast on the outside.
Simon and Nigel, both of them
coming through very fast.
There's Nigel, number three.
And there's Gervaise coming
through just out of shot.
And now, the positions.
Simon and Vivian at the front
coming into the matchbox jump.
Three layers of matchboxes
to clear.
And Simon's over.
And Vivian's over,
beautifully.
Oh, the jump of a lifetime!
If only his father
could understand.
Here's Nigel. He's confused--
No. And Gervaise is over.
No, he's, uh-- Nigel is over.
He's only just hit the top.
And now it's Gervaise.
Gervaise is going to jump it.
No, he's jumped the wrong way.
Well done, Gervaise.
There he goes.
Nigel's over, beautifully.
Now it's only Oliver.
Oliver and Gervaise--
Oh, bad luck.
And now it's Kicking
the Beggar.
Simon's there
and he's putting the boot in,
and not terribly hard
but he's down!
And he goes down,
so Simon can move on.
Now, Vivian's there.
Vivian is there
and waiting for a chance.
Here he comes. Oh!
The old pile driver.
A real pile driver.
And now, uh, Simon's
our number one,
Vivian two, Nigel three,
Gervaise in four,
and Oliver bringing up
the rear.
Uh, there's Oliver. There's
Oliver now. He's at the back.
I think he's having
a little trouble
with his old brain injury.
He's gonna have a go.
No, no. Bad luck.
But he's up. He doesn't know
when he's beaten, this boy.
He doesn't know
when he's winning, either.
He doesn't have any sort
of sensory apparatus there.
Outstanding. Outstanding--
Oh, my.
Oh, there's Gervaise,
putting the boot in there.
He's got the beggar down. The
steward's giving him advice.
Yes, he can move on, now.
He can move on
to the Hunt Photograph.
There's Ger-- I think he's
real-- Yes, he's off.
Gervaise is there and Oliver's
still at the back
having trouble
with the matchboxes.
Now, here's
the Hunt Ball Photograph
and the first here is Simon.
He's going to enjoy a joke
with Lady Arabella Plunkett.
She hopes to go into films.
And Vivian's through there,
and Nigel's there
enjoying a joke with Lady
Sarah Pencil Farthing Vivian
Steamroller Adams Thigh
Biscuit
Aftershave Gore
Stringbottom Smith.
And there's Simon, now,
in the sports car.
And he's reversing
into the old woman.
He caught her beautifully.
Now he's going to accelerate
forward, there,
to wake up the neighbor.
There's Vivian, I think.
No, Vivian's lost his keys.
No, there's Vivian.
He's got the woman, slowly but
surely, right in the midriff.
And here he is. Here he is
to wake up the neighbor now.
Simon, right in the lead,
comfortably in the lead,
but he can't get this neighbor
woken up.
He's slamming away there
as best he can.
He's getting absolutely
no reaction at all.
No-- There! There, he's woken
him up. And Simon's through.
Here comes Vivian.
Vivian to slam the door.
There we are, back at the
ball. I think that's Gervaise.
That's Gervaise
going through, there.
And here-- Here comes Oliver,
brave Oliver.
Is he gonna make it to the
table? No, I don't
think he is.
Yes, he is. Oh!
[CHATTERING]
And the crowd are rising
to him, there.
And there I can see--
Who is that there?
Yes, that's Nigel.
Nigel has woken the neighbor.
My God, this is exciting.
Nigel's very excited.
He's going through.
Here comes Gervaise.
Gervaise-- Oh, no, this is...
Out in the front there
is Simon
who's supposed to insult
the waiter and he's forgotten.
And Oliver
has run himself over!
What a great twit.
And there--
Now, here comes Vivian.
Vivian to insult the waiter,
and he is heaping abuse
on him.
He's just humiliating him,
there and he's gone
into the lead.
Simon's not with him.
No, Vivian's hit the bar.
Now, they've got to get
under this bar.
This is extremely difficult
as it requires
absolutely expert coordination
between mind and body.
Now, they need to get there.
Here we go again.
Simon's fallen backwards.
Here's Nigel, and he's
tripped.
Nigel has tripped
and he's under.
Simon fails again.
Uh, now here is Gervaise
coming through--
And Simon is through
by accident.
There's Gervaise, he's the
last one, but here we are.
Here's Nigel right at the head
of the field.
He's gotta shoot the rabbit.
These rabbits have been tied
to the ground,
but they tend to be frisky,
and this is only a one-day
event.
And they're blazing away
there.
They're not getting the
results they might.
Gervaise is in there,
trying to bash it to death
with the butt of his rifle.
And I think, Nigel's in there
with his bare hands,
but they're not getting
results. It is a little misty,
and they must be shooting from
a-- A range of at least
one-foot.
But there's a couple of hits
there, I think.
Yes, they've had a couple
of hits,
and the whole field
is up again
and here they are.
They're coming up to the debs.
Gervaise first, Vivian second,
Simon third.
And now they've got to take
the bras off from the front.
This is really difficult. This
is the most difficult part of
the entire competition.
My God, they're having a bit
of trouble in there, I think.
They're really trying now and
the crowd is getting excited
and I think some of the twits
are getting rather
excited too.
But anyway, Vivian is there.
Vivian is coming through.
Simon's in second place.
And-- Oh, there's Oliver!
He's dead, but he's not
necessarily out of it.
There goes Nigel. No, he's
lost something. No, he hasn't.
And Gervaise running through
to this final obstacle.
Now, all they have to do here
to win the title
is to shoot themselves.
Simon has a go. Bad luck,
he misses. Nigel misses.
Now there's Gervaise,
and Gervaise has shot himself.
Gervaise is
Upper-class Twit of the Year.
There's Nigel.
He's shot Simon by mistake.
Simon is second,
and there's Nigel.
Nigel has shot himself.
Nigel is third in this fine
and most exciting Upper-class
Twit of the Year I have ever
seen.
Wait! Nigel's clubbed himself
into fourth place.
And so the final result,
Upper-class Twit of the Year:
Gervaise Brook-Hampster
of Kensington and Weybridge.
Runner up: Vivian Smith-
Smythe-Smith of Kensington.
And third: Nigel
Incubator-Jones of Henley.
Well, there will certainly be
some car-door slamming
in the streets
of Kensington tonight.
WOMAN:
Dear sir,
how splendid it is to see
the flower of British manhood
wiping itself out with
such pluck and tenacity.
Britain need have no fear
with leaders of this caliber.
If only a few of the so-called
working classes
would destroy themselves
so sportingly.
Yours et cetera,
Brigadier Mainwaring
Smith Smith Smith, et cetera.
Deceased, et cetera.
P.S., et cetera, come on
other ranks. Show your stuff.
Yes, sir.
I'll do me best, sir.
[CLEARS THROAT]
MAN:
No, not good enough.
[COUGHS]
MAN:
No, still not good enough.
[HACKS]
MAN:
Yeah, that's better.
CHOIR:
♪ Hallelujah
Hallelujah ♪
Eww! Ugh! Oh!
Okay, all clear.
[♪]
Now, I understand that you
want to marry my daughter.
That's right. Yeah, yeah.
Yes. You realize,
of course,
that Rosamund is still
rather young?
Daddy, you make me
feel like a child.
Oh, yeah, you know.
Get 'em when
they're young, eh? Eh?
Know what I mean?
Well, I'm-- I'm sure you know
what I mean, Mr...?
-Mr...?
-Uh, Shabby. Ken Shabby.
Mr. Shabby, I just want
to make sure
that you'll be able
to look after my daughter.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I'll be able to look after her
all right, sport, eh?
Know what I mean, eh?
[LAUGHS, COUGHS]
And, uh, what job do you do?
Oh, I clean out
public lavatories.
Is there a promotion involved?
Oh, yeah, yeah!
[COUGHING AND HACKING]
After five years,
they give me a brush.
-Yes.
-[COUGHS]
Oh, I'm sorry, squire.
I've gobbed on your carpet.
And, uh, where--where
are you going to live?
Well, 'round at my gran's.
She trains polecats,
uh--
[COUGHS]
But most of them
have suffocated
so there should be a bit
of spare room in the attic,
eh?
-Know what I mean?
-Yes, I see. I see.
And when do you expect
to get married?
Oh, right away, sport.
Right away, you know.
I haven't had it for weeks.
[HACKING]
Yes.
Well, look, I'll--
I'll phone the bishop
and see
if we can get the abbey.
Oh, diarrhea. Oh.
[COUGHING]
NARRATOR:
The story so far:
Rosamund's father
has become ensnared
by Mr. Shabby's extraordinary
personal magnetism.
Bob and Janet have eaten
Mr. Farquar's goldfish
during an Oxfam lunch.
And Mrs. Elsmore's marriage
is threatened
by Doug's insistence
that he is on a different
level of consciousness.
Louise's hernia
has been confirmed,
and Jim, Bob's brother, has run
over the editor of the Lancet
on his way to see Jenny,
a freelance pagoda designer.
On the other side
of the continent,
Napoleon still broods
over the smoldering remains
of a city he had crossed
half the Earth to conquer.
Whilst Mary,
Roger's half-sister,
settles down
to watch television.
ANNOUNCER:
There now follows
a party political broadcast
on behalf of the Wood Party.
Good evening.
We in the Wood Party
feel very strongly
that the present weak drafting
of the local government bill
leaves a lot to be desired.
And we intend to fight.
[SCREAMING]
Hello?
Hello.
Uh, I-- I'm afraid
the minister's fallen
through the Earth's crust.
Uh, excuse me a moment.
Hello?
WARBECK:
Hello.
Are you all right,
minister?
WARBECK:
I appear to have landed
on this kind of ledge thing.
Shall we lower down
one of the BBC ropes?
If you would be so kind.
What length of BBC rope
will we be likely to need?
I should use the longest
BBC rope.
That would be a good idea,
I would imagine.
Okey-doke, chief.
Uh, Tex, get the longest
BBC rope
and bring it here,
pronto.
In the meantime,
since I am on all channels,
perhaps I'd better carry on
with this broadcast
by shouting about
our housing plans
from down here, as best I can.
Could someone
throw me down a script?
The script would appear to
have landed on a different
ledge
somewhat out of my grasp,
don't you know.
Well, perhaps when the rope
reaches you, minister,
you could kind of swing
over to the ledge and grab it.
Good idea.
Well, I'm going to carry on
if I can read the script.
Good evening.
We in the Wood Party...
feel very strongly about...
the present weak drafting
of the local government bill,
and-- No. No, it's no good.
It's not working.
I think I'll have to try
and make a grab for it.
I think it's in back--
Ah, there we are.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Good evening.
We in the Wood Party
feel very strongly
about the present--
Aah! Aah!
Oh, dear.
-Hello.
-STAGEHAND: Hello.
Look, look, I-- I must look
a bit of a chump,
hanging upside down like this.
STAGEHAND:
Uh, don't worry, minister.
I think, um, if we turn
the picture upside down
we should help the minister,
Hen.
Oh, good. Look, uh,
I'm sorry about this.
Uh, there seem to be a few
gremlins about.
Um, I think I'd better start
from the beginning. Um...
Good evening.
We-- We in the Wood Party
feel very strongly about--
Oh, bloody heck. Oh!
Um, oh, dear.
[CHUCKLES]
Uh, terribly sorry about this.
Um, about saying bloody heck
on all channels, but, um--
STAGEHAND:
There's another script
on the way down, minister.
Oh. Oh, good. Good.
Well, uh...
[CHUCKLES]
...um, good evening.
Um, well, um...
How are you? Uh...
Oh, look, I don't want you
to think of the Wood Party
as a load of old men that like
hanging around on ropes,
only, uh... Oh. Oh.
Uh, thank you.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Good evening.
We in the Wood Party
feel very strongly about
the present weak drafting--
[SCREAMS]
Look, I think we'd better
call it a day.
Now, is this the furthest
distance that a minister
has fallen, Robert?
Uh, surprisingly not.
The Canadian minister
for External Affairs
fell nearly seven miles
during a Liberal conference
in Ottawa about six years ago.
And then, quite recently,
the Kenyan minister
for Agric and Fish
fell nearly 12 miles
during a Nairobi debate
in Parliament,
although this hasn't
been ratified yet.
How far did the Filipino
cabinet fall last March?
Uh, well, they fell
nearly 39 miles,
but it's not nearly
so remarkable,
as that was due to their
combined weight, of course,
Robert.
Yes. Well, thank you, Robert.
Well, now, what are your
reactions to all this, Robert?
Well, Robert, the main thing
is that it's terribly
exciting.
You see, the minister is quite
clearly lodged between rocks
that we know terribly
little of.
The main thing is
we're getting color pictures
of extraordinarily high
quality. Extraordinarily
high quality.
But-- But the important
thing-- The really exciting
thing is
he'll get samples
of the Earth's core,
which will give us a
tremendous, really
tremendous clue
as to the origins of the Earth
and what God himself is
made of.
[GRUNTING]
Oh. Oh.
Oh, I needed that.
Oh, thank you, Robert.
That seems to be about all
we have time for tonight.
Unless anyone
has anything else to say.
Has anyone
anything else to say?
-No.
-Nope. Nope.
No.
♪ No ♪
-No.
-No!
Bloody fairy.
-No.
-No!
Uh...
-No.
-Nein-- No.
No.
No, no, no...
What do we mean by no?
What do we mean by yes?
What do we mean by, "No, no"?
Tonight, Spectrum
looks at what is no.
What is not--
[PINBALL MACHINE
CLATTERING AND RINGING]
[♪]