[♪]
It's...
ANNOUNCER:
There will now be
a short intermission.
[♪]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
There will now be
a medium-sized intermission.
[QUACKING]
[BELCHES]
Not bad for a starter,
but now perhaps something
a little more savory.
Ooh, I don't like this.
Ooh, I don't like that.
I don't think much to all
this. Fancy using that
wallpaper.
Fancy using mustard.
Ooh, is that a proper one?
It's not real.
It's not a restaurant unless
they have finger bowls.
I don't like him. I'm going
to have a baby in a few years.
Uh, please excuse my wife.
She may appear
to be rather nasty,
but underneath she has
a heart of Formica.
Sorry about that.
That's all right. We get
all sorts of lines in here.
The headwaiter will be along
to abuse you in a few moments.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I have to go and commit
suicide.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Oh, it's all right.
It's not because
of anything serious, heh-heh.
[BANGING, SCREAMING]
Quite frankly, I'm against
people who commit suicide.
I don't like that sort at all.
I'm plain people,
and I'm proud of it.
Mom's the salt of the earth,
and I don't take the pill
'cause it's nasty.
Please excuse my wife.
She may not be very beautiful,
and she may have no money,
and she may be a little
talentless, boring and dull,
but on the other hand...
Sorry, I can't
think of anything.
Fine. I'm the headwaiter.
This is a vegetarian
restaurant only.
We serve no animal flesh
of any kind.
We're not only proud of that,
we're smug about it.
So if you were to come in here
asking me to rip open a
chicken,
so you could chew its skin
and eat its intestines,
-then I'm afraid I would
have to ask you to leave.
-No, no. No.
Likewise, if you were to ask
me to slice the sides of a cow,
and serve it with
a small piece of its liver...
or indeed drain the life's blood
from a pig before cutting off
one of its legs,
or carve the living
giblets from a sheep
and serve them
with the fresh brains,
bowels, guts and spleen
of a small rabbit,
we wouldn't do it!
Not for food anyway.
Quite frankly I'm against
people who give vent to their
loquacity
by extraneous bombastic
circumlocution.
Ooh, I don't
like that.
Sometimes, Shirley,
I think you're almost human.
Do you know I still wet
my bed?
Once I married someone
who was beautiful and young,
and gay and free.
Whatever happened
to her?
You divorced her
and married me.
[CANNED APPLAUSE]
I met my second wife at a
second-wife-swapping party.
Trust me to arrive late.
Always were late,
weren't you, Thompson?
Hello, headmaster.
What are you doing here?
Fine, fine, thank you.
Fine, thank you.
Uh, no more sherry
for me, don't you know.
Warner House
beat Badger House
for the Second Cuppa.
Remarkable. Hm.
We had to put most of the second
form to sleep. No padre.
They were beginning
to play with themselves.
Still, you haven't seen
my wife anywhere, have you?
-No.
-Oh, thank God for that.
SHIRLEY:
Ooh, I don't like him.
Do you know what I mean?
Do you know?
I mean, do you know what I
mean? Do you know what I mean?
All men are
the same.
Imagine not
that these four walls
contain the Mighty Owl
of Thebes.
For, gentles all,
beauty sits most closely
to them it can construe.
No, it doesn't.
Sorry.
Fine. Would you care
for a glass of blood?
Oh, what a giveaway.
Uh, we'd like to see
the menu, please.
It's not a restaurant
unless you have a menu.
And anyway I might
be pregnant.
Perhaps you would, uh,
care for a drink?
Ever since you've
married me, Douglas,
you've treated me
like an albatross.
-Evening.
-Good evening.
I hope you're going to enjoy me
this evening. I'm the special.
-Try me with some rice.
-I beg your pardon?
Uh, Hopkins au gratin
à la chef.
-Oh. How do you do?
-Don't play with your food.
[LAUGHS]
I don't like that.
Ooh, there's dust on here.
It's not a proper meal
without pudding.
My husband's an architect.
Oh, uh, one word of warning,
sir. A little tip.
Uh, don't have any
of the vicar over there.
He's been here two weeks
and nobody's touched him.
Enough said?
DOUGLAS:
Yes, thank you.
Well, I must get along,
or I'll spoil.
Janet! To the kitchen.
[♪]
[CLEARS THROAT]
There's a dead bishop
in the lobby, sir.
I don't know who keeps
bringing them in.
Oh, I don't like that.
I think it's silly.
It's not a sketch
without a punchline.
I don't know much
about anything,
I'm stupid. I'm muggins.
Nobody cares what I think.
Always have to do everything.
Nobody cares about me.
I'm going to have bloody babies,
they can care about me.
Makes you sick, television.
They never stop talking.
He'll be
the ruination--
Rhythm method.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
There will now be
a whopping great intermission,
during which small ice creams
in very large boxes
will be sold.
Another way we can drive
people away from the cinema
is by showing you
advertisements.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Do you like this?
Or how about this?
Or perhaps you prefer
this latest model.
Then why not come to us?
We supply only
the very best models.
After the show, why not visit
the La Gondola Restaurant?
Just two minutes
from this performance.
The manager,
Mr. Luigi Vercotti,
will be pleased to welcome
you,
and introduce you
to a wide variety
of famous Sicilian delicacies.
Here, you can relax in comfort
in friendly surroundings.
Or if you wish, you may drink
and dance till midnight.
At the La Gondola Restaurant
you can sample
all the spicy pleasures
of the Mediterranean.
The headwaiter will be pleased
to show you his specialties.
Or why not ask the cook
for something really hot?
Yes, for an evening
you'll never forget,
it's the La Gondola
Restaurant, Chelsea...
Parkhurst, Dartmoor
and the Scrubs.
[♪]
[SHOUTING]
Albatross!
-Albatross?
-Two choc-ices, please.
I haven't got choc-ices!
I only got the albatross!
Albatross!
What--?
What flavor is it?
It's a bird, isn't it?
It's a bloody seabird.
It's not any bloody flavor.
Albatross!
Do you get wafers
with it?
'Course you don't get
bloody wafers with it!
Albatross.
-How much is it?
-Nine pence.
I'll have two, please.
Gannet on a stick.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
There will now be
a very short--
[EXPLOSION]
[♪]
ANNOUNCER [SPEAKS]:
Well, that's quite
enough of that.
And now a policeman
near Rottingdeans.
Albatross!
-Inspector. Inspector.
-Mm-hmm?
I'm terribly sorry, but I was
sitting on a bench over there,
took my coat off
for a minute,
and then I found my wallet
had been stolen,
and 15 pounds taken
from it.
Well, did you, uh--
Did you, uh, see anyone
take it?
Anyone hanging
around or...?
No, no. There was no
one there at all.
That's the trouble.
Well, there's not very much
we can do about that, sir.
Oh.
Do you want to
come back to my place?
Yeah, all right.
Albatross.
-Mr. Burtenshaw?
-Me, doctor?
No, me doctor,
you Mr. Burtenshaw.
My wife, doctor?
No, your wife patient,
me doctor.
-Come this way, please.
-Uh, me, Sister?
No. She Sister. Me doctor.
You Mr. Burtenshaw.
Dr. Walters?
Me nurse. You Mr. Burtenshaw.
She Sister.
-You, doctor.
-No, doctor.
No doctor. Call ambulance.
Keep warm.
-Drink, doctor?
-Drink doctor. Eat Sister.
Cook Mr. Burtenshaw.
Nurse me.
You, doctor?
Me doctor. You Mr. Burtenshaw.
She nurse.
-But my wife, nurse.
-Your wife not nurse.
She nurse. Your wife patient.
Be patient.
She nurse, your wife.
Me doctor.
Yew tree, Utrecht,
Utrillo, U Thant, euphemism.
Me doctor.
Albatross!
I would like to meet...
someone...
of superior intelligence.
I'd like to hear the sound...
of two bricks
being bashed together.
I would like to see
John the Baptist's
impersonation
of Graham Hill.
ANNOUNCER:
Yes, it's
Historical Impersonations.
When you in the present
can make those in the past
stars of the future.
And here is your host
for tonight,
Wally Wiggin.
Hello, good evening and
welcome to Historical
Impersonations.
And we kick off tonight
with Cardinal Richelieu
and his impersonation
of Petula Clark.
♪ Oh, don't sleep
In the subway darlin' ♪
♪ Don't stand
In the pouring rain ♪
Cardinal Richelieu,
16 stone of pure man.
And now, your favorite
Roman Emperor, Julius Caesar,
as Eddie Waring.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN DIALECT]
Wigan, Hunslett,
and Hull Kingston Rovers.
Well done indeed,
Julius Caesar.
A smile, a conquest
and a dagger up your strap.
Our next challenger comes
all the way from the Crimea.
It's the very lovely
Florence Nightingale
as Brian London.
-[BELL DINGS]
-[GRUNTS]
And now for our most
ambitious attempt tonight.
All the way from Moscow,
in the USS of R,
Ivan the Terrible
as a sales assistant
in Freeman, Hardy and Willis.
[YELLS]
And now W.G. Grace
as a music box.
[♪]
And now it's France's turn.
One of their top statesmen,
Napoleon, as the R-101
disaster.
[♪]
[CRASHING]
And now it's request time.
I would like to see
John the Baptist's
impersonation of Graham Hill.
[ENGINE REVS]
And now a short intermission,
during which Marcel Marceau
will impersonate a man
walking against the wind.
WALLY WIGGIN:
And now Marcel will mime
a man being struck
about the head
by a 16-ton weight.
[CROWD CHEERING]
What's your name?
Eric.
Would you like to have
a 16-ton weight
dropped on top
of you, Eric?
Don't know.
How about you?
I want to
have...
What do you
want to have?
I want to have...
What?
I want to have
Raquel Welch...
dropped on top
of me.
Yes. Dropped
on top of you?
Oh, yes,
not climbing.
She's got a big
bottom.
-And what's your name?
-Trevor Atkinson.
And how old are you,
Trevor?
I'm 42.
Are you a friend
of Trevor's?
Yes. We're all
colleagues from
the Empire and General
Insurance Company.
And what do you do?
Well, I deal mainly with
mortgage protection policies,
but I also do certain types
of life assurance.
Now if you and your pal
had one big wish, Trevor,
what would you like
to see on television?
I'd like to see more fairy
stories about the police.
-[TINKLING MUSIC]
-And so you shall.
[WHISTLING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[HUMMING]
[CONTINUES HUMMING]
[WHISTLING]
[AIR BLOWING]
Mm-hm. Hm.
[HUMS]
[CHUCKLES]
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[TINKLING MUSIC]
Yes, we in the Special Crime
Squad have been using wands
for almost a year now.
I find it's easy
to make yourself invisible,
you can defy time and space,
and you can turn violent
criminals into frogs.
Something you could never do
with the old truncheons.
[♪]
Yes, tonight ProbeAround
takes a look at crime.
[GUNSHOT]
I'm sorry
about that,
but I always introduce
this program, not him.
[CRASHING]
Yes, tonight ProbeAround
takes a look at crime.
Is it true that the police
are using dachshunds
to combat the crime wave?
Uh, can the head of
the Vice Squad
turn himself into an albatross
whenever he wants to?
Just what are the police
up to?
Oh, I'm up to page 39,
where Peter Pan
first manifests himself.
With me now is Inspector
Harry H. "Snapper" Organs
of H Division.
Good evening.
Uh, Inspector, I believe
you are encouraging magic
in the police force.
That is correct.
The criminal mind is
a strange, contorted one.
Good evening.
The mind is subject to severe
mental stresses. Good evening.
Guilt fears abound--
Good evening.
--in the subconscious.
In this state, one of
our lads,
with a fair training
in the black arts,
can scare the fertilizer
out of them.
Just how are the police
combating
the increase with the use
of the occult?
-Ex-King Zog of Albania reports.
-[PHONE RINGS]
We seem to have lost ex-King
Zog there, but who cares?
Just what kinds of magic
are the police introducing
into their crime-prevention
techniques?
[OWL SCREECHING]
ALL:
"U."
"P."
"Y."
"O."
"U."
"R."
"S."
"Up yours"?
What a rude Ouija board.
[DINGS]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[CHANTING]
Now this is the kind of thing
that gives the police
a bad name, sergeant.
I know, sir.
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
Yes, Beryl?
Attila the Hun to see you, sir.
-Who?
-Attila the Hun, sir.
Oh, botherkins.
Uh, constable,
go and see to him, will you?
What?
In this dress?
Oh, all right, I'll go.
Oh, I have got a little
green pinny I could wear.
No, no, no, I'll go.
You stay here.
Oh, goody.
I can get on with the ironing.
Right, where is he?
BERYL:
Over there, sir.
Right, uh-- All right,
sergeant, leave this to me.
Uh, now then, sir,
you are Attila the Hun.
That's right, yes. A.T. Hun.
My parents were
Mr. and Mrs. Norman Hun,
but they had a little joke
when I was born.
-[LAUGHS]
-Yes. Uh, well, Mr. Hun, uh...
Oh, call me "The,"
for heaven's sake.
-Oh. Well, The...
-Yes?
Uh, what do you want
to see us about?
I've come to give
myself up.
What for?
Looting, pillaging
and sacking a major city.
I beg your pardon?
Looting, pillaging,
sacking a major city,
and I'd like 9000 other
charges to be taken
into consideration, please.
I say, excuse me,
Mr. Hun.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Have you any objection
to taking a breath test?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Right. Uh, sergeant, will you
bring the "Hunalyzer," please?
-Here we are, sir.
-Uh, how does it work?
Well, if he breathes
into it, sir,
and the white crystals
turn lime green,
-then he is Attila the Hun, sir.
-I see.
-Would you mind breathing
into this, Mr. Hun?
-Right.
[BLOWING RASPBERRY]
Oh.
What if nothing happens,
sergeant?
He's Alexander
the Great.
A-ha! Caught you,
Mr. A.T. Great.
Oh, curses, curses.
I thought I was safe
disguised as Attila the Hun.
Oh, perhaps so. But you
made one fatal mistake.
You see,
this wasn't a "Hunalyzer,"
it was an
"Alexander the Greatalyzer."
Take him away, Beryl.
MAN 1:
Dear Sir, I object very
strongly to that last scene,
and to the next letter.
MAN 2:
Dear Sir, I object to being
objected to by the last letter
before my drift
has become apparent.
I spent many years in India
during the last war,
and am now a part-time
notice board
in a prominent public school.
Yours etc., Brigadier
Zoe La Rue, deceased.
P.S. Aghhh!
MAN 3:
Dear Sir,
when I was at school,
I was beaten regularly
every 30 minutes,
and it never did me any harm,
except for psychological
maladjustment
and blurred vision.
Yours truly, Flight Lieutenant
Ken Frankenstein, Mrs.
[SIREN WAILING]
[SCREAMS]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[METAL CLANGING]
Huh?
-[SIREN WAILING]
-Mmm.
[CAR ENGINE STOPS]
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE]
[PANTING]
MAN:
I want to see the doctor.
Dr. Larch. There's
a Mr. Phelps to see you.
-Uh-- Uh, nurse.
-Yes?
[QUIETLY]
Uh, you don't think you should
make it clear
that I'm a psychiatrist?
What?
Well, I could be
any type of doctor.
[SCOFFS]
-Well, I can't come in and say,
"Psychiatrist Larch..."
-Shh.
...or "Dr. Larch
who is a psychiatrist."
Uh. Anyway, look,
it's written on the door.
[WHISPERS]
That's outside.
Well, I don't care.
You'll just have to
do it yourself.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[IMITATES PHONE RINGING]
Hello. Uh, no, wrong number,
I'm afraid.
This is a psychiatrist
speaking.
-Next, please.
-[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Uh, come in.
Bo-whoa-whoa.
Ah, Mr. Phelps, come on in.
Take a seat.
What seems to be
the matter?
No, no, no, no, no.
-I'm sorry?
-Oh, can't you do
better than that?
It's so predictable.
I've seen it a million times.
Knock, knock, knock.
"Come in. Ah, Mr. Phelps,
take a seat."
I've seen it and seen it.
Well, look, will you
please sit down
and do your first line?
No, no. I've had enough.
I've had enough.
-[DOOR CLOSES]
-Mmm.
I can't even get it started.
-MAN [IN THE DISTANCE]:
Albatross.
-Shut up!
Oh, it drives me mad.
A mad psychiatrist,
that would be new. Hmm.
Next, please.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Uh-- Oh.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Cross the threshold,
arrive, ingress,
gain admittance, infiltrate.
Ah, Mr. Notlob.
Uh...
park your hips
on the sitting device.
-It is a mad psychiatrist.
-I'm not. I'm not.
Come on in. Take a seat.
What's the matter?
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
Now, what's the matter?
I keep hearing guitars playing
and people singing
when there's no one around.
Yes, well this is
not at all uncommon.
In certain mental
states we find
that auditory hallucinations
occur which are of a most-- Uh--
♪ Zoo tomorrow,
We can stay all day ♪
♪ Goin' to the zoo, zoo, zoo ♪
♪ How about you, you, you ♪
Is that "We're All
Going to the Zoo Tomorrow"?
Yes. Yes.
-Is it always that?
-No.
Well, that's something.
-But it's mainly folk songs.
-Oh, my God.
Last night was
"We'll Never Fall in Love Again"
for six hours.
Well, look, I think I'd better
have a second opinion on this.
I want you to see a colleague
of mine, a specialist in these
sort of things,
who has an office very much like
this one, as a matter of fact.
Oh. [CLEARS THROAT]
[IMITATES PHONE RINGING]
Um. No, no, wrong number.
I'm a colleague of his,
a surgeon,
who specializes
in these kind of things.
Yes. Thank you very much.
-Next, please.
-[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Come in.
Ah, come in.
Please take a seat.
My colleague,
who has a similar office,
has explained
your case to me.
♪ We can stay all day ♪
Mr. Notlob, as you know,
I am a leading
Harley Street surgeon...
as seen on television.
[♪]
I'm afraid I'm going
to have to operate.
It's nothing
to worry about,
although it is
extremely dangerous.
I shall be juggling
with your life.
I shall be playing
ducks and drakes
with your very existence.
I shall be running me mitts
over the pith of your marrow.
Yes. These hands...
these fingers...
these sophisticated
organs of touch,
these bunches of five,
these maulers,
these German bands
that have pulled many
a moribund unfortunate back
from the very brink
of Lazarus's box.
No, it was Pandora's box
wasn't it?
Anyway, these mitts have earned
yours truly a lot of bread.
So if you'll just step through
here, I'll slit you up a treat.
What?
Mr. Notlob, there's
nothing wrong with you
that an expensive operation
can't prolong.
[SONG CONTINUES FAINTLY]
Right. I'm ready
to make the incision.
Knife please,
Sister.
What's that supposed to be?
Give me a big one.
Thank you very much.
Oh, I do enjoy this.
Right.
Oh, what a great slit.
Now, gentlemen,
I am going to open the slit.
♪ All day
We been to the zoo ♪
Too much, man.
Groovy, great scene.
Great light show,
baby.
What are you
doing in there?
We're doing
our own thing, man.
Have you got Mr. Notlob's
permission to be in there?
-We're squatters, baby.
-What?
Nurse,
wake him up.
Don't get
uptight, man.
Join the scene,
and other phrases.
Money isn't real.
It is where I'm standing,
and it blows my mind,
young lad.
Good Lord,
is that a nude woman?
She's doing an article
on us for Nova, man.
-Hi, everyone.
-[SNAPS]
Are you part of the scene?
Are you rolling your own
jelly babies in there?
What's going on? Who are they?
-We're trying to find out.
-Why are they in my stomach?!
We don't know.
Are they paying you any rent?
'Course they're not paying
rent.
You're not furnished,
you fascist.
Get them out!
-I can't.
-Get them out!
No, I can't. Not--
Not without a court order.
Shut up. You're
keeping us awake.
You are hereby
ordered to vacate
Mr. Notlob
forthwith and/or.
Push off, fuzz.
Right. That's it.
We're going in.
Release
the vicious dogs.
[DOGS BARKING]
What a terrible way
to end a series.
Why couldn't it end
with something like this?
Smile.
-[GRUNTING]
-Smile.
Smile.
Now there's an ending for you.
Romance. Laughter--
[GROANING]
[♪]
[GUNSHOTS]
ANNOUNCER:
When this series returns,
it will be put out on Monday
morning as a test card,
and will be described
by the Radio Times
as a history
of Irish agriculture.