[RHYTHMIC WHIRRING]
[HUMMING]
[HUMMING INCREASES]
[HUMMING STOPS]
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
And now for something
completely different.
It's...
[JOHN PHILIP SOUSA'S
"LIBERTY BELL" PLAYING]
NARRATOR:
Monty Python's
Flying Circus-sss.
[FART]
[♪♪]
-[KNOCK AT DOOR]
-Come in.
Trouble at mill.
Oh, no.
What sort of trouble?
One of crossbeams
gone out askew on treadle.
Pardon?
One of crossbeams
gone out askew on treadle.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
One of the crossbeams has gone
out askew on the treadle.
Well, what on earth
does that mean?
I don't know. Mr. Wentworth
told me to come in here
and say that there was
trouble at the mill,
that's all.
I didn't expect a kind
of Spanish Inquisition.
[♪♪]
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
Our chief weapon is surprise.
Surprise and fear.
Fear and surprise.
Our two weapons
are fear and surprise.
And ruthless efficiency.
Our three weapons
are fear and surprise
and ruthless efficiency.
And an almost fanatical
devotion to the pope.
Uh! Four. No.
Amongst our weapons...
Amongst our weaponry are
such elements as fear, su--
I'll come in again.
I didn't expect
a kind of Spanish Inquisition.
[♪♪]
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
Amongst our weaponry
are such diverse elements
as fear, surprise,
ruthless efficiency,
and almost fanatical devotion
to the pope.
And nice red uniforms.
Oh, damn!
I-I can't say it,
you'll have to say it.
What?
You'll have to say the bit,
"Our chief weapons are:"
Why, I couldn't do that.
I didn't expect
a kind of Spanish Inquisition.
[♪♪]
Uh-uh, nobody, um...
-Expects.
-Um, expects.
Nobody expects
the, um, Spanish, um...
-Inquisition.
-I know, I know.
Nobody expects
the Spanish inquisition.
-In fact, those who do--
-Our chief weapons are...
Our chief weapons are, um...
Uh... Su--
-Surprise.
That's it. Stop, stop.
Stop there. Stop there. Stop.
Our chief weapon
is surprise...
Blah-blah-blah-blah-blah.
Cardinal, read the charges.
"You are hereby charged
that you did,
"on diverse dates,
commit heresy
against the Holy Church."
-♪ My old man-- ♪
-That's enough.
Now...
how do you plead?
We're innocent.
[DIABOLICAL LAUGHTER]
We'll soon change your mind
about that!
Fear, surprise,
and a most ruthless... Ooh!
Now.
Cardinal, the rack.
[GRUNTING]
You...
Right.
Tie her down.
[MEN LAUGHING
AND GRUNTING]
Right.
How do you plead?
Innocent.
Ha! Right!
Cardinal, give the rack--
Oh, dear.
Give the rack...
-a turn.
-I-I--
I know. I know you can't.
I didn't want to say anything.
-I just wanted to try
and ignore your crass mistake.
-I-I--
It makes it all
seem so stupid.
Shall I, um--?
Oh, God, just pretend,
for God's sake.
[LAUGHING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Ah, hello. Uh, you don't
know me, but I'm from the BBC.
Um, we were wondering if
you'd come and answer the door
in a sketch over there
in that sort of direction?
You wouldn't have to
do anything, just open
the door and that's it.
-Oh, well, all right, yes.
-Jolly good, come this way.
Yes, uh, we're on film
at the moment, you see?
It's a link, is it?
Yes, that's right,
that sort of thing. Yes,
a link.
Uh, it's all a bit zany,
you know, a bit madcap
funster.
I don't fully
understand it myself.
The kids seem to like it.
I much prefer, uh,
Des O'Connor,
Rolf Harris, Tom Jones,
you know...
[CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY]
[ENGINE STARTS]
You do a lot of this
sort of thing, do you?
Quite a lot, yes, quite a lot.
I'm mainly in comedy.
Uh, I'd like to be in
program planning, actually,
but, uh, unfortunately,
I've got a degree.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Joke, sir?
Guaranteed amusing.
As used by the crowned heads
of Europe.
Has brought tears
to the eyes of royalty.
"Denmark has never
laughed so much."
The Stage.
Nice little novelty number,
a "naughty Humphrey."
Breaks the ice at parties.
Put it on the table,
press the button, it vomits.
Absolutely guaranteed.
With refills.
Black soap,
leave it in the bathroom,
they wash their hands,
real fungus grows
on the fingers.
Can't get it off for hours.
Guaranteed to
break the ice at parties.
Frighten the elderly.
Real snakes.
Comedy-hernia kit.
Plastic flesh wounds, just
keep your friends in stitches.
Guaranteed to
break the ice at parties.
Hours of fun with
"Honeymoon Delight."
Empty into their beds,
real skunk juice.
They won't forget
their wedding night.
Sticks to the skin,
absolutely waterproof,
guaranteed to
break the ice at parties.
Amuse your friends.
CS gas canisters.
Smells, tastes and acts
just like the real thing.
Can blind, maim or kill.
Or for drinks, why not buy
a Wicked Willy,
with a life-size winkle?
Serves warm beer.
Makes real cocktails.
Hours of amusement.
Or get the new
Pooh-Pooh Machine.
Embarrass your guests,
completely authentic sound.
Or why not try
a new Naughty Nightie.
Put it on and it melts.
Just watch their faces.
Guaranteed to break the ice
at naughty parties.
-Go on, go on.
-What?
Do the punch line.
What punch line?
The punch line for this bit.
I don't know it.
They didn't say anything
about a punch line.
Oh!
Uh, well, in that case,
I'll be saying, uh,
goodbye then, sir.
Goodbye, then, sir.
It's funny they didn't say...
-What's the punch line?
-Punch line?
I don't think there's a punch
line scheduled, is there?
Where are we?
Week 39.4, no.
It's Friday,
isn't it? 39.7.
Uh... Here we are.
Oh.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, very good.
What a good punch line. Ah.
Pity we missed that.
Still, uh, never mind,
we can always do it again.
Make a series out of it.
Now, if you'll just sign there,
I'll put this through
to our contracts department,
and, uh, you should be hearing
from them in a year or two.
Can you give me
a lift back?
Ah, can do. But won't.
Uh, we were wondering
if we could possibly
borrow your head
for a piece of animation.
-What?
-Oh, jolly good.
Thanks very, very, very much.
-Ah!
-You will get expenses.
Ah! Ah! Ah!
[GROANING]
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
MAN 1:
Sergeant, somehow we've got to
get in there and get it.
MAN 2:
I know, but it's
going to be difficult.
-MAN 1:
You'll need some diversion.
-MAN 2: Yes, sir. But what?
MAN 1:
Well, we could, uh--
No, no, no, it's got to be--
No, not right.
Wait, I've got it.
[♪♪]
Well done, soldier.
Load and fire.
Yes, sir.
Fire.
MAN:
Ah! Ready, aim, fire!
We are not amused.
[MAN HUMMING]
[MAN CLEARS THROAT]
Gentlemen, our MP
saw the PM this a.m.,
and the PM wants more
LSD from the PIB
by tomorrow a.m.
or p.m. at the latest.
I, uh, told the PM's PPS
that a.m. was NBG
so tomorrow p.m. it is
for the PM nem. con.
Give us a fag
or I'll go spare.
Now, the fiscal deficit,
uh, with regard
to the monetary balance
the current financial year,
excluding invisible exports,
adjusted, of course,
for seasonal variations
and the incremental
statistics
of the fiscal
and revenue arrangements
for the forthcoming
annual budgetary period
terminating in April.
I-I think he's talking
about taxation.
Bravo, Madge. Well done.
Taxation is indeed
the very nub of my gist.
Gentlemen, we have to
find something new to tax.
I understood that.
Uh, if I might put my head
on the chopping block
-so you can kick it around
a bit, sir.
-Mm-hm.
Um, well, most things
we do for pleasure
nowadays are taxed.
Except one.
What do you mean?
Well, uh,
smoking's been taxed.
Drinking's been taxed.
But, uh, not, uh...
thingy.
You're not suggesting
we should tax...
thingy?
Pooh-poohs?
No!
Thank God for that.
Excuse me for a moment.
No, no, no. Thingy.
Number ones?
No. Thingy.
Thingy.
Oh!
Well, it'll certainly
make chartered accountancy
a more interesting job.
[GRUNTING]
I would put a tax...
on all people...
who stand in water.
Ooh!
To boost the British economy,
I'd tax all foreigners
living abroad.
I would tax the nude
in my bed.
No, not tax.
What is the word? Um...
Welcome.
I would tax Raquel Welch.
And I've a feeling
she'd tax me.
I would bring back hanging
and go into rope.
I would cut off the more
disreputable parts of the body
and use the space
for playing fields.
I would tax holiday snaps.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
This is Uncle Ted
in front of the house.
at the back of the house.
And this is Uncle Ted
at the side of the house.
This is Uncle Ted back again
at the front of the house,
but you can see
the side of the house.
And this is Uncle Ted even
nearer the side of the house,
but you can still
see the front.
This is the back
of the house,
with Uncle Ted
coming round the side
to the front.
And this is
the Spanish Inquisition
hiding behind
the coal shed.
Oh, I didn't expect
the Spanish Inquisition.
[♪♪]
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
[NARRATOR RECITING]
[MAN LAUGHING]
Ha!
Now, old woman,
you are accused of heresy
on three counts.
Heresy by thought,
heresy by word,
heresy by deed
and heresy by action.
Four counts.
Do you confess?
I don't understand
what I'm accused of.
[LAUGHING]
Ha!
Then we shall
make you understand.
Biggles...
Fetch... the cushions.
[♪♪]
Here they are, lord.
Now, old lady,
you have one last chance.
Confess the heinous sin
of heresy,
reject the works
of the ungodly--
Two last chances.
And you shall be free.
Three last chances.
You have three last chances
the nature of which
I have divulged
in my previous utterance.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Right!
If that's the way
you want it. Cardinal...
poke her
with the soft cushions!
[LAUGHING]
Confess!
It isn't hurting her,
lord.
Have you got all the stuffing
up one end?
Yes, lord.
Hm. She's made
of harder stuff.
Cardinal Fang,
fetch the comfy chair.
The comfy chair?
Yes.
-Ha-ha!
So, you think
you are strong
because you can survive
the soft cushions.
Well, we shall see.
Biggles! Put her
in the comfy chair!
Now,
you will stay in the comfy
chair until lunchtime,
with only a cup of coffee
at 11:00--
-Is that really all it is?
-Oh, yes, lord.
I see.
I suppose we make it worse
by shouting a lot, do we?
Confess, woman.
Confess. Confess!
Confess! Confess!
Oh, I confess!
Not you!
I confess.
Who was that?
[BUZZER]
Ooo.
["GOD SAVE THE QUEEN" PLAYING]
I confess.
[BUZZER]
Ooo.
["GOD SAVE THE QUEEN" PLAYING]
I confess.
-[BUZZER]
-Ooo.
I confess.
Well, madame, I'm glad
you've come to see me.
As a doctor, I shall
be trying to help you
and do everything I can to
assist you in any way I can.
Of course,
in the medical profession--
Very high stakes--
Would you repeat that?
I'm a bit deaf.
Now, the BMA, the
British Medical Association--
Louder, please.
I still can't hear.
Now, I do make certain
charm...
-Speak up. I can't hear you.
I'm deaf, I say.
-I confess!
I can't hear a word
you're saying.
You have to speak louder. Oh!
MAN:
Now, for the very first time
on the silver screen,
comes the film
from two books that once
shocked a generation.
From Emily Bronte's
Wuthering Heights
and from the International
Guide to Semaphore Code,
Twentieth Century Vole
presents:
The Semaphore Version
of Wuthering Heights.
[♪♪]
From the pulsating pages
of history,
from the dark and furious
days of Imperial Rome,
we bring you a story
that shattered the world.
A tale so gripping that they
said it could not be filmed.
A unique event
in cinema history.
Julius Caesar
on an Aldis Lamp.
From the makers of
Gunfight at O.K. Coral
in Morse Code.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
We have, my lord.
And how do you find
the defendant?
Two words. First word.
Rope? String?
Point?
Belt?
Tie?
Cravat? Silk square?
Knot?
-[APPLAUSE]
-Knot. Knot.
Second word.
Two syllables.
First syllable.
Bird?
Swimmer?
Breaststroke.
Brian Phelps.
No, no, no,
he was a diver.
-Esther Williams, then.
-No, no, don't be silly.
How can you find someone
Not Esther Williams?
Fish.
Fish... wheeze.
-Fish wheeze?
-[ACTOR GASPING]
Fish breathe.
Fish breathe throat.
Fish breathe throat?
Gill!
-Gill!
-Gill.
Not gill.
Second syllable.
Drink.
Sip? Imbibe?
MAN 1:
Not gill...
Cup!
Not gill-cup!
You've been found
not gill-cup
of the charges
brought against you
and may leave
this court a free man.
Right. My turn.
Four words.
Uh, first word "shout"?
-Bellow?
-Call?
-Call!
-[APPLAUSE]
Second word is very small.
Um. A?
-An?
-Up?
The? The!
Call the.
Third word.
Gill?
Fish?
-Adam's apple.
-Neck.
Sounds like neck?
Next.
Call the next!
[APPLAUSE]
Fourth word, three syllables.
First syllable.
-Uh, ear?
-Hear. Can't hear.
Deaf?
-MAN 2: Deaf!
-[APPLAUSE]
Call the next deaf...
-Uh, bottom?
-Seat?
Trouser? Cheek?
End! Call the next def-end!
ALL:
Ant!
Very good.
Call the next defendant!
Call the next defendant.
The Honorable
Mr. Justice Kilbraken.
If I may charge you, my lord?
You are charged, my lord,
that on the fourteenth day
of June, 1970,
at the Central Criminal Court,
you did commit acts
likely to cause a breach
of the peace.
How plead you, my lord,
guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty. Case not proven.
Court adjourned.
JUDGE:
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
No-no. No.
No, you're in the dock,
my lord.
I'm a judge, my lord.
So am I, my lord. So watch it.
Ha! Call this a court?
MAN 1:
Call this a court.
ALL:
Shut up. Right.
Now, get on with the spiel.
My lord, and my other lord,
uh, the prosecution
will endeavor to show,
my lord,
that my lord--
Uh, not you, my lord.
That my lord, my lord.
While passing sentence
at the Central Criminal Court
blotted his copybook.
Call exhibit Q.
Q?
Sorry, did I say Q? I meant A.
Sorry, call exhibit A.
MAN 1:
Call exhibit A.
Exhibit A, my lord,
Miss Rita Thang.
An artist's model,
Swedish accordion teacher,
and cane-chair saleslady,
was found guilty
under the Rude Behavior Act
in the accused's court.
The accused, my lord,
sentenced her to be
taken from this place
and brought round
to his place.
-Objection, my lord.
-Objection sustained.
You shut up!
Objection overruled.
Now, the accused
then commented
on Miss Thang's
bodily structure,
made several not-at-all legal
remarks on the subject of fun,
and then placed his robes
over his head
and began to emit low moans.
Have you anything to say
in your defense?
I haven't had any for weeks.
Oh, no? What about
that little number you've got
tucked away in Belsize Park?
Oh, I never!
Oh, no. Ho-ho-ho-ho!
All right, then what about
8A Woodford Square?
You say anything about that
and I'll do you for treason.
Uh, my lord,
if we could continue.
He's got a Chinese
bit there.
No, that's contempt
of court.
-Oh, it's only a joke.
-Contempt of court.
However, I'm not
going to punish you
because we're so short
of judges at the moment.
What with all of them
emigrating to South Africa.
I'm going tomorrow,
I've got me ticket.
Get out there and get
some decent sentencing done.
Ooh! England makes you sick.
Best I can manage here
is life imprisonment.
Hardly worth coming in
in the morning.
Now, South Africa,
you've got your
cat-o'-nine-tails,
you've got
four death sentences a week.
You've got cheap drinks,
slave labor
and a booming stock market.
I'm off, I tell you.
Yes. I'm up to here
with probation
and bleeding
psychiatric reports.
That's it, I'm off. That's it.
Right. But I'm going to have
one final fling before
I leave.
So I sentence you
to be burnt at the stake.
Blimey. I didn't expect
the Spanish Inquisition.
[♪♪]
Two-- Three
for the Old Bailey, please.
-Look, they've
started the credits.
-Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Hurry, hurry!
There's the lighting credit.
Only five left.
Hell, it's the producer.
Quick!
Nobody expects the Span--
Oh, bugger.