[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER 1]
In the fifth century,
as the once-mighty
Roman Empire crumbled,
the soft underbelly
of Western Europe
lay invitingly exposed
to the barbarian hordes
to the east.
Alaric the Visigoth,
Gaiseric the Vandal,
and Theodoric the Ostrogoth
in turn swept westward
in a reign of terror.
But none surpassed
in power and cruelty
the mighty Attila the Hun.
[ANNOUNCER 2]
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's The Attila the Hun Show.
[TONY ROMEO'S
"JUST A LITTLE LOVE" PLAYING]
♪ With a little love
Just a little love ♪
♪ Open you heart ♪
♪ And see where it's needed ♪
♪ With a little love
Just a little love ♪
♪ Feel it in your heart
When you've succeeded ♪
♪ Making all the sounds
Of love ♪
♪ Getting some sun
And you're alive ♪
♪ Making all the clouds
Roll away ♪
♪ Letting some sun
In your life ♪
♪ And you can light ♪
♪ Light up
The gloomiest night ♪
♪ Color the gloomiest day ♪
♪ Chase all your cares away ♪
♪ With a little love
Just a little love ♪
♪ With a little love ♪
♪ Just a little love ♪
[ANNOUNCER 1]
In the second quarter
of the fifth century,
the Huns became a byword
for merciless savagery.
Their khan was
the mighty warrior Attila.
With his devastating armies,
he swept across
Central Europe.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Oh, darling,
I'm home.
Hello, darling. Have
a busy day at the office?
Not at all bad.
Another merciless sweep
across Central Europe.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Well...I won't say
I'm glad to see you,
but, boy,
am I glad to see you.
[CANNED APPLAUSE]
Hi, Daddy.
Hi, Jenny. Hi, Robby.
[CANNED APPLAUSE]
Hey, I've got a present
for you two kids
in that bag.
I want you kids
to get ahead.
[CANNED LAUGHTER, APPLAUSE]
[EXAGGERATED BLACK ACCENT]
Here you are, Mr. Hun!
Hi, Uncle Tom.
There's a whole
horde of them
marauding Visigoths
to see y'all.
[♪♪]
And now for something
completely different.
It's...
[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER]
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
[ANNOUNCER 1]
Yes, it's Attila the Nun.
[CRASH]
[ANNOUNCER 2]
A simple country girl
who took a vow
of eternal brutality.
[ALL GRUNTING]
Nurse.
Hello, Miss Norris.
How are you?
Not too bad,
thank you, doctor.
Yes, well, I think
I'd better examine you.
Um, what are they
doing here?
[DOCTOR]
Uh, i-it's all right,
they're students. Um...
Light, please,
nurse.
Oh, and, uh, music too.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKER]
Breathe in...
out.
In...
[APPLAUSE]
out.
Thank you, thank you.
Charles Crompton,
the stripping doctor.
And next, gentlemen
and ladies,
here at the Peephole Club,
for the very first time,
a very big welcome, please,
for the secretary of state
for commonwealth affairs.
Good evening.
Tonight, I'd like to restate
our position
on agricultural
subsidies
and their effect on our
commonwealth relationships.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
Now, although we believe
theoretically
in ending guaranteed
farm prices,
we also believe in the need
for the corresponding,
uh, import levy
to maintain consumer prices
at a realistic, uh, level.
But this would have the effect
of consolidating our gains
of the previous fiscal year
prior to the entry.
But I pledge that, should we
join the Common Market,
even maintaining the present
position on subsidies,
we will never jeopardize,
we will never compromise
our unique relationship
with the commonwealth
countries.
A prices structure related
to any, uh, import charges
will be systematically
adjusted
uh, to the particular
requirements
of our commonwealth partners,
so that, together,
we will maintain a positive
and mutually
beneficial alliance
in world trade
and for world peace.
Thank you and good night.
[APPLAUSE]
Wasn't he marvelous?
The secretary of state
for commonwealth affairs.
And now, gentlemen and ladies,
a very big welcome, please,
for the minister
of pensions
and social security!
[ARABIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER]
Yes, today in Britain,
there is a new wave
of interest in politics
and politicians.
Well, we're in it
for the lobbying, you know.
We just love lobbying.
And the debates.
You know, a good debate
is just fabulous.
Well, I've been going
with ministers
for five years now,
and, uh, you know,
I think they're wonderful.
Oh, yes. I like
civil servants.
- Oh, yes, they're nice.
- Yeah.
- I-- I like the Speaker.
- Oh, yeah.
I like
Black Rod.
[ANNOUNCER]
What do their parents think?
Well, she's broken our hearts,
the little bastard.
She's been nothing
but trouble,
and if she comes
round here again,
I'll kick her teeth in.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Have you been talking
to television again, dear?
Yes, I bloody told them.
What about?
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, was it Reginald
Bosanquet?
No, no, no.
Did he have his head
all bandaged?
No, it wasn't like that.
They had lights and cameras
and tape recorders,
all that sort of thing.
Oh, that'll be
Ray Baxter,
and the boys and girls
from Tomorrow's World.
Oh, I prefer Reginald
Bosanquet. There's not
so many of them.
- Hm.
- [DOORBELL RINGS]
Oh, that'll be
the ratcatcher.
Hello. Mr. and Mrs.
Concrete?
- Yes.
Well, well, well,
well, well,
well, well, well,
how very nice.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Leslie Ames,
the chairman of the Test
Selection Committee.
And I'm very pleased
to be able to tell you
that your flat has been chosen
as the venue for the third
test against the West Indies.
Really?
No, it was just a little joke.
I'm the council ratcatcher.
Oh, yes, we've
been expecting you.
Oh. I gather you've got
a little rodental problem.
Oh, blimey, you'd think
he was awake all the night,
scrabbling down
by the wainscoting.
Mm. that's an interesting
word, isn't it?
What?
Wainscoting.
Sounds like
a little Dorset village.
Wainscoting.
We've been mentioned
on telly!
Uh, where is it worst?
Well, uh,
down here,
- you can usually
hear them.
- Ah. Shh.
Sh.
[SHEEP BLEATING]
No, that's sheep
you've got there.
No, that's
definitely sheep.
- Bit of a puzzle, really.
- Is it?
Yeah, well,
I mean, it's A,
not gonna respond
to a nice piece of cheese,
and B, it isn't gonna
fit into a trap.
Whoa. What
you gonna do?
Well, we'll have to look
for the hole.
Oh, yeah.
Mm. Oh.
Oi. There's one here.
[LESLIE]
No, no, no.
No, that's mice.
Oh. This is what
we're after.
Move that.
Yup.
[MAN]
Oh, yeah.
E-excuse me,
is the third test in here?
No, no, that was a joke.
It was a joke.
It was
a joke.
Right. Well, I'm going
in the wainscoting.
They said it again!
Lay down some sheep poison.
Ooh.
[SHEEP BLEATING]
[BANG]
[GROANING]
It's got a gun.
Oh. Blimey.
Now, normally, a sheep
is a placid, timid creature,
but you've got a killer.
It's an entirely new strain
of sheep.
A killer sheep that can
not only hold a rifle,
but is also
a first-class shot.
But where are they
coming from, professor?
That I don't know.
I just don't know.
I really just don't know.
I'm afraid I really
just don't know.
I'm afraid even I
really just don't know.
I have to tell you I'm afraid
even I really just don't know.
I'm afraid I have to
tell you that--
Thank you.
I don't know.
Our only clue is this portion
of wolf's clothing,
which the killer sheep--
Was wearing.
--in yesterday's raid
on Selfridges.
I'll carry out tests on it
straightaway, professor.
[WEST-INDIAN ACCENT]
Hello, is the third test
in here, please, man?
Professor, there are some
cricketers in the laboratory.
This may be
even more serious
than even I had at first
been imagining.
What a strange, strange line.
There's no time
to waste.
Get me the commissioner
of police.
Yes, sir.
No, no, on the phone!
Look of fear!
Another strange line.
Look out,
Miss Garter Oil!
Professor, what is it?
What have you seen?
Look, it's there,
in the doorway.
[SCREAMS]
Arthur X, leader of
the Pennine Gang.
Don't nobody move.
We're reverting to putting
Plan A into operation.
Mugsy, Louie, Luau.
[GUNSHOTS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
Next, Basil.
You and the kid. Move.
[GUNSHOTS]
Okay, boys, this time
we go for the heavy stuff.
[BANJO MUSIC PLAYING]
But soon the killer sheep
began to infect other animals
with its startling
intelligence.
Pussycats began
to arrange mortgages.
Cocker spaniels began
to design supermarkets.
And parrots started
to announce television
programs.
It's 8:00, and time
for the news.
Good evening.
Here is the news for parrots.
No parrots were involved
in an accident on the M1 today
when a lorry carrying
high-octane fuel
was in collision with
a bollard.
That is a bollard
and not a parrot.
A spokesman for parrots
said he was glad
no parrots were involved.
The minister of technology
today met the three
Russian leaders
to discuss a 664 million
airliner deal.
None of them went in the cage
or swung on
the little wooden trapeze,
or ate any
of the nice millet seed.
Yum, yum.
That's the end of the news.
Now our programs
for parrots continue
with part three
of A Tale of Two Cities,
specially adapted for parrots
by Joey Boy.
The story so far:
Dr. Manette is in England
after 18 years
in the Bastille.
His daughter, Lu-- Lucie,
awaits her lover,
Charles Darnay,
whom we just learnt
is, in fact, the nephew
of the Marquis de
St. Evremond,
whose cruelty had placed
Manette in the Bastille.
Darnay arrives to find Lucie
tending her aged father.
[HIGH-PITCHED SQUAWK]
Hello. Hello.
- Hello.
- Hello, hello, hello.
- Who's a pretty boy, then?
- Hello, hello.
- Who's a pretty boy?
- Ooh.
- Hello, hello.
Hello, hello.
- I'm a pretty parrot.
- Hello, hello.
And while that's going on,
here is the news for gibbons.
No gibbons were involved in...
[ANNOUNCER]
While that's going on,
here from Westminster
is a parliamentary report
for humans.
In the debate,
a spokesman accused
the government of being silly
and doing not-at-all-good
things.
The member accepted this in
a spirit of healthy criticism,
but denied that he'd ever
been naughty with a choirboy.
Angry shouts of "What about
the watermelon, then?"
were ordered by the Speaker
stricken from the record
and put into a brown paper bag
in the lavvy.
Any further interruptions
would be cut off
and distributed amongst
the poor.
For the government,
a front-bench spokesman said
the agricultural tariff
would have to be raised,
and he fancied a bit.
Furthermore, he argued,
this would give a large
boost to farmers
and a lot of fun to him,
his friend
and Miss Moist
of Knightsbridge.
From the back benches
there were opposition shouts
of "Postcards for sale"
and a healthy cry
of "Who likes a sailor, then?"
from the minister
without portfolio.
Replying,
the shadow minister said
he could no longer deny
the rumors,
but he and the dachshund
were very happy.
And in any case, he argued,
rhubarb was cheap,
and what was the harm
in a sauna bath?
--were not involved.
The minister of technology
met the three
Russian leaders today
to discuss
a 664 million airliner deal.
None of them were indigenous
to Australia,
carried their babies
in pouches,
or ate any of those yummy
eucalyptus leaves.
Yum, yum.
That's the news for wombats,
And now, Attila the Bun.
[BUN YELLING]
Well, that's all
for Attila the Bun.
And now...idiots.
[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER]
Arthur Figgis is an idiot.
A village idiot.
Tonight, we look
at the idiot in society.
Well, I feel very keenly
that the idiot is a part
of the old village system,
and as such
has a vital role to play
in the modern rural society.
Because, you see--
[BLITHERING]
And the birds fly nightly
on the-- Thank you, vicar.
Because there is this
very real need in society
for someone whom almost anyone
can look down on and--
And ridicule.
And this is the role that--
[BLITHERING]
Nightly ramble...
Oogly-oogly-oogly-ooh!
Thank you, Mrs. Thompson.
This is the role that
I and members of my family
have fulfilled in this village
for the past 400 years.
Ah, good morning,
Mr. Jenkins.
ICI have increased their
half-yearly dividend, I see.
Yes, splendid.
That's Mr. Jenkins.
He's another idiot.
And so, you see, the--
The idiot does provide
a vital psychosocial service
for this community.
Oh, excuse me,
uh, a coach party's
just arrived.
I shall have to fall
off the wall, I'm afraid.
[BLITHERING]
[GLASS BREAKS]
[ANNOUNCER]
Arthur takes idioting
seriously.
He is up at 6:00 every morning
working on special
training equipment
designed to keep him silly.
And, of course, he takes
great pride in his appearance.
Like the doctor,
- the blacksmith,
the carpenter...
- Ah!
...Mr. Figgis is an important
figure in this village.
And like them,
he uses the local bank.
Yes, we have quite a number
of idiots banking here.
[ANNOUNCER]
What kind of money
is there in idioting?
Well, nowadays,
a really blithering idiot
can make anything up
to 6610,000 a year,
if he's the head of some
big industrial combine.
But of course, the more
old-fashioned idiot
still refuses to
take money.
He takes bits
of string, wood,
dead budgerigars,
sparrows, anything,
But it does make the cashier's
job very difficult.
Of course, they're
fools to themselves.
The rate of interest
over 10 years
on a piece of moss or a dead
vole is almost negligible.
- Mr. Brando.
- Yes?
Hollywood on
the phone.
Uh, I'll take it
in the office.
[ANNOUNCER]
But Mr. Figgis
is no ordinary idiot.
He is a lecturer in idiocy
at the University
of East Anglia.
Here he is taking a class
of third-year students.
[ALL BLITHERING]
[ANNOUNCER]
After three years of study
these apprentice idiots
receive a diploma of idiocy,
a handful of mud
and a kick on the head.
But some of the older idiots
resent the graduate idiot.
I'm a completely
self-taught idiot.
I mean, "Ooh-ah, roo-ah,
roo-ah, roo-ah!"
Nobody does that anymore.
Anybody who did
that around here
would be laughed off
the street.
No, uh, nowadays,
people want something wittier.
[ANNOUNCER]
Kevin O'Nassis works
largely with walls.
Whoa!
[KEVIN]
Well, you gotta know
what you're doing.
I mean, some people
think I'm mad.
Villagers say I'm mad,
tourists say I'm mad.
Well, I am mad.
But I'm naturally mad.
I don't use any chemicals.
Whoa!
[ANNOUNCER]
But what of the idiot's
private life?
How about his relationship
with women?
Well, I may be an idiot,
but I'm no fool.
[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER]
But the village idiot's
dirty smock
and wall-falling
are a far cry
- from the modern world
of the urban idiot.
- Hey!
What kinds of backgrounds
do these city idiots
come from?
[NASAL ACCENT]
Woo!
[LAUGHING]
Uh! Uh!
[POSH ACCENT]
Uh...
[HIGH-PITCHED ACCENT]
Well, uh...
[POMPOUS ACCENT]
The headquarters
of these urban idiots
is here in St. John's Wood.
Inside, they can enjoy
the company of other idiots
and watch special performances
of ritual idioting.
[LIGHT APPLAUSE]
Well left.
Well
played.
Well, well.
Well-bred.
[GROANING]
[JIM]
Good afternoon
and welcome to Lord's
on the second day
of the first test.
So far today, we've had five
hours batting from England,
and already,
they're naught for naught.
Uh, Cowdrey is not out naught
and Naughton is not in.
Knott is in
and is not not out.
Naughton of Northants
got a nasty knock
on the nut in the nets
last night,
but it's nothing of note.
Uh, next in is Nat Newton
of Notts.
Not Nutting,
Nutting's at 9.
Nutting knocked neatie nightie
knock knock nar nar...
Anyway, um,
England have played
extremely well for nothing,
not a sausage,
in reply to Iceland's
first innings total
of 722 for 2 declared,
uh, scored yesterday
disappointingly fast
in only 21 overs,
with lots of wild slogging
and boundaries and--
And all sorts of
rubbishy things.
But the main thing is
that England have made
an absolutely outstanding
start so far.
[GROANS SHARPLY,
THEN INHALES SHARPLY]]
Peter?
Uh, splendid.
Just listen to those thighs.
And now it's the Northeast's
turn with the samba.
- Brian.
- Uh, rather.
I'm reminded of the story
of Gubby Allen in '32--
Oh, shut up,
or we'll close the bar.
And now Bo Wildeburg
is running up
to bowl to Cowdrey.
He runs up,
he bowls to Cowdrey,
and no shot at all.
Extremely well-not-played
there.
Yes, beautifully
not-done-anything-about.
A superb shot of
no kind whatsoever.
I well remember
Plum Warner
leaving a very similar
ball alone in 1732.
Oh, shut up,
long-nose.
And now it's Bo Wildeburg,
running in again to bowl
to Cowdrey.
He runs in.
He bowls to Cowdrey.
And no shot at all.
A superb display
of inertia there.
And that's the end of
the over. And drinks.
Gin and tonic, please.
No, no, the players
are having drinks.
And now, uh,
what's happening?
I think Cowdrey's
being taken--
Yes, Cowdrey is being
carried off.
Well, I never.
Now, who's in next?
It should be number three,
Natt Newton of Notts.
Get your hand off
my thigh, West.
Uh, no, I don't think it is.
I think it's, uh...
It's a sofa.
No, it's a chesterfield!
The green chesterfield
is coming in at number three
to take guard now.
I well remember a similar
divan being brought on
at Headingley in 9 B.C.
against the darkies.
Oh, shut up,
elephant-snout.
And now, the green, uh,
chesterfield has taken guard.
And, uh...
Ah, Iceland are putting on
their spin-dryer
to bowl.
The spin-dryer moving
back to its mark.
It runs up to the wicket,
bowls to the table...
A little bit short, but it's
coming in a bit there,
and it's hit him on the pad!
There's an appeal.
And the table is out,
leg before wicket.
That is England
naught for one.
[ANNOUNCER]
And now we leave Lord's and go
over to Epsom for the 3:00.
[COMMENTATOR]
Well, here at Epsom,
we take up the running,
50 yards of this
mile-and-a-half race to go.
It's the wash basin
in the lead from WC pedestal.
Tucked in nicely there
is the sofa,
going well with Joanna
Southcott's box
making a good run
from hat stand on the rails.
And Standard lamp
is fading fast.
Wash basin taking up
the running, strongly pressed.
At the post,
it's the wash basin from WC
then sofa, hat stand,
Standard lamp,
and lastly,
Joanna Southcott's box.
[IN UNISON]
Open the box! Open the box!
Open the box!
Can we have the next
contender, please?
[CHUCKLING]
[CONTINUES
CHUCKLING]
Good evening, madam.
And your name is...?
Yes, yes.
- Ha-ha. And what's your name?
- I go to church regularly. Mm.
Jolly good. I see.
And which prize
do you have particular eyes
on this evening?
Oh, I'd like
the blow on the head.
The blow on the head.
- Just there.
- Jolly good.
- Well, your first question...
- Mm.
...for the blow on the head
this evening is:
What great opponent
of Cartesian dualism
resists the reduction
of psychological phenomena
to physical states?
I don't know that!
Well, have a guess.
Oh.
Uh, Henri Bergson.
Is the correct answer!
That was lucky.
I never even heard of him.
- Jolly good.
- I don't like darkies.
[LAUGHING]
Who does?
And now, your second
question
for the blow
on the head is:
What is the main food
that penguins eat?
Pork luncheon meat.
No.
- Spam?
- No, no, no, no.
What do penguins eat?
Penguins.
- Penguins?
- Yes.
- They eat penguins?
- No, no, no.
- They eat themselves?
- No, no, what do penguins eat?
Horses! Armchairs!
No, no.
What do penguins eat?
- Oh, penguins.
- Penguins.
- Cannelloni.
- No.
Lasagna, moussaka,
lobster thermidor,
escalopes de veau
à l'estragon
avec endives gratinéed
with cheese.
[LAUGHING]
No. I'll give you a clue.
Oh.
Oh!
Brian Close.
[LAUGHING]
No, no.
- Brian Inglis? Brian Johnson?
Bryan Forbes?
- No, no, no.
- Nanette Newman.
- No.
What swims in the sea
and gets caught in nets?
- Henri Bergson.
- No!
Goats. Underwater goats,
with snorkels and flippers.
- No.
- A buffalo with an aqualung.
- Oh, Reginald Maudling.
Yes, that's near enough.
I'll give you that.
Right. Now. Uh, Mrs. Scum,
you have won your prize.
Do you still want
the blow on the head?
Yes, yes.
I'll offer you
a poke in the eye.
No, I want the blow
on the head.
- A punch in the throat?
- No.
All right, then,
a kick in the kneecap.
- No.
- Mrs. Scum,
I'm offering you a boot
in the teeth
and a dagger
up the strap.
Oh.
- Hm.
- [WOMAN 1] Blow on the head!
[WOMAN 2]
Take the blow on the head!
Oh. Oh, o-okay. I'll take
the blow on the head.
Very well, then,
Mrs. Scum.
You have won tonight's
star prize:
the blow
on the head!
- [LAUGHING]
- [DING]
- [SCREAMS]
- [LAUGHS]
[♪♪]
[FART]