[♪♪]
Mm.
And now for something
completely different.
It's...
[♪♪]
[ANNOUNCER]
Monty Python's
Flying Circus.
[ANNOUNCER]
How to recognize
different parts of the body.
Number one, the foot.
Number two...
the shoulder.
And number three...
the other foot.
Number four...
the bridge of the nose.
Number five...
the naughty bits.
Number six...
just above the elbow.
Number seven...
two inches to the right
of a very naughty
bit indeed.
Number eight, the kneecap.
["WALTZING MATHILDA"
ON RECORD PLAYER]
♪ Once a jolly swagman
Camped by a billabong ♪
♪ Under the shade... ♪
- Good day, Bruce.
- Oh, hello, Bruce.
- How are you, Bruce?
- A bit crook, Bruce.
- Where's Bruce?
- He's not here, Bruce.
Blimey. It's hot
in here, Bruce.
It's hot enough
to boil a monkey's bum.
That's a strange-- That's
a strange expression, Bruce.
Well, Bruce, I heard
the prime minister use it.
"Hot enough to boil
a monkey's bum in here,
Your Majesty,"
he said.
And she smiled quietly
to herself.
She's a good sheila, Bruce.
And not at all stuck-up.
Ah. Here comes
the boss fellow now.
- Ah, good day, Bruce.
- Hey, Bruce.
Hello, Bruce.
How are you, Bruce?
Gentlemen, I'd like
to introduce a chap
from Pommyland
who'll be joining us
this year
here in the Philosophy
Department
of the University
of Woolamaloo.
Uh, Michael Baldwin,
this is Bruce.
Michael Baldwin,
Is your name
not Bruce, then?
Uh, no,
it's Michael.
That's going to cause
a little confusion.
Yeah. Mind if we call
you Bruce,
just to keep it clear?
Well, gentlemen, I think
we better start the meeting.
Before we start,
though,
I'll ask the Padre
for a prayer.
Oh, Lord, we beseech thee,
have mercy
on our faculty, amen.
- Amen.
Crack the tubes,
right.
Ah, Bruce,
I now call upon you
to welcome Mr. Baldwin
to the Philosophy Department.
I'd like to welcome
the pommy bastard
to God's own earth.
And I'd like to remind him
that we don't like stuck-up
stickybeaks here.
[ALL]
Hear, hear!
Well spoken, Bruce!
Now, Bruce teaches
classical philosophy,
Bruce teaches
Hegelian philosophy.
Bruce here teaches
logical positivism
and is also in charge
of the sheep dip.
What does, um--
What does new Bruce teach?
Our new Bruce will teach
political science,
Machiavelli, Bentham, Locke,
Hobbes, Sutcliffe,
Bradman, Lindwall, Miller,
Hassett and Benaud.
- Those are cricketers, Bruce.
- Oh, spit.
Howls. Howls of derisive
laughter, Bruce.
Ha-ha! In addition, as he's
gonna be teaching politics,
I told him that
he's welcome to teach
any of the great
socialist thinkers,
provided he makes it clear
that they were wrong.
[ALL]
Australia, Australia,
Australia, Australia.
We love you. Amen.
Any questions?
New Bruce, are you a poofter?
- Are you a poofter?
- No.
No, right. Well, gentlemen,
I'll just remind you
of the faculty rules.
Rule one,
no poofters.
Uh, rule two, no member
of the faculty
is to maltreat the Abos
in any way whatsoever
if there's anyone watching.
Rule three, no poofters.
Uh, rule four, I don't wanna
catch anyone not drinking
in their room
after lights out.
Rule five, no poofters.
Rule six,
there is no rule six.
Rule seven, no poofters.
That concludes the reading
of the rules. Bruce.
This here is the wattle,
the emblem of our land.
You can stick it in a bottle,
you can hold it in your hand.
- Amen.
- [ALL] Amen!
Gentlemen, it's 6:00.
I want every man-Bruce of you
in the Sydney
Harbor Bridge room
to take a glass of sherry with
the flying philosopher, Bruce.
And I now call upon you,
padre,
to close the meeting
with a prayer.
Oh Lord,
we beseech thee,
et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera, amen.
- [ALL] Amen!
- Right, let's get some sheilas.
- Okay.
- Ah! Elevenses.
Ah! This
should tide us--
This should tide us over
till lunchtime.
Reckon so, Bruce.
Sidney Nolan.
What's that?
[ANNOUNCER]
Number nine, the ear.
Number 10, the big toe.
Number 11...
more naughty bits.
And number 12...
the naughty bits of a lady.
And number 13,
the naughty bits of a horse.
Number 14...
the naughty bits of an ant.
Number 15, the naughty bits
of Reginald Maudling.
Number 16, the hand.
Good evening. I have with me
in the studio tonight
Mr. Norman-- Mr. Norman
St. John Polevaulter,
who, for the past few years,
has been contradicting people.
Mr. Polevaulter, why do you
contradict people?
- I don't.
- You told me you did.
I most certainly did not.
Oh, I see.
I'll start again.
- No, you won't.
- Shh.
Mr. Polevaulter, I understand
you don't contradict people.
- Yes, I do.
- When didn't you start
contradicting people?
Well, I did, in 1952.
- 1952?
- 1947.
- Twenty-three years ago?
- No.
And so on and so on and so on.
And now...
number 17...
the top of the head.
Number 18...
the feather.
Rare.
Number 19...
the nose.
[♪♪]
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
[MAN]
Come in.
Ah, Mr. Luxury Yacht.
Do sit down, please.
Uh, no, no. My name is
spelt Luxury Yacht,
but it's pronounced
Throatwobbler Mangrove.
Ah, well, do sit down then,
Mr. Throatwobbler Mangrove.
Thank you.
Now, what seems to be
the trouble?
Um...
I'd like you to perform
some plastic surgery on me.
I see. And which particular
feature of your anatomy
is causing you distress?
Well-- Well,
for a long time now--
In fact, even when
I was a child
- -uh, I, you know, ever--
whenever I left home...
- Mm-hm.
- uh, to catch a bus or--
Or to catch a train--
- Fine.
Uh, and even my tennis
has suffered, actually.
- Uh--
- Yes. To be absolutely blunt
you're worried about
your enormous hooter.
- No.
- No?
- Yes.
Yes.
You want me to hack a bit off.
- Please.
- Fine.
It is a startler,
isn't it?
Uh, do you mind
if I, uh...?
What?
Oh, no, nothing then.
I'll just examine your nose.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Mr. Luxury Yacht,
this, um...
This nose of yours
is false.
It's made of
polystyrene.
And your own
hooter's a beaut.
No pruning necessary.
I'd still like
the operation.
Well, you've had
the operation,
you strange person.
Please do an operation.
Well, all right.
All right.
But only if you'll come
on a camping holiday with me.
He asked me,
he asked me!
[♪♪]
Next week, we'll be
showing you
how to pick up an architect,
how to pull a prime minister,
and how to have fun
with a wholesale poulterer.
Now the men of the Derbyshire
Light Infantry entertain us
with a precision display
of bad temper.
[MAN]
Attention!
My goodness, me.
I am in a bad temper today,
all right, two, three.
Damn, damn, two, three.
I am vexed and ratty,
two, three.
And hopping mad.
And next, the men
of the Second Armored Division
regale us with their famous
close-order swanning about.
Squad!
Camp it...up.
[ALL]
Ooh, get her. Whoops.
I've got your number, ducky.
Couldn't afford me, dear,
two, three.
I'll scratch your eyes out.
Don't come the brigadier bit
with us, dear.
We all know where you've been,
you military fairy.
Whoops, don't look now, girls.
The major's just minced
in with that dolly
color sergeant.
- [SOLDIER] Two, three.
- [ALL] Oooh.
And finally...
[TCHAIKOVSKY'S "NUTCRACKER
SUITE" PLAYING]
God, if they don't stop,
I'll kill myself.
I swear I will.
All right. That's it.
[GUNSHOT]
[ANNOUNCER]
For three days and nights,
the displaced eyeball
plummeted earthward.
Until finally...
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
Oh.
Excuse me.
[MAN]
Keep low, keep down. Don't lag
behind. Come on, everybody.
Right. Keep close.
That's right.
Watch out for the killer cars.
[MOTOR ROARS]
[ANNOUNCER]
Yes, the killer cars.
For years, the city
had been plagued
by ever-increasing
pedestrian congestion.
In an attempt
to eliminate this problem,
certain fanatical cars
had taken the law
into their own hands.
[MOTORS ROARING]
But the days of the killer
cars were numbered,
thanks to the miracle
of atomic mutation.
[RUMBLING]
[MOTORS ROARING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[MAN]
Oh, thank you.
You've saved our city.
[ANNOUNCER]
But at what cost?
[GOBBLING]
[CATERWAULS]
[MAN]
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
[CROWD CHEERING]
You've saved our city.
Except for those
who chose to leave town.
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
This, then, is the story
of two of them.
[WHISTLING]
Morning, sir.
Can I help you?
Uh, yes. We've-- We've booked
on your flight for America.
Oh, we don't fly
to America.
Oh, the American flight.
Ah, on the plane. Oh, yes.
Oh, we do that, all right.
[LAUGHS]
Safe as houses,
no need for panic.
Is it really
37 and 6?
Thirty bob.
I'm robbing meself.
- Thirty bob?
- Twenty-five.
Uh, two quid, the pair of you.
Uh, that's without insurance.
- How much is it with insurance?
- Hundred and two quid.
That's including
the flight.
How long will it take?
Uh, let me put it this way.
No idea.
- Six hours.
- Six?
Five. Ten for
the pair of you.
- Oh, is it a jet?
- Uh, well, no.
It's not so much a jet.
It's more your...
Triumph Herald engine
with wings.
When are you taking off?
- 3300 hours.
- [MAN] What?
- 2600 hours for the pair.
- [WOMAN] What?
After the injections,
you won't care.
- What injections?
- Barley sugar. Calm you down.
They're compulsory.
Board of trade. Promise.
I don't like the sound
of injections.
Ring, ring.
Hello. Yes. Right.
You've got to make
your mind up straightaway
if you're coming
or not.
- [BOTH] Yes.
- Right. You can't
change your mind.
I'll ring
the departure lounge.
Hello? Two more on their way,
Mrs. Turpin.
[WOMAN]
Ah.
Now, uh, the duty-free
trolley is over there.
There's some lovely
drop scones
and some duty-free
broccoli,
and there's fresh
Eccles cakes.
You're allowed 200 each
on the plane. Ahem.
The Verrifast Plaine Company
announce the departure
of flight one
to over the hills
and far away.
Will passengers
for flight one
please assemble
at gate one?
Passengers are
advised
that there is still plenty
of time to buy Eccles cakes.
Nearly ready.
All passengers please
get ready
for their barley sugar
injections, okay?
Oh. Today,
we all take vow.
Today, we smash
the enemy fleet.
We smash, smash.
[INDISTINCT
SCREAMING]
[MEN
LAUGHING]
Uh, now, that's Mr. Kamikaze,
the pilot.
He's very nice, really,
but make sure he stays clear
of battleships.
[ANNOUNCER] There have been
many stirring
tales told of the sea,
and also some fairly
uninteresting ones
only marginally
connected with it.
Uh, like this one.
Sorry, this isn't a very
good announcement. Sorry.
And here is the result
of the "Where to Put Edward
Heath's Statue" competition.
The winner was
a Mr. Ivy North,
who wins 10 guineas
and a visit to the sailors'
quarters.
[ALL GRUNTING, YELPING]
That was last year's
reenactment of the battle
of Pearl Harbor
performed by the Batley
Townswomen's Guild.
It was written, directed
and produced
by Mrs. Rita Fairbanks.
Hello again.
[INTERVIEWER]
And what are your ladies
gonna do for us this year?
Well, this year, we decided
to reenact something
with a more modern flavor.
We had considered a version
of Michael Stewart's
speech on Nigeria,
and there were several votes
on the committee
for a staging
of Herr Willy Brandt's
visit to East Germany.
But we've settled, instead,
for a dramatization
of the first heart transplant.
Incidentally, my sister,
Madge, will be playing
the plucky little
springbok pioneer,
Dr. Christian Barnard.
[INTERVIEWER] Off we go then,
with the Batley Townswomen's
Guild reenactment
of the first heart
transplant.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[ALL GRUNTING, YELPING]
The first heart transplant.
But this is not the only
open-air production here
that has used the sea.
Theatrical managers
in this area
have not been as slow
to appreciate
the sea's tremendous
dramatic value.
And somewhere,
out in this bay,
is the first underwater
production
of Measure for Measure.
[MUFFLED SHAKESPEARIAN
DIALOGUE]
[INHALING NOISILY]
[MUFFLED SHAKESPEARIAN
DIALOGUE CONTINUES]
[INHALING NOISILY]
[INDISTINCT DIALOGUE]
[YELLS INDISTINCTLY]
Right.
The underwater version
of Measure for Measure.
And further out to sea,
Hello, Dolly!
is also doing
good business.
[MEN GURGLING]
♪ Hello, Dolly ♪
And over there
on the oyster beds,
Formula Two car racing.
[MOTORS ROARING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[ANNOUNCER]
Number 20...the armpits.
Number 21...
the bottom two-thirds
of the nape of the neck.
Number 22...
the nipple.
[MAN OVER RADIO]
And that concludes
this week's episode
of How to Recognize
Different Parts of the Body,
adapted for radio
by Ann Haydon-Jones
and her husband, Pip.
And now we present
the first episode
of a new radio
drama series:
The Death of Mary,
Queen of Scots.
Part One:
The Beginning.
[MUSIC PLAYING
OVER RADIO]
[MAN] You are Mary,
Queen of Scots?
[WOMAN]
I am.
- [THUMPING]
- [WOMAN] Ow! Ow!
[WOMAN SCREAMING OVER RADIO]
[THUMPING, OBJECTS CRASHING]
[WOMAN CONTINUES
SCREAMING]
Oh! No!
[SCREAMS]
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO]
[THUMPING, SCREAMING STOPS]
Episode two of The Death
of Mary, Queen of Scots
can be heard on Radio 4
almost immediately.
[MUSIC PLAYING
OVER RADIO]
[SAWING]
[THUMPING, WOMAN
SCREAMING]
[THUMPING,
SCREAMING STOPS]
[MAN]
I think she's dead.
[WOMAN]
No, I'm not.
[GUNSHOT, THUMPING,
SCREAMING RESUMES]
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO]
[ANNOUNCER]
That was episode two
of The Death of Mary,
Queen of Scots,
adapted for the radio
by Bernard Hollowood
and Brian London.
And now Radio 4
will explode.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[EXPLOSION]
Oh.
We'll have to watch
the telly then.
Yes.
Well...what's on
the television then?
Looks like
a penguin.
No, no, no, no.
I didn't mean what's on
the television set.
I meant
what program.
- Ohh.
- Oh.
[HUMMING]
♪ Young and handsome ♪
[BOTH] ♪ Girl from Ipanema
Goes walking ♪
It's funny that penguin
being there, isn't it?
- What's it doing there?
- Standing.
I can see that.
If it lays an egg...
it will fall down the back
of the television set.
- We'll have to watch that.
- Mmm.
Unless it's a male.
Ooh, I never thought
of that.
Yes.
Looks fairly butch.
Perhaps it comes
from next door.
Penguins don't come
from next door,
they come
from the Antarctic.
Burma!
- Why'd you say "Burma"?
- I panicked.
Oh.
Perhaps it's
from the zoo.
Which zoo?
How should I know which zoo?
I'm not Dr. Bloody Bernowski.
How does Dr. Bernowski know
which zoo it came from?
He knows everything.
Oh, I wouldn't
like that.
It'd take the mystery
out of life.
Anyway, if it came
from the zoo,
it'd have "Property
of the Zoo" stamped on it.
No, it wouldn't.
They don't stamp animals
"Property of the Zoo."
You couldn't stamp
a huge lion.
They stamp them
when they're small.
What happens
when they molt?
Lions don't molt.
No, but penguins do.
There, I've run rings
around you, logically.
Oh. Intercourse
the penguin.
It's, uh, just gone 8:00
and time for the penguin
on top of your television
set to explode.
How did he know that
was going to happen?
It was an inspired guess.
And now...
Number 23...the shin.
Number 24...
Reginald Maudling's shin.
Number 25...the brain.
Number 26...
Margaret Thatcher's brain.
And number 27...
more naughty bits.
Number 28...
the naughty bits
of the cabinet.
Number 29...
the interior
of a country house.
That's not
a part of the body.
No, it's a link, though.
I didn't think
it was very good.
No, it's the end
of the series.
They must be out of ideas.
All right,
don't anybody move.
There's been
a murder.
A murder?
No, no.
Not murder. No.
Uh, what's like a murder
but begins with B?
Birmingham?
- No, no, no, no, no.
- [MAN 1] Burnley?
Burnley, that's right.
Burnley in Lancashire.
There's been
a Burnley.
Burglary.
Yes. Good man.
That's it, of course.
- There's been a burglary.
- Where?
In the back,
just below the rib.
No, that's murder.
Oh, no. In the--
Eh, in the band.
In the bat. Barclays bat.
- Barclays Bank?
- Yes. Nasty business.
Got away with 23,000 pounds.
Any clues?
Any what?
[MAN 2] Well, any evidence
as to who did it?
Any clues, eh?
Ooh, we don't half talk
posh, do we? Ha-ha!
I suppose you say "ehnvelope"
and "larngerie,"
and "sarndwiches
on the settee."
This is a murder
investigation, young man,
and murder is
a very serious business.
[MAN 1]
I thought you said
it was a burglary.
Burglary is almost as serious
a business as murder.
Some burglaries
are more serious.
A burglary in which someone
gets stabbed is murder.
So don't come to these
petty distinctions with me.
You're as bad as a judge.
Right. Now...
the first thing to do
in the event of a breach
of a peace of any kind
is to go and...
Sorry, sorry.
I was miles away.
- Ah, ring the police?
- Ring the police.
Get them
over here fast.
No, get them
over here slowly
so they don't
drop anything.
Shall I make us all
a cup of tea?
Make what you like,
Boskovitch.
It won't help you
in court. Hm-hm.
I beg your pardon?
I'm sorry. Sorry.
I'm on top of being
on two cases at once.
I keep thinking I've got
Boskovitch cornered,
whereas in fact,
I'm investigating a Burnley.
- Burglary?
- Yes, good man.
[SIREN WAILING]
Um...w-who's--?
Who's Boskovitch?
Ha!
Boskovitch is
a Russian scientist
who's passing information
to the Russians.
Classified
information?
Oh, there
he goes again.
"Classified
information."
Oh, sitting on the settee
with our scones
and our classified
information.
Hello.
Oh, hello, Duckie.
Hello, sir.
How are you?
I'm fine, thanks.
Well, sir, I'm a little bit
moody today, sir.
- Why's that, Duckie?
- [MUSIC PLAYS]
Because...
♪ I'm a little bit sad
And lonely ♪
♪ Now, my baby's gone away ♪
♪ I'm feeling kind of blue
I don't know just what to do ♪
♪ I feel a little sad today ♪
[ALL]
♪ He's a little bit sad
And lonely ♪
♪ Now, his baby's gone away ♪
♪ He's feeling kind of blue
He don't know just what to do ♪
♪ He ain't feeling so good
Today ♪
- ♪ When I smile ♪
- ♪ Ahhhh ♪
- ♪ The sun comes flooding in ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no,
no, no ♪
- ♪ When I'm sad ♪
- ♪ Ahhh ♪
♪ It goes behind the clouds
Again ♪
♪ I'm a little bit sad
And lonely ♪
♪ When my baby's
Gone away ♪
♪ I'm feeling kind of-- ♪
[ALL]
Et cetera, et cetera.
[INSPECTOR]
A lovely song, Duckie.
[APPLAUSE]
And that's
the final entry:
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
And now, Guten Abend.
Die scores.
Das scores.
Les scores. Die scores.
Dei scores.
Oh, scores. Ha! Scores.
Yes, Monaco is the winner.
[ASIAN ACCENT]
Ha! Monaco is a linner.
[JAMAICAN ACCENT]
Oh, yes, man. Monaco's won
the big prize, bwana.
[NORMAL VOICE] And now here
is Chief Inspector
Jean-Paul Zatapathique
with the winning song
once again.
[ANNOUNCER]
And so Inspector
Zatapathique,
the forensic expert
from the Monaco
Murder Squad,
sings his song,
"Bing Tiddle Tiddle Bong."
[CHOIR HUMMING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[SINGING IN FRENCH]
[ALL]
♪ Bing tiddle tiddle bang ♪
[CHOIR]
♪ Bong tiddle fiddle bang ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle tiddle
Tiddle tiddle ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bong ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bing ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bang ♪
♪ Bing tiddle tiddle
Bang tiddle tiddle ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle tiddle
Bang bong bing ♪
♪ Bang bong tiddle tiddle
tiddle Bang bong bing ♪
♪ Tiddle tiddle bang ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bang ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle tiddle
Tiddle, tiddle ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bong ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bing ♪
♪ Bong tiddle tiddle bang ♪
- ♪ Bing bang bong ♪
- ♪ Tiddle tiddle ♪
♪ Tiddle tiddle
Bing bang bong ♪
Bong tiddle tiddle bing ♪
[PANTING]
[ANNOUNCER]
Number 31...the end.