[SEAGULLS CAWING]
[SEAGULL CAWING FADES]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SLOWLY HUMMING
"LA MARSEILLAISE"]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Ah.
[CHUCKLING]
[LAUGHING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Ah.
[GROANS]
Ah. Ha-ha.
Brian Distel and
Brianette Zatapathique there
in an improvised scene
from Jean Kenneth Longueur's
new movie,
Le Fromage Grand.
Brian and Brianette
symbolize
the breakdown
in communications
in our modern society
in this exciting new film.
And Longueur is saying to us,
his audience:
"Go on, protest.
Do something about it.
Assault the manager.
Demand your money back."
Later on in the film,
in a brilliantly conceived
montage,
Longueur mercilessly
exposes
the violence
underlying our society,
when Brian and Brianette
again meet
on yet another rubbish dump.
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
Ah.
[CHUCKLES]
[BOTH LAUGH]
[LAUGHS]
[TICKING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
Pretty strong meat there
from Longueur,
who is saying, of course,
that ultimately, materialism--
in this case,
the Webb's Wonder lettuce
--must destroy us all.
That was for O. Simon,
K. Simon,
P. Simon
and R. Sparrow of Leicester.
Later on, we're
going to take a look
at John Wayne's latest movie,
Buckets of Blood Pouring
Out of People's Heads.
But now, we look ahead.
On Tuesday, Chris Conger
took a BBC film unit
to the location where
20th Century Vole
are shooting their latest
epic, Scott of the Antarctic.
[MAN]
Sea, sand and sunshine
make Paignton the queen
of the English Riviera.
But for the next six months,
this sleepy Devonshire resort
will be transformed
into the blizzard-swept wastes
of the South Pole.
For today, shooting
starts on the epic,
Scott of the Antarctic,
produced by
Gerry Schlick.
Hello.
Gerry, you chose Paignton
as the location for Scott.
Right, right.
Isn't it a bit of a drawback
that there's no snow here?
Well, we have 28,000
cubic feet of Wintrex,
which is a new
white foam rubber,
which actually, on-screen,
looks more like snow than
snow.
And 1600 cubic U.S. furlongs
of white paint
with a special snow finish.
And I believe Kirk Vilb
is playing the title role.
That is correct.
We were very thrilled
and honored
when Kirk agreed to play
the part of Lieutenant Scott.
Because a star of his
magnitude can pick and choose.
But he read the title
and just flipped.
And directing, we have a very
fine young British director,
James McRettin,
who's been collaborating
on the screenplay, of course.
- Jimmy.
- Oh. There you are.
Hello. Hello. No problem.
Have a drink. Have a drink.
Oh. Great. Hello.
Marvelous. Marvelous. Hello.
Rewrite. Oh,
this is really great.
I mean, it's really saying
something, don't you think?
Have you started
shooting yet?
Yes, yes.
Great. Perfect.
No, no, we haven't started
yet. No. But great, great.
What is
the first scene
that you shoot
this morning?
Great. Terrific.
Oh, it's great. Uh, no
problem. We'll sort it out
on the floor.
Sort it out on the floor.
No problem.
This film is
basically pro-humanity
and anti-bad things.
And it rips aside
the hypocritical façade
of our society's
gin and tonic,
and leaves a lot of sacred
cows rolling around in agony.
Have a drink,
have a drink.
Uh, but which scene are
we shooting first, Jimmy?
Yes. Great.
Oh, marvelous.
Well, which scene
are we shooting first?
Why, it's scene one.
Scene one.
Scene one. It's
in the middle of the movie.
Well, it is now.
I rewrote it.
Besides, uh,
I thought we cut that.
Didn't we cut--?
- No, we didn't.
- We didn't?
Oh, great, that's even better.
I'll put it back in.
Uh, rewrite.
Scene one's back in, everyone.
Scene one's back in.
Great. Great.
This is the scene
that's outside the tent.
Ah! And it's so bloody
marvelous,
it makes you wanna
throw up.
Now, in this scene,
Lieutenant Scott returns
to camp in the early morning
after walking
the huskies,
to have brunch
with the rest of his team.
Oates, played by your very own
lovely Terence Lemming,
who is an English
cockney officer,
seconded to
the U.S. Navy,
and Bowers, played by
Seymour Fortescue,
the Olympic
pole-vaulter.
Hi, lieutenant.
Hi, Oatesy.
Sure is a beautiful
day already.
Great. Great.
What? What? What are
you saying?
I was just saying
"Great, great."
Cue Evans.
[GERRY]
And this is Vanilla Hoare
as Miss Evans.
- Miss Evans?
- [GERRY] Right.
Good morning,
Miss Evans.
Oh. I've forgotten my line.
- Uh, what's her line?
- [CLAPS]
What's her line?
"Good morning,
Captain Scott."
Oh, yeah.
Good...morning, Capt--
Oh. I'm just not really
very happy
with that line.
Could I just say,
"Hi, Scottie"?
Great. Great.
Rewrite. Cue.
Hi, Scarrie. Oh. Sorry.
Hi, Stocky.
Oh. I'm sorry again.
Oh, Jim,
I'm just unhappy
with this line.
Hey, can I do it
all sort of kooky, like this?
[OVEREXCITED]
Hi, Scottie!
Great. We'll
shoot it.
Are you sure
that's right?
Oh, it's great.
[GERRY]
Jim.
- Jim.
- [CLAPS]
Jim. J-- Oh, me.
Uh, Jim, I feel
we may be
running into
some problems here
in the area
of height.
Great, where are they?
Where are who?
I dunno, I was
getting confused.
- Jim.
- Great.
I feel here
that Scott may be
too tall in the area
of height,
with reference to Vanilla,
who is too near the ground,
in the area of being
too short at this time.
Great.
Oh, I know. I'm gonna
dig a pit for Scott
and put a box
in Vanilla's trench.
Say. Why don't I take
the boxes off,
and Vanilla get up
out of the trench?
Wouldn't work.
It's even better.
Great. Rewrite.
[VANILLA]
What was that?
Oh, it's easy.
I've worked it out.
Uh, Scott takes
his boxes off,
and you don't stand
in the trench.
I say my lines
out of the trench?
Even better. Great.
But I've never acted
out of a trench.
I might fall over.
It's dangerous.
Oh, well,
could you just try it?
Look, you crumb-bum,
I'm a star.
Star, star, star.
I don't get a million dollars
to act out of a trench.
I played Miss John
the Baptist in a trench.
And I played Miss Napoleon
Bonaparte in a trench.
And I played Miss Alexander
Fleming in a furrow.
So if you want this scene
played out of a trench,
well, you just get yourself
a goddamn stuntman.
Heh.
I played Miss Galileo
in a groove.
And I played
Mrs. Jesus Christ
in a geological
syncline.
So don't tell me
how to act.
I know
I know how to act...
Great.
Uh, great, great, everyone.
Uh, lunch now. Lunch.
It's all in the can.
Good morning's work.
[GERRY]
But you haven't
done a shot.
I'm just keeping
morale up.
Now this afternoon,
we're gonna shoot the scene
where, uh, Scott
gets off the boat
onto the ice floe,
and he sees the lion.
And he fights it
and he kills it,
And the blood goes...
fsss...
In slow motion.
But-- But there aren't
any lions in the Antarctic.
What?
There aren't any lions
in the Antarctic.
You're right. There are
no lions in the Antarctic.
That's ridiculous.
Whoever heard of a lion
in the Antarctic?
Right. Lose the lion.
Got to keep the lion.
It's great.
Lose
the lion.
Great. We're losing the lion.
Rewrite.
Lose the lion, everyone.
That's fantastic.
Say, what's this about,
uh, losing the lion?
Uh, w-well, Kirk,
we-- We thought
perhaps we might, uh,
lose the fight with the lion
a little bit, Kirk angel.
Why?!
Uh, well,
Kirkie doll,
there are no lions
in the Antarctic, baby.
I get to fight
the lion!
It'd be silly.
Listen! I gotta
fight the lion.
That's what that guy
Scott's all about.
I know.
I studied him already.
But why couldn't
you fight a penguin?
Great!
Fight a rotten
little penguin?
It needn't be
a little penguin.
It can be the biggest penguin
you've ever seen.
An electric penguin,
20 feet high,
with long, green tentacles
that sting people.
And you can stab it
in the wings,
and the blood
can go spurting...
pshh...
In slow motion.
The lion is
in the contract.
He fights
the lion.
Even better. Great!
Have a drink.
Hey, lose the penguin.
Stand by to shoot.
Where do they have
lions?
Africa.
That's it. Scott's in Africa.
As many lions as we need.
Great.
Scott's looking for a pole
no one else knows about.
That ties in
with the sand. Right.
Paint the sand
yellow again.
Okay, let's get
this show on the road.
Scott of the Sahara.
[♪♪]
[NARRATOR]
Booming out of the pages
of history
comes a story of three men
and one woman
whose courage
shocked a generation.
From the same team
that brought you...
[READING]
and...
comes the story of three
people
and a woman united by fate
who set out
in search of the fabled
Pole of the Sahara
and found...
themselves.
See Lieutenant Scott's
death-struggle
with a crazed desert lion.
[LION ROARING]
[SPITS]
[GROWLING]
[NARRATOR]
See Ensign Oates'
frank, adult death-struggle
with the spine-chilling,
giant electric penguin.
[METALLIC SQUEAL]
Oh. Ahh!
[SCREAMING, GRUNTING]
[GRUNTING]
Ha!
See Miss Evans pursued
by the man-eating
roll-top writing desk.
[SQUEALING]
[SCREAMS]
[PANTING]
[TEETH CHOMPING]
[GASPS]
[SCREECHES]
And now for something
completely different.
It's...
[♪♪]
[NARRATOR]
Monty Python's
Flying Circus.
[FARTING NOISES]
[MAN]
Hello.
Tired of the sounds
of dancing feet?
Then listen to the sounds
of dancing teeth.
Yes, mothers,
it's time, once again,
for Conrad Poohs
and his dancing teeth.
[♪♪]
[CROWD SHOUTING]
Excuse me,
I'd like to make a correction.
Conrad is, in fact, holding
a letter, not a telegram.
Thank you.
A letter.
[♪♪]
[SUCKING]
Five pence,
please.
Excuse me,
I would like to
buy a fish
license, please.
[SIGHS]
The man's sign
must be wrong.
I have, in the past,
noticed a marked discrepancy
between these
post-office signs
and the activities
carried out beneath.
But soft, let us
see how Dame Fortune
smiles upon
my next postal adventure.
Hello.
I would like to buy
a fish license, please.
A what?
A license for
my pet fish, Eric.
How do you know
my name is Eric?
No, no, no.
My fish's name is Eric.
Eric the fish.
He's an halibut.
He's a what?
He is an halibut.
You've got a pet
halibut?
Yes. I chose him
out of thousands.
Didn't like the others.
They were all too flat.
You're a loony.
I am not a loony.
Why should I be tarred
with the epithet "loony"
merely because
I have a pet halibut?
I've heard tell
that Sir Gerald Nabarro
has a pet prawn
called Simon,
and you wouldn't call
Sir Gerald a loony, would you?
Furthermore, Dawn Palethorpe,
the lady showjumper
had a clam called
Sir Stafford, after the late
chancellor.
Alan Bullock has two pikes,
both called Norman.
And the late, great
Marcel Proust had an haddock.
If you're calling the author
of  À la recherche
du temps perdu a loony,
I shall have to ask you
to step outside.
All right, all right,
all right.
You want a license?
- Yes.
- For a fish?
Yes.
You are a loony.
Look, it's a bleeding pet,
isn't it?
I've got a license
for me pet dog, Eric,
and I've got a license
for me pet cat, Eric.
You don't need
a license for a cat.
You bleeding well do,
and I got one. Ho-ho!
You're not
catching me out there.
There is no such thing
as a bloody cat license.
Yes, there is.
No, there isn't.
Is.
Isn't.
- Is.
- Isn't.
Is.
Isn't.
Is!
What's that, then?
That is a dog license with
the word "dog" crossed out
and the word "cat"
written in in crayon.
Well, the man didn't
have the proper form.
What man?
The man from
the cat-detector van.
Loony-detector van,
you mean.
Look, it's people like you
what causes unrest.
All right,
what cat-detector van?
The cat-detector van
from the Ministry of Housinge.
Housinge?
Yes, it was spelt that way
on the van.
I'm very observant.
I've never seen so many
aerials in me life.
The man told me their
equipment
could pinpoint a purr
at 400 yards.
And Eric,
being such a happy cat,
was a piece of cake.
How much did this cost?
Sixty quid. And 8 guineas
for the fruit bat.
What fruit bat?
Eric the fruit bat.
Are all your pets called Eric?
There's nothing so odd
about that.
Kemal Ataturk had an entire
menagerie all called Abdul.
No, he didn't.
Did, he did, he did,
he did and did.
There you are:
Kemal Ataturk: The Man
by E.W. Swanton
with a foreword
by Paul Anka.
Page 91, please.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Oh, I owe you an apology, sir.
Spoken like a gentleman.
Now, are you gonna give me
this fish license?
I promise you
there is no such thing.
You don't need one.
Then I would like a statement
to that effect
signed by the Lord Mayor.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
You're in luck.
[NARRATOR]
And now, there is the mayor.
Surely the third-tallest mayor
in Derby's history.
And there are the aldermen,
magnificently resplendent
in their aldermanic hose.
And just look at the power
in those thighs.
The New Zealanders are gonna
find it pretty tough going
in the set pieces
in the second half.
So Dawn Palethorpe with one
clear round on Sir Gerald.
And now the mayor has reached
the great customer,
Mr. Eric Praline.
And now,
the mayoral human being
takes the mayoral pen
in his mayoral hand.
And watched by
the Lady Mayoress,
who, of course,
scored that magnificent try
in the first half,
signs the fishy exemption.
And the great customer,
Mr. Eric Praline,
who is understandably awed
by the magnificence
and even the absurdity
of this great occasion here
at Cardiff Arms Park,
has finally gone spare.
And there is
the going-sparal look
on the front of his head.
And now, the aldermen
are finishing their oranges
and leaving the post office
for the start
of the second half.
And here come
the Derby Council XV
following the All Blacks
out onto the pitch.
Uh, there, at the--
In the center of the pitch,
you can see Dawn Palethorpe
on Sir Gerald--
One of the fastest wingers
we must have seen this season.
On the left,
the Lord Mayor's been running
such wonderful possession for
Derby Council in the
lines-out.
And it's the, uh,
All Blacks to kick off.
Uh, Wilson to kick off.
Oh, and I can see there,
the chairman of the Byways
and Highways Committee,
who's obviously recovered
from that very nasty blow
he got in the first half.
And, uh, Wilson kicks off.
And it's-- Town clerk's taken
the ball beautifully there.
The All Blacks
are up on it very fast,
and-- And the whistle
has gone.
I'm not sure
what happened there,
I couldn't see,
but there's a scrumdown.
I think it's
an All Blacks' ball.
They were up on them
very fast.
Obviously, they're gonna try
very hard in this half
to wipe out
this five-point deficit.
Derby Council,
eight points and three up.
And, uh, Derby Council have
got the ball against the head.
There is the borough surveyor,
the scrum half is up.
The chairman of the Highway
and Byway Committee's
kicked for touch.
The line-out, and it's--
And the mayor-- The mayor
has got the ball again.
To the borough surveyor.
He's left-out
the medical officer of health.
Straight along the line,
and the Lady Mayoress
is gonna go through.
Number two has missed her.
Only the fullback to beat.
And she has scored.
The Lady Mayoress has scored.
It's 11 points to 3.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Cliff, this must have been
a very disappointing result
for the All Blacks.
Well, they've had very bad
luck on their tour so far.
In fact, they missed
four very easy kicks
against the Exeter
Amateur Operatic Society,
which must have
cost them the match.
And then, of course, there was
that crippling defeat
at the hands of the Derry &amp;
Toms Soft Toy Department.
So I don't think they can
be fancying their chances
against the London Pooves
on Saturday.
And what about
China?
Well, whether Mao Zedong
is alive or not,
Lin Biao has a stranglehold
on the Central Committee
which Lin Shao-Chi
can't break.
So it remains to be seen
whether Zhou Enlai can
really get his finger out
and get going
in the second half.
Well, thank you,
Cliff.
Tonight's other
outstanding match
was the semifinal between
the Bournemouth Gynecologists
and the Watford Long John
Silver Impersonators.
We bring you edited highlights
of the match.
[PIRATES SHOUTING]
Well, that's it for tonight,
ladies and gentlemen.
But remember, If you've
enjoyed watching this show
just half as much
as we've enjoyed doing it,
then we've enjoyed it
twice as much as you.
Ha-ha-ha.
[♪♪]