[♪♪♪]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
I, Erik--
[PLAYING BOLD MELODY]
And now--
It's...
[THEME MUSIC]
MAN:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
Michael Norman Randall,
you have been found guilty
of the murder
of Arthur Reginald Webster,
Charles Patrick Trumpington,
Marcel Agnes Bernstein,
Lewis Anona Rudd,
John Malcolm Kerr,
Nigel Sinclair Robinson,
Norman Arthur Potter,
Felicity Jayne Stone,
Jean-Paul Reynard,
Rachel Shirley Donaldson,
Stephen Jay Greenblatt,
Karl-Heinz Muller,
Belinda Anne Ventham,
Juan-Carlos Fernandez,
Thor Olaf Stensgaard,
Lord Kimberley of Pretoria,
Lady Kimberley of Pretoria,
The Right Honorable
Nigel Warmsly Kimberley,
Robert Henry Noonan
and Felix James Bennett
on or about the morning
of the 19th of December, 1972.
Have you anything
to say before I pass sentence?
Yes, sir. I'm very sorry.
Very sorry?
Yes, sir. It was a very, very
bad thing to have done,
and I'm really
very ashamed of myself.
I can only say
it won't happen again.
To have murdered so many
people in such a short
space of time
is really awful, and
I really am very, very,
very sorry that I did it.
And also, that I've taken up
so much of the court's
valuable time
listening to the
sordid details
of these senseless killings
of mine.
I'd particularly like to say
a very personal
and sincere sorry to you,
my lord,
for my appalling behavior
throughout this trial.
I'd also like to say sorry too
for the police
for putting them
to so much trouble.
For the literally
hours of work
they've had to put in
collecting evidence
and identifying corpses
and so forth.
You know, I think sometimes we
ought to realize the difficult
and often dangerous work
involved
in tracking down
violent criminals like myself,
and I'd just like them
to know that their fine work
is at least appreciated by me.
Oh, no, no, we were only
doing our job.
No, no, really.
It's very good of you
to say that, but I know
what you've been through.
Oh, no, no,
we've had worse.
It was plain sailing,
apart from the arrest.
I know and I'm grateful.
I'd like to apologize too
to the prosecuting counsel
for dragging him in here
morning after morning
in such lovely weather.
Well, I would've had
to come in anyway.
Oh, good.
But, uh, what a presentation
of a case.
-Oh, thank you.
-Oh, no.
It's a privilege to watch you
in action.
I never had a chance.
Oh, but yes, you did.
Oh, not after that summing up.
Great.
And now I must come
to the jury.
What can I say?
I've dragged you in here,
day after day,
keeping you away
from your homes,
your jobs, your loved ones,
just to hear the private
details of my petty
atrocities.
Uh, no, no. It was, uh,
very interesting.
You could've had
a much nicer case.
Oh, no, no, no.
Murder's much more fun.
Yes, and so many of them.
-Excellent.
-We've had a terrific time.
[ALL APPLAUD]
I'm sorry, I'm very moved.
So, my lord, it only remains
for you to pass
the most savage sentence on me
that the law can provide.
Uh, well, uh,
not necessarily--
No, my lord, the full penalty
of the law is
hardly sufficient.
I insist I must
be made an example of.
Well, yes and no.
I mean, society at large--
Oh, no, my lord.
Not with mass murder.
Oh, but in this case,
don't you think?
ALL:
Yes, yes!
Oh, come on, my lord,
you've gotta give me life.
ALL:
No, no, no.
Well, ten years at least.
Come on.
Ten years?
ALL:
Shame, shame.
-Well, five then. Be fair.
-JUDGE: No, no, no.
I'm giving you three months.
Oh, no,
that's so embarrassing,
I won't hear of it.
Give me six, please.
Well, all right. Six months.
-Thank you, my lord.
-But suspended.
-Oh, no.
-ALL: Hooray!
Three cheers for the
defendant. Hip. Hip.
ALL:
Hooray!
-Hip, hip.
-ALL: Hooray!
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ Which nobody can deny ♪
It's no good, Spider,
you can't escape that easily.
We're coming in after you.
Whoop!
[GRUNTS]
DETECTIVE:
This way, Davis.
Hmm, we'd best separate.
I'm going down there.
You check the right ventricle.
Whoop!
Any sign of him, Davis?
There's nothing here.
All right,
we'll check the spleen.
-Wait!
-[BRISK FOOTSTEPS]
Oh, my God,
he's doubled back on us.
Quick, we've got to catch him
before he reaches the neck.
Oh, no, too late, Davis.
He's got out.
[CHOMPING]
DAVIS:
Oh, he's eating!
DETECTIVE:
Run for it!
BOTH:
Ooh! Ah! Oh! Ooh!
Oh, my God!
Remember not to struggle.
Oh!
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
This little-known
Icelandic saga,
written by an unknown hand
in the late 13th century,
has remained undiscovered
until today.
Now it comes to your screens
for the first time.
Fresh from the leaves
of Iceland's history.
The terrible Njorl's Saga.
It's not that terrible.
No, I meant terribly violent.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
NARRATOR:
Erik Njorl, son of Frothgar,
leaves his home
to seek Hangar the Elder
at the house of
Thorvald Nlodvisson.
The son of Gudleif,
half-brother of Thorgier,
the priest of Ljosa Water,
who took to wife Thurunn,
the mother of
Thorkel Braggart,
the slayer
of Gudmund the Powerful,
who knew Howal,
son of Geernon,
son of Erik from Valdalesc,
son of Arval Gristlebeard,
son of Harken
who killed Bjortguaard
in Sochnadale
in Norway over Cudreed,
daughter of Thorkel Long,
the son of Kettle-Trout,
the half son
of Harviyoun Half-troll,
father of Ingbare the Brave,
who, with Isenbert
of Gottenberg,
the daughter
of Hangbard the Fierce...
VOICE-OVER:
We apologize for an error
in the saga.
Evidently, Thorgier,
the priest of Ljosa Water,
who took to wife Thurunn,
the mother of
Thorkel Braggart,
the slayer
of Gudmund the powerful,
who knew Howal,
son of Geernon,
son of Erik from Vadalesc--
ANNOUNCER #3:
I'm afraid we're having
trouble
getting this very exciting
Icelandic saga started.
If any of you at home
have any ideas
about how to get this exciting
saga started again,
here's the address
to write to.
Help the Exciting Icelandic
Saga.
18-B MacNorton Buildings, Oban.
Hello. Um, well, I was
the third voice you heard
just now.
Uh, I'm sorry about
that terrible mess.
It wasn't all that terrible.
No, no, I meant terrible
in the sense of unfortunate.
-Oh.
-Anyway, um, our plea for
assistance has been answered
by the North Malden Icelandic
Saga Society
who've given us some
very useful information
about the saga.
And so, uh, we carry on now
with Njorl's Saga
with our thanks going,
uh, once again
to the North Malden
Icelandic Saga Society.
NARRATOR:
Erik Njorl, son of Frothgar,
rode off into the desolate
plain.
Day and night he rode,
looking neither to right
nor left.
Stopping neither for food
nor rest.
Twelve days and nights
he rode.
Through rain and storm.
Through wind and snow,
beyond the enchanted
waterfall,
through the elfin glades
until he reached his goal.
He had found the rich
and pleasant land
beyond the mountains.
The land where golden streams
sang their way
through fresh green meadows.
Where there were halls
and palaces,
an excellent swimming pool
and one of the most attractive
bonus-incentive schemes
for industrial development
in the city.
Only 15 miles from excellent
Thames-side
docking facilities,
and within easy reach
of the proposed M25.
Here it was that Erik Njorl,
son of Frothgar,
met the mayor.
Mr. Arthur Huddinut,
a local solicitor.
Uh, welcome to North Malden.
Yes, everyone is welcome
to North Malden,
but none more so than
the businessmen and investors
who shape our society
of the future.
Here at North Malden--
VOICE-OVER:
We apologize to viewers
of Njorl's Saga
who may be confused
by some of the references
to North Malden.
And after a frank exchange
of views,
we have agreed to carry on
showing this version
supplied to us by the North
Malden Icelandic Saga Society
on the undertaking that future
scenes will adhere
more closely
to the spirit
of 12th-century Iceland.
NARRATOR:
With moist eyes,
Erik leaves this happy land
to return to the harsh
uneconomic realities
of life in the land
of Ljosa Water.
On his way, Erik rested a
while in the land of
Bjornsstrand,
the land of dark forces
where Gildor was king.
These were the dukes
of the land of Bjornsstrand.
Proud warriors,
who bore on their chests
the letters
of their dread name.
[PHONE RINGS]
MILLS:
Hello? Is that the North
Malden Icelandic Society?
-NARRATOR: Yes, that's right.
-MILLS: It's about this saga.
NARRATOR:
Oh, yes, the Icelandic saga.
Good, isn't it?
MILLS:
Well, um, well,
I don't know.
But you promised us you would
stick to the spirit
-of the original text.
-NARRATOR: Yes, that's right.
MILLS:
These things
that are happening
just don't quite ring true.
NARRATOR:
It's a new interpretation.
MILLS:
We didn't want a new--
We wanted the proper thing.
Look what's happening now.
NARRATOR:
Banners were an
important part
of Icelandic lore, Mr. Mills.
MILLS:
I'm sorry,
I can't accept that.
It's gone too far.
I'm very sorry,
but we'll have to terminate
the agreement.
You're just trying to cash in
on the BBC's exciting
Icelandic saga.
NARRATOR:
That's business, Mr. Mills.
MILLS:
That may be, but it's not
the way the BBC works.
NARRATOR:
I'm sorry you feel that way,
but, uh, you know, if you ever
want to come to Malden--
[HANGS UP PHONE]
[♪♪♪]
Eight o'clock
is a peak viewing hour,
so naturally we tend
to stick to our comedy output.
Unless of course there's
sport. Because we know
this is popular,
and popularity
is what television is about.
Quite frankly, I'm sick
and tired of people
accusing us
of being ratings conscious.
-Ratings conscious?
-Transmitting bland garbage,
my lord.
-Oh, thank you.
-Now, I'm really cheesed off.
I mean, it's not your highbrow
bleeding plays
-that pull in the viewers.
-Thank you.
Joe Public doesn't want to
watch three hours
of documentaries.
-Thank you.
-He wants to sit down and
he wants to be entertained.
He doesn't want a load of--
No, look, really, I'm fed up
with this, I really am!
-Case dismissed.
-[BANGS GAVEL]
Case dismissed, my lord?
Oh, all right, five years.
Thank you, my lord.
Call the next case, please.
Call Erik Njorl,
son of Frothgar,
brother of Hangnor,
-son of--
-Call Erik Njorl,
son of Frothgar,
brother of Hangnor...
WOMAN:
Call Erik Njorl...
[ALL OVERLAPPING EACH OTHER]
MAN:
...the mother
of Thorkel Braggart,
the slayer of Gudmund,
son of--
-[THUMP]
-MAN: Ooh!
You are Erik Njorl,
son of Frothgar--
Get on with it.
Will you raise
your right hand?
He obviously can't raise
his right hand,
you silly usher person.
Can you raise your right leg,
Mr. Njorl?
Can you raise any part
of your body, Mr. Njorl?
I see.
Well, we'll skip that.
If you'll just take the book
in your right hand, Mr. Njorl,
without raising
any part of your body.
Oh.
What is it now,
you persistently silly usher?
He can't hold the Bible,
my lord.
Oh, screw the Bible! Let's get
on with this bleeding trial.
I've got a Gay Lib meeting
at 6:00.
Superintendent Lufthansa,
will you please
read the charge?
Is a charge strictly
necessary, my lord?
The press is here.
Oh! Oh, sorry.
Um, right, here we go.
You are hereby charged:
one, that you did,
on or about 11/26
conspire to publicize
a London borough
in the course of a BBC saga.
Two, that you were willfully
and persistently a foreigner.
Three, that you conspired
to do things
not normally considered
illegal.
Four, that you were caught
in possession
of an offensive weapon
viz., the big brown table
down at the police station.
The big brown table
down at the police station?
It's the best we could find,
my lord.
And five-- All together, now.
ALL:
Assaulting a police officer.
SUPER:
Thank you.
Call Police Constable Pan-Am.
Oh! Ow!
In-- Into the witness box,
constable.
There will be plenty of time
for that later on.
Now, you are
Police Constable Pan-Am?
No, I deny that
to the last breath in my body.
Oh, sorry, yes.
Police constable,
do you recognize
the defendant?
No. Never seen him before
in me life.
Oh, yes, yes, he's the one!
He done it.
I'd recognize him anywhere.
Sorry, super.
Constable, uh, will you
please tell the court
in your own words
what happened?
Oh, yes!
I was proceeding in a
northerly direction up
Alitalia Street
when I saw the deceased
standing at an upstairs window
baring her bosom
at the general public.
She then took off her--
Wait a tick. Wrong story.
Oh, yes.
There were three nuns
in a railway compartment
and the ticket in--
No? Anyway,
I clearly saw the deceased--
-Defendant.
-Defendant. Sorry.
Sorry, super.
I clearly saw the defendant
doing whatever
he's accused of, uh,
red-handed.
When kicked a caution,
he said:
"It's a fair.
Cop, I done it all.
Right no. Doubt about. That."
Then, bound as he was
to the chair,
he assaulted myself
and three other constables
while bouncing around
the cell.
The end.
[ALL APPLAUD]
Thank you. Thank you. And for
my next piece of evidence--
Uh, I think we'd better
leave it there.
-All right.
-COUNSEL: Excellent evidence.
Thank you very much.
Now, Mr. Njorl, will you tell
the court, please,
uh, where were you
on the night of 11/26?
Move any part of your body
if you were north of a line
from the Humber to the Mersey.
Is he in there,
do you think?
Hello? Hello?
Defendant, are you there?
Coo-ee! Defendant?
Uh, I think you'd better go
and have a look, Maurice.
-Don't call me Maurice in court.
-I'm sorry.
Are you in there?
Mr. Njorl?
This way, Davis.
He's not getting away
this time.
We'll try and trap him
in the left lung.
If we surround the left lung
then we can get in the kidney
and get in the left, okay?
[SNICKERS]
Once again,
I've proved too clever for--
ANNOUNCER:
And now the Stock Market
Report
by Exchange Telegraph.
Trading was crisp
at the start of the day
with some brisk business
on the floor.
Rubber hardened
and string remained confident.
Little bits of tin
consolidated,
although biscuits sank
after an early gain
and stools remained anonymous.
Armpits rallied well
after a poor start.
Nipples rose dramatically
during the morning,
but had declined
by mid-afternoon,
while teeth clenched
and buttocks remained firm.
Small, dark, furry things
increased severely
on the floor
whilst rude jellies wobbled
up and down
and bounced against
rising thighs,
which had spread to all parts
of the country
by mid-afternoon.
After lunch, naughty things
dipped sharply,
forcing giblets upwards
with the nicky nacky noo.
Ting tang tong
rankled dithely,
little tipples pooped,
and poppy things went pong.
Gibble gabble gobble went
the rickety rackety
roo as the--
Mm, that'll teach you
to be normal.
Oh!
[FOOTSTEPS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[HUMS]
Hmm?
Oh!
Hm. Mm.
Oh, hello, Mrs. Premise.
Hello, Mrs. Conclusion.
-Busy day?
-Busy?
I just spent four hours
burying the cat.
Four hours to bury a cat?
Yes. It wouldn't keep still.
Wiggling around,
howling its head off.
Oh, it wasn't dead,
then?
Well, no, no,
but it's not at all
a well cat.
So, uh, as we were going away
for a fortnight's holiday
I thought I better bury it
just to be on the safe side.
Quite right.
You don't want
to come back from Sorrento
to a dead cat.
-Nope.
-It'd be so anticlimactic.
Yes, kill it now,
that's what I say.
-Yes.
-We're going to have to have
our budgie put down.
Really? Is it very old?
No. We just don't like it.
We're going to take it
to the vet tomorrow.
Oh. Tell me, how do they
put budgies down, then?
Well, it's funny
you should ask that
because I've just been reading
a great big book
about how to put
your budgie down.
And apparently, you can either
hit them with a book
or you can shoot them
just there,
just above the beak.
-Just there?
-Yes.
-Well, well, well.
-Mm.
Of course, Mrs. Essence
flushed hers down the loo.
Oh! No, you shouldn't do that.
No, that's dangerous.
Yes, they breed in the sewers.
Yes, eventually
you get evil-smelling flocks
of huge soiled budgies flying
out of people's lavatories,
infringing their personal
freedom.
Good morning, Mrs. Cutout.
Morning, Mrs. Cutout.
-It's a funny thing, freedom.
-Yes.
I mean, how can any of us
be really free
when we still have
personal possessions?
You can't. You can't. How can
I go off and join FRELIMO
when I've got nine more
installments to pay
on the fridge?
-No, you can't.
-No.
Well, this, of course,
is the whole crux
of Jean-Paul Sartre's
Roads to Freedom.
No, it bloody isn't.
The nub of that is, his
characters stand for all of us
in their desire
to avoid action.
Mind you,
the man at the
off-license says
it's an everyday story
of French country folk.
-What does he know?
-Nothing.
Sixty new pence for a bottle
of Maltese claret.
-Mm.
-Ha! Well, I personally think--
Oh, beg your pardon.
I personally think
that Jean-Paul's masterwork
is an allegory
of man's search
for commitment.
-No, it isn't.
-Yes, it is.
-Isn't. No, it isn't!
-'Tis.
All right.
We'll soon settle this.
We'll ask him.
-Do you know him?
-Yes.
We met on holiday
last year.
-In Ibiza?
-Yes.
He was staying there
with his wife
and Mr. and Mr. Genet.
Oh, I did get on well
with Madame S.
We were like that.
What was Jean-Paul like?
Well, you know,
a bit moody.
-Yes.
-Yes, he didn't join
in the fun much.
-No.
-Just sat there, thinking.
Still, Mr. Rotter caught him
a few times
with a whoopee cushion.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
-[IMITATES FARTING]
-[BOTH LAUGH]
-Oh, we did laugh.
-Oh, dear.
Uh, well, we'll give him
a tinkle, then.
Yes, all right.
She said they were
in the book.
Hmm-- Oh! Where's the Paris
telephone directory?
MRS. INFERENCE:
It's on the dryer.
Oh. No, no, that's Budapest.
Oh, here we are.
Sartre, Sartre...
It's 621036.
Oh, thank you, Mrs. Varley.
Hello. Uh, Paris 621036,
please, and make it snappy,
buster.
[BOTH SING IN FRENCH]
Hello? Hello, Mrs. Sartre.
It's Beulagh Premise here.
Oh, pardon.
C'est Beulagh Premise ici.
Oui! Oui! Dans Ibiza.
Oui.
Uh, we met--
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Hotel Mirimar.
Oui! A la barbecue.
C'est vrai. Madame S.,
est-ce que Jean-Paul
est chez vous ?
Oh, merde.
Well...
Uh, when will he be free?
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[CACKLES]
Oh!
She says he's spent
the last 60 years
trying to work that one out.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Well, he's out distributing
pamphlets to the masses,
but he'll be in at six.
Oh, well, I'll ring BEA then.
Oh, look, Paris!
MRS. CONCLUSION:
That's not Paris.
Jean-Paul wouldn't live here.
It's a right old dump.
But this is where
they were wrong.
For this was no old dump,
but a town with a future.
An urban El Dorado
where the businessmen of today
can enjoy the facilities
of tomorrow
in the comfort of yesterday.
Provided by a go-getting,
go-ahead council
who know just how loud
money can talk.
Interest rates--
Well, it's none of my
business,
but we had the same trouble
with our Icelandic saga.
Now, these people
are terribly keen,
but they do rather tend
to take over.
Um, I think I'd stick
to Caribbean Islands
if I were you.
Fine.
And now, uh, back to the saga.
[♪♪♪]
Here. This is not Paris.
This is Iceland.
Oh.
Well, Paris must
be over there, then.
Oh.
[BOTH HUM]
[♪♪♪]
Oh, here we are,
number 25.
Oh, yes.
"Flat 1, Yves Montand,
Flat 3, Jacques Cousteau.
Flat 4, Jean Genet
and friend."
BOTH:
Ooh! Ah! Yes.
MRS. CONCLUSION:
"Flat 5, Maurice Leroux"?
-Who's he?
-Never heard of him.
"Flat 6, Marcel Marceau,
Walking Against the Wind Ltd.
Flat 7, Indira Gandhi"?
She gets about a bit,
doesn't she?
BOTH:
Yes.
"Flat 8, Jean-Paul
and Betty-Muriel Sartre."
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
BETTY [OVER INTERCOM]
Oui?
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Okay.
Oui, merci.
[MAN SINGS IN FRENCH
OVER RADIO]
[RASPY COUGH]
[KNOCK]
Oh, rubbish.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Bonjour.
Parlez-vous anglais ?
Oh, yes. Good day.
Hello, love.
Hello, how are you?
Oh, this is Mrs. Conclusion
from number 46.
-Oh, nice to meet you, dear.
-Hello.
How's the old man, then?
Oh, don't ask. He's in one
of his bleeding moods.
"The bourgeoisie this
is the bourgeoisie that."
He's like a little child
sometimes.
[COUGHS]
I was only telling
the Rainiers the other day--
Of course, he's always rude
to them,
only classy friends we got.
I was saying,
"Solidarity with the masses."
I said, "Pie in the sky!"
[LAUGHS]
Oh, you're not a Marxist,
are you, Mrs. Conclusion?
No, I'm a Revisionist.
Oh, good.
I mean, look at this place.
I'm at my wits' end.
Revolutionary leaflets
everywhere.
One of these days
I'll revolutionary
leaflets him.
[ALL LAUGH]
If it wasn't for the goat,
you couldn't get in here
for propaganda.
Oh, very well. Can we, uh,
pop in and have a word
with him?
-Yes, come along.
-Thank you.
But be careful.
He's had a few.
Mind you, he's good as gold
in the morning,
I've got to hand it to him.
But come lunchtime,
it's a bottle of
vin ordinaire.
Six glasses
and he's ready to agitate.
Uh, coo-ee!
Jean-Paul?
Uh, it's only us.
Oh, pardon. C'est mêême nous.
-JEAN-PAUL: Oui.
-Jean-Paul,
your famous trilogy
Rues àà Liberté.
Is it an allegory
of man's search
for commitment?
-JEAN-PAUL: Oui.
-Told you so.
Oh, coitus.
[♪♪♪]
Today, we look
at a vanishing race.
A problem people who are fast
disappearing
off the face of the earth.
A race who, one might say,
are losing a winning battle.
They live in a sunshine
paradise, a Caribbean dream,
where only reality is missing.
For this is Whicker Island.
An island inhabited entirely
by ex-international
interviewers
in pursuit
of the impossible dream.
The whole problem
of Whicker Island
is here in a nutshell.
There are just too many
whickers.
The lightweight suits.
The old-school tie.
The practiced voice
of the seasoned campaigner...
Cannot hide
the basic tragedy here.
There just aren't enough
rich people left to interview.
You can't teach an old dog
new tricks,
and so you find them...
Sitting beside
elegant swimming pools...
Sipping martinis...
And waiting
for the inevitable interview.
I talked to the island's
only white man, Father Pierre.
Father Pierre,
why did you stay on
in this colonial Campari-land
where the clink of glasses
mingles
with the murmur
of a million mosquitoes,
where waterfalls
of whisky wash away
the worries of
a world-weary whicker?
Where gin-and-tonics jingle
in a gyroscopic jubilee
of something
beginning with J?
Father Pierre,
why did you stay on here?
Well, mainly
for the interviews.
Well, there you have it.
A crumbling...
Empire in the sun-drenched...
Caribbean, where the clichés
sparkle on the waters...
Like the music of repeat fees.
And so...
From Whicker Island...
-It's...
-Fare...
-Well and...
-Bon...
-Voy...
-Age.
[♪♪♪]