ANNOUNCER:
The Kon-Tiki!
Ra 1!
Ra 2!
And now...
Mr. and Mrs. Brian Norris'
Ford Popular!
NARRATOR:
Who, a year ago, had heard
of Mr. and Mrs. Brian Norris
of 37 Gledhill Gardens,
Parsons Green?
And yet their epic journey
in EBW 343
has set them alongside
Thor Heyerdahl
and Sir Edmund Hillary.
Starting only with a theory,
Mr. Norris set out to prove
that the inhabitants
of Hounslow
could have been descendants
of the people of Surbiton,
who had made
the great trek north.
No newcomer to this field,
Mr. Norris'
A Short History of Motor
Traffic Between Purley
and Esher
had become a bestselling
minor classic
in the car-swapping belt.
But why would the people
of Surbiton go to Hounslow?
Mr. Norris had noticed
three things.
Firstly, the similarity
of houses.
Secondly, the similarity
of costume
between Hounslow and Surbiton.
And thirdly,
the similarity of speech.
Are you still running
the GDBDMDB?
Uh, yes, but I've had
the excess nipples woppled
to remove tamping.
Jolly good.
Were these just coincidences,
or were they,
as Mr. Norris believed,
part of an identical
cultural background?
One further discovery
convinced him:
the lawn mower.
Surely, such a sophisticated
household gadget
could not have been
generated independently
in two separate areas.
Mr. Norris was convinced.
MR. NORRIS:
I'm convinced.
NARRATOR:
But how to prove it?
MR. NORRIS:
NARRATOR:
There was only one way
to see
if the journey between
Surbiton and Hounslow
was possible.
And that was
to try and make it.
Months of preparation followed
while Mr. Norris
continued his research
in the Putney Public Library
and Mrs. Norris
made sandwiches.
Finally, by April,
they were ready.
[♪♪♪]
On the 23rd,
Mr. and Mrs. Norris set out
from Abide-A-Wee
to motor the 15 miles
to Surbiton
watched by a crowd
of local well-wishers.
That evening,
they dined at Tooting.
This would be the last
they'd see of civilization.
Mr. Norris' diary for the 23rd
reveals the extraordinary
calmness
and deep inner peacefulness
of his mind.
MR. NORRIS:
Seven-thirty, fed cat.
Eight o'clock, breakfast.
Eight-thirty, yes,
successfully.
Nine o'clock,
set out on historic journey.
NARRATOR:
On the morning of the 24th,
early, to avoid the traffic,
Mr. Norris' historic
expedition set out
from Surbiton.
Destination: Hounslow.
Early on, they began
to perceive
encouraging signs.
The writing on the sign
was almost exactly the same
as the writing in the AA book.
They were on the right route.
During the long hours
of the voyage
Mr. Norris' wife, Betty,
kept a complete
photographic record
and made sandwiches.
This is some
of the unique footage
which Mrs. Norris got back
from the chemist's.
Mile succeeded mile
and the terrific strain
was beginning to tell,
when suddenly...
by an amazing stroke of luck
Mr. Norris had come across
the Kingston bypass.
This was something
to tell the roundtable.
At this stage,
Mr. Norris was faced
with two major
divergent theories
concerning his
Surbiton ancestors.
Did they take
the Kingston bypass,
turning left at Barnes
or did they strike west
up the A308
via Norbiton to Hampton Wick?
Both these theories ran up
against one big obstacle:
The Thames,
lying like a silver turd
between Richmond
and Isleworth.
This was a major setback.
How could they possibly
cross the river?
Several hours of thought
produced nothing.
There was only one
flask of coffee left
when suddenly, Mr. Norris
spotted something.
Could this have been
the method used?
Hardly daring to believe,
Mr. Norris led his expedition
onto the 3:47.
Forty minutes later,
via Clapham, Fulham,
Chiswick and Brentford,
they approached their goal:
Hounslow.
Was this, then,
the final proof?
Something aroused
the accountant's instinct
buried deep
in Mr. Norris' makeup.
The journey was possible,
and yet...
"Wrong-way" Norris
had accidentally stumbled
on a piece
of anthropological history.
It was the inhabitants
of Hounslow
who had made
the great trek south
to the sunnier pastures
of Surbiton
and not vice versa,
as he had originally surmised.
This was the secret
of Surbiton.
Happy and contented,
Mr. Norris returned
to the calmer waters
of chartered accountancy
for, in his way,
"Wrong-way" Norris was right.
[♪♪♪]
-And now--
-It's...
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
Knock, enter and approach.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Right. It's come to my notice
that certain boys have been
running a unit-trust-linked
assurance scheme
with fringe benefits
and full cash-in
endowment facilities.
Apparently, small investors
were attracted
by the wide-ranging portfolio
and that in the first week,
the limited offer
was oversubscribed
eight times.
It was Tidwell's idea, sir.
Shut up, I haven't finished.
Oh, by the way,
congratulations on winning
the Italian Grand Prix
at Monza.
-Thank you, sir.
-Shut up.
Now, then, this sort
of extracurricular
capitalist expansion
has got to stop.
I made it quite clear,
when Potter tried
to go public last term
that these massive
stock-exchange deals
must not happen
in Big School.
-Is that clear, Balderston?
-Yes, sir.
Oh, and, Balderston,
next time you do a Panorama
report on the black ghettos
you must get an exeat form
from Mr. Dibley.
-Sorry, sir.
-Shut up.
And stop slouching.
Now, the reason I called you
in here today
is that my wife is having
a little trouble
with her, um...
with her waterworks.
And I think she needs
a bit of attention.
Now, which one of you
is the surgeon?
Come on, I know one of you is.
Now, which one is it?
Ah. Tidwell. Good.
I want you to come along
and have a look at the wife.
Sir, why don't you ask
Stebbins? He's a gynecologist.
Oh, you rotten
stinker, Tidwell.
Tch!
Is this true, Stebbins?
-Are you a gynecologist?
-Yes, sir.
Right, just the man.
How much you charge?
Thirty guineas, sir.
Excellent. Right.
I want you to go along,
see the wife.
Give her a full examination.
Let me know the results
by the end of break.
And don't pick your nose.
[♪♪♪]
-Hello.
Well, last week we showed you
how to become a gynecologist.
And this week
on How To Do It
we're going to show you
how to play the flute,
how to split an atom,
how to construct
a box-girder bridge,
how to irrigate
the Sahara desert
and make vast new areas
of land cultivatable.
But first, here's Jackie
to tell you all
how to rid the world
of all known diseases.
Hello, Alan.
Hello, Jackie.
Well, first of all,
become a doctor
and discover a marvelous cure
for something.
When the medical profession
starts to take notice of you
you can tell them what to do,
make sure they get
everything right
so there'll never be
any diseases ever again.
Thanks, Jackie.
Great idea.
And now,
how to play the flute.
Well, here we are.
You blow there and you move
your fingers up and down here.
Great. Great. Great, Alan.
Well, next week
we'll be showing you
how black and white people
can live together
in peace and harmony.
And Alan will be over in
Moscow
showing us how to reconcile
the Russians and the Chinese.
So, until next week, cheerio.
-Bye.
Bye-bye.
[♪♪♪]
[CHATTING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, yes, he's such a clever
little boy.
Just like his father.
Oh, do you think so,
Mrs. Nigger-Baiter?
Oh, yes. Spitting image.
-Mmm.
Good afternoon, Mother.
Afternoon, Mrs. Nigger-Baiter.
Oh, he's walking already.
Yes, he's such
a clever little boy.
Aren't you, hoochie-coo?
-Hello, hoochie-coo.
-Look at him laughing, eh?
-Yeah.
He's a chirpy little fellow,
isn't he?
Isn't he a chirpy
little fellow, eh?
Does he talk?
Does he talk, eh?
Of course I can talk.
I'm Minister
for Overseas Development.
Oooh!
Clever little boy.
He's a clever little boy.
Do you like
your rattle, eh?
Do you like your rattle?
Look at his little eyes
following it, eh?
Look at his iggy-tiggy-biggy
little eyeballs.
Oh, he's got
a tubby tum-tum.
Oh, he's got a tubby
tum-tum.
Mother, could I have
a quick cup of tea, please?
I have an important statement
on Rhodesia to make
in the Commons at six.
-[CRASH]
-[MOAN]
Mrs. Nigger-Baiter's
exploded.
Good thing too.
She was my best friend.
Oh, Mother, don't be
so sentimental.
Things explode every day.
Yes, I suppose so.
Anyway, I didn't really
like her that much.
-[DOORBELL RINGS]
-Ooh.
Hello, I'm your new vicar.
Can I interest you
in any encyclopedias?
No, thank you.
We're not church people,
thank you.
How about brushes?
Nylon or bristle?
Strong-tufted,
attractive colors.
No, really,
thank you, vicar.
Oh, dear. Turkey?
Cup Final tickets?
No. No, really.
We're just not religious.
Thank you.
-Oh, well. Bye-bye.
-Bye-bye, vicar.
If you do want anything,
jewellery,
Ascot water heaters...
Thank you, vicar.
It's funny, isn't it, how--
How your best friend
can just blow up like that.
I mean, you wouldn't think
it was medically possible,
would you?
This is where Mrs. Shazam
was so wrong.
Exploding is a perfectly
normal medical phenomenon.
In many fields
of medicine nowadays,
a dose of dynamite
can do a world of good.
For instance, athlete's foot,
an irritating condition,
can be cured
-by applying a small charge
of TNT between each toe.
-[DOORBELL RINGS]
Excuse me.
Hello, I'm your new vicar.
Can I interest you in any of
these watches, pens or biros?
No, I'm not religious,
I'm afraid.
Oh, souvenirs, badges,
little noddy dog
for the back of the car?
-No, thank you, vicar.
Good morning.
-Morning.
Now, many of
the medical profession
are skeptical
about my work.
They point to my record
of treatment
of athlete's foot sufferers:
Eighty-four dead,
65 severely wounded
and 12 missing,
believed cured.
But then, people laughed
at Bob Hope.
They laughed at my wife
when she wrapped herself up
in greaseproof paper
and hopped into
the Social Security office.
But that doesn't mean
that Pasteur was wrong.
Look, I'll show you
what I mean.
Watch it, mate.
I'm not gonna stay
around here getting poked
and prodded all day.
I'm off.
I've got a decent body.
I get poked and prodded
in the chest.
I'm gonna get another
line of work.
MAN 1:
Watch it!
Turn back. Stop.
MAN 2:
Please! Oh, stop!
[SCREAMS]
MAN 1:
Oh, my God, he's fallen off
the edge of the cartoon.
MAN 2:
Well, so much for that link.
John Cobbley is the musical
and artistic director
of Covent Garden.
He is himself
a talented musician,
he's a world-famous authority
on 19th-century Russian music,
and he's come
into the studio tonight
to talk about Tchaikovsky.
Which is a bit of a pity,
as this is Farming Club.
And on Farming Club tonight
we'll take a look
at the Ministry's
latest preventative proposals
to deal with possible
outbreaks of foot-and-mouth.
We'll be talking
later on to the man
who believes that milk yields
can be increased dramatically.
But first,
a Farming Club special:
The Life of Tchaikovsky.
[♪♪♪]
Tchaikovsky.
Was he the tortured soul
who poured out
his immortal longings
into dignified passages
of stately music?
Or was he just an old poof
who wrote tunes?
Tonight on Farming Club
we're going to take
an intimate look
at Tchaikovsky
and an intimate look
at his friends.
Incidentally, BBC publications
have prepared a special
pamphlet to go
with this program
called Hello Pianist.
And it contains material
which some people
might find offensive
but which is really smashing.
Peter Ilyich Tchaikovsky was
born in 1840 in
a Ken Russell film
just outside Saint Petersburg.
His father, Leo McKern,
a freelance bishop,
was married to Vera Plachenka,
Julie Christie,
but secretly deeply in love
with Margo Farenka,
Shirley Abicair,
and the strangely flatulent
Madame Ranevsky,
Norris McWhirter.
Soon, however, the family,
Eldridge Cleaver, Moira Lister
and Stan the Bat,
moved to the neighboring
industrial village of Omsk,
Eddie Waring, where they soon
found themselves, sadly,
quite unable to cope,
Anthony Barber.
In 1863, however,
Tchaikovsky was sent to Moscow
to study the piano.
And when he'd finished that,
the living room.
Maurice takes up the story.
Well, guess what?
The very next thing he did was
to go to this extraordinary,
but extraordinary
duckety-poos,
semi-Mondrian house
in Robin Russia.
Harry here,
Tammy Tchaikovsky wrote
the most Sammy
super symphonies
you've Henry heard
in the whole of your
Lily life.
She was such a good composer
that everybody but everybody
wanted to know.
And quite right too because
she wrote some lovely bits
such as Sally
Sleeping Beauty,
Patsy "Pathétique,"
Adrian "1812,"
and lots of Conny concerti
for Vera "Violin"
and Peter "Piano" Fanny forte.
But what do we really know
of this tortured ponce?
Well, if you can imagine
the size of Nelson's Column,
roughly three times the size
of a London bus,
then Tchaikovsky
was much smaller.
His head was about
the same size
as that of an extremely
large dog.
That is, say,
two very small dogs
or four very large hamsters.
Or one medium-size rabbit
if you count the whole body,
not just the head.
Robin?
Thank you. Here's your
three-stage model of
Tchaikovsky.
Um, here you see the legs,
used for walking around
which can be jettisoned
at night.
And, uh, this is
the main trunk,
the powerhouse
of the whole thing,
incorporating, of course,
the naughty bits
which were extremely naughty
for his time.
And the whole thing
is subservient
to this small command module
the, as it were, head of
the whole, as it were, body.
-Robin.
-Peter.
-Simon.
-Maurice.
Me. Well, poor pet,
she was like
a lost lamb in an abattoir.
Eventually, she Dickie died
of Colin cholera
in Saint Patsy Petersburg
in Gertie great Percy pain.
MAN: Here to play Tchaikovsky's
"First Piano Concerto
in B-flat minor"
is the world-famous soloist
Sviatoslav Richter.
[APPLAUSE]
During the performance,
he will escape from a sack,
three padlocks
and a pair of handcuffs.
[♪♪♪]
[PLAYING PIANO]
Good evening. This new series
of Trim-Jeans Theatre Presents
will enable you to enjoy
the poetry of T.S. Eliot
whilst losing
unsightly tummy bulge. Jean.
Well, yes, um,
the inches stay off. Mark?
Terrific. Thrill
to Thomas à Becket's
Kierkegaardian
moment of choice
whilst making your physique
tighter, firmer, neater.
I am here.
No traitor to the king.
Absolve all those
you have excommunicated.
Resign those powers
you have abrogated.
Renew the obedience
you have violated.
Lose inches off your hips,
thighs, buttocks and abdomen.
A terrific product.
BOTH:
Terrific.
And this comes complete
with the most
revolutionary guarantee
in slenderizing history.
This was Kevin Francis
before last season's
Trim-Jean's Play of the Month
production of The Seagull
by Anton Chekhov and the Sauna
Belt Trim-Jean
Company Limited.
See? Kevin has slipped into
his slenderizing garment
and is inflating it with
the handy little pump
provided.
Three acts and a few special
torso exercises later,
Kevin, as Trigorin, the failed
writer of sentimental romances
has lost over 33 inches.
Wow, what a difference.
That Anton Chekhov
can certainly write.
-Terrific.
Yes, why not join us
for a season of classic plays
and rapid slenderizing?
Enjoy Sir John Gielgud
and Sir Ralph Richardson
losing a total of 15 inches
in David Storey's Home.
Enjoy The Trim Gentlemen
of Verona
and Long Day's Journey
Into Night
while inches melt away.
Enjoy Glenda Jackson
with a constant snug fit
and solid support
in all four areas.
Other productions
will include:
Treasure Island,
Swan Lake,
The Life and Loves
of Toulouse-Lautrec,
and the Trim-Jeans version
of The Great Escape
with a cast of thousands
losing well over 1500 inches.
[♪♪♪]
[SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
Halt! Halt!
[GUNSHOTS]
Halt!
Wasn't that terrific,
ladies and gentlemen?
Really great.
Now, the next item
on the program--
I can't stand it, man.
Really, now.
I've had it with this idiot.
Every night, making me
say the most--
--really terrific act.
The next item on the--
Hey, man, I'm off, gone,
split, through, eh?
Gonna find a gig elsewhere.
Somewhere that's
a bit cooler, man.
I mean, it's terrible,
the way I hide.
I think this Christmas
I'm gonna cool down.
I'm gonna get with a guy
who really, you know,
digs me, you know?
A man who feels--
Really feels the same way
I do, man--
[GURGLE, CLANKING]
[MUFFLED VOICE]
[♪♪♪]
GERMAN MAN:
Welcome aboard, Britisher pig.
Quite a little surprise, ja?
[LAUGHS]
But perhaps you would be so
kind as to tell us all
you know
about certain
Allied shipping routes, ja?
Come on, talk--
BRITISH MAN:
Hello, Fritz. The tables seem
to have turned, old chap.
Let's see how you like a bit of
your own medicine, eh?
-[SLAPPING SOUNDS]
-Come on, Fritz. Now, tell us.
Tell us about--
CHINESE MAN:
Oh, greetings, capitalist dog.
Very sorry, but must
inform you
that you are now prisoner
of People's Republic.
I'm very sorry,
Comrade commander,
but have just picked up
a capitalist ship
on radar scanner.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
This is your captain speaking.
There is no need for panic.
Women and children first.
I repeat that.
Do not rush for the lifeboats
and remember,
women and children first.
And Red Indians.
Why did you
dress up like that?
It was the only
thing left.
All right.
Women, children
and Red Indians.
And spacemen.
Here is a revised list:
Women, children, Red Indians
and spacemen--
What's that meant to be?
It's a sort of impression
of what a Renaissance courtier
artist might look like
at the courts
of the great families,
the Medicis or the Borgias.
No, it's not. It looks
more Flemish than Italian.
Yes, that's a Flemish merchant
of the 15th or 16th centuries.
-What, with these tassels?
-Yes, yes.
They had those fitted doublets
going tapering down
into the full hose.
You know.
Exactly like that.
One moment, please.
Don't panic.
What's it meant to be? I've got
to tell them something.
Is it a Flemish merchant?
No, it is not
a Flemish merchant.
It's more a sort
of idealized version
of the complete
Renaissance man.
-No, it's not.
-All right, all right,
all right.
This is your captain speaking.
Do not rush for the lifeboats.
Women, children,
Red Indians, spacemen
and a sort of
idealized version
of the complete
Renaissance men first.
MAN:
Flemish merchants did not wear
hand-embroidered chevrons.
They did not.
Yes, Gomez?
"We found them walking
on the beach, my cap--"
Gomez, why can't you say this?
What? Oh, I see.
We can't afford it.
Ah, you see, the BBC
has to pay an actor
20 guineas if he speaks
and it makes a bit
of a hole in the budget.
Twenty-eight guineas, sir.
Oh! You fool, Gomez.
Sorry. Sorry.
That's 28 guineas.
What about me, sir?
-Are you supposed to speak?
-No.
-You've just spoken!
-Sorry.
You fool, that's 56 guineas
before we've even started.
Yes?
[SCREAMS]
What did he do that for?
It's a stunt.
An extra 20 guineas.
Look, we can't afford it.
The BBC are short
of money as it is.
The BBC wishes to deny rumors
that it is going
into liquidation.
Mrs. Kelly, who owns the flat
where they live,
has said that they can stay on
till the end of the month.
And we've just heard that
Huw Weldon's watch
has been accepted by the
London Electricity Board
and transmissions
for this evening
can be continued as planned.
[COUGHS]
Well, that's all from me,
-so good night.
-[KNOCK ON DOOR]
MAN:
Are you gonna
be in there all night?
It's just a bulletin,
Mr. Kelly.
And now back to the story.
-[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Come out.
All right.
We found these men walking
on the beach, my captain.
We are British naval officers,
and entitled to be--
ALL:
It's Puss.
CHILDREN'S VOICES:
Hello, Puss.
Hello, children.
Stop! Stop this adaptation
of Puss in Boots.
This is the police department
of the state of Venezuela!
Oh, no, it isn't.
Oh, yes, it is!
ALL:
Oh, no, it isn't.
Oh, yes, it is.
ALL:
Oh, no, it isn't.
Shut up!
Now, I'm going to ask you
some questions.
And remember, if you do not
give me correct answers
we have ways
of making you answer.
MAN:
Like not paying 28 guineas.
Shut up!
Now, what ship are you from?
We are from the
SS Mother Goose.
We were 12 days out
from Port of Spain, and--
I got 30 bob
for the trousers.
We are from the
SS Mother Goose.
We were 12 days out
from Port of Spain.
And one night,
I was doing my usual rounds
when I had occasion to pass
the forward storage lockers.
Go on.
Oh, um. Well, I--
I noticed
something unusual.
The main bilge hatches
had been opened.
And there,
crouching amidst the scuppers,
was the most ghastly creature
I'd ever seen in my life.
As soon as it saw me,
its horrible face split aside
in a ghastly look of terror.
Its head,
which was like a--
Could you sign
this, please?
--a small rat, was ghastly
and horrible and befurred.
Its little
red eyes glinted
in the unaccustomed glare
of the midday sun.
And before I could
shut the hatch
it sprang upon me
with one almighty bound--
What's this about doing
Horse of the Year Show
in here tonight?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Kelly.
We don't know.
This is drama.
Mr. Fox told me,
before he went down
to the pub,
they're doing
Horse of the Year Show in here
tonight at 9:10.
-Well, this is BBC Two.
-BBC One are in the kitchen.
I'm not having Harvey Smith
jumping over my binette.
No. Come on.
Tearing at my throat,
ripping my clothes.
And turn the gas off
before you leave!
All right!
I fought it
with all my strength,
but it was
too much for me. It--
ANNOUNCER:
Another clear round for
Harvey Smith on O'Malley.
And now it's Mrs. David Barker
riding Atalanta,
number three.
[HORSE GALLOPING]
[CRASH]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
Right, that's it.
Come on, out, out,
all of you.
Get out of my kitchen.
Go on. Harvey Smith.
Get out of here,
you lunkers.
It's one of our most
popular programs.
That's what you think,
Mr. Fox.
Well, that's all
from BBC television--
Come on, get out. Out.
Get out of here.
Out. Out. Get out.
Out. Out.
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Tonight, from London,
your special guests are:
Lulu...
Ringo Starr...
and the man you've all
been waiting for,
your host for tonight.
Love the outfit, dear.
It's gorgeous.
Hello. Good evening.
Welcome.
It's...
[♪♪♪]
[FART]