[♪♪♪]
Good evening, and welcome
to The Money Programme.
Tonight on
The Money Programme,
we're going to look at money.
Lots of it.
On film, and in the studio.
Some of it in nice piles,
others in lovely,
clanky bits of loose change.
Some of it neatly counted into
fat little hundreds,
delicate fivers
stuffed into bulging wallets,
nice, crisp, clean checks,
pert pieces of copper coinage
thrust deep
into trouser pockets.
Romantic foreign money
rolling against the thigh,
with rough familiarity.
Beautiful, wayward,
curlicued banknotes.
Filigreed copper plating
cheek by jowl,
with tumbling hexagonal
milled edges,
rubbing gently against
the terse leather
of beautifully balanced
bankbooks.
I'm sorry.
But I love money.
All money.
I've always wanted money.
To handle, to touch.
The smell of
the rain-washed florin.
The lure of the lira.
The glitter and the glory
of the guinea.
The romance of the ruble.
The feel of the franc.
The heel of a Deutschmark.
The cold, antiseptic sting
of the Swiss franc.
And the sunburnt splendor
of the Australian dollar.
♪ I've got 90 thousand pounds
In my pajamas ♪
♪ I've got 40 thousand
French francs in my fridge ♪
♪ I've got lots
And lots of lira ♪
♪ Now the Deutschmark's
getting dearer ♪
♪ And my dollar bills
Would buy the Brooklyn Bridge ♪
♪ There is nothing
Quite as wonderful as money ♪
Quite as beautiful as cash ♪
♪ Some people say it's folly
But I'd rather have the lolly ♪
♪ With money you can
Make a smash ♪
♪ There is nothing
Quite as wonderful as money ♪
Like a newly minted pound ♪
♪ Everyone must hanker
For the butchness of a banker ♪
♪ It's accountancy that
Makes the world go 'round ♪
♪ You can keep
Your Marxist ways ♪
♪ For it's only just a phase ♪
♪ Money, money, money
Makes the world go round ♪
♪ Money, money, money, money
Money, money, money, money ♪
♪ Money ♪
-And now.
-It's...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[♪♪♪]
I bling a dispatch
flom Prymouth.
Flom Prymouth?
Flom Sil Flancis Dlake.
Entel and apploach the thlone.
What news flom Prymouth?
Dlake has sighted the Spanish
freet, Youl Majesty.
So Phirip's garreons ale hele.
How many?
A hundled and thilty-six
men of wal.
Broody herr.
Is Dlake plepaled?
He has oldeled the whore freet
into the Blitish Channer.
So we must to Tirbuly.
Reicestel,
Sil Wartel Lareigh,
Groucester,
we sharr lide--
Groucestel! Groucestel!
Not Groucester.
Come on,
ret's get this arr light.
Reicestel,
that was tellibre.
-What?
-Tellibre.
-Oh, solly.
-When you have a rine,
ling your berr.
-Ling my berr?
-Ling, ling. Rike this.
And cut the
"Broody herr."
-Erizabeth.
-Yes?
You should be on a bicycre.
Why?
You rook odd rike that.
I do not look odd like this,
it's that lot that looks odd.
It's bleeding weird having
half the Tudor nobility
ligging around
on motorized bicycles!
-It's vely sullearist.
-Horsefeathers!
Listen, I'm beginning
to have my doubts about you.
-What do you mean?
-I'm telling you
straight, mate.
I don't think you're
Luchino Visconti at all.
[LAUGHS]
Of course I am.
Me vely impoltant
Itarian firm dilectol.
You are a Nip.
Lubbish!
Me genuine wop.
[SINGING IN ITALIAN]
He's bluffing.
-Pfft.
Is that the time?
I must fry.
Not so fast, Yakomoto!
[TRUMPETS PLAY FANFARE]
Shut up!
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Inspector Leopard
of Scotland Yard's
Special Fraud
Film Director Squad.
ALL:
Leopald of the Yald?
The same,
only more violent!
Ohh!
Right, "Slit-eyes" Yakomoto.
I'm arresting you for
the impersonation
of Signor Luchino Visconti,
famous Italian director
of such movie classics as:
Ossessione, 1942,
La Terra Trema, 1948,
and Bellissima, 1951--
A satisfyingly ironic
slice-of-life drama.
1957 brought to the silver
screen his Le Bianche Notti,
adapted by Dostoyevsky.
A mannered and romantic
melancholy of snow, and mists
and moonlit encounters
on canal bridges.
Boccaccio '70
followed five years later,
and the following year saw
The Leopard!
So impressed was I,
with his motion-pic treatment
of the Risorgimento
that I went along
to Somerset House...
and changed me own name
to Leopard,
preferring it to me
original handle, Panther.
[GROWLS]
I digress.
1969 saw The Damned,
a Gotterdammerung epic of
political and industrial
shenanigans in good old
Nazi Germany.
Starring Helmut Berger
as a stinking transvestite
what should have his face
sawn off,
the curvaceous Charlotte
Rampling as a bit of tail,
and the impeccable
Dirk Bogarde as Von Essen.
The association of the latter
with Signor Visconti,
fructified with Dirk's
magnificent portrayal
of the elderly poof
what expires in Venice.
And so, Yakomoto...
Blimey, he's gone!
Never mind.
I'll have you instead.
-What?
-I haven't time
to go chasing after him.
There's violence to be done.
Oh, yes.
[POLICE CAR SIREN BLARING]
[MUTTERING]
Arrgh!
All right, buster,
hands up.
[GULPS]
Aah!
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
I would like to ask the team
what they would do
if they were Hitler.
[APPLAUSE]
MAN:
Gerald?
GERALD:
Well, I'd, uh,
annex the Sudetenland
and sign a non-aggression
pact with Russia.
[APPLAUSE]
MAN:
Norman?
NORMAN: Well, I'd do
the Reichstag bathroom
in purples and golds,
and ban abortion-on-demand.
[APPLAUSE]
Liberal rubbish.
Klaus, what do you want
with your jugged fish?
Halibut.
The jugged fish
is halibut.
Well, what fish have you got
that isn't jugged, then?
-Rabbit.
-What, rabbit fish?
Yes. It's got fins.
Is it dead?
Well, it was coughing up
blood last night.
All right, I'll have the dead,
unjugged rabbit fish.
Well, that was really
horrible.
Oh, you're always
complaining.
What's for afters?
Well, there's rat cake,
rat sorbet, rat pudding
or strawberry tart.
Strawberry tart?
Well, it's got some rat in it.
-How much?
-Three.
Rather a lot, really.
Well, I'll have a slice
without so much rat in it.
-Appalling.
-Moan, moan, moan.
Hello, Mum. Hello, Dad.
Hello, son.
There's a dead bishop
on the landing.
Where did that come from?
What do you mean?
What's its diocese?
Well, it looked a bit
Bath and Wells-ish to me.
Oh, I'll go
and have a look.
Don't know who keeps
bringing them in here.
Well, it's not me.
I've put three out
by the bin and the dustmen
won't touch them.
-Leicester.
-How'd you know?
Tattooed on the back
his neck.
I'm gonna call the police.
Shouldn't you call the church?
Call the church police.
All right.
The church police!
Yes?
[STAMMERS]
There's a dead bishop!
[INDISTINCT SHOUT]
There's another dead bishop
on the landing.
Suffragan or
diocesan?
How should I know?
It's tattooed
on the back of their necks.
Here.
Is that rat tart?
Yes.
Disgusting.
Right!
The hunt is on.
O Lord,
we beseech thee,
tell us
who croaked Leicester.
[♪♪♪]
All right, it's a fair cop,
but society is to blame.
Agreed.
I'd like the three
by the bin to be taken
into consideration.
Right. And now, I'd like
to conclude this arrest
with a hymn.
[ALL SINGING]
[SINGING CONTINUES]
Oh, shut up.
[SINGING STOPS]
Thank you.
[CLACKING]
What?!
Eww! Oh! Mmm.
[MUTTERING]
[CHATTERING]
Ooh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
[RUSTLING]
Hoo-hoo. Oh!
Ah. Oh, ooh.
[LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
Ah!
Oh, whee-hee-hee-hee!
Whoo! Yahoo!
Yay! Whee!
ANNOUNCER:
Meanwhile,
in the jungle next door...
[SAFARI MUSIC PLAYING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
What a simply super
little place.
Yes, they've done wonders
with it.
You know, this used to be
one of the most swampy,
disease-infested areas
of the whole jungle
and they've turned it into
this smashing
little restaurant.
Here you are, Onkwame.
Thank you.
Hello, Mr. Akwekwe.
Hello there, Mr. Spare-Buttons-
Supplied-With-The-Shirt.
Nice to see you again.
These are some of
my fellow explorers.
Sir Charles Farquarson,
Brian Bailey...
-Hello, there.
-...Betty Bailey.
And this is Mr. Akwekwe,
who started the whole place.
-It really is super.
-Oh, terrific idea.
May I recommend
the alligator purée--
Ahhhh!
-[GORILLA GROWLING]
-[MAN SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOT]
Now then,
have you decided?
Uh, yes. Well, there's two
avocado vinaigrette here,
and what are you
gonna have, Brian?
Quiche Lorraine for me,
please.
Right. So that's
two avocado, one quiche.
[YELLING IN AFRIKAANS]
So, that's two avocado,
one quiche.
And a soup of the day.
Right.
[TRIBAL MUSIC BEGINS PLAYING]
And to follow?
Uh, two chicken a la Reine,
please.
Uh, with sauce Provençale.
And one scampi desirée.
And a boeuf bourguignon
with a green salad.
Right-o.
Two chicken, one scampi,
one boeuf with
the green salad.
There may be a little delay.
That's fine,
but we have to be out by three.
Yes, sir.
Yes, we'll try.
We'll try.
[TRIBAL DRUMMING QUICKENS]
ANNOUNCER: The BBC would like
to announce that the next scene
is not considered
suitable for family viewing.
It contains scenes
of violence,
involving people's heads and
arms getting chopped off,
ears nailed to trees,
and their toenails pulled out
in slow motion.
There are also scenes of naked
women with floppy breasts.
And also, at one point,
you can see a pair of buttocks.
And there's another bit where I
swear you could see everything,
but my friend says it's just
the way he's holding the spear.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Because of the unsuitability
of the scene,
the BBC will be
replacing it with a scene
from a repeat of
Gardening Club for 1958.
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHING, CHATTERING]
[SQUAWKING]
[YELLING, MOANING]
And now back to the story.
It was a nasty business
back at the restaurant.
Yes, I thought most places
took Barclaycard nowadays.
Where do you think
they're taking us, Brian?
God knows.
Look!
The sacred volcano Andu,
which no man
has seen before.
No, no, no.
Next to that.
MAN: The London Brick Company?
No, no, no, no, no.
Next to that.
MAN: The forbidden plateau
of Roiurama.
The lost world,
thrown up by mighty
earth movements
thousands of millions
of years ago,
where strange primeval
creatures defying evolution
lurk in the dark,
impenetrable forests,
cut off forever
from the outside world.
I still can't
see it.
You don't think that's where
they're taking us?
Yes, and God knows
what we'll find there.
-What page, please?
-What?
What page in the script?
Page seven.
"Come on, you dogs,
we have far to go.
We must lose no time."
Come on, you dogs,
we have far to go.
We must lose no time.
Come on, you dogs--
Come on, you dogs!
We have time to lose.
This has gone too far.
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER: Meanwhile, back
in London, at the British
Explorers Club in the Mall...
Any news of Betty Bailey's
expedition, Hargreaves?
Uh...uh...
Page-- Page nine.
Oh, thank you.
Uh, "The Lost World
of Roiurama."
That's--
That's my line.
Oh. Sorry.
"Where were they going,
sir?"
The Lost World of Roiurama.
"Yes, sir.
We've got a telegram?"
Oh.
"Reads it."
"Expedition superb.
Weather excellent.
Everything wonderful."
I wonder
what's gone wrong.
-For God's sake, be careful--
-Wait a minute.
I'm going to go
after them.
Oh! For God's sake,
be careful, sir.
[♪♪♪]
My God, Betty,
we're done for.
We'll never
get out of here.
We're completely
lost.
Lost!
Even the natives
have gone.
Goodbye, Betty.
Goodbye, Farquarson.
Goodbye, Brian.
It's been a great
expedition.
Great expedition.
All that'll be left of us
is a map, a compass,
and a few feet of film,
recording our last moments.
Wait a moment!
What is it?
If we're on film,
there must be
someone filming us.
My God, Betty, you're right!
Look!
-Hello!
-Great to see you!
So good to see you.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Wait a minute!
What is it, again?
If this is the crew
who were filming us,
who's filming us now?
Look!
Cut there, man.
Cut there.
No. No good.
How we going to get that
feeling of personal alienation
of self from society,
with this load
of Bulldog Drummond crap?
When I was doing La Notte
with that Monica Vitti gal,
she didn't give me none of this
empire-building shit, man.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Not so fast, Akarumba!
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Inspector Baboon,
of Scotland Yard's
Special Fraud
Film Director Squad,
Jungle Division.
-Baboon of the Yard?
-Shut up!
-[GUNSHOT]
-[SCREAMS]
Right, Akarumba.
I'm arresting you, for
impersonating Signor
Michelangelo Antonioni,
an Italian film director who
co-scripts all his own films,
largely jettisoning narrative
in favor of vague incident,
and relentless
character study.
In his first film,
Cronaca di un Amore, 1950,
the couple are brought
together by a shared
irrational guilt.
Le Amiche followed in 1955.
And 1959 saw the first of
Antonioni's
world-famous trilogy,
L'Avventura.
An acute study of boredom,
restlessness
and the futilities and agonies
of purposeless living.
In L'Eclisse,
three years later,
this analysis of the
sentiments was taken up
once again.
"We do not have to know each
other to love,"
says the heroine.
"And perhaps
we do not have to love."
The eclipse of the emotions
finally casts its shadow....
[♪♪♪]
Signor Antonioni first makes
use of color to underline...
ANNOUNCER:
And now on BBC 1,
another six minutes of
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
Yes, sir?
I'd like to
have an argument, please.
Certainly, sir.
Have you been here before?
No, this is
my first time.
I see.
Do you want to have
the full argument,
or were you thinking
of taking a course?
Well, uh,
what would be the cost?
Yes, it's one pound
for a five-minute argument,
but only eight pounds
for a course of ten.
Hmm... Well, I think
it's probably best
if I start with the one,
and see how it goes
from there, okay?
Fine. I'll see who's free
at the moment.
Uh... Mr. Du-Bakey's free,
but he's a little bit
conciliatory.
Yes, try Mr. Barnard.
Room 12.
Thank you. Ahem.
What do you want?!
Well, I was told outside--
Don't give me that,
you snotty-faced
heap of parrot droppings!
What?
Shut your festering gob,
you tit!
Your type makes me puke!
You vacuous, toffee-nosed,
malodorous pervert!
What?! I came in here
for an argument!
Oh, oh, I'm sorry,
this is abuse.
Oh.
Oh, I see,
that explains it.
No, you want 12A,
next door.
I see. Sorry.
Not at all.
No, that's all right.
Stupid git.
MAN:
Come in.
Is this the right room
for an argument?
I've told you once.
-No, you haven't.
-Yes, I have.
-When?
-Just now.
-No, you didn't.
-Yes, I did.
-Didn't. Didn't.
-Did.
-I'm telling you, I did.
-You did not!
I'm sorry. Is this
a five-minute argument,
or the full half hour?
Oh-- Oh, just
the five-minute one.
Fine.
-Ah.
-Thank you.
-Anyway, I did.
-You most certainly did not.
Now, let's get one thing
quite clear.
I most definitely told you.
-You did not.
-Yes, I did.
-You did not. Didn't!
-Yes, I did. Yes, I did.
-Didn't.
-Yes, I did.
Look, this isn't an argument.
-Yes, it is.
-No, it isn't.
It's just contradiction.
-Yes, it is.
-It is not.
-It is.
-You just contradicted me.
-No, I didn't.
-Oh, you did.
-No, no, no.
-You did, just then.
-No, nonsense.
-Oh, look, this is futile.
-No, it isn't.
-I came for a good argument.
-No, you came here
for an argument.
An argument's not the same
as contradiction.
-Can be.
-No, it can't.
An argument is a collected
series of statements
to establish a
definite proposition.
No, it isn't.
Yes, it is.
It isn't just contradiction.
Look, if I argue with you,
I must take up
a contrary position.
But it isn't just saying,
"No, it isn't."
-Yes, it is.
-No, it isn't.
Argument's an intellectual
process.
Contradiction is just
the automatic gainsaying
of anything
the other person says.
-No, it isn't.
-Yes, it is.
-Not at all.
-Now, look--
-[BELL DINGS]
-Thank you. Good morning.
What?
That's it. Good morning.
But I was just getting
interested.
Sorry,
the five minutes is up.
That was never
five minutes, just now.
-I'm afraid it was.
-No, it wasn't.
Sorry, I'm not allowed
to argue anymore.
What?
If you want me to
go on arguing,
you'll have to pay
for another five minutes.
But that was never
five minutes, just now.
Oh, come on.
This is ridiculous.
I'm very sorry,
but I told you,
I'm not allowed to argue
unless you've paid.
Oh, all right.
-There you are.
-Thank you.
Well?
-Well, what?
-That was never five minutes.
-I'm not arguing unless
you pay.
-I just paid.
-No, you didn't.
-I did! I did! I did!
-Look, I don't want
to argue about that.
I'm sorry, but you didn't pay.
A-ha!
Well, if I didn't pay,
why are you arguing? Got you.
-No, you haven't.
-Yes, I have.
If you're arguing,
I must've paid.
Not necessarily.
I could be arguing
in my spare time.
-I've had enough of this.
-No, you haven't.
Oh, shut up.
-I want to complain.
-You want to complain?
Look at these shoes.
Only had them three weeks,
the heels are worn right
through.
-No, I wanna complain about--
-If you complain,
nothing happens.
You might just as well
not bother. My back hurts and...
-I want to com-- Ow!
-No, no, no.
Hold your head like this,
and then go:
Whaa!
-Try it again.
-Ohhhh!
Better, better,
but "Whaa! Whaa!"
-Hold your hands here.
-No!
-Now. Look, that's it.
That's it!
-Whaaa!
-Good.
-Stop hitting me!
-What?
-Stop hitting me.
-Stop hitting you?
-Yes.
What did you come
in here for?
I came here to complain.
Oh, I'm sorry,
that's next door.
It's being-hit-on-the-head
lessons in here.
What a stupid concept.
Right, hold it, there.
-What?
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Inspector Fox of the
Light Entertainment Police
Comedy Division,
Special Flying Squad.
-Flying Fox of the Yard?
-Shut up!
-Ow!
No, no, no.
"Whaaa!"
-And you!
-Whaaa!
He's good. You could learn
a thing or two from him.
Right, now, you two, me old
beauties, you are nicked.
-What for?
-I'm charging you
under Section 21
of the Strange Sketch Act.
-The what?
-You are hereby charged
that you did willfully
take part in a strange sketch.
That is, a skit, spoof or
humorous vignette
of an unconventional nature
with intent to cause grievous
mental confusion
to the Great British public.
Evening, all.
It's a fair cop.
-And you tosh.
-Whaaa!
That's excellent!
Right, come on down the Yard.
Hold it. Hold it.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Inspector Thompson's
Gazelle of the Program
Planning Police,
Light Entertainment Division,
Special Flying Squad.
Flying Thompson's
Gazelle of the Yard?
-Shut up!
-Gahh!
-He's good.
-Shut up!
-Whaa!
-Rotten.
Ahhh!
Good!
Right, I'm arresting this entire
show on three counts:
One, acts of
self-conscious behavior,
contrary to the
Not-In-Front-of-the-Children
Act.
Two, always saying,
"It's so-and-so of the Yard,"
every time the fuzz arrives.
And, three...
And this is the cruncher.
...offenses against
the Getting-Out-of-Sketches
Without-Using-a-Proper-Punchline
Act.
Namely, simply ending
every bleeding sketch,
by just having
a policeman come in and--
Wait a minute.
-Hold it.
-It's a fair cop.
And now on BBC 1,
one more minute of
Monty Python's Flying Circus.