[♪♪♪]
Hello, good evening and welcome
to another edition of
Blood, Devastation,
Death, War and Horror.
And later on, we'll be talking
to a man who does gardening.
But our first guest--
Our first guest
in the studio tonight
is a man who talks
entirely in anagrams.
Taht si crreoct.
Do you enjoy this?
I stom certainly od.
Revy chum so.
And what's your name?
Hamrag. Hamrag Yatlerot.
Well, Graham, nice to have you
on the show.
Now, where do you
come from?
-Uh, Bumcreland.
-Cumberland?
Staht sit sepreicly.
And I believe you're working
on an anagram version
of Shakespeare?
Sey, sey, taht si crreoct.
Uh, ta the mnemot I'm wroking
on The Mating of the Wersh.
The Mating of the Wersh,
by William Shakespeare?
-Nay, by Malliwi Rapessheake.
-Ah.
And, uh, what else?
Uh, Two Netlemeg of Verona,
Twelfth Thing
The Chamrent of Venice.
-Have you done Hamlet?
-Thamel.
"Be ot or bot ne ot,
tath is the noestqui."
And what is your next project?
Uh, Ring Kichard the Thrid.
I'm sorry?
"A shroe! A shroe!
My dingkom for a shroe."
Ah, ha, ha.
Ring Kichard, yes.
But surely that's
not an anagram,
that's a spoonerism.
If you're gonna split hairs,
I'm gonna piss off.
[PLAYING FANFARE]
-And now...
-It's....
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Tony M. Nyphot's
Flying Risccu.
[♪♪♪]
Mrs. Scab, you have 12 hours
to beat the clock.
Correct!
I've done it.
[SCREAMS AND LAUGHS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Ah, Mr. Victim, yes,
I'm glad to say
that I've got the go-ahead to
lend you the money you require,
yes.
Uh, we will, of course,
want as security
the deeds of your house,
of your aunt's house,
of your second cousin's house,
of your wife's parents' house
and of your granny's bungalow.
And, uh, we will,
in addition,
need a controlling interest
in your new company,
uh, unrestricted access
to your private bank account,
the deposit in our vaults of
your three children as hostages,
and a full legal indemnity
against any acts
of embezzlement
carried out against you
by any members of our staff
during the normal course
of their duties.
No, we couldn't accept your dog
instead of your youngest child.
We would like to suggest
a brand-new scheme of ours,
under which 51 percent of both
your dog and your wife
pass to us
in the event of your suffering
a serious accident.
Fine. No, not at all.
Nice to do business with you.
Uh...
Miss Godfrey, could you
send in Mr. Ford, please?
Now, where's that dictionary?
Ah, yes, here we are.
Oh, dear.
Inner life...
[CLEARS THROAT]
-Inner life...
-[KNOCKING]
Come in!
Ah, uh, Mr. Ford, isn't it?
-That's right, yes.
-How do you do?
I'm a merchant banker.
How do you do, Mr...?
Um, I forget my name
for the moment,
but I am
a merchant banker.
I wondered whether
you'd like to contribute
to the orphans' home?
Well, I don't wanna
show my hand too early,
but, actually,
here at Slater Nazi,
we are quite keen
to get into orphans.
You know, uh, developing market
and all that.
What sort of sum
did you have in mind?
Well, uh, you're a rich man.
Yes, I am. Yes, yes.
Very, very rich.
Quite phenomenally
wealthy, yes.
I do-- I do own the most
startling quantities of cash.
Yes, quite right.
You're rather a smart
young lad, aren't you?
We could do with you to feed
the pantomime horse.
-Very smart.
-Thank you, sir.
Now, you were saying, I'm--
I'm-- I'm very, very, very,
very, very, very, very, very,
very, very, very, very rich.
So, um, how about a pound?
A pound. Yes, I see.
Now, uh, this loan would be
secured by the poor--
It's not--
It's not a loan, sir.
-What?
-It's not a loan.
Ah.
You get one
of these, sir.
It's a bit small for a share
certificate, isn't it?
Look, um, I think-- I think
I'd better run this over
to our Legal Department.
If you could possibly
pop back on Friday--
Do you--
Do you have to that?
Couldn't you just
give me the pound?
Yes, but, you-- You see,
I don't know what it's for.
Well, it's for the orphans.
Yes?
It's a gift.
-A what?
-A-- A gift.
[RATTLES]
-Oh, a gift!
-Yes.
-A tax dodge.
-No, no, no, no.
No? Then, well,
I'm awfully sorry,
I don't understand.
Um, can you just explain
exactly what you want?
Well, I want you
to give me a pound
and then I go away
and give it to the orphans.
Yes?
Well, that's it.
No, no, no,
I don't follow this at all.
I mean, um--
I don't want to seem stupid,
but it looks to me as though I'm
a pound down on the whole deal.
Well, yes, you are.
I am?
Well, what is my incentive
to give you the pound?
Well, the incentive is
to make the orphans happy.
Happy?
You quite sure you've
got this right?
Yes, lots of people
give me money.
-What, just like that?
-Well, yes.
Must be sick.
Uh, I don't suppose
you could give me
a list of their names
and addresses, could you?
No. No, I just go up to them
in the street and ask.
Good Lord.
That's the most exciting
new idea I've heard in years.
It's-- It's so simple
it's brilliant!
Well, if that idea of yours
isn't worth a pound
-I'd like to know what is.
-Oh, thank you, sir.
The only trouble is,
you gave me the idea before
I'd given you the pound.
And that's not
good business.
Isn't it?
No, I'm afraid it isn't.
So, um, off you go.
[SCREAMS]
-Nice to do business with you.
-Anyway--
And off we go again.
Uh, Miss Godfrey.
Uh, could you send in
the pantomime horses, please?
[♪♪♪]
-Now, I've asked you in here--
-[♪♪♪]
-Now, I've asked you--
Shut up!
Now, I've asked you in here
to see me this morning
because I'm afraid we're going
to have to let one of you go.
I'm very sorry, but the present
rationalization of this firm
makes it inevitable
that we hive one of you off.
Now, you may think that this
is very harsh behaviour,
but let me tell you that
our management consultants
actually queried the necessity
for us to employ
a pantomime horse at all.
And so the decision has to be
made which one of you is to go.
Champion, how many years have
you been with this firm?
Trigger?
I see. Well, it's
a difficult decision.
But in accordance with our
traditional principles
of free enterprise
and healthy competition,
I'm going to ask the two of you
to fight to the death for it.
No, I'm afraid there's
no redundancy scheme.
GERMAN ANNOUNCER:
In the hard and unrelenting
world of nature,
the ceaseless struggle
for survival continues.
This time, one of the pantomime
horses concedes defeat
and so lives
to fight another day.
[♪♪♪]
Here, in a colony of sea lions,
we see a huge bull sea lion
seeing off an intruding bull
who is attempting
to intrude on his harem.
This pattern
of aggressive behavior
is typical
of these documentaries.
Here we see two limpets
locked in a life-or-death
struggle for territory.
The huge bull limpet,
enraged by the rock,
endeavors to encircle
its sprightly opponent.
Here we see an ant.
This ant is engaged
in a life-or-death
struggle with the wolf.
You can see the ant
creeping up on the wolf
on all sixes.
Now he stops to observe.
Satisfied that the wolf
has not heard him,
he approaches nearer.
With great skill he chooses
his moment and then,
quick as a limpet,
with one mighty bound,
buries his fangs
in the wolf's neck.
The wolf struggles
to no avail.
A battle of this kind can take
anything up to 15 years
because the timber ant
has such a tiny mouth.
Here we see Heinz Sielmann
engaged in a life-or-death
struggle with Peter Scott.
They are engaged
in a bitter punch-up
over repeat fees
on the overseas sales
of their nature
documentaries.
Now they have been joined by
an enraged Jacques Cousteau.
This is typical of the harsh
and bitchy world
of television features.
Here we see a honey bear
not engaged in a life-or-death
struggle about anything.
These honey bears are placid
and peaceful creatures
and, consequently,
bad television.
Here we see
a pantomime horse.
It is engaged
in a life-or-death struggle
for a job
with a merchant bank.
However, his rival employee,
the huge bull
pantomime horse,
is lying in wait for him.
Poor pantomime horse.
Here, we see
a pantomime goose
engaged in a life-or-death
struggle with
Terence Rattigan.
The enraged goose fires.
[BOINGS]
Poor Terence.
Another victim
of this silly film.
Here we see an enraged
pantomime Princess Margaret.
She is lying in wait
for her breakfast.
The unsuspecting breakfast
glides ever closer to its doom.
The enraged pantomime
royal person
is poised for the kill.
She raises her harpoon
and fires.
Ping!
Right in the toast.
A brief struggle
and all is over.
-Poor breakfast.
Another victim of the--
-[SCREAMS]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[GROANS]
Oh, the pantomime flea
has caught himself
a nice little
dinner, Fred.
[ROARING]
I think the dining room
wants his din-dins too.
Your turn today, dear.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
[BURPS]
[ROARING]
All right, Mr. Bedroom,
you'll get your dinner too.
[MAN SCREAMING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Postman.
[POSTMAN SCREAMING]
[HUMMING "GREENSLEEVES"]
[GROWLS]
-[SCREAMING]
-[GROWLING]
-[ROARS]
-[SCREAMING]
WOMAN:
Oh, the 69's late again.
-[ROARS]
-[GROUP SCREAMING]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[GROANING]
You hear that, Tim?
Yep.
Could just be the house
we're lookin' for.
ANNOUNCER:
This, then, is the story
of two desperate men
hired by the good people
at NCP Car Parks
to hunt down and destroy
houses too dangerous
to live.
-Hmm, eh.
-Mm-hm.
MAN 1: Well, what do you think?
MAN 2: Oh, these are
house droppings, all right.
Fresh ones too.
MAN 1: Okay, let's go.
Psst. Over here.
That's the one.
Cover me.
I'm gonna make a try for it.
[HOUSE SNORING]
[PANTING]
[BOTH SQUEALING GLEEFULLY]
Get away! Hey!
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[BUZZING]
ANNOUNCER:
And so, thanks once again
to the unceasing efforts
of the good people
at NCP Car Parks,
the world is made
just a little bit safer.
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Sketch just starting,
actor wanted.
-Good-- Good morning.
-Morning, sir.
-I'd like to join
the army, please.
-I see.
Uh, short service or long
service commission, sir?
Um, long
as possible, please.
Right, well, I'll just take
a few particulars and then--
Shove off!
And then there'll be
a few forms to sign.
Of course, we'll need some
references and then
a full medical examination by--
Yes, I see. I--
I was just wondering
whether it would be possible
for me to join the women's army?
The Women's Royal Army Corps,
sir?
Yes, I-- I was just thinking,
you know, if it was possible
for me to have my choice,
I'd prefer to be
in the Women's Royal Amy Corps.
Well, I'm afraid that
the people that recruit here
normally go straight
into the Scots Guards.
Uh, which is all men,
I suppose?
Yes, it is.
Yes.
Are there any regiments
which are more...
effeminate than others?
Well, no, sir. I mean,
apart from the marines,
they're all dead butch.
See, what I-- I really
wanted was a regiment
where I could be really quiet
and have more time to myself
to work with fabrics
and creating new concepts
in interior design.
Working with fabrics
and experimenting
with interior design?
Yes.
Oh, well, you want the
Durham Light Infantry, then.
-Oh.
-Oh, yes.
That's the only regiment
that's really doing
something new with design,
with color, texture and line
and that. Oh, yeah.
-I see.
-Oh, yes.
I mean, their use of color
with fabrics is fantastic.
I saw their pattern book
the other day.
Beautiful, beautiful.
Savage tans,
great slabs of black
set against aggressive orange.
It really makes you
want to shout out,
-"This is good! This is real!"
-Really?
Oh, yes. I mean,
The Inniskilling Fusiliers and
Anglian regiment are all right,
if you're interested
in the art nouveau
William Morris revival bit.
But if you really want
a regiment of the line
that is really saying something
about interior decor,
then you've got to go
for the Durham Light Infantry.
I've had enough of this,
I'm handing in my notice.
-What do you mean?
-Well, I mean, when I applied
for this job,
I thought I'd get
a few decent lines,
but you end up
doing the whole thing.
My last five speeches
have been:
"Really. Really. I see.
I see," and, "Really."
I wouldn't give
those lines to a dog.
All right! All right.
All right, sonny.
I'll tell you what,
we'll do something different.
I'll be a bus conductor
and you can be a really funny
passenger on a bus.
Any more fares, please?
I've got a chauffeur,
and every time
I go to the lavatory
he drives me potty.
Boom, boom.
One in a row.
-♪ I'm not unusual, I'm-- ♪
-Fivepenny, please.
Five beautiful pennies
going into the bag,
and you are
the lucky winner of...
one fivepenny ticket.
What's the Welshman
doing under the bed?
He's having a leak.
Oh, they're all
in here tonight.
[LAUGHING, CLAPPING]
-Look!
-I am looking.
It's the only way
I can keep my eyelids apart.
Boom, boom.
Everyone a Maserati!
Look, you said
I was gonna be
a funny passenger.
-What do you mean?
-Well, all I said was,
"Fivepenny, please." You can't
call that a funny line.
Well, it's the way
you said it.
No, it isn't!
Nobody can say,
"Fivepenny, please,"
and make it funny.
Fivepenny, please.
[LAUGHING, CLAPPING]
-Morning.
-[LAUGHING]
Not so warm today,
eh, George?
[LAUGHING]
-Good morning.
-MAN 1: Good morning.
-WOMAN: Good morning.
-MAN 2: Good morning.
[LAUGHING]
[KNOCKING]
Come in, Mr. Horton.
Morning, sir.
[SNORTS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Do, uh--
Do sit down.
-Thank you, sir.
-[SNORTS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now then, Horton,
you've been with us
for 20 years,
and your work
in the Accounts Department
has been immaculate.
[GIGGLING]
No, no, please don't
say anything.
As I say, your work has been
beyond reproach.
[CLEARS THROAT]
But unfortunately,
the effect you're having
on your colleagues
has undermined
the competence--
[SNICKERING]
Has undermined the competence
of this firm
to such a point
that I'm afraid
I've got no option...
[CLEARS THROAT]
...but to sack you.
-I'm sorry to hear that, sir.
-[SNORTS]
It couldn't have come
at a worse time.
[LAUGHS]
There's school fees
for the two boys coming up,
and the wife's treatment
costing more now, sir.
I don't know where
the money's coming from as
it is, and now...
I don't see any future.
I'd been hoping I might
be able to hang on here
just for the last
couple of years,
but now I--
-I just want to go out
and end it all.
-[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING, CLAPPING]
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
And now for the fish.
The fish
down the trousers.
It's your laugh, mate,
it's not mine.
It's your trousers,
not my trousers,
your trousers.
And now for the whitewash.
The whitewash over you.
Not over me.
It's over you.
You get the laughs.
You get all the laughs.
And now for the custard pie
in the mush.
It's not my mush,
it's your mush.
It's your laugh.
It's your laugh, mate,
it's not mine.
It's your bleeding laugh.
[♪♪♪]
Good evening.
Tonight we're
going to talk about--
That is,
I'm going to talk about--
Well, actually,
I'm talking about it now. Ha.
I'm not talking about it now,
but I am talking.
I know I'm pausing occasionally,
and not talking
during the pauses,
but the pauses are part of
the whole process of talking.
When one talks,
one has to pause.
Uh, like then.
I paused, but I was
still talking.
And again there.
Well, no, the real point
of what I'm saying is,
that when I appear not to be
talking, don't go nipping out
to the kitchen,
putting the kettle on,
buttering scones,
or getting crumbs and bits of
food out of those round,
brown straw mats
that the teapot goes on,
you know,
because in all probability,
I'm still talking and what
you heard was a pause.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Like there again.
Look, to make it
absolutely easier,
so there's no problem at all,
what I'll do is I'll give you
some kind of sign, like this...
while I'm still talking, and
only pausing in between words,
and when I've finished
altogether,
I'll do this, all right?
No, no, sorry, no, no.
Sorry, just demonstrating.
Haven't finished.
Haven't started yet.
Oh, dear.
Nearly forgot the gesture.
I hope none of you are
nipping out into the kitchen,
getting bits of food out
of those round, brown mats,
which the...
Good evening.
Tonight, I want to talk about--
ANNOUNCER:
We interrupt this program
to annoy you
and make things generally
irritating for you.
--with a large piece
of wet paper.
Turn the paper over--
Turn the paper over,
keeping your eye on the camel,
and paste down the edge
of the sailor's uniform
until the word "maudling"
is almost totally obscured.
Well, that's one way
of doing it.
ANNOUNCER 1:
Good evening. We interrupt
this program again.
"A": to irritate you,
and "B": to provide work
for one of our announcers.
ANNOUNCER 2:
Good evening. I'm the announcer
who's just been given this job
by the BBC.
And I'd just like to say
how grateful I am to the BBC
for providing me with work,
particularly at this time
of year when things are a bit
thin for us announcers.
Um...
I don't know whether I should
tell you this, but...
Well, I have been going through
a rather tough time recently.
Things have been pretty
awful at home.
My wife, Josephine,
"Joe-jums," as I call her,
-who is also an announcer...
-JOSEPHINE: Hello.
ANNOUNCER 2: ...has not been
able to announce since our
youngest, Clifford, was born
and, well... I've just got
no confidence left.
I mean, I can't get up
in the morning,
I feel there's nothing
worth living for--
ANNOUNCER 3:
Hello, I'm another
announcer, my name's Dick.
Joe-jums just rang me and said
Jack was having a bad time
with this announcement,
so I've just come
to give him a hand.
-How is he, Joe-jums?
-JOSEPHINE: Pretty bad, Dick.
DICK:
Jack, it's Dick.
-Do you want me
to make the announcement?
-JACK: No.
No, Dick, I--
I must do it myself.
It's my last chance
with the BBC,
I can't throw it away.
I've got to do it for--
For Joe-jums, for the kids.
I've got to go
through with it.
DICK: Good man. Now, remember
your announcer's training:
deep breaths.
And try not to think about
what you're saying.
JACK:
Good evening. This is BBC 1.
JOSEPHINE:
Good luck, Jack.
DICK:
Keep going, old boy.
JACK:
It's 9:00
and time for the news
read... by Richard Baker.
-JOSEPHINE: You've done it.
-DICK: Congratulations, old man!
-JOSEPHINE:
Absolutely marvellous.
-JACK: Oh, thank God.
JOSEPHINE: Darling, you were
brilliant. No, no,
it's the best you ever did.
-JACK: Thank God. Really?
-JOSEPHINE:
It was absolutely superb.
DICK:
Here, Joe-jums, have a drink.
For God's sake, drink this.
Seriously, you were fabulous.
Your voice was superb.
-JACK: Didn't it shake too much?
-DICK: No, no, no.
-DICK: You were rock solid.
-JACK: Thanks very much.
DICK: Listen, I've got Babu
on the phone. He's on red.
-Can you speak to him?
-DICK: Can I?
DICK: He really thinks
it's marvelous.
JACK: Fantastic.
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
JACK: Oh, well, thank you.
DICK:
Hey, the least I could do.
DICK: I thought,
"I must come over."
JACK:
No, really, thanks.
Oh, I-- I just can't
possibly--
Can't tell you
how much that means.
DICK: I think it's
the turning point here.
I really do.
[ALL CHATTERING]
-JACK: Hello, Reggie. What?
-DICK: Is that Gordon on three?
JACK: Yes. Hang on, Reggie.
DICK:
Hello, Gordon?
[LAUGHING]
--until the name "Maudling"
is almost totally obscured.
That is the ned
of the nicro-not wens.
And now it's time
for the late-night flim.
[♪♪♪]
Oh...
Oh, pantomime horse,
that was wonderful.
Would you like
another glass?
Oh, no, no, I mustn't,
it makes me throw up.
Oh...
Oh, I'm so bleeding happy.
Oh, Simone!
Oh, pantomime horse.
Then...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Now, the English pantomime
horse has nearly caught up
with the Russian pantomime
horse. I think he's gonna
take him any moment--
But what is this?
What is this?
Yes, it's the pantomime
Princess Margaret
and the pantomime goose.
And they're attacking the
English horse and the Russian
pantomime horse has got away.
But who is this?
My goodness me, it's the Duke
of Kent to the rescue.
It's the Duke of Kent!
[INDISTINCT COMMENTARY]
GERMAN ANNOUNCER:
Here you see
some English comic actors
engaged in a life-or-death
struggle
with a rather weak ending.
This is typical
of the zany, madcap world
of the irresistible
kooky funsters.
The English
pantomime horse wins,
and so is assured of a place
in British history
and a steady job
in a merchant bank.
Unfortunately,
before his pension rights
are assured,
he catches bronchitis and dies.
Another victim of the need to
finish these shows on time.