NARRATOR:
In the modern Britain,
united under a great leader,
it's the housewives of Britain
who are getting things moving.
Here, a coach load of lovely
ladies are on their way
to speed up production
in a car factory.
And here we are, boys,
it's the no-hurry brigade,
hanging around for endless
overtime.
And just watch these gallant
girls go into action.
Not working fast enough?
Well, there's
an answer for that.
Yes, this is certainly the way
to speed up production.
This is the recipe
for increased productivity,
to meet the threat of those
nasty foreigners
when Britain takes
her natural place
at the head
of the British common market.
And how's this for a way
to beat strikers?
[ALL WHOOPING]
Those spotty continental boys
will soon have to look out for
Mrs. Britain.
And talking of windmills,
these girls aren't afraid
to tilt at the permissive
society.
Business is booming
in the so-called arts,
but two can play
at that game, chum.
And it's not just the modern
so-called plastic arts
that get the clean-up
treatment.
-Desdemona.
-Come on, dear.
Don't let that fool...
[ALL SHOUTING]
And those continentals
had better watch out
for their dirty foreign
literature.
Jean-Paul Sartre and
Jean Genet won't know
what's hit them.
Never mind the foulness
of their language,
come '73 they'll all
have to write in British.
You can keep your fastidious
continental bidets,
Mrs. Foreigner,
Mrs. Britain knows how to keep
her feet clean.
But she'll battle
like bingo boys
when it comes to keeping
the TV screen clean.
Better watch out for those
nasty continental shows
on the sneaky second channel.
But apart from attacking
that prurient hotbed
of left-wing continentalism
at Shepherd's Bush,
what else do these
ordinary mums think?
-Do they accept Hegelianism?
-No.
Do they prefer Leibnitz
to Wittgenstein?
No. No.
And where do they stand
on young people?
Just here, dearie.
Their power is growing daily,
and when these girls
roll their sleeves up,
it's arms all the way.
Yes, this is the way to fight
the constant war
against pornography.
[PLAYING ORGAN]
-And now...
-It's...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[♪♪♪]
[SOFT KNOCKING]
[LOUDER KNOCKING]
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Doctor!
-Doctor!
-[DINGING]
Doctor!
Doctor! Where is the doctor?
Hello.
Are you the brain specialist?
Are you the brain specialist?!
No!
No, I am not
the brain specialist.
No. No, I am not.
Yes! Yes, I am.
My brain hurts.
Well, let's take a look at it,
Mr. Gumby.
No, no, no,
my brain in my head.
Ohhh! Huh.
It will have to come out.
-Out of my head?
-Yes.
All the bits of it.
Nurse!
Nurse, take Mr. Gumby
to a.... brain surgeon.
Yes, doctor.
-Where's the lancet?
-NURSE: He's brilliant,
you know.
Where's the bloody lancet?
My brain hurts, too.
[SIREN WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
Gloves.
Glasses.
Moustache.
Handkerchief.
I'm going to operate.
ALL:
Operate.
Going to operate.
Get better, brain.
ALL:
Hello!
Ooh! We forgot
the anesthetic.
-Anesthetic.
-ALL: Anesthetic.
Anesthetic.
ALL:
I've come
to anesthetize you.
[METAL CLANGING]
-[FOOTSTEPS]
-[CLEARS THROAT]
Good evening. Tonight, I'd like
to talk to you about--
Oh, oh, uh...excuse me,
this is all wrong.
One moment.
[CLATTERING]
[METAL CLANGING]
Hello, again.
As I was saying...
Oh, wait, this is, uh,
still not quite right.
Sorry.
[CREAKING, CLATTERING]
No, no. Sorry?
No. No, not right.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[METAL CLANGING, CRASHING]
[WATER SPLASHING]
[BUZZER RINGING]
Ah. This is better.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now, tonight I want
to look at the
meaning of life--
No. Oh, ah, oh, ow.
[CLATTERING]
-[GIGGLING]
-[STAMMERS]
[CLATTERING]
[SQUABBLING, GRUNTING]
[METAL CLANGING]
[COW MOOS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[EXPLOSION, METAL CLANGING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Hmm. Oh, well.
This will do nicely.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Good evening.
Tonight, I'd like to talk
to you about the meaning of life
in the context of--
[SCREAMS]
The Nine O'clock News,
which was to have followed,
has been cancelled tonight,
so that we can bring you
the quarterfinals
of the All-Essex
Badminton Championship.
Your commentator, as usual,
is Edna O'Brien.
O'BRIEN:
Hello, fans.
Begorra, and to be sure
there's some fine badminton
down here in Essex
this afternoon.
We really--
[DOORBELL RINGS]
-Hmm... George?
-Yes, Gladys?
There's a man at the door
with a moustache.
Tell him I already got one.
All right, all right,
all right.
What's he want then?
He says do we want
a documentary on mollusks.
-Mollusks?
-Yes.
-What's he mean, "mollusks"?
-Mollusks!
Gastropods, lamellibranches,
cephalopods.
Oh, mollusks,
I thought you said "bacon".
All right, all right,
all right.
-What's he charge then?
-It's free.
Oh, where does he
want us to sit?
He says yes.
Good evening.
Tonight, mollusks.
The mollusk is a soft-bodied,
unsegmented,
invertebrate animal,
usually protected
by a large shell.
One of the most numerous
groups of invertebrates,
it is exceeded
in number of species
only by the arthropods, viz.
Not very interesting,
is it?
-What?
-I was talking to him.
Oh. Anyway, the typical
mollusk, viz., a snail,
consists of a prominent
muscular portion,
the head-foot,
a visceral mass, and a shell,
which is secreted by the free
edge of the mantle.
-Dreadful, isn't it?
-What?
I was talking to him.
Oh. Well, anyway,
in some mollusks, however,
viz., slugs,
the shell is absent
or rudimentary.
Switch him off.
Whereas in others,
viz., cephalopods
the head-foot
is greatly modified,
and forms tentacles,
viz., the squid.
-What are you doing?
-Switching you off.
-What? Don't you like it?
-Oh, it's dreadful.
-Embarrassing.
-Is it?
Yes, it's perfectly awful.
Disgraceful. I don't know how
they got the nerve
to put it on.
It's so boring.
Well, it's not much of
a subject, is it? Be fair.
What do you think, George?
Oh, give him
another 20 seconds.
-All right.
-Oh, um, anyway,
the majority of mollusks
are included
in three large groups:
The gastropods,
the lamellibranches
and the cephalopods.
We know that.
However,
what is more interesting
is the, uh, mollusks',
uh, s-sex life.
Ooh.
Yes, the mollusk
is a randy little fellow,
whose primitive brain
scarcely strays
from the subject
of you-know-what.
-Disgusting.
-Ought not to be allowed.
The randiest of the gastropods
is the limpet.
This hot-blooded little beast,
with its tent-like shell,
is always on the job.
Its extramarital activities
are something startling.
Frankly, I don't know how
the female limpet
finds the time to adhere
to the rock face.
-How am I doing?
-Disgusting.
-But more interesting.
-Oh, yes.
Another loose-living gastropod
is the periwinkle.
This shameless
little libertine,
with its characteristic
ventral locomotion,
is not the marrying kind.
"Anywhere, anytime,"
is its motto.
Up with the shell
and they're at it.
What about the lamellibranches?
I'm coming to them.
The great scallop.
Pwah! This tatty,
scrofulous old rapist
is second in depravity
only to the common clam.
This latter is a right whore.
A harlot. A trollop.
A cynical, bed-hopping,
firm-breasted,
Rabelaisian bit of seafood,
that makes Fanny Hill
look like a dead pope.
And finally, among
the lamellibranch bivalves,
that most depraved of the whole
subspecies, the whelk.
The whelk is nothing but a
homosexual of the worst kind.
This gay boy
of the gastropods,
this queer crustacean,
this mincing mollusk,
this screaming, prancing,
limp-wristed queen of the deep
makes me sick.
-Have you got one?
-Here.
-Let's kill it.
-Yeah.
Disgusting!
There, yeah,
that'll teach it.
Well, thank you for a very
interesting program.
Oh, not at all.
Thank you.
-Yes, that was very nice.
-Thank you.
-Oh, thank you.
-And good night.
And now a word from
the man in the--
-Street.
-Anyway.
[BABY TALK]
Hello. Oh, and dear little
fellow. Hey, hey. Look at him.
Oh, aye,
little twinkle in his eye.
[BABY TALK]
Oh, he is a little dear,
isn't he?
But you shouldn't let him
suck on a dummy, my dear.
Oh, my God.
No! Don't touch it.
[SUCTIONING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[WHEELS CREAKING]
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
The minister for not listening
to people toured Batley today
to investigate allegations
of victimization
in home-loan
improvement grants
made last week
by the shadow minister
for judging people
at first sight
to be marginally worse
than they actually are.
At the Home Office,
the minister
for inserting himself
in between chairs and walls
in men's clubs
was at his desk
after a short illness.
He spent the morning dealing
with the Irish situation,
and later in the day,
had long discussions
with the minister for running
up stairs two at a time,
flinging the door open, saying:
"Ha, ha, caught you, Mildred."
In the Commons, there was
another day of heated debate
on the third reading
of the Trade Practices Bill.
Mr. Roland Penrose,
the undersecretary for making
deep growling noises...
[GROWLS]
...launched a bitter
personal attack
on the ex-minister for delving
deep into a black satin bag
and producing a tube
of Euthymol toothpaste.
Later in the debate,
the junior minister
for being frightened
by any kind of farm machinery,
challenged the undersecretary
of state
for hiding from
Terence Rattigan
to produce the current year's
trading figures,
as supplied by the Department
of Stealing Packets
of Bandages
From the Self-Service
at Timothy White's,
and Selling Them Again
at a Considerable Profit.
Parliament rose at 11:30,
and, crawling along a dark
passageway
into the old rectory,
broke down the door
to the serving hatch,
painted the spare room,
and next weekend,
they'll be able to make a start
on the boy's bedroom,
while Amy and Roger,
up in London for two days,
go to see the mysterious
Mr. Grenville.
He in turn has been
revealed by D'Arcy
as less than an honest man.
Sybil feels once again a
resurgence of her old affection,
and she and Boileau return
to a little house
in Clermont-Ferrand.
The kind of two-up,
two-down house that
most French workers,
and, indeed, most workers
throughout the European
community,
are living in today.
PRESENTER:
The ease of construction,
using on-site prefabrication
facilities,
makes cheap housing a reality.
The walls of these houses
are lined with pre-stressed
asbestos,
which keeps the house
warm and snugly,
and ever so safe
from the big bad rabbit,
who can scratch and scratch
for all he's worth,
but he just can't
get into Porky's house.
Where is Porky?
Here he is.
What a funny little chap.
But Porky's
one of the lucky ones.
He survived the urban upheaval
of the '30s and '40s.
For him,
Jarrow is still just a memory.
The hunger marches,
the East End riots,
the collapse of the Labour
government in 1931.
Dim reminders
of the days before
a newfound affluence
swept the land,
making it clean and tidy,
and making all the shops
full of nice things,
lovely choo-choo trains
and toys,
and shiny cars that go
vroom, vroom, vroom.
And everybody was happy
and singing all the day long,
and nobody saw the big bad
rabbit ever again.
But of course, it's all
very easy to blame
the big, bad rabbit
when by-elections are going
against the government.
But how often do you think we
should be blaming ourselves?
Because, you know, that's where
we ought to start looking.
[♪♪♪]
MAN READS:
Hello. All the activity
you can see here in progress,
is part of the intricate--
Ah.
--preparations for the British
naval expedition to Lake Pahoe.
The leader of the expedition
is Sir Jane Russell.
What is the main purpose
of your expedition?
Well, this is a completely
uncharted lake,
with like hitherto
unclassified marine life, man,
so the whole scene's wide open
for scientific exploration.
One can see the immense amount
of preparation involved.
Have there been difficulties
in setting up this venture?
Well, the real hang-up
was with the bread, man,
but when the top-brass
pigs came through,
we got it together
in a couple of moons.
Commodore Betty Grable,
who's a real sub-aqua head,
has got it together diving-wise,
and, like, the whole gig's
-been a real gas, man.
-Thank you.
Lieutenant Commander
Dorothy Lamour.
Pieces of eight.
Dorothy, you're in charge
of the security
and liaison for
this operation.
Right on.
You've kept this all very
hush-hush so far, shipmate.
Yeah, it's been, uh,
really heavy, man,
with all these freaks
from the fascist press
trying to blow
the whole scene.
There's no doubt about it,
this expedition does have some
rather unusual aspects, Jim lad.
For starters,
why do the senior personnel
all bear the names of Hollywood
film stars of the '40s,
and female ones at that?
Shiver me timbers,
'tis the black spot.
And secondly-- I be not afraid
of thee, Blind Pew.
--why do they talk
this rather strange,
stilted,
underground jargon--?
Belay the main brace,
Squire Trelawney.
This be my ship now.
Ha, ha.
Ah. A tranquillizing dart
fired by the cowardly
BBC health-department dogs.
They've done filled me
full of chlorpromazine. Damn.
[SCREAMS]
I'm sorry about my colleague's
unconventional behavior.
The navy's out of sight.
Come together with the RN.
It really is something
other than else.
[♪♪♪]
Can you dig it, man?
Hello. I'm sorry about
my colleague's
rather unconventional
behavior just now,
but, uh, things haven't been
too easy for him recently.
Trouble at home.
Rather confidential,
so I can't give you
all the details,
interesting though they are.
[MUMBLING]
Three bottles of rum with a
Weetabix and so forth.
Anyway-- Apparently,
the girl wasn't even, uh--
Anyway, the activity
you see behind me--
It's the mother
I feel sorry for.
I-I'll start again.
The activity you see
is part of the preparations
for the new naval expedition
to Lake Pahoe.
The man in charge
of this expedition
is Vice Admiral
Sir John Cunningham.
-Sir John, hello there. Hello.
-Oh, hello.
Well, first of all, I'd like
to apologize for the behavior
of certain of my colleagues
you may have seen earlier.
But they are from broken homes,
circus families and so on.
And they are in no way
representative
of the new, modern,
improved British navy.
There is a small,
vociferous minority.
And may I take this
opportunity of emphasizing
that there is no cannibalism
in the British navy.
Absolutely none.
And when I say none, I mean
there is a certain amount,
more than I'm prepared
to admit.
But all new ratings
are warned
that if they wake up
in the morning, and find
any tooth marks at all,
anywhere on their bodies,
they're to tell me
immediately,
so that I can immediately
take every measure
to hush the whole thing up.
And finally,
necrophilia is right out.
Now, this expedition
is primarily to investigate
reports of cannibalism
and necrophilia in--
This expedition is primarily
to investigate
reports of unusual
marine life
in the as yet uncharted
Lake Pahoe.
And, uh,
where exactly is the lake?
Uh, 22-A Runcorn Avenue,
I think.
-Yes, that's right, 22-A.
-Runcorn Avenue?
Yes, i-it's just by Blenheim
Crescent. Do you know it?
You mean it's in, uh,
an ordinary street?
Of course it's not ordinary,
it's got a lake in it.
Yes, but I--
Look, how many streets
do you know that have
got lakes in them?
You mean--?
Is it very large?
Of course it's not large.
You couldn't get a large lake
in Runcorn Avenue.
You'd have to knock down
the tobacconist's.
Jenkins, no!
[♪♪♪]
I'm now standing
in Runcorn Avenue.
Sir John,
where exactly is the lake?
Now, let's see,
that's 18, that's 20,
so this must be the one.
Um, excuse me, um--
-Yes, this is the one
all right.
-But it's an ordinary house.
Look, I'm getting irritated
with this line of questioning.
But it doesn't even
look like a lake.
Your whole approach since
this interview started
has been to mock the navy.
When I think that it was
for the likes of you
I had both my legs blown off--
You haven't had both
your legs blown off.
I was talking metaphorically,
you fool.
Jenkins, put that down.
Right, is the equipment ready?
Diving equipment
all ready, man.
Right. Now, quite simply,
the approach to Lake Pahoe
is up the steps,
and then we come to the shores
of the lake.
Now, I'm going to
press the bell just to see
if there's anyone in.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hello.
Good morning.
I'm looking for a Lake Pahoe.
There's a Mr. Padgett.
No, no, a lake.
There's no lake here, mate.
This is Runcorn Avenue.
What's that camera doing?
Camera? What's he want?
Oh, are we on the telly?
He's looking for a lake.
Lake Pahoe.
Oh, you want downstairs, 22-A.
The basement.
Ah. Thank you very much.
Good morning.
Come on men, downstairs.
-Were you successful, Sir John?
-It's in the basement.
In the basement?
Pieces of eight.
-[GROANS]
-[BIRD THUDS]
Hello?
Ooh, I think it's someone
about the damp.
Hello?
Tell them about
the bleeding rats too.
I know. Yes?
SIR JOHN:
Good morning.
Is this Lake Pahoe?
Well, I don't know about that,
but it's bleeding damp.
Are you from the council?
SIR JOHN:
No. We are the official British
naval expedition to this lake.
May we come in?
Hang on.
[SCREAMS]
-Bloody sharks.
-Get back in.
-Get in.
Well, that would appear to be
the end of the expedition.
Magna Carta, was it a document
signed at Runnymede
in 1215 by King John,
pledging independence
to the English barons,
or was it a piece of chewing gum
on a bedspread in Dorset?
The latter idea
is the brainchild of a man
new to the field
of historical research.
Mr. Badger, why--
why are you on this program?
Uh, well, I think I can
answer this question
more successfully in mime.
But why Dorset?
Uh, well, I have for
a long time been suffering
from a species
of brain injury,
which I incurred during
the rigors of childbirth.
And I'd like to conclude by
putting my finger up my nose.
Mr. Badger, I think you're
the silliest person
we've ever had
on this program,
and so I'm gonna ask you
to have dinner with me.
My wife, Maureen, ran off
with a bottle of Bell's whisky
during the Aberdeen
versus Raith Rovers match,
which ended
in a goalless draw.
Robson, particularly in goal,
had a magnificent first half.
His fine positional sense
preventing the build-up
of any severe pressure
on the suspect
Aberdeen defense.
McLoughlan missed
an easy chance
to clinch the game
towards the final whistle,
but Raith must be well-satisfied
with their point.
Do, please, go on.
This is the least fascinating
conversation I've ever had.
Would you like to order, sir?
Ah, yes, Mr. Badger, what would
you like to start with?
Uh... I'll have a whisky
to start with.
-For first course, sir?
-Aye.
And for main course, sir?
Uh, I'll have a whisky
for main course,
and I'll follow that
with a whisky for pudding.
Yes, sir. And what would you
like with it, sir?
-A whisky?
-No, a bottle of wine.
"Fine, sir," he said
between clenched teeth,
knowing full well it was
the most unrewarding part.
This is the silliest sketch
I've ever been in.
Shall we stop it?
Yeah, all right.
[♪♪♪]