[APPLAUSE]
[♪♪♪]
-And now...
-It's...
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
NARRATOR:
The Adventures of Biggles.
Part 1:
Biggles Dictates a Letter.
Miss Bladder, take a letter.
Yes, Señor Biggles.
Don't call me "señor"!
I'm not a Spanish person.
You must call me "Mr. Biggles",
or "Group Captain Biggles"
or "Mary Biggles",
if I'm dressed as my wife.
But never "señor".
Sorry.
I've never even been to Spain.
You went to Ibiza last year.
That's still no grounds
for calling me "señor",
or "Don Biggles"
for that matter.
Right. Dear King Haakon.
Of Norway, is that?
Just put down what I say.
Do I put that down?
Of course you don't
put that down!
Well, what about that?
Look!
Don't put that down.
Just put down what I--
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Now, when I've got
these antlers on...
when I've got these antlers on,
I am dictating.
And when I take them off,
I'm not dictating.
"I'm not dictating."
What?
Read that back.
"Dear King Haakon,
I am not dictating. What?"
No, no, no, no,
you loopy brothel inmate.
I've had enough of this.
I'm not a courtesan.
Oh, oh, "courtesan."
Oh, aren't we grand?
"Harlot's" not good enough
for us, eh?
"Paramour, concubine,
fille de joie."
That's what we're not.
Well, listen to me,
my fine fellow.
You are a bit of tail,
that's what you are.
I am not, you demented
fictional character.
Algy says you are.
He says you're no better
than you should be.
And how would he know?
And just what do
you mean by that?
Are you calling
my old fictional
comrade-in-arms a fairy?
"Fairy"!
"Poof's" not good enough
for Algy, is it?
He's got to be
a bleeding fairy.
Mincing old RAF queen.
Algy, I have to see you.
ALGY [ON INTERCOM]:
Right-o.
What ho, everyone.
-[BIGGLES] Are you gay?
-I should bally well say so,
old fruit.
Ugh.
Dear King Haakon.
Oh. Dear, King Haakon.
Just a line to
thank you for the eels.
Mary thought they
were really scrummy, comma,
so did I, full stop.
I've just heard that Algy
was a poof, exclamation mark.
What would Captain W.E. Johns
have said, question mark.
Sorry to mench, but if you've
finished with the lawn edger,
could you pop it
in the post?
Love Biggles, Algy deceased,
and Ginger.
-Ginger!
-What?
Rhyming slang, ginger beer.
-Oh...
-Ginger.
-GINGER [ON INTERCOM]:
Hello, sweetie.
-Uh, I have to see you.
Yes, Biggles?
Are you a poof?
I should say not.
Thank God for that.
Good lad. Stout fellow.
Salt of the earth,
backbone of England.
Funny, he looks like a poof.
Dear Princess Margaret.
Hello.
Get back in the cupboard, you
pantomimetic royal person.
Lemon curry?
Dear real Princess Margaret,
thank you for the eels,
full stop.
They were absolutely delicious
and unmistakably regal,
full stop.
Sorry to mench,
but if you've finished
with the hair dryer,
could you pop it in the post?
Yours fictionally, Biggles.
Oh, P.S., see you at the
Saxe-Coburg's canasta evening.
That should puzzle her.
Si, Señor Biggles.
Silence, naughty
lady of the night!
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR:
Next week, Part 2:
Biggles Flies Undone.
-Wheee!
-Oooh!
[HELICOPTER ROTOR
SOUNDS]
Baaah!
Whaaa!
Whaaaaaa!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CRASHING]
NARRATOR:
Meanwhile,
not very far away...
ANNOUNCER:
Climbing.
The world's loneliest sport,
where hardship and philosophy
go hand in glove.
And here, another British
expedition,
attempting to be the first man
to successfully climb
the north face of the
Uxbridge Road.
This four-man rope has been
climbing tremendously.
BBC cameras were there
to film every inch.
The major assault
on the Uxbridge Road
has been going on
for about three weeks...
really, ever since they
established base camp
here at the junction of
Willesden Road.
From there, they climbed
steadily to establish Camp Two,
outside Lewis's, and it's
taken them another three days
to establish Camp Three,
here outside the post office.
Well, they've spent a good
night in there last night,
in preparation for
the final assault today.
The leader of the expedition
is 29-year-old Bert Tagg,
a local headmaster and
mother of three.
Bert, uh, how's it going?
Oh, it's a-- It's a bit
gripping, is this, Chris.
I've got to, uh, try and reach
that bus stop in an hour or so
and, eh, I'm doing it
by-- Damn.
I'm doing it by--
by layback up this gutter.
So I'm kind of guttering and--
and laying back at
the same time,
and philosophizing.
Uh, Bert, some
people say this is crazy.
Aye, well, they said
Crippen was crazy,
didn't they?
Well, Crippen was crazy.
Oh, well,
there you are, then.
Eh, John, I'm sending you down
this carabiner on white.
Lemon curry?
Now, see, he's putting in
a peg down there
because I'm quite
a way up now
and if I come unstuck here,
I go down quite a long way.
[LAUGHS]
Such quiet courage
is typical of the way
these brave chaps
shrug off danger.
Like it or not,
you've got to admire
the skill that goes into it.
Ahhh!
[ALL SCREAMING]
[WIND HOWLING]
Oh, it's terrible
up on deck.
Up on deck?
Yeah, on deck.
It's diabolical weather.
Uh, what deck, dear?
The deck.
The deck of the lifeboat.
This isn't a lifeboat, dear.
This is 24 Parker Street.
This is the Newhaven lifeboat.
No, it's not, dear.
[WIND HOWLING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
You're right.
This isn't a lifeboat
at all.
No, I wouldn't live here
if it was.
Do you mind if I sit down for
a minute and collect my wits?
No, you do that.
I'll make a nice cup of tea.
Thanks very much, thanks.
-[WIND HOWLING]
-It's a wild night up top.
Your turn on deck soon,
Charlie.
It's not a lifeboat, Frank.
-What?
-What do you mean?
It's not a lifeboat.
It's this lady's house.
[WIND HOWLING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Captain!
Captain, ahoy, there!
-MAN 2: Ahoy, there!
-MAN 1: Ahoy, there!
-MAN 1: Captain?
Who's that shouting?
It's a man outside number 24.
Try it on the five-inch,
Gladys.
I can't. I got that fixed on
the Baileys at number 13.
Their new lodger
moves in today.
Alright, hold 13
on the five-inch
and transfer the Cartwrights
to the digital scanner.
Okay.
Hold on, Mrs. Pettigrew's
coming back from the doctor's.
Oh, bring her up on two.
What's the, uh--
What's the duration reading
on the oscillator?
Forty-eight-point-four-seven.
Well, that's a long time
for someone who's just
had a routine checkup.
Yeah, her pulse rate's 146!
Zoom in on the 16 mil
and hold her, Enid.
Roger, Gladys.
I'll try and get her
on the 12-inch.
GLADYS: Move the curtain, Enid.
Thank you, love.
Yes, it's one of those
new self-righting models.
Newhaven was about the first
place in the country to get one.
What's the displacement
on one of them jobs?
Oh, about 140-150
per square inch.
Uh, who's for fruitcake?
-ALL: Oh, yes, please, please.
-Yes?
Right, uh, macaroons.
That's two dozen fruitcakes,
half a dozen macaroons.
Right, then.
Won't be a jiffy, then.
[WIND HOWLING]
Yoo-hoo!
Mrs. Edwards!
-Hello.
-Hello, love.
I want two dozen
fruitcakes,
and half a dozen
macaroons.
Oh, sorry, love,
no macaroons.
How about some nice
vanilla sponge?
Yeah, that'd be
lovely.
-Right-o.
-[HORN BLOWS]
Ooh! There's that nice
herring trawler
come for their cupcakes.
-Excuse me.
-Right-o.
Hello, Captain Smith?
CAPTAIN SMITH [OVER MEGAPHONE]:
Hello!
Cupcakes to starboard!
Coming!
For crying out loud.
Don't forget your fruitcake.
Oh, yes,
throw 'em in.
I'll pay you at
the end of the week.
Here you are.
Okay, right-o.
-All right.
-[HORN BLOWS]
[CHOIR SINGS]
Here! It's the Ark Royal,
Doris.
Have you got their
rock buns ready?
[HORN BLOWS]
Hang on!
Yes.
Here we are.
Uh, five for them
and five for HMS Eagle.
-Right-o.
-All right.
[GRUNTING]
Yes?
HMS Defiant.
Two set teas, please.
Two set teas, Doris.
That'll be 48 pence.
-There we are, thank you.
-Yeah.
By the way,
do you do lunches?
No, morning kippers
and teas only.
Right-o, then.
[♪♪♪]
Good evening and welcome to
another edition of Storage Jars.
On tonight's program,
Mikos Antoniarkis,
the Greek rebel leader
who seized power in Athens
this morning,
tells us what he keeps
in storage jars.
[FANFARE]
From strife-torn Bolivia,
Ronald Rodgers reports on
storage jars there.
[FANFARE]
And, closer to home,
the first dramatic pictures
of the mass jailbreak
near the storage-jar factory
in Maidenhead.
All this and more
in Storage Jars.
This is La Paz, Bolivia.
Behind me, you can hear
the thud of mortars,
and the high-pitched
whine of rockets
as the battle for control
of this volatile republic
shakes the foundations
of this old city.
But whatever
their political inclinations,
these Bolivians are all
keen users of storage jars.
Here, the largest size is used
for rice and for mangos,
a big local crop.
And unlike most revolutionary
South American states,
they've an intermediary size
in between the two-pound
and five-pound jars.
This gives this poor
but proud people
a useful jar for apricots,
plums and stock cubes.
The smallest jar?
This little two-ounce jar,
for sweets, chocolates
and even little shallots.
No longer used in the West,
it remains here
as an unspoken monument
to the days
when La Paz knew
better times.
Ronald Rodgers,
Storage Jars, La Paz.
MAN [ON TV]:
In London, the prime minister
met officials
from the Department
of the Environment
to discuss the whole question
of national parks.
[CONTINUES INDISTINCT]
A cassette-tape recorder is
to replace the salon quartets
and trios
which have played beside the
potted palms at Manchester Town
Hall reception
for nearly 100 years.
A shortage in money has caused
a switch to taped music.
It will be relayed over
a new public address system,
replacing one which relayed
both music
and the clink of glasses
to other reception halls.
Stock market prices
hit record levels
in the last part of the year.
The Financial Times index
rose 3.7 points to 476.5,
the highest increase from July.
[MECHANICAL WHIRRING]
[CONTINUES INDISTINCT]
The BBC has reported that
radio-free Solent,
a pirate station,
was marking the first birthday
of the BBC--
Henry,
turn that television off.
You know it's bad
for your eyes.
Yes, dear.
Ah, that's better.
Henry, will you stop
sitting around?
-Yes, dear.
-There's an entire TV studio
waiting around here
to do the next link.
[OPENS, CLOSES DOOR]
And when you've got that done,
I've got some more work for you.
Yes, dear.
Henry, do you hear me?!
Henry!
Henry, get a move on!
Now, you sod!
That's better.
Hup, two, hup, two, hup, two,
hup, two, hup, two.
[PANTING]
CROWD [YELLING]:
Hurray!
Hello. I'm the good fairy
from Program Control,
where we're all grateful for
your work on this link.
So much so that
I'm here to release you
from the evil spell
you've been under.
Huh?
Mwah!
Hmm. Well, it doesn't always
work the first time.
Mwah. Mwah.
Mwah.
Mwah!
[CROAKS]
Thank you, mind you.
No, no need to.
You see, it's all in a day's
work for Program Control.
[♪♪♪]
MAN READS:
Hello, the, uh, show so far.
Well, it all started with
the organist losing his clothes
as he sat down at the organ.
And after this had happened,
uh, and we had seen
the titles of the show,
we saw Biggles dictating
a letter to his secretary
who thought he was Spanish,
and whom he referred to
as a harlot
and a woman of the night,
although she preferred
to be called a "courtesan".
[CHUCKLES]
Then we saw some people trying
to climb a road in Uxbridge.
And then there were
some cartoons,
and then some lifeboatmen came
into a woman's sitting room,
and, uh, after a bit,
the woman went out to buy some,
uh, cakes on a-- a lifeboat.
And then a-- a naval officer
jumped into the sea.
Uh, then we saw a man telling us
about storage jars from Bolivia,
and then there were some
more cartoons,
and then a man told us about
what had happened on the show
so far
and a great hammer came
and hit him on the head.
I don't remember that.
Lemon curry?
[FOLK MUSIC PLAYING]
[FOLK MUSIC CONTINUES]
Morning, sir.
Good morning, um...
I was, uh, sitting
in the public library
on Thurmon Street just now,
skimming through Rogue Herries
by Horace Walpole
when I, um, suddenly
came over all peckish.
Peckish, sir?
-Esurient.
-Eh?
[IN SCOUSE ACCENT]:
Eee, I were all hungry, like!
Oh, hungry.
[NORMAL VOICE]:
In a nutshell.
So I thought to myself,
a little fermented curd
will do the trick.
So I curtailed my Walpoling
activities, sallied forth
and infiltrated your place
of purveyance
to negotiate the vending
of some cheesy comestibles.
MAN: Come again?
[IN SCOUSE ACCENT]:
I want to buy some cheese.
Oh, I thought you were
complaining about the music.
[NORMAL VOICE]: Oh, heaven
forbid. I am one who delights
in all manifestations
-of the terpsichorean muse.
-MAN: Sorry?
[IN SCOUSE ACCENT]:
I like a nice dance.
You're forced to.
-Anyway.
-Who said that?
Well, my good man,
some cheese, please.
Yes, certainly, sir.
What would you like?
Well, how about
a little Red Leicester?
I'm afraid we're fresh out
of Red Leicester, sir.
Never mind.
How are you on, uh, Tilsit?
Never at the end of the week,
sir. Always get it fresh
first thing on Monday.
Tish-tish.
No matter.
Umm...
Well, four ounces of Caerphilly,
then, if you please,
stout yeoman.
Ah. Well, it's been on order
for two weeks, sir. I was
expecting it this morning.
Yes, it's not my day,
is it?
Ah, Bel Paese?
Sorry.
Red Windsor?
Normally, sir, yes.
-But today, the van broke down.
-Ah.
Uh, Stilton?
Sorry.
-Gruyère? Emmental?
-No.
-Any Norwegian Jarlsberg?
-Liptauer?
-No.
-Lancashire?
-White Stilton?
-No.
-Danish Blue?
-Double Gloucester?
-No.
-Cheshire?
-Any Dorset Blue Vinney?
-No.
Brie, Roquefort,
Pont l'evêque,
Port Salut, Savoyard,
Saint-Paulin,
Carre de l'est, Boursin,
Bresse Bleu,
Perle de Champagne,
Camembert?
Ah. We do have some
Camembert, sir.
You do, excellent.
It's a bit runny, sir.
Oh, I like it runny.
Well, as a matter of fact,
it's very runny, sir.
No matter. No matter.
Hand over...
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
I think it's runnier
than you'd like it, sir.
I don't care how
excrementally runny it is.
Hand it over with all speed.
Yes, sir.
Ohhhh!
What?
The cat's eaten it.
-Has he?
-She, sir.
-Gouda?
-No.
-Edam? Caithness?
-No. No.
-Smoked Austrian?
-No.
-Sage Derby?
-No, sir.
You do have some cheese?
Certainly, sir.
It's a cheese shop, sir.
-We've got--
-No, no, no.
No, don't tell me.
I'm keen to guess.
Fair enough.
-Wensleydale.
-Yes, sir?
Splendid! Well, I'll have
some of that, then, please.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir, I thought
you were referring to me,
Mr. Wensleydale.
Heh.
-Gorgonzola?
-No.
-Parmesan? Mozzarella?
-No. No.
-Pipo Crème?
-No.
-Any Danish Fynbo?
Czechoslovakian
sheep's milk cheese?
No.
Venezuelan beaver cheese?
Not today, sir, no.
Well, let's keep it simple.
Um, how about cheddar?
Well, I'm afraid we don't get
much call for it
around these parts, sir.
Not much call--?
It's the single most
popular cheese in the world.
Not round these parts, sir.
And pray, what is
the most popular cheese
round these parts?
Ilchester, sir.
I see.
Yes, sir. It's quite
staggeringly popular
in the manor, squire.
-Is it?
-Yes, sir, it's our
number one seller.
-Is it?
-Yes, sir.
-Ilchester, eh?
-Right.
Okay, I'm game.
"Have you got any?" he asked,
expecting the answer "no".
I'll have a look, sir.
[HUMMING]
No.
It's not much of
a cheese shop, really, is it?
Finest in the district, sir.
What leads you to that
conclusion?
Well, it's so clean.
Well, it's certainly
uncontaminated by cheese.
You haven't asked me about
Limburger, sir.
Is it worth it?
Could be.
Okay.
Have you got--? Will you shut
that bloody dancing up?!
Told you so.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Have you got any Limburger?
-No.
-No, that figures.
It was pretty predictable,
really.
It was an act of pure optimism
to have posed the question
in the first place.
Tell me something,
do you have any cheese at all?
Yes, sir.
Now, I'm going to ask you
that question once more.
And if you say no,
I'm going to shoot you
through the head.
Now, do you have
any cheese at all?
No.
Uugh!
What a senseless waste
of human life.
[♪♪♪]
Hugh Walpole's Rogue Cheddar,
one of the first of the
cheese Westerns. [SNIFFS]
To be later followed by
Gunfight at Gruyère Corral,
Ilchester '73,
and The Cheese Who
Shot Liberty Valance.
While I'm on the
subject of Westerns,
I want to take a closer look
at one of my favorite film
directors. [SNIFFS]
Sam Peckinpah, the expatriate
from Fresno, California.
[SNIFFS]
In his earliest films,
Major Dundee...
[SNIFFING] ...The Wild Bunch,
and Straw Dogs...
[SNIFFS] ...he showed
his predilection for
the utterly truthful,
and very sexually arousing,
portrayal of violence...
[SNIFFING]
...in its darkest form.
In his latest film, Peckinpah
has moved into the calmer,
and more lyrical waters...
[SNIFFS]
...of Julian Slade's Salad Days.
[♪♪♪]
Hello, everybody.
ALL [IN UNISON]:
Hello, Lionel.
I say, what a simply
super day.
ALL [IN UNISON]:
Gosh, yes.
It's so, you know,
sunny.
Yes, isn't it?
I say, anyone for tennis?
Oh, super!
What fun.
I say, Lionel, catch.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, crikey.
[SCREAMS] Oh, crikey!
Damn it!
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[INJURED PEOPLE GROANING]
Pretty strong meat there,
from... [SNIFFS] Sam Peckinpah.
[GUNSHOTS]
[GROANS]
[YELLS]
[♪♪♪]
MAN READS:
MAN 2 READS:
We've just heard that
an explosion in the kitchens
of the House of Lords,
has resulted in the breakage
of 17 storage jars.
Police rule out foul play.
Lemon curry?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Um, I'm sorry about the, uh...
the, uh... pause.
Only, um, I'm afraid the show
is a couple of minutes short
this week.
Um, you know, sometimes, uh,
the shows aren't really quite
as--as, uh, as long as they
ought to be.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Uh, look, there's not really
a-a great deal of point
in your sort of
hanging on at your end,
because I'm afraid
there aren't any more, uh,
jokes or anything.