[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING]
PITHER:
August the 18th.
Fell off near Bovey Tracey.
The pump caught
in my trouser leg.
My pump caught
in my trouser leg,
and my sandwiches
were badly crushed.
Thirty-five p, please.
These sandwiches were
an excellent substitute.
Give us ten woods,
Barney.
Hello. It's funny how one can
go through life, as I have,
disliking bananas and being
indifferent to cheese,
but still be able
to eat and enjoy
a banana-and-cheese sandwich
like this.
-Thirty-five p.
-Oh.
Oh, I have only a 50.
Do you have change?
Well, I'll have to look,
-but I may have to
go to the bank.
-I'm most awfully sorry.
-Fifteen p.
-Oh, what a stroke of luck.
Well, all the very best.
And thank you again
for the excellent
banana-and-cheese delicacy.
[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING]
PITHER:
August the 23rd. Fell off
near Budleigh Salterton.
And the pump got caught
in my trouser leg.
And that's how
they were damaged.
The eggs. You remember,
the hard-boiled eggs
I was telling you about.
They were in a Tupperware
container,
reputedly self-sealing,
which fell open
upon contact
with the tarmacadam surface
of the road.
The B489.
The Dawlish Road.
That shouldn't happen to
a self-sealing container,
now, should it?
What do you keep
your hard-boiled eggs in?
I think, in future,
I will lash them to the
handlebars with adhesive tape.
This should obviate a recurrence
of the same problem.
Well, I can't stand around
here chatting all day.
I'm on a cycling tour
of North Cornwall.
Must be off.
[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING, COW MOOS]
PITHER:
August the 26th. Fell off
near Ottery St. Mary.
The pump caught
in my trouser leg.
Decided to wear short
trousers from now on.
[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING, HORSE WHINNIES]
PITHER:
Fell off near Tiverton.
Perhaps a shorter pump
is the answer.
Excuse me, madam,
I wonder if you could tell me
of a good bicycle shop
in this village
where I can either find a means
of adapting my present pump,
or, failing that,
of purchasing a replacement?
There's only one shop here.
What a stroke of luck.
Now perhaps cycling
will become less precarious.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Yes?
Um, a Mr. Pither
to see you, doctor.
His bicycle pump
got caught in his sock.
Ah, thank you, nurse,
show him in, please.
This way, please.
Morning.
And a very good morning
to you too, doctor.
I understand
you had an accident.
That's right.
My pump got--
-Caught in your sock.
-Absolutely, yes.
My fruitcake
was damaged on one side.
Well, now--
In fact,
it's got grit all over it.
Well, now,
are you in pain?
-Oh, heavens no.
-Well, where are you hurt?
Fortunately,
I escaped without injury.
Well, what is the trouble?
Please, could you tell me
the way to Iddesleigh?
-I'm a doctor, you know.
-Oh, yes, absolutely.
Normally, I would have asked
a policeman or a minister
of the church.
But finding no one available,
I thought it better
to consult a man with
professional qualifications,
rather than rely on
the possibly confused
testimony of a passerby.
Oh, all right.
Take this to a chemist.
Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[MUSIC STOPS]
PITHER:
September the 2nd.
Did not fall off
outside Iddesleigh.
[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING]
PITHER:
Fell off in Tavistock.
My foot caught
in my trouser leg,
and that's how
the bottle broke.
Tell her today,
you could ring her.
I can't. I can't.
I said you'd never guess.
Sixteen years
we've been together.
I can't just
ring her up.
If you can't do it now,
you never will.
Do you like Tizer?
-What? No.
-Look.
Do you want me or not, James?
It's your decision.
I suppose it is still
available in this area.
Do you want me or not,
James?
-What?
-A Tizer.
Yes or no?
Is it still available
in this area?
-I don't know.
-I see.
In that case,
it's goodbye forever, James.
No. I mean, yes.
Oh, it is, is it?
-No!
-Oh!
You never could
make up your mind.
I can.
Goodbye, James.
I have.
No, wait, Lucille.
Does your lovely little
daughter like Tizer, eh?
Lucille!
Wouldn't mind buying her
a bottle of Tizer.
If it's still available
in this area, that is.
Would you like me
to show you the door?
Oh, that's kind of you,
but I saw it on the way in.
You stupid little rat!
The very words of the garage
mechanic in Bude.
I'd just fallen off my bicycle--
This is most kind of you.
--and my lemon curd tartlet--
Damn your lemon curd tartlet!
[SOBBING]
Hmph. Hm.
Just had a chat
with your dad.
[CRYING]
[♪♪♪]
[CRASHING]
My rubber instep caught on the
rear mudguard stanchion and--
Really? And what happened
to the corned-beef rolls?
The rolls were crushed
out of all--
How did you know about
my corned beef rolls?
I noticed them, or what remained
of them, in the road.
I noticed also
that the lemon curd tart
had sustained
some superficial damage.
That's right.
The curd had become--
-Detached from the pastry base.
-Absolutely right, yes.
Otherwise, the contents
of the sandwich box
were relatively unharmed,
although I detected
small particles of bitumen
in the chocolate cupcakes.
But they were wrapped
in foil.
Not the hard chocolate top,
I'm afraid.
Oh, that's the bit I like.
The sausage roll, the crisps
and the ginger biscuit
were unscathed.
How do you know
so much about cycling?
Well, I'm making a special study
of accidents involving food.
-Really?
-Yes.
Do you know, in our
laboratories, we have
developed a cheese sandwich
that can withstand an impact of
4000 pounds per square inch?
-Good heavens.
-Amazing, isn't it?
We've also developed a tomato
which can eject itself
when an accident is imminent.
-Even in an egg-and-tomato roll?
-Anywhere.
Even in your stomach,
it senses an accident,
it'll come up your throat
and out of the window.
You know what this means?
-Safer food!
-Exactly.
No longer will food be squashed,
crushed and damaged
by the ignorance
and stupidity of the driver.
Whole picnics will be
built to withstand
the most enormous forces.
Snacks will be safer
than ever.
A simple pot of salad dressing,
treated in our laboratories
has been subjected to the impact
of a 4000-pound steam hammer
every day for
the last 16 years.
-And has it broken?
-Well--
Of course it has. But there
are things that haven't.
Safety straps for sardines,
for example.
-[WHIZZING NOISE]
-Here, that tomato's
just ejected itself.
Really?
It works! It works!
[CRASHING]
PITHER:
What a strange turn
this cycling tour has taken.
Mr. Gulliver appears
to have lost his memory,
and far from being interested
in safer food
is now convinced
that he is Clodagh Rodgers,
the young girl singer.
I am taking him
for medical attention.
Is this
the Casualty Department?
Yes, that's right.
[CRASHING]
And what can I do for you?
[SCREAMS]
I am at present on a cycling
tour of the North Cornwall area
taking in Bude and--
Yes. Could I have
your name, please?
Ah. My name is Pither.
-What?
-P-I-T-H-E-R.
As in brotherhood, except
with a "P-I" instead of a
"B-R-O", and no "hood."
I see.
-I had just visited Taunton--
-[CRASHING]
Shh!
--and was cycling north
towards the--
Yes, where were
you injured?
Oh, just where
the A237 Ilfracombe--
-On your body.
-Ah!
No, no, it's not I who was
injured, it's my friend.
-Name?
-Pither.
No, no, no.
Your friend's name.
Oh, Clodagh Rodgers.
Clodagh Rodgers?
Well, only since about 4:30--
Yes. I think you'd better
talk to Dr. Wu. Doctor?
What? Damn.
[SCREAMS]
What's the trouble?
I'm on a cycling tour
of North Cornwall--
He thinks
he's had an accident.
I have friend who,
as a result of his injuries,
thinks he is Clodagh Rodgers.
-He what?
-Well, what happened was--
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[SCREAMING]
PITHER:
September the 4th.
Well, I never.
We are now in the
Alpes-Maritimes region
of Southern France.
Clodagh seems more intent
on reaching Moscow
than on rehearsing
her new BBC 2 series
with Buddy Rich
and the Younger Generation.
Oh, hello.
We cannot stay here.
We must leave immediately.
There is a ship
in Marseilles.
I did enjoy your song
for Europe, Clodagh.
I have seen an agent
in the town.
My life is in danger.
Danger, Clodagh?
Stalin has always hated me.
No one hates you, Clodagh.
I will not let myself fall
into the hands of these scum.
I think you should go have
a little lie-down, my dear.
It's a busy day tomorrow of
concerts and promotional tours.
I was one of the founders
of the greatest nation on earth!
I, whom Lenin has called
his greatest friend.
-[MAN SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
-Oh, dear.
I, who have worked all my life
that my people should live.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
Oh, my name is Pither.
Oh, you are English?
Yes, that's right.
I'm on a cycling tour
of North Cornwall--
I will not be defeated.
I will return to my country
to fight against
this new tyranny!
This is Clodagh Rodgers,
the Irish-born girl singer.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
"Jack in the Box."
♪ I'm just a jack-in-the-box ♪
♪ You know
Whenever love knocks ♪
♪ I'm gonna bounce up and down
On my spring ♪
♪ Bam, bam, bam ♪
Michelle, Paul!
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
And I will never surrender!
-I will never surrender.
-Excusez-moi, Madame Clodagh.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
-Wha...?
-[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Trotsky?
[BOTH SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
...Lenin.
Ah, Lenin.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
♪ If I ruled the world ♪
♪ Every day would be
The first day of spring ♪
Lenin. My friend. I come!
Oh, excuse her, she has not
been very well recently.
Pressure of work, laryngitis,
you know.
[IN FRENCH]
"Little White Bull," eh?
Oh, formidable.
Lenin!
-Clodagh! Clodagh, my dear!
-GULLIVER: Lenin.
I come.
I come. My friend, I come.
Lenin!
Clodagh!
Lenin.
Je t'aime...
Mmm.
Maurice, regardez!
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[BOTH SINGING IN FRENCH]
♪ You know
Whenever love knocks ♪
♪ I'm gonna bounce up and down
On my spring ♪
PITHER:
After several days,
I succeeded in tracking down
my friend, Mr. Gulliver,
on the outskirts of Smolensk.
Smolensk,
200 miles east of Minsk.
Two hundred north of Kursk.
Fifteen hundred miles
west of Omsk.
Thank you.
PITHER:
Anyway, as we were
so far from home,
and as Mr. Gulliver,
still believing himself
to be Trotsky,
was very tired from haranguing
the masses from Monte Carlo--
Monte Carlo.
Hundred miles south of Turin.
Hundred miles east of Pisa.
Five hundred miles
west of Bilbao.
Thank you.
I decided to check--
PITHER:
Sorry, you go on.
I decided
to check him into a hotel
while I visited
the British Embassy
to ask for help
in returning to Cornwall.
And so we registered
at the Smolensk
Young Men's
Anti-Christian Association.
YMACA. Corner of Anti-Semitic
Street and Pogrom Square.
Go away. No, not you.
No, no, no.
A single room
for my friend, please?
Yes, sir.
Bugged or unbugged?
I think I'd be happier
with a bugged one.
Right, one bugged with bath.
Well, just have a nice
lie-down and I'll go down to
the Embassy.
Trotsky?
My lack of God, it's Trotsky!
Comrades.
Socialism is not a--
[♪♪♪]
Oh, uh, excuse me.
Is this the British Consulate?
Yes, yes, si, si,
that is correct.
Yes. Piccadilly Circus,
miniskirt and Joe Lyons.
Oh. I'd to see the consul,
please.
Yes, yes, speaky-speaky,
me Blitish consul.
Oh.
You are Rear Admiral
Sir Dudley Compton?
No. He died.
He have heart attack
and fell out of window
onto exploding bomb
and was killed
in a shooting accident.
Oh, yes.
I his, how you say...?
Succa...
Sussor...
Oh, successor.
I'm his successor,
yes, Mr. Atkinson.
Oh.
Would you like drinky,
or game bingo?
Oh. A drink
would be very nice, yes.
Mr. Livingstone.
-Go get sake.
-Yes, boss.
Oh.
How is Tunblidge Wells?
How I long to see again
walls of famous
Shakespeare-style theatre
in Stlatford-on-Avon.
I'm a West Country man myself,
Mr. Atkinson.
Oh, Texas, Arizona,
Kit Carson, super scout.
No, no. West of England.
Cornwall.
Oh. Coronworl.
Coronworl. Oh, yes,
know Coronworl very well.
Went to school there,
mother and father live there.
Oh, yes, go many weekend parties
and polo playing in blidge club.
Belong many clubs
in Coronworl.
Ah, Mr. Livingstone, thank you.
Sake and Bakewells tart.
Well, chaps,
buttocks up.
Rather.
-Now, Mr...?
-Ah, Pither.
Mr. Pither,
we Blitish here in Smolensk
very interested in clicket.
Oh, cricket?
No, no. You no speak English
very wells.
No. Not clicket, clicket.
Clickety-click. Clicket.
Housey, housey. Bingo.
-Oh, bingo.
-Oh, bingo!
-Bingo!
Bingo. Bingo.
ALL:
Bingo! Bingo! Bingo!
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Bingo!
Sorry. Our boys
got very excited.
-Bingo.
-Shut face!
Now, Mr. Pither, perhaps you
could put in good word for us
so we can join a very smart
bingo club in Coronworl.
Well,
it's not really my--
We sit very quiet at back,
not say anything
except shout "housey, housey."
Housey, housey!
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
CROWD:
Housey, housey!
[SHOUTING IN CHINESE
GIBBERISH]
...bingo cards!
Bingo cards.
[BOTH SPEAKING
IN CHINESE GIBBERISH]
Now, Mr. Pither,
tell me which better:
Hackney Star Bingo or
St. Albans Top Rank Suite?
I was hoping you could
help me and my friend
get back to England.
Hackney Star Bingo.
You see, we're on a cycling
tour of North Cornwall.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE
GIBBERISH]
Bingo. Bingo. Bingo.
Housey, housey!
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Is Mr. Trotsky in his room,
please?
No.
He has gone to Moscow.
Moscow.
Fifteen hundred miles south--
-Shut up!
-Moscow?
Come with us, please.
Oh, who are you?
Well, we're not
secret police, anyway.
That's for sure.
If anything, we are ordinary
Soviet citizens
with no particular interest
in politics.
None at all.
Come with us.
Oh,
where are you taking me?
What do we tell him?
-Don't tell him any secrets.
-Agreed.
Tell him anything except
we're taking him to Moscow
where Trotsky is reuniting
with the Central Committee.
We are taking you
to a clambake.
Oh, a clambake. I've never
been to one of those.
Right, let's go.
Who's giving orders
around here?
I am. I'm senior to you.
No. You're a greengrocer,
I'm an insurance salesman.
Greengrocers are senior
to insurance salesmen.
-No, they're not.
-Cool it!
I'm an ice cream salesman,
I am senior to both of you.
You're an ice cream
salesman?
I thought you were
a veterinarian.
I got promoted.
-Taxi.
-CABBY: Yes.
Drive us to Moscow.
-I have no cab.
-Why not?
I'm in the secret police.
[♪♪♪]
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
And now, comrades,
the greatest moment
of a great day,
the moment when I ask you
to welcome the return
of one of Russia's
greatest heroes,
creator of the Red Army,
Lenin's greatest friend,
Lev Davidovich Trotsky!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Comrades, Bolsheviks,
friends of the revolution,
I am returned.
The bloodstained shadow of
Stalinist repression is past.
I bring you the new light
of permanent revolution.
I may have been ousted
from power,
I may have been expelled from
the party in 1927,
I may have been
deported in 1926...
♪ But I'm just
An old-fashioned girl ♪
♪ With an old-fashioned mind ♪
Comrades, I don't want
to destroy in order to build.
I don't want a state founded
on hate and division.
♪ I want
An old-fashioned house ♪
♪ With an old-fashioned fence ♪
♪ And an old-fashioned
Millionaire ♪
PITHER:
Our friend, Mr. Gulliver,
was clearly undergoing
another change of personality.
So you have duped us.
You shall pay for this.
Guards, seize him!
♪ The sound of oil wells ♪
♪ As they slurp
Slurp, slurp...♪
Shall I seize him too?
No, I think we have to keep
him, he's going down well.
He's more fun
than he used to be.
He's loosened up a lot.
This is an old Lenin number.
♪ That are labeled
"Hers" and "hers"... ♪
PITHER:
April 26th.
Thrown into Russian cell.
Severely damaged my Mars bar.
Shall I ever see
Bude bus station again?
Oh, excuse me.
What a pleasant exercise yard.
How friendly
they were all being.
Cigarette?
Oh, no, thank you,
I don't smoke.
After a few moments,
I perceived a line
of gentlemen with rifles.
They were looking
in my direction.
I looked around,
but could not see the target.
Blindfold?
No, thank you, no.
[SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN]
[DRUMROLL]
Nyet! Nyet!
Nyet!
A telegram?
From the Kremlin.
The Central Committee.
It says:
"Carry on
with the execution."
[SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN]
[DRUMROLL]
PITHER:
Now I was really for it.
[SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN]
How could you miss?
He moved.
Shut up. Go and practice.
I'm so sorry. Would you mind
waiting in your cell?
PITHER:
What a stroke of luck.
My Crunchie was totally intact.
I settled down
to a quick inter-meal snack.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
-[DRUMROLL]
-[OFFICER SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN]
[GUNSHOTS]
Next time, definitely.
Now, how many
have been injured?
Oh, God.
PITHER:
As I lay down to the sound
of the Russian gentlemen
practicing their shooting,
I realized
I was in a bit of a pickle.
My heart sank as I realized
I should never see
the Okehampton Bypass again.
Come on, dear.
Wake up, dear.
Mother.
Come on, dear.
So it was all a dream.
No, dear, this is the dream,
you're still in the cell.
We're going to have another
try. I think we've got it now.
My boys have been looking down
the wrong bit, you see.
Oh, no, you've got to look
down that bit there.
I thought you had
to look down that bit.
You've got to look down that,
or you won't hit anything.
All right, we'll give it
a whirl. Guards, seize him!
Listen, you've got
to look down this bit.
[♪♪♪]
[APPLAUSE]
[CHUCKLING]
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[LAUGHING]
...Eartha Kitt!
[APPLAUSE]
[MIMING TO EDWARD HEATH'S
VOICE] Trade Union leaders,
I would say this:
We've done our part.
Now, on behalf
of the community,
we have a right to expect you
the Trade Union leaders,
to do yours.
[CHATTERING IN RUSSIAN]
Nyet! No talking!
Edward Heath!
[TALKING IN RUSSIAN]
--an unjustifiable wage today.
-MAN: Sing "Old-fashioned Girl!"
[CROWD SHOUTING]
Sing "Old-fashioned Girl"!
"Old-fashioned Girl"!
"Old-fashioned Girl!"
That turnip's
certainly not safe.
Oh, no. Mr. Pither. Pither!
CROWD [CHANTING]:
"Old-fashioned Girl!"
Pither! Mr. Pither!
Mr. Pither.
Mr. Pither! Mr. Pither!
Mr. Pither!
PITHER: Here.
Gulliver.
Pither.
What a stroke of luck.
Well, yes and no.
Squad, fix bayonets!
-Charge!
-[ALL SHOUTING]
Phew. What an amazing escape.
Well, goodbye, Reginald.
Goodbye, Mr. Pither,
and good luck with the tour.
[♪♪♪]
Hey,
I think he's finally gone.
Oh, yeah.
Ready, Maurice?
Right-o, Kevin. Let's go.
All right,
maestro, hit it.
♪ I'm just your
Jack-in-the-box ♪
♪ You know
Whenever love knocks ♪
♪ I'm gonna bounce up and down
On my spring ♪
♪ A toy used up when it stops ♪
♪ I'm just your
Jack-in-the-box ♪