This is Captain MacPherson
welcoming you aboard
East Scottish Airways.
You'll have had your tea.
Our destination is Glasgow.
There is no need to panic.
There's a bomb
onboard this plane,
and I'll tell you where it is
for a thousand pounds.
I don't believe you.
If you don't tell me
where the bomb is--
If I don't
give you the money--
Unless you give me the bomb--
The money.
Thank you, pretty lady.
The bomb will explode,
killing everybody.
Including you.
I'll tell you where it is
for a pound.
All right.
Here's a pound.
Uh, I don't want
Scottish money.
They've got the numbers.
They can be traced.
One English pound.
Now, where's the bomb?
I can't remember.
You've forgotten?
Aye, you'd better have
your pound back.
Oh, fingerprints.
Now,
where's the bomb?
Uh, wait a tic,
wait a tic.
Uh, my first is in Glasgow,
but not in Spain,
my second is in steamer,
but not in train,
my whole is in the luggage
compartment on the plane.
I'll tell you where
it is for a pound.
It's in
the luggage compartment.
Right.
Here's your pound.
Is this character
giving you any trouble?
-He's just ruined this sketch.
-Absolutely.
Right, let's go on
to the next one.
Uh, no. Wait a tic,
wait a tic.
-I won't ruin your sketch
for a pound.
-ALL: No, no.
-Seventy-five p.
-Next item.
I see my role in it as, um--
Oh, how can I put it?
Uh, the nude man.
As sort of symbolizing
the two separate strands
of existence.
The essential nudity
of man.
The-- Oh, um...
It's a very
interesting question.
Personally, I rather adhere
to the Bergsonian idea
of laughter
as a social sanction
against inflexible
behavior but...
Excuse me a moment.
And now...
It's...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[CLOCK TICKING]
ANNOUNCER:
Well, we'll be continuing
with Monty Python's Flying
Circus in just a moment.
[TINKLING]
Yes, yes, we're--
We're going back to the show
in just one moment from...
[CLEARS THROAT]
[HUMMING]
...now!
ANNOUNCER:
This new housing development
in Bristol
is one of the most interesting
in the country.
It's using a variety
of new techniques:
shockproof curtain-walling,
a central high-voltage,
self-generated
electricity source,
and extruded acrylic
fiberglass fitments.
It's also the first major
housing project in Britain
to be built entirely
by characters
from 19th-century
English literature.
Here Little Nell, from Dickens'
Old Curiosity Shop
fits new nylon siphons into
the asbestos-lined ceiling.
But it's the electrical system
which has attracted
the most attention.
Arthur Huntingdon, who Helen
Graham married as a young girl,
and whose shameless conduct
eventually drove her back
to her brother Lawrence
in Anne Bronte's
The Tenant of Wildfell Hall,
describes why it's unique.
Because, sir,
it is self-generating.
Because we have harnessed here,
in this box,
the very forces
of life itself.
The very forces
that will send Helen
running back
to beg forgiveness.
The on-site building techniques
involve the construction
of 12-foot walling blocks
by a crowd of farmhands
from Tess of the d'Urbervilles,
supervised by
the genial landlady, Mrs. Jupp,
from Samuel Butler's
Way of All Flesh.
In contrast
to the site in Bristol,
there's progress here
on Britain's first
18-level motorway interchange,
being built by characters
from Milton's
Paradise Lost.
What went wrong here?
Well, nobody really got on.
Satan didn't get on
with Eve, uh...
Archangel Gabriel
didn't get on with Satan.
Nobody got on with
the Serpent.
So now they have to work
a rota.
Forces of good from 10 till 3,
forces of evil 3 till 6.
But even more modern building
techniques are being used
on an expanding new town site
near Peterborough.
Here, the Amazing Mystico
and Janet
can put up a block of flats
by hypnosis in under a minute.
The local council here
have over 50 hypnosis-induced
25-story blocks put up
by El Mystico and Janet.
I asked Mr. Ken Verybigliar
the advantages of hypnosis
compared to other
building methods.
Oh, there is a considerable
financial advantage
in using the services
of El Mystico.
A block like
Mystico Point here
would normally cost
in a region
of one and a half
million pounds.
Uh, this was put up for
5 pounds and 30 bob for Janet.
But the obvious question is:
Are they safe?
Of course they're safe.
There's absolutely
no doubt about that.
They are as strong,
solid and as safe
as any other building method
in this country.
Provided, of course,
people believe in them.
Yes, uh, we received a note
from the council,
uh, saying that if we
ceased to believe
in this building,
it would fall down.
You don't mind living
in a figment
of another man's
imagination?
No, it's much better
than where we used to live.
Where did you use to live?
We had an 18-room villa
overlooking Nice.
Really?
That sounds much better.
Oh, yeah. You're right.
Oh, no, no, no.
Of course not.
Phew.
That was close.
But the construction of these
vast new housing developments,
providing homes
for many thousands of people,
is not the only project
to which he has applied
his many talents.
He also has
an infallible pools method,
a school of Spanish dancing,
and a car-hire service.
What is the driving force
behind a man
of such restless energies
and boundless vision?
Here, as with so many
great men of history,
the answer lies in a woman.
As Antony has his Cleopatra,
as Napoleon has
his Josephine...
[SCREAMS]
...so Mystico has his Janet.
Yes, Janet.
A quiet, shy girl.
An honors graduate
from Harvard University,
American junior
sprint record holder,
ex-world skating champion,
Nobel Prize winner,
architect, novelist
and surgeon.
The girl who helped crack the
Oppenheimer spy ring in 1947.
She gave vital evidence
to the Senate Narcotics
Commission in 1958.
She also helped to convict the
woman at the chemist's in 1961,
and a year later,
she gave police information
which led to the arrest
of her postman.
In October of that same year,
she secured the conviction
of her gardener for bigamy,
and three months later,
personally led the police
swoop
on the couple next door.
In 1967, she became
suspicious of the man
at the garage
and it was
her dogged perseverance
and relentless enquiries
that two years later
finally secured his conviction
for not having a license
for his car radio.
He was hanged
at Leeds a year later,
despite the abolition
of capital punishment
and the public outcry.
Also in Leeds that year,
a local butcher was hanged
for defaulting
on mortgage repayments.
And a Mr. Jarvis
was electrocuted
for shouting in the corridor.
We admit there have been
outbreaks of hanging recently,
but the police are trying
to keep the situation
under control.
Uh, you must remember
the courts are very busy
at the moment,
and the odd death sentence
is bound to slip through.
-[LOUD RADIO CHATTER]
-Um, electrocutions
are another big worry.
Uh, but, uh, we hope
that guillotining has been
eradicated, uh,
from the urban areas.
-[LOUD CHANTING ON RADIO]
-And garroting is confined
almost entirely to Luton.
So if you have, um--
If you have a friend in prison
or under sentence of death,
be sure to let us know
at this address:
ANNOUNCER:
NEWSCASTER 1: And Premier
Zhou Enlai, who called it
a "major breakthrough".
Twelve men were accidentally
hanged at Whitby Assizes
this afternoon
whilst considering
their verdict.
This is one of the worst
miscarriages of justice
in Britain since Tuesday.
[♪♪♪]
NEWSCASTER 2:
Well, it's 13 minutes
to the hour of 9-9-9
here on wonderful Radio 1-1-1.
So, ha, ha, if
you're still lying in your--
Your big, big bed,
now is the time
to get up out of it!
We've got another
13 hours of tip-top sounds
here on wonderful Radio 1.
[HONKING, SQUEAKING]
Sorry about that.
So unless you have
brain cells,
or have completed
the process of evolution,
there's a wonderful day--
It must be
on Radio 4.
Radio 2.
Radio 3.
Radio 4.
It's 9 o'clock
and time for Mortuary Hour.
An hour of talks,
tunes and downright tomfoolery
for all those
who work in mortuaries.
Introduced as usual
by Shirley Bassey.
[♪♪♪]
BASSEY:
Well, we're going
to kick straight off this week
with our Mortuary Quiz,
so have your pens
and pencils ready.
Turn that radio off
and look lively!
Oh, but it's Mortuary Hour,
Mr. Wang.
Don't argue, Battersby.
This is our mortuary
in here, Your Grace.
I see, I see, yes.
I, uh...
I-I, uh... I, uh...
I-- I-I, uh...
I, uh...
I-- I, uh...
I-I-I-- I can't think
of anything to say about it.
Well, we're very proud
of it here, sir.
It's one of the most
up-to-date in the country.
I see, yes, yes, yes.
Uh, now, um...
Uh, what, uh...?
Oh, uh...
What, uh...?
Uh...
Uh, wh-what?
Uh... What?
What, uh...? What is it?
Is it a power station?
No, Your Grace,
it's a mortuary.
I see, I see.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Well-- Well, it has
one of the most advanced
thermostat control systems
in the country.
And it has computer-controlled
storage facilities.
I see, I see.
I, um...
I, uh...
I...
Uh...
Well...
I, uh...
I-I, uh...
I...
I'm a good little doggie.
I'm sorry,
Your Grace?
I'm a good little dog.
Oh, dear.
Perhaps we should
postpone the visit?
No, no, no, no.
You see, it's just that
his brain is so tiny
that the slightest movement
can dislodge it.
Your Grace?
Oh, dear.
It's rather like
one of those games you play
where you have to get
the ball into the hole.
[GROANS]
Ah. Oh, excellent, excellent,
excellent, excellent, excellent.
Now, then. Oh...
Uh, um...
What--? What happens when the
steel is poured into the ingots?
Uh, perhaps we should go and
have a look at the new showers?
Yes, yes, yes.
Rather, yes, yes, yes.
Jolly good, jolly good,
jolly good, jolly good.
No fear. Yes, yes, yes.
Well played. Jolly good chop.
BASSEY:
Well, the answers
were as follows:
Number one, the left hand.
Two, no. Three, normal.
Four, yes, it has.
In 1963, when a bird
got caught in the mechanism.
Turn that thing off.
But it's Mortuary Dance Time,
Mr. Wang.
Never mind that, Battersby.
This is the big one.
I've just had Whitby Police
on the phone with 12 hangees.
Yeah, we heard about that
on the radios.
No, these are 12 different
ones, so shtoom.
Uh, I'll not interrupt
this sketch for a pound.
-What?
-Eh, for one pound,
I'll leave this sketch
totally uninterrupted.
-Uh, 50p.
-What?
MAN: I'm prepared
to negotiate a 40-p deal.
For 35p I won't interrupt
any of the next three items.
-WANG: No, it's no good. No.
-MAN: Twenty-five p.
Ten p and a kiss.
GILLIAM: You see, it's very
simple. I just take these
cutout figures,
and by putting them together--
What?
Oh, you mean we're on?
Oh!
Sorry.
[SENSUAL MOANING]
Hm?
[MOANING CONTINUES]
BRUCE:
Wait, Nigel.
I've got this strange feeling
we're being watched.
NIGEL:
Oh, my God, Bruce.
It's the police. Run for it.
[MUTTERING IN LATIN]
[SIREN WAILS]
Oh, lunch break.
[WHISTLING]
[BUZZING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CROWD CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER:
Meanwhile, 55 years later,
back in London...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Hello, good afternoon,
and welcome to the second leg
of the Olympic final
of the men's hide-and-seek,
here in the heart
of Britain's London.
Uh, we'll be starting in just
a couple of moments from now.
And there you can see
the two competitors.
Francisco Huron,
the Paraguayan,
who in this leg
is the seeker,
and there's the man
he'll be looking for,
our own Don Roberts
from Hinckley
in Leicestershire,
who, his trainer tells me,
is at the height
of his self-secreting form.
Now, in the first leg,
which ended on Wednesday,
Don succeeded
in finding the Paraguayan
in the new world-record time
of 11 years, two months,
26 days, nine hours,
three minutes, 27.4 seconds
in a sweet shop in Kilmarnock.
And now they're
under starter's orders.
STARTER:
On your marks...
get set...
[GUN FIRES]
[COUNTS IN SPANISH]
[♪♪♪]
[CONTINUES COUNTING IN SPANISH]
Well, Don's off
to a really great start there.
Remember, the Paraguayan
has got 11 years, two months,
26 days, 9 hours, three minutes,
27.4 seconds to beat.
[CONTINUES COUNTING IN SPANISH]
Coming!
[♪♪♪]
Well, we'll be
taking you back there
as soon as there are
any developments.
Well, we've just heard
that something is happening
in the hide-and-seek final,
so let's go
straight over there.
Hello, again,
and welcome to Madagascar,
where Francisco Huron
is seeking Don Roberts.
And I've just been told
that he's been
unofficially described
as cold.
Uh, wait a minute.
I've just been told
that Huron has requested
a plane ticket to Budapest,
so he's definitely
getting warmer.
So we'll be back again
in just a few years.
Really beginning
to hot up now.
Here we are
on the very last day
of this fantastic final.
Huron now has
less than 12 hours left
to find British ace
Don Roberts.
Earlier this morning,
he finished combing
the outskirts of Lisbon,
and now he seems to have
staked everything on one final
desperate seek here
in the Tagus Valley.
But Roberts
is over 1500 miles away,
and it's beginning
to look all over,
bar the shouting.
The sands of time are running
out for this delving dago,
this señor of seek,
this perspicacious
Paraguayan.
He's still
desperately cold,
and it's beginning to look like
another gold for Britain.
[♪♪♪]
[SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Found him. Here he is.
All right.
The official result
of the World Hide-and-Seek.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Mr. Don Roberts from Hinckley,
Leicestershire.
Eleven years, two months,
26 days, nine hours,
three minutes, 27 seconds.
Mr. Francisco Huron,
Paraguay.
Eleven years,
two months, 26 days,
nine hours,
three minutes, 27 seconds.
The result: A tie.
ANNOUNCER:
A tie! What a fantastic
result.
Well, the replay will start
tomorrow at 7:30 a.m.
Well, hello again.
Nice to be back.
Glad to see the show
has been going well.
Well, now, uh,
sorry about Mon-trerx.
That was a little item
entitled "Hide-and-Seek."
Very anarchic, very effective,
not quite my cup of tea,
but, uh, very nice
for the younger people.
Well, the next item
the boys have put together
takes place in a,
uh, sitting room.
Sorry it's just
a sitting room,
but, uh, the bank account's
a bit low
after the appallingly expensive
production of Clochmerle--
This is a totally
free interruption,
and no money has
changed hands whatever.
Sorry about that, darling.
-Gravy?
-Yes, please, dear.
-[DOORBELL RINGS]
-Oh, dear.
That'll be the Cheap-Laughs
from next door.
[RINGING]
Come in.
No, just breathing
heavily!
[LAUGHS]
Oh, we just
dropped in.
[LAUGHS]
[SQUEALS]
Would you like
to come through?
Oh, yes.
Well, good night
and give us a kiss.
Mwah, mwah.
Well, thank you very much
for a very nice evening.
-After you, dear.
-Right-o.
[BOTH SCREAM]
[HOOTS]
[BREAKS WIND]
Oh.
Oh, honestly, dear,
why do we always
have to buy everything
just because
the Cheap-Laughs have one?
This is not
an interruption at all.
It's just neighborliness,
dear, that's all.
Well, I think we should try and
lead our own lives from now on.
[SCREAMS]
Can't you be serious
for just one moment?
[CLICKS]
Honey, I'm sorry
I was cross earlier.
Oh, that's all right, dear.
It's just that I get so sick
of always having to be
like the Cheap-Laughs.
Yes, well, from now on,
we'll be like ourselves.
Oh, Roger.
Oh, Beatrice.
[♪♪♪]
Many people in this country
are becoming increasingly
worried about bullfighting.
They say it's not only cruel,
vicious and immoral,
but also blatantly unfair.
The bull is heavy, violent,
abusive and aggressive,
with four legs
and great sharp teeth,
whereas the bullfighter is
only a small, greasy Spaniard.
Given this basic inequality,
what can be done
to make bullfighting safer?
We asked Brigadier
Arthur Farquar-Smith,
chairman of the British
"Well Basically" Club.
Well, basically
it's quite apparent
that these miniscule dago
chappies have got it all wrong.
They prance round the bull,
like a lot of bally
nightclub dancers,
looking like
the younger generation
or a less smooth version
of the Lionel Blair Troupe,
with much of
the staccato rhythms
of the Irving Davies Dancers
at the height
of their success.
In recent years, Pan's People
have often recaptured--
And what we must do now
is to use devices like radar
to locate the bull,
and sound missiles
fired from underground silos
to knock the bull over.
Then I would send in
Scottish boys with air cover
to provide a diversion
for the bull,
whilst the navy came in round
the back and finished him off.
That, to me,
would be bullfighting,
and not this pansy kind of
lyrical evocative movement
which George Balanchine and
Martha Graham in the States,
and our very own
Sadler's Wells--
Troops could also be used
in an auxiliary role
in international chess--
What?
BADGER:
I'll put the lights
on again for a pound.
I'm sorry about
this interruption,
but we'll soon put things
right with just a simple
little push of a button.
Oh, ow.
[MUTTERING]
Oh. Oh, dear. That's okay.
No, no, please.
[MOANS]
Oh. No, no, no.
[GAGS]
Oh. Oh, dear.
Ow. Oh.
[MOANING]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[♪♪♪]
What?!
I'm very sorry,
but I don't know why I've been
included in this cartoon.
That's a bloody lie.
It's quite obvious
what's going on here.
This whole thing is loaded
with political significance.
I was right.
ANNOUNCER:
This is the planet Algon.
Fifth world
in the system of Aldebaran.
The red giant in the
constellation of Sagittarius.
Here, an ordinary
cup of drinking chocolate
costs four million pounds.
An immersion heater
for the hot-water tank
costs over six billion pounds,
and a pair
of split-crotch panties
would be almost unobtainable.
A simple rear-window
demisting device for an 1100
costs 8000 million
billion pounds.
And a new element for an
electric kettle like this,
would cost as much as the
entire gross national product
of the United States
of America,
from 1770 to the year 2000,
and even then they wouldn't
be able to afford
the small fixing ring,
which attaches it
to the kettle.
Our computers have been working
all day to try and analyze
the dramatic information that's
coming in from this first-ever
intergalactic probe, Algon I.
And we're just getting an
interesting development now,
which is that attachments
for rotary mowers,
that is mowers that have
a central circular blade,
are relatively inexpensive.
Still in the region
of 9 to 10 million pounds,
but it does seem to indicate
that Algon might be
a very good planet
for those with larger gardens.
Perhaps even an orchard
that's been left for two years,
needs some heavy work,
some weeding.
Uh, but we're now getting
some live pictures
through from Algon.
Harry, perhaps you could
talk us through them.
HARRY:
Very little evidence
of shopping facilities here.
There don't seem to be
any large supermarkets.
Uh, there may be some
on-the-corner grocery stores
behind those rocks,
but it's difficult to tell
from this angle.
It does seem to suggest
that most of the shopping here
is by direct mail.
Well, of course the big question
that everyone's asking here
is what about
those split-crotch panties?
Are they going to be
unobtainable throughout
the universe,
or merely on Algon itself?
Professor.
We must remember that Algon
is over 75,000 miles wide.
The probes come down
in this area here,
and we're really only getting
signals from a radius
of 30 or 40 miles
around the probe.
Uh, split-crotch panties,
or, indeed, any items
of what we scientists call
sexy underwear
or erotic lingerie
may be much more plentiful
on other parts of the planet.
Professor, you were
responsible for finding
scanty-panties
and Golden Goddess
High-Lift Bras
on planets which weren't
thought able to sustain life.
And now that man has
discovered a new galaxy,
do you think we're going to see
underwear become even naughtier?
Oh, naughtier
and naughtier.
Well, so much for that.
But of course,
the probe itself
has excited
a great deal of interest,
for it contains uranium-based
dual-transmission cells
entirely recharged
by solar radiation,
which can take off
a bra and panties
in less than 15 seconds.
It is, of course, the first
piece of space hardware
to be specially designed
to undress ladies,
and so there are bound to be
some teething troubles,
such as how to cope
with the combination
of elastic-sided
boots and tights.
But I think we're getting
some pictures now
from Algon itself.
And it looks as though-- Yes!
The satellite
has found a bird.
The probe has struck crumpet,
and she looks pretty good too.
Professor?
Yeah, she's a real honey.
ANNOUNCER:
The pictures
are a bit sporadic.
I think probably
the solar radiation
-during the long journey
to Algon...
-[GROANS]
MAN: She's fantastic.
[ALL GROANING]
Oh, dear, I'm sorry,
we've lost contact.
We'll try and re-established
contact with Algon...
Uh, hello.
Uh, the BBC have offered me
the sum of 40p,
uh, to read the credits
of this show.
Personally, I thought
I should have held out
for the full 75,
but the BBC have explained to me
about their
financial difficulties,
and, uh, I decided to accept
the reduced offer.
So, uh, the show was conceived,
written and performed
by, uh, the usual lot.
Uh, also appearing
were Carol Cleveland,
uh, Marie Anderson,
uh, Mrs. Idle.
Uh, makeup, Madelaine Gaffney.
Costumes, Hazel Pethig.
Animations by Terry Gilliam.
Uh, visual effects designer,
Bernard Wilkie.
Graphics, Bob Blagden.
Film cameraman,
Alan Featherstone.
Film editor, Ray Millichope.
Sound, Richard Chubb.
Uh, lighting, Bill Bailey.
Designer, Bob Berk.
Produced by Ian MacNaughton
for 92p and a bottle
of Bell's whiskey.
It was a BBC color production.
Uh, and I think that's
just it.
I'd like to say,
if there are any, uh,
BBC producers looking in, uh,
who need, uh, people to read
the credits for them, I--
[CRASHES]