Oh, good morning, sir.
Can I help you?
Yes, I wonder if you had
any part-time vacancies
on your books.
Part-time,
I'll have a look, sir.
I think we've got...
Um... Ah, yes.
Sir Walter Raleigh
is equipping another
expedition to Virginia.
He needs traders
and sailors.
Ah, vittlers needed at
the Court of Philip of Spain.
Oh, yeah, and they want master
joiners and craftsmen
for the building
of the Globe Theatre.
I see. Have you got
anything a bit more modern?
You know, like a job
on the buses, or--
or digging
the Underground?
Oh, no, we only have
Tudor jobs.
That can't be very
profitable, can it?
Well, you'd be
surprised, sir.
The Tudor economy's booming.
Ever since
Sir Humphrey Gilbert
opened up the Northwest
Passage to Cathay
and the Cabots'
expansion in Canada,
there's been a tremendous
surge in exports.
And trade with the
Holy Roman Empire is going--
No. Quite right.
It's no good at all.
What?
It-- Well, it's
a dead loss.
We haven't put anyone
in a job since 1625.
I see.
-That's all?
-What?
-That's all you say?
-Yes.
No, no, we were
the tops, then.
Drake got all
his sailors here.
Elizabeth, we supplied
the archbishops
for her coronation.
Shakespeare started off
from here as a temp.
Then came James I, and the
bottom fell out of Tudor jobs.
1603, 800 vacancies
filled. 1604, 40.
1605, none. 1606, none.
The rest of the Stuart period,
nothing. Hanoverians, nothing.
Victorian, nothing.
Saxe-Coburgs, nothing.
Windsors-- What did you want?
-Dirty books, please.
-Right. All right.
Have a look
through these, sir.
Uh, sorry about
the Tudor bit,
but you can't be
too careful, you know.
Have you got anything--
-Anything a bit--
-A bit stronger.
Hold on. My Lord of Warwick!
-MAN: Hello!
-Raise high the drawbridge.
-Gloucester's troops approach.
-MAN: Right.
Can't be too careful
you know, sir.
[MURMURS]
There's, uh... There's
Bridget, Queen of the Whip.
Yeah.
Or there's, uh,
Naughty Nora.
-No.
-Or there's this one:
Doug, Bob and Gordon
Visit the Ark Royal.
Or there's, uh...
Sister Teresa,
The Spanking Nun.
You don't have anything
specifically
about, uh, Devon
and Cornwall?
No. I'm afraid not, sir.
The one I was after
was Arthur Hotchkiss'
Devonshire
Country Churches.
Well, how about this,
sir: Bum Biters.
No, not really.
Um, I don't suppose
you've got any general surveys
of English church
architecture?
No, it's not really
our line, sir.
No, I see. Well, never mind.
I'll just take
the Lord Lieutenant in Nylons,
then, and, uh...
I'll trade in these two copies
of Piggie Parade.
Thank you.
-MAN: My Lord of Warwick!
-Hello.
Raise high the drawbridge.
Gloucester's troops approach.
Right.
Uh, just these, then.
All right.
This is a raid.
My name's
Superintendent Gaskell
and this is
Sergeant Maddox.
Sir Philip Sidney.
'Tis good to see thee
on these shores again.
-Shut up.
-Thy suit is fair
and goodly cut.
-Was't from Antwerp?
-Shut up. It's a disguise.
Right! Confiscate
the smutty books, Maddox.
Sir Philip, prithee, nay.
Listen, mate. Don't come that
Philip Sidney bit with me.
I'm not a bloody Tudor
at all!
I'm Gaskell of the Vice Squad,
and this is Sergeant Maddox.
Maddox?!
Where's he gone?
Sir Philip, prithee,
rest a while.
Look, this is the last time.
I'm warning you.
I'm not Sir Philip
bleeding Sidney.
I'm Superintendent Harold
Gaskell, and this is a raid!
That'll be
540 quid, sir.
All right then. Oh,
I'll just have this one then.
Maddox!
Look, this is
a raid.
Honestly. I promise you.
-Where are you going?
-I'm going home.
Right.
Right, I'll remember you.
Don't you worry.
I'll remember.
Prithee, good
Sir Philip.
Don't you start. Maddox!
Listen, I can prove
to you I'm a policeman.
I'll give the name
of all the men
down in F division
at Acton.
Inspector Arthur Perry.
Superintendent
Charles Frodwell,
my best friend.
Police dogs Butch,
Wolf, Panther, Maudling.
How would I know those names
if I was Sir Philip Sidney?
Vicar, vicar.
You know me.
The Gargoyle Club.
I got you off the charge.
Farewell,
good Sir Philip.
Hey, stop!
Maddox!
You'll never get away
with this, you porn merchant!
Blimey.
Maddox?
Oh, good sir.
How glad I am
to see thee come.
[SOBS]
Forgive me weeping...
but my love has gone.
Uh, listen.
My name is Gaskell.
Uh, Superintendent Gaskell
of Vice Squad.
-Myself and Sergeant Maddox
are on a raid.
-[SOBBING]
We are not Tudor people,
we are the police.
Frances, what
idleness is this?
Why, good
Sir Philip Sidney,
what hast
thou here?
You are
Sir Philip Sidney?
Possibly.
But I may be Superintendent
Gaskell of the Vice Squad.
Ha-ha. Good Sir Philip.
Thy sharp-tongued wit
has not deserted thee.
Come. Let us
eat and drink.
Stay with us awhile.
All right, sir.
I think I will.
[PLAYING FOLK TUNE]
[LAUGHTER, CHATTER]
Then... Then did we bust
the Harry Tony mob,
who did seek to import
Scandinavian filth
via Germany.
For six years
they cleaned up a packet.
The day I got whiff of them
through a squealer
did within a week
mop up right good.
They're now languishing, doing
five-year bird in Parkhurst.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Sir Philip, the Spaniards have
landed in the Netherlands.
My Lord Walsingham
needs you there forthwith.
Mm.
[WOMAN GASPS]
-Right. Let's go.
-ALL: Good luck, Sir Philip!
Fighter against filth!
[TRUMPETS BLARING]
Where are
the Spaniards?
Down below, Sir Philip.
Their first boats
are landing even now.
Right. You stay here,
I'll go and get them.
Sir Philip. Not alone.
[♪♪♪]
Hello, hello.
What's
going on here?
It's nothing, señor.
It's just some literature.
[SPEAKS INAUDIBLY]
I know what literature is,
you dago dustbin.
I also know
what porn is.
What's this then, eh?
It is one of Lope de Vega's
latest plays, señor.
Toledo Tit Parade?
What kind of a play is that?
It's very visual, señor.
Right. I'm taking
this lot in
in the name of Her Gracious
Majesty, Queen Elizabeth.
Oh, but, señor--
Don't give me any trouble.
Just pile up these baskets
of filth and come with me.
Never.
Ow.
[SCREAMS]
NARRATOR:
The battle raged long
and hard.
But as night fell,
Sidney overcame the Spaniards.
Six thousand copies of
Tits and Bums,
and 4000 copies of Shower
Sheila were seized that day.
The tide of Spanish porn
was stemmed.
Sir Philip Sidney returned
to London in triumph.
Covered in glory, Sir Philip
rode home to Penshurst
to see his beloved wife.
But all was not well.
Good evening all,
my love.
I have returned safe from
the Low Countries.
[WHISTLES]
What art thou reading,
fair one?
Oh. 'Tis nothing, husband.
I can see
'tis something.
Uh...'tis one of
Shakespeare's latest works.
Oh.
Gay Boys
in Bondage.
What is't?
Tragedy? Comedy?
Uh...Uh, 'tis, um...
Uh, 'tis the story of a...
a... man's great love for his
uh, fellow men.
How fortunate
we are indeed
to have such a poet
on these shores.
Indeed. Um, how was
the war, my lord?
The Spaniards
were defeated thrice.
Six dozen chests
of hardcore captured.
Hast brought home
any spoils of war?
Yes, good, my wife. This fair
coat, trimmed with ermine.
Oh. Lovely.
Naught else?
No, no, fair lady.
The rest was too smutty.
Now, good my wife,
while I rest,
read to me a while
from Shakespeare's
Gay Boys in Bondage.
Uh... yes, my lord.
[SIGHS]
"Gay Boys in Bondage."
[CLEARS THROAT]
"Ken, 25, is a mounted policeman
with a difference.
And what a difference.
Even Roger is surprised.
And he's...
he's used to real men."
'Tis like Hamlet.
What a genius.
"But who is going to do
the cooking tonight?
Roddy's got a mouth full--"
All right,
this is a raid!
Oh. We are disgraced.
There you are, Maddox.
Cut the chat
and get in the van.
Maddox. You recognize me.
Indeed I do,
Sir Philip Sidney,
and sad I am
to see you caught up
in this morass
of filth.
Ooh. That's a long one.
Oh. Oh. The glorious name of
Sidney is besmirched.
All is lost.
Oh, alas the day.
Shut up!
I know this man.
It's me old mate,
Sergeant Maddox.
You'll do time for this.
Oh, Maddox, it's me, Gaskell.
F division down at Acton.
Inspector
Arthur Frodwell--
Come on, Sidney!
And you, miss.
I'm not Sir Philip bleeding
Sidney. Where were you?
We could have mopped up
that Tudor shop.
Yeah. Ooh, that's
a good one.
It's me.
It's me, Gaskell.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
You'll hear more about this when
I get back to the station.
Maddox, you've got
the wrong man.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
Petty bodice
that here I hold.
If this be Brian's,
then to fight I go. But no.
Alas, if Roger doth proceed,
I am undone.
No, Cyril must not know.
But no.
Yes. Now I am resolved.
But hold,
someone approacheth.
Take heed, my lord.
Kevin and Bruce are here.
[PERSON SCREAMING]
[BUBBLING]
[PLAYING ORGAN]
It's so nice here,
isn't it, darling?
Oh, it's beautiful.
It's...
It's Paris
all over again.
Excuse me,
do you mind if I join you?
Uh... no, no.
N-not at all.
Are you sure
you don't mind?
Uh, yes, yes,
absolutely.
Y-you're sure I won't be
disturbing you?
No, no.
You're absolutely sure
I'm not disturbing you?
No. No, really.
Good. I don't want
to disturb you.
-I'm sorry?
-I don't want to disturb you.
Especially, as you're being
so kind about me
not disturbing you.
Oh, no, no, we don't mind,
do we, darling?
-No. No, darling.
-Good.
So I can go ahead and join you,
then. Can I?
-Yes.
-Yes, please.
-Won't be disturbing?
-No, no, no.
-No.
-Good, good. You're very kind.
A lot of people are far less
understanding than you are.
Oh.
A lot of people take offense
when I even talk to them.
Let alone when I specifically
tell them about my...
being disturbing.
Well, i-- it's not
particularly disturbing.
No, absolutely, absolutely.
That's what I always say.
But you'd be amazed...
You'd be amazed
at the number of people
who really get
worried by it.
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-- ♪
I mean, even doing this
gets people looking at me
in the most
extraordinary way.
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo
Doodle-oodle-oodle ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doodle-doo ♪
Well, we must be getting on.
I knew I'd disturb you.
It always happens.
Whenever I find someone
that I-- I really think
I'm gonna be able to
get on with--
You see, we're going
to be a little bit late.
Oh, darling.
Come on. Let's stay.
-What?
-Well...
-[SOBS]
-Well, uh, just a little bit.
Only-- I mean, we will
be late if we don't...
Oh, thank you.
You're very kind.
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo
Doodle-oodle-oo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
WOMAN:
As it turned out,
our chance meeting
with the
Reverend Arthur Belling
was to change
our whole way of life.
And every Sunday
we'd hurry along
to St. Loony Up the Cream Bun
and Jam in time for night Mass.
ALL:
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
[EXPLOSION]
[PLAYS]
-And now...
-It's...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[GUNSHOTS]
Baa!
[SQUAWKS]
[MEOWS]
[BELLS DINGING]
[WHINNIES]
[BELLS AND GUNSHOTS CONTINUE]
[SCREAMS]
[SPLASHING]
MAN:
Right, sir.
One safari snowball.
That comes to
1,369 pounds 48p.
And we'll throw
the nude man in for free.
[REGISTER RINGS]
All right, gentleman,
last orders, please.
Oh, do you want a drink
before they close?
No, I want a kiss.
Oh, goody.
Mwah.
NARRATOR:
And so they lived
happily ever after.
But now...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
The Free Repetition
of Doubtful Words
Skit, Spoof,
Jape or Vignette.
By a Very Underrated Writer.
I have come for
some free repetition
of doubtful words
on an inland telegram.
Have you the telegram
in question?
I have the
very thing here.
Well, slip it to me,
my good chap,
and let me
eye the contents.
At once,
Mr. Telegram Enquiry Man.
Thank you,
Mr. Customer Man.
Ha-ha.
"Parling, I glove you.
Clease clome at bronce,
your troving swife, Pat."
Which was the word
you wanted checking?
-Pat.
-Pat?
My wife's name
is not Pat at all.
No?
It's Bat. With a B.
And therefore, I will take
a quick look in the book.
Ripping.
You're quite right,
old cock.
There has been
a mistake.
I thought as much.
What really does it say?
It say, "Go away,
you silly little bleeder.
I am having
another man.
Love, Bat."
Quite some error.
Yes. She wouldn't call
herself "Pat". It's silly.
Daft, I call it.
Well, it has been
a pleasure working with you.
For me also it has
been a pleasure.
And that concludes
our little skit.
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR:
The Free Repetition
of Doubtful Words Thing
by a Justly Underrated Writer.
The end.
[♪♪♪]
Good evening.
Tonight on
Is There?
we examine the question,
"Is there a life after death?"
And here to discuss it
are three dead people.
The late
Sir Brian Hardaker,
former curator of
the Imperial War Museum,
the late Professor Thynne,
until recently
an academic, critic
and broadcaster...
and putting the point of view
of the Church of England,
the very late
Prebendary Reverend Ross.
Gentlemen, is there a life
after death or not?
Sir Brian?
Professor?
Prebendary?
Well, there we have it.
Three say no.
On Is There? next week,
we'll be discussing
the question
"Is there enough of it about?"
Until then, good night.
[♪♪♪]
Good doctor, morning. Nice
year for the time of day.
Come in.
Can I down sit?
Certainly.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Well, then.
Not going to bush the doctor
about the beat too long.
I'm going to come to point to
the straight immediately.
Good, good.
My particular prob,
or buglem bear,
I've had ages. For years,
I've had it for donkeys.
What?
I'm up to here with it,
sick to death.
I can't take you any longer,
so I've come to see it.
Now, this is
your problem with words?
This is my problem
with words.
Oh. That seems
to have cleared it.
♪ Oh, I come from Alabama
With my banjo on my knee ♪
Yes, that seems to be all right.
Thank you very much.
I see. But recently,
you have been having
this problem with
your word order?
Oh, absolutely. Sometimes,
at the end of a sentence,
I'll come out with
the wrong fuse box.
Fuse box?
The thing about saying
the wrong word is that,
A: I don't notice it,
and B: sometimes orange water
given bucket of plaster.
Yes. Tell me more
about your problem.
Well, as I say, you'll just
be talking and out will pudenda
the wrong word,
and ashtray's your uncle.
-I'm awfully strawberry
about it.
-Upset?
It's so embarrassing when
my wife and I go to an orgy.
A party?
No, an orgy.
-We live in Esher.
-Quite.
That's what I said. Feel such
a bloody whack the diddle-o.
Folderol fa-di-da,
loady-doady do, fum-fum.
Mr. Burrows, this is
no common problem.
You are suffering from
a disease so rare
that it hasn't
got a name. Not yet.
But it will have.
Oh, yes.
This is the opportunity
I've been waiting for.
The chance
of a lifetime.
I'll show them at
the Royal College of Surgeons.
I'll make them
sit up and take notice.
Thripshaw's disease.
Discovered by
E. Henry Thripshaw, M.D.
I'll be invited on
Call My Bluff.
And the merchandising!
There'll be
E. Henry Thripshaw T-shirts.
I'll turn it into a game.
I'll sell the film rights!
[♪♪♪]
That clip
comes from the new
David O. Seltzer film.
The author...
of that film clip
is with me...
now.
Dr. E. Henry...
Thripshaw.
Well, uh-- Uh, I, uh--
I feel that they've missed
the whole point of my, uh--
my disease.
This is...
always the problem...
with directors...
of film... clips.
Yes, well, you see,
they--they've dragged in all
this irrelevant mush. Uh--
What...
are you doing...
...now?
Well, um,
at the present moment,
I am working on a new disease
uh, which I hope
to turn into a musical.
Um, but, uh, primarily, uh,
we are working on--on a remake
of my first disease
and this time we're hoping
to do it properly.
Well...
let's just...
take a...
look at this new...
film...
clip.
[♪♪♪]
Well, now, what seems
to be the matter?
[SPITS]
The next sketch follows
after some silly noises.
[FLATULENT SOUNDS]
-[CUCKOO CLOCK SOUNDS]
-[TAPPING]
[MAN YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
[CHICKENS CLUCKING]
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
-Come in.
-Oh.
I wondered if I could have
a word with you for a moment.
By all means. By all means,
sir. Do sit down.
Um...
-sit on the desk here.
-Oh, thank you.
Now, then,
glass of sherry?
Uh, no, thank you.
Are you sure?
I'm gonna have some.
If you're having some,
yes, then perhaps, vicar.
Oh, well there's only
just enough for me.
Well, in that case,
I won't, don't worry.
If I split what's left, there'd
be hardly any for me at all.
No. Well, I'm not
a great sherry drinker.
-Good. So I can have it all.
-Um...
Now, then,
what's the problem?
Well, just recently
I've begun to worry about...
-well, the last--
-Oh!
-Found another bottle.
-Oh.
You can have some now
if you want to.
Oh, well, then, yes,
perhaps a little.
You don't have to.
I can drink a whole bottle.
-Um...in that case, no.
-Good.
That's another
bottle for me.
I've begun to worry
recently, that...
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Come in.
Ah, Mr. Husband.
This is Mr. Kirkham,
one of my parishioners.
This is Mr. Husband of the
British Sherry Corporation.
Look, uh, perhaps I'd better
come back later--
No, no, no. Do stay. You won't
be long, will you, Husband?
No, vicar, it's just
a question of signing
a few forms.
There we are.
There we are, Mr. Husband.
How about you, Mr. Kirkham?
Um...well, only
if there's enough.
Oh, well, there's
not much now.
Oh. Uh, i-in that case,
no, I won't bother.
Good. Right.
Right. Now, then,
what is the problem,
Husband?
Well, vicar, I've made
inquiries with our shippers,
and the most sherry
they can ship
in any one load
is 12,000 gallons.
And how many glasses is that?
That's roughly
540,000 glasses, vicar.
That's excellent, Husband.
Excellent.
Yes. You can still keep
your main supply on the roof,
but have an emergency
supply underneath the vestry,
of 5000 gallons.
I could have dry sherry
on the roof,
and amontillado
in the underground tank.
-Absolutely.
-Excellent work, Husband.
Excellent work.
Not at all,
vicar.
You're one of
our best customers.
You and
the United States.
[LAUGHS]
Bye-bye.
Terrific. Now, then,
Mr. Kirkham, I am so sorry.
Do go on.
Well, i-it's just
that recently, I've begun
to worry about--
-Mm-hm.
-Well, look,
does the Bible intend--?
♪ Amontillado, amontillado
Amontillado ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Amontillado
Amontillado ♪
[SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
[PEOPLE WHOOPING]
ALL:
Olé!
-What did you want?
-Dirty books, please.
Right.
[ALL CHATTERING]
[♪♪♪]
[MUSIC STOPS, PEOPLE CONTINUE
CHATTERING LOUDLY]
ANNOUNCER:
E. Henry Thripshaw T-shirts
are now available
from BBC Enterprises.
The price hasn't finally
been decided,
and the address to write to,
they haven't yet
quite worked out.