[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Boxing Tonight comes
from the Empire Pool, Wembley,
and features the main
heavyweight bout
-between Jack Bodell...
-[CROWD CHEERS]
...British and Empire
Heavyweight Champion,
and Sir Kenneth Clark.
It's the first time these two
have met, so there should be
-some real action tonight.
-[BELL DINGS]
This, then, is the height
of the English Renaissance.
The triumph of classical
over Gothic.
-Oof!
-ANNOUNCER: He's down.
Sir Kenneth Clark is down
in eight seconds.
[GARBLED COUNTING]
ANNOUNCER: But he's up again.
He's up at six.
The almost ordered facades
of Palladio's villas reflect--
-Ooh!
-ANNOUNCER: And he's down again.
And I don't think he's gonna
get up this time.
[GARBLED COUNTING]
-Winner.
-[BELL DINGS]
ANNOUNCER:
No. So, Jack Bodell has
defeated Sir Kenneth Clark
in the very first round
here tonight.
And so, this big Lincolnshire
heavyweight
becomes the new Oxford
professor of fine art.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, ladies
and gentlemen.
And now...
[PLAYS ORGAN]
It's...
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Stand and deliver.
Drop that gun.
-[GUNSHOT]
-[MAN GROANS]
Let that be a warning
to you all.
You move at your peril,
for I have two pistols here.
I know one of them isn't loaded
anymore, but the other one is.
So that's one of you
dead for sure.
Or just about
for sure, anyway.
Certainly wouldn't be worth
your while risking it,
because I'm
a very good shot.
I practice every day.
Well, not absolutely every day,
but most days in the week.
I expect I must practice...
four or five times
a week at least.
At least four or five.
Only, some-- Some weekends,
like last weekend,
there wasn't much time, so that
moves the average down a bit.
But I should say
it's definitely
a solid four days'
practice every week.
At least. I mean,
I reckon
I could hit that tree
over there.
The one behind the hillock.
Not the big hillock.
The little hillock on the left.
You-- You see the three trees.
The third from the left
and back a bit. That one.
I reckon I could hit that
four times out of five...
on a good day.
Say, with this wind, say--
Say, seven times out of 10.
-What, that tree there?
-Which one?
The, uh, big beech
with the sort of bare branch
coming out of the top left.
No, no, not that one.
No, no. He means
the one over there.
-Look. Do you see
that one there?
-Yes.
Well, now, go two along
to the right.
Uh, just near
that little bush?
Well, it's the one
just behind it.
Oh. The elm.
No, that's not an elm.
An elm's got sort of great
clumps of leaves like that.
That's either a beech
or a, um... a, uh...
a hornbeam.
-A hornbeam?
-No, not a hornbeam.
What's the--? What's the tree
that has a leaf with regular
veins coming out.
And the veins go all the way
out to the, uh--?
-Serrated?
-To the serrated edges.
-A willow.
-Oh, that's right.
That's nothing like a willow.
Well, it doesn't matter,
anyway.
I could hit it seven times
out of 10. That's the point.
-Never a willow.
-Shut up!
This is a hold-up,
not a botany lesson.
Right. Now, my fine friends...
no false moves, please.
I want you to hand over
all the lupines you've got.
Lupines?
Yes, lupines.
Come on, come on.
What do you mean, "lupines"?
Don't try and play for time.
I'm not. You mean
the flower, lupines?
Yes, that's right.
-Well, we haven't
got any lupines.
-Honestly.
Look, my fine friends,
I happen to know
that this is
the Lupine Express.
You must be out of
your tiny mind.
Get out of the coach.
Come on, get out.
Just as I thought.
Not clever enough,
my fine friends.
Come on, Concorde.
Well, so much for the lupines.
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore
Galloping through the sward ♪
And his horse, Concorde ♪
♪ He steals from the rich
And gives to the poor ♪
♪ Mr. Moore, Mr. Moore ♪
Here we are.
-I'll be back.
-♪ Mr. Moore ♪
[WOMAN HUMS]
Morning,
Mrs. Trepidatious.
Oh, I don't know
what's good about it.
My right arm's hanging off
something awful.
Oh, you want to
have that seen to.
What, by that Dr. Morrison?
He's killed more patients
than I've had severe boils.
What do the stars say?
Well, Petula Clark says burst
them early. But David Frost--
No, the stars in the paper,
you cloth-eared heap of
anteater's catarrh.
The zodiacal signs.
The horoscopic fates.
The astrological portents.
The omens, the genethliac
prognostications.
The mantalogical harbingers.
The vaticinal utterances.
The fatidical
premonitory utterances
of the mantalogical omens.
What do the bleeding stars
in the paper predict?
Forecast, prophesy,
foretell...
ANNOUNCER:
And this is where you at home
can join in.
-...augur, spell,
foretoken, presage...
-[AUDIENCE JOINS IN]
...portend, foreshow,
foreshadow, forerun,
herald, point to,
betoken, indicate.
I don't know.
Well, what are you?
I'm Nesbitt.
There's not a zodiacal sign
called Nesbitt.
All right,
Derry and Toms.
Aquarius, Scorpio, Virgo,
April the 29th
to March the 22nd.
Even dates only.
Well, what does it
presage?
You have green, scaly skin,
and a soft,
yellow underbelly
with a series of fin-like ridges
running down your spine
and tail.
Although lizard-like in shape,
you can grow anything
up to 30 feet in length
with huge teeth that can bite
off great rocks and trees.
You inhabit arid subtropical
zones and wear spectacles.
Oh. That's very good
about the spectacles.
-It's amazing.
-Hm.
-What's yours, Irene?
-Basil.
I'm sorry.
What's yours, Basil?
No. That's
my star sign, Basil.
-Oh. There isn't a--
-Yes, there is.
Aquarius, Sagittarius,
Derry and Toms, Basil.
Oh.
June the 21st
till June the 22nd.
Well, what does it say?
You have green, scaly skin
and a series
of yellow underbellies
-running down your spine--
-That's exactly the same.
Oh. Try another one.
What's Aquarius?
It's a zodiacal sign.
I know that.
What's it say in the paper,
Mrs. Flan-and-Pickle?
Well, all right.
Oh. It says,
"A wonderful day ahead.
You will be surrounded
by family and friends.
Roger Moore will drop in
for lunch,
bringing Tony Curtis with him.
In the afternoon, a substantial
cash sum will come your way.
In the evening, Petula Clark
will visit your home
accompanied by
The Mike Sammes Singers.
She will sing for you
in your own living room.
Before you go to bed,
Peter Wyngarde will come
and declare his undying love
for you."
-Yuck!
-Ew!
What's Scorpio?
Oh, that's very good.
"You will have lunch with a
school friend of Duane Eddy's,
who will insist on whistling
some of Duane's greatest
instrumental hits.
In the afternoon,
you will die.
-You will be buried--"
-Good morning.
-Oh.
-Oh. Morning, doctor.
And how's the old arm
this morning, Mrs. Ikon?
Oh, it's still hanging off
at the shoulder.
Good. Well, let's, uh,
have a look at it, shall we?
[CHUCKLES]
Mm. Oh, damn.
Oh, damn this wretched
little bag.
Oh, damn this wretched,
bloody little bag.
If there's one thing I hate
about being a doctor,
it's this wretched,
bloody little bag.
Oh, damn this wretched,
bloody little bag!
Damn the bloody little bag!
Damn the bloody--
Damn you, wretched little bag.
There. Right.
What's that
doing in here? Ugh.
Eww!
All right. Well... hm-hm.
Uh, hand over
the money.
[SCREAMS]
Hm-hm.
Come on,
all of it.
[GROANS]
Thank you.
Yes. Good, that
seems to be okay.
Well, I'll just, uh,
test your reflexes.
[BOTH SCREAM]
Right. Now then,
everything seems to be okay.
I'll see you
next week.
Uh, keep collecting
the pension.
Try not to spend
too much on food.
-Thank you, doctor.
-Uh.
Morning, Mr. Henson.
How are you today?
Not too bad, doctor.
Okay. Take it easy.
Expecting any postal orders
this week?
No.
Righty-o.
Ah, Mr. Rodgers,
have you got your unemployment
benefits, please?
Right. Well, can you
write me a check then, please?
[HUMS]
Thank you very much.
Soon have you down to nothing.
Ahh.
Ah, Mr. Millichope.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[BLARING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[DOOR CLOSES,
FOOTSTEPS]
[KEYS JINGLING]
[MAN GROANS]
MAN:
Oh! Whoa!
[MAN GROANS]
[SIREN WAILING]
[SIREN STOPS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[DOORS SLAM]
Hm. Well, this will
have to do.
[TICKS]
[CLOCK CHIMES]
Cuckoo! Cuckoo! Cuckoo!
[CLOCK TICKS]
[ALARM RINGING]
WOMAN:
Ooh, lovely.
Dinner's ready,
dear.
[CLOCK RESUMES TICKING]
[ALARM BUZZES]
MAN:
Sorry. Your time's up,
Mr. Spume.
I'm afraid you lose both
the three-piece suite
-and your youngest daughter.
-[GUNSHOT]
[CLOCK RESUMES TICKING]
[LIT FUSE DISSOLVING]
[♪♪♪]
Hello. Should there be
another television channel
or should there not?
On tonight's program,
the minister for broadcasting,
-the Right Honorable
Mr. Ian Throat, MP.
-Good evening.
The Chairman
of Amalgamated Money TV,
-Sir Abe Sappenheim.
-Good evening.
The shadow spokesman
for television,
-Lord Kinwoodie.
-Hello.
And a television critic,
Mr. Patrick Loone.
Hello.
Gentlemen, should there be
a fourth television channel
or not?
-Ian?
-Yes.
-Francis?
-Nope.
-Sir Abe?
-Yes.
-Patrick?
-No.
Well, there you have it.
Two say will, two say won't.
We'll be back again next week.
Uh, next week's great debate
will be about government
interference in broadcasting,
and will be cancelled
mysteriously.
[♪♪♪]
[ALL SPEAK INAUDIBLY]
ANNOUNCER:
Just starting on BBC One now,
Victoria Regina,
the inspiring tale
of the simple
crofter's daughter
who worked her way up to
become queen of England
and empress of
the greatest empire
television has ever seen.
On BBC Two now,
episode three of George I,
the new 116-part serial
about the famous English king
who hasn't been done yet.
On ITV now, the--
-[THUD]
-[ANNOUNCER GROANS]
That's awful, but
absolutely delightful.
-[BOTH LAUGHING]
-But of course.
But of course, you know,
who cares?
He said, "Look--" Ah,
'tis my lord of Buckingham.
-Pray welcome, Your Grace.
-Thank you, Grantley.
Ladies, may I introduce
to you the man who prophesied
that a German monarch would
soon embroil this country
in continental affairs.
Oh. How soon,
my lord?
Madam, uh, you'll recall
that prior to his accession,
our gracious sovereign,
George, had become involved
in the long-standing
Northern War,
through his claim
to Bremen and Verden.
Uh, these duchies would
provide an outlet to the sea
of utmost value
to Hanover.
The Treaty of Westphalia
has assigned them to Sweden.
-In 1648.
-Exactly.
Meanwhile, Frederick William
of Denmark
taking advantage of the
absence of Charles XII,
seized them, 1712.
-Oh, yes?
-It all falls into place.
-More wine?
-Oh, thank you.
However, uh, just prior
to his accession,
uh, George made an alliance with
Frederick William of Prussia,
uh, on the, uh, grounds
of party feeling.
While Frederick William had
married George's only
daughter.
I remember the wedding.
But chiefly through
the concerted action
-against Charles XII.
-[GLASS BREAKS]
[ALL GASP, SCREAM]
Stand and deliver.
ALL:
Dennis Moore.
The same. And now, my lords,
my ladies...
your lupines, please.
Our--? Our what?
Come, come, don't
play games with me,
my Lord of Buckingham.
What can you mean?
Your life or your lupines,
my lord.
[EXASPERATED SIGH]
In a bunch. In a bunch.
Thank you, my friends.
And now, a good evening
to you all.
-[HORSE WHINNIES]
-MOORE: Giddyap! Forward!
He seeks them here.
He seeks them there.
He seeks those lupines
everywhere.
The murdering blackguard.
He's taken all our lupines.
Not quite.
-Oh! You-- You tricked him.
-We still have one.
ALL:
Hooray!
[♪♪♪]
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore
Riding through the night ♪
♪ Soon every lupine
In the land ♪
♪ Will be in his mighty hand ♪
♪ He steals them from the rich
And gives them to the poor ♪
♪ Mr. Moore, Mr. Moore ♪
♪ Mr. Moore ♪
[GROANING]
Try to eat some,
my dear.
It'll give you strength.
Oh, Mr. Moore.
Mr. Moore, she's going fast.
Don't worry. I've--I've
brought you something.
-Medicine at last?
-No.
-Food?
-Nope.
Uh, some blankets, perhaps?
Clothes? Wood for the fire?
Nope.
Lupines.
-Oh, Christ!
-I thought you liked them.
I'm sick to bloody
death of them!
So am I!
She's bloody dying, and
all you bring us is lupines.
All we've eaten, mate, for
the last four bleeding weeks
is lupine soup, roast lupine,
steamed lupine,
braised lupine
in lupine sauce,
lupine in the basket
with sautéed lupines,
lupine meringue pie,
lupine sorbet.
We sit on lupines.
We sleep in lupines.
We feed the cat on lupines.
We burn lupines.
We even wear the bloody things.
Looks very smart.
Oh, shut up!
We're sick to death
with the stench of them.
[CAT MEOWS]
[THUMP]
Look! The cat's just choked
itself to death on them.
I don't care if
I never see another lupine
till the day I die!
Why don't g--? You go out
and steal something useful?
Well, like what?
Like gold and silver,
and clothes and wood
and jewels and--
-Hang-- Hang on, I'll
get a piece of paper.
-Oh.
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore ♪
♪ Dum, dum, dum
The night ♪
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore ♪
♪ Dum, dum, dum, dum
Plight ♪
♪ He steals, dum, dum, dum ♪
♪ And dum, dum
Dum dee ♪
♪ Dennis, dum, Dennis, dee ♪
♪ Dum, dum, dum ♪
This, coupled with
the presence of Peter
and his Prussians
in Mecklenburg,
and Charles and his Swedes
in Pomerania,
made George and Stanhope eager
to come to terms with France.
-Meanwhile, a breach--
-[GLASS BREAKS]
-Oh, no. Not again.
-No!
-Oh, come on.
-Stand and deliver again.
Your money, your jewllery,
your-- Hang on.
Your clothes...your snuff,
your ornaments, your
glassware, your pussycats...
Don't say anything
about the lupine.
...your watches, your lace,
your spittoons...
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore
Riding through the woods ♪
With a bag of things ♪
♪ He gives to the poor
And he takes from the rich ♪
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore ♪
-Here we are.
-♪ Dennis Moore ♪
BOTH:
Ooh.
[MURMUR INDISTINCTLY]
ANNOUNCER:
It may be the end of that,
but it's far from the end of--
Well, in--in fact,
it's the beginning.
Well, not quite the beginning.
Well, certainly nearer
the beginning--
Well, yes, damn it, it is
to all intents and purposes
the beginning of this year's
Ideal Loon Exhibition,
sponsored by
the Daily Express.
Numbskulls and boobies
from all over the country
have been arriving to go
through their strange paces
before a large paying crowd.
This is the 15th
Ideal Loon Exhibition,
and we took a good look round
after it was opened
by its patron.
Here's Kevin Bruce,
the digger duffer
from down under,
who's ranked 14th in the World
Silly Positions League.
This kind of incoherent
behavior
is really beginning to catch
on down under.
There's Norman Kirby
from New Zealand,
whose specialty is standing
behind a screen
with a lady with no
clothes on.
In real life,
Norman is a gynecologist,
but this is his lunch hour.
And from France,
there's a superb exhibition
of rather silly behavior
by the Friends of
the Free French Osteopaths.
ALL:
Un, deux, trois.
ANNOUNCER:
They do this over 400 times
a day.
Nobody knows why.
But for sheer pointless
behavior,
you've got to admire
Brian Broomers,
the battling British boy,
who, for two weeks,
has been suspended over a tin
of condemned veal.
Always popular with the crowd
is the Scotsman
With Nae Trew's exhibit.
And this year is no exception.
Sponsored by Natural Gas
and Glasgow City Council,
this exhibit is
entirely supported
by voluntary contributions.
But for a truly magnificent
waste of time,
you've got to go no further
than the exhibit from Italy.
Italian Priests in Custard,
discussing vital matters
of the day.
These lads from a seminary
near Cremona
have been practicing
for well over a year.
As always,
one of the great attractions
of this 14-day exhibition
is the display
of counter-marching
given by the massed pipes
and toilet requisites
of the Colwyn Bay Massed Pipes
and Toilet Requisites Club.
An interesting point
about these boys
is they all have one thing
in common:
hip injuries.
Not far away, the crowds
are flocking to see
a member of the famous
Royal Canadian Mounted Geese.
But the climax of the whole
event is the judging.
MAN [OVER MICROPHONE]:
Mr. Justice Burke.
Well, that's the last,
and let's just see
those last six once again.
And the winner is number 41,
Mr. Justice Burke.
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
[WHEELS SQUEAKING]
[MISCHIEVOUS CHUCKLE]
Attention. Attention.
Uh, suspect heading due north.
Uh, plan 13-A
is now in effect.
[SQUEAKING]
Whoop!
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING RESUMES]
Yet fear, not like
an aged florin,
can so disseminate men's eyes
that fortune,
straining at a kissing touch,
may stop a ceaseless search
to sport amidst the rampant
thrust of time,
and bring the thing undone
to pass,
by that with which the cock
may chance an arm.
Well, that's all very well, sir,
but this is an off-license.
Uh, just a bottle
of sherry then, please.
Certainly.
Uh, amontillado?
-Yes, I think amontillado.
-Mm-hm.
Finely grown. Well-chosen
from the cask of Pluto's hills.
Celled deep within
the vinous soil of Spain,
wrenched thence from
fiery regions of the sun.
Yes, yes, sir.
Uh, just one bottle?
Just one bottle.
Just one jot.
Just one tittle.
That's a lot.
There we are, sir.
That'll be a pound, please.
A pound, a pound,
and all-around abound.
A pound, found, found.
Lost, lost the cost
till was embossed.
-Yes, uh-- Uh, excuse me, sir.
-Yes, good victualer.
Nature's trencherman,
mine honest tapster--
Be-- Uh, I was just wondering:
Um, are you a poet?
Uh, no. No, I'm--
I'm a solicitor.
Solicitor. Well...
Well-versed within
the written law of man.
-Who can to those who need--
-Oh, shut up.
I'm sorry.
I'm-- I'm afraid
I've caught poetry.
Oh, really? Oh, well,
don't worry, sir.
I used to suffer
from short stories.
Really? When?
Oh, once upon a time...
there lived in Wiltshire a young
chap called Dennis Moore.
Now, Dennis was
a highwayman by profession.
And for several months, he had
been stealing from the rich
to give to the poor.
One day...
Here we are again.
Mr. Jenkins.
There we are.
I'll be back.
Meanwhile, Frederick William,
busily engaged in defending
against the three great powers,
the province of Silesia...
Oh, which had seized in the
War of the Austrian Succession
-against his word.
-Yes, I remember.
-...was now dependent on--
-[GLASS BREAKS]
My lords, my ladies,
on your feet, please.
-Oh.
-[INDISTINCT MURMURS]
I must ask you
to do exactly as I say,
or I shall be forced to shoot
you right between the eyes.
-Oh!
-Oh, not right between the eyes.
I mean...
when I say "between the eyes,"
obviously, I don't have
to be that accurate.
I mean, if I hit you in that
sort of area, like that,
obviously, that's
all right for me.
I don't have to try and sort of
hit a point bisecting a line
drawn between your pupils
or anything.
I mean, from my point of view,
it's perfectly satisfactory--
What do you want?
Why are you here?
Well, why are
any of us here?
I mean...
when you get down to it,
it's all so meaningless,
isn't it?
I mean, what do any of us
want?
-No, no. What do you want now?
-Oh, I see.
Oh, just the usual things:
Uh, a little place of my own,
the right girl, a--
No, no, no.
What do you want from us?
Oh, s-- Um, your gold,
your silver, your jewelry.
You've taken
it all.
This is all
we've got left.
That's nice.
I'll have them.
Come on.
You'd better take
the bloody lupine too.
Thank you very much.
I've gone through that stage.
[♪♪♪]
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore ♪
♪ Et cetera, et cetera ♪
What you got
for us today then?
Well, I managed
to find you
four very nice
silver spoons,
Mr. Jenkins.
Who do you think you are,
giving us poor this rubbish?
Bloody silver.
I won't have it in me house.
Uh, and those candlesticks
you got us last week
were only 16 carat.
Yeah, why don't you go out
and steal something nice,
like some Venetian silver?
Yeah, or a Velasquez
for the outside loo.
Oh. All right.
♪ Dennis Moore, Dennis Moore ♪
♪ Riding through the land ♪
♪ Without a merry band ♪
♪ He steals from the poor
And gives to the rich ♪
♪ Stupid bitch ♪
What did you sing?
SINGERS:
We sang:
"He steals from the poor
and gives to the rich."
Wait a tic.
Blimey, this redistribution
of wealth is trickier
than I thought.
Oh, good evening,
and welcome to another
edition of Prejudice.
The show that gives
you a chance to have a go
at wops, krauts,
nigs, Eyeties, gyppos,
bubbles, froggies, Chinks,
yids, Jocks, Polacks,
Paddies and dagos.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
Tonight's show comes live
from the tiny village
of Rabid in Buckinghamshire.
And our first question tonight
is from Mrs. Elizabeth Scrint,
who says she is going on a
Mediterranean cruise next week
and can't find anything wrong
with the Syrians.
Well, Mrs. Scrint, apart from
being totally unprincipled
left-wing troublemakers, the
Syrians are also born skivers.
They're dirty, smelly
and untrustworthy.
And of course, they're friends
of the awful gyppos.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
Well, there you are,
Mrs. Scrint.
I hope that answers
some of your problems.
Have a nice trip.
Well, now the result
of last week's competition,
when we asked you to find
a derogatory term
for the Belgians.
Well, the response
was enormous,
and we took quite a long time
sorting out the winners.
There were some
very clever entries.
A Mrs. Hatred of Leicester
said:
"Let's not call them anything,
let's just ignore them."
-[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
-[LAUGHS]
And a Mr. St. John
of Huntingdon said
he couldn't think of anything
more derogatory than "Belgians."
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
But in the end we settled
on three choices.
Number three: the Sprouts.
Sent in by Mrs. Vicious
of Hastings.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
Very nice.
Number two: the Phlegms.
From Mrs. Childmolester
of Worthing.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
But the winner
was undoubtedly,
from Mrs. No-Supper-for-You
from Norwood in Lancashire:
miserable, fat Belgian
bastards.
-[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
-[LAUGHS]
Very good. Very good.
Thank you, Carol.
But, as you know,
on this program,
we're not just prejudiced
against race or color.
We're also prejudiced
against-- yes, you've guessed
--stinking homosexuals!
[ALL APPLAUD, CHEER]
So before the streets start
emptying in Chelsea tonight,
let's go over to our popular
prejudiced panel game
and invite you once again
to shoot the poof.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
And could our first contestant
sign in, please.
ANNOUNCER:
Our first contestant
is a hairdresser from--
-[GUNSHOT]
-[SCREAMS]
Oh, I never did like
that kind of person.
-[GUNSHOT]
-[GRUNTS]
DENNIS: Halt. Halt.
Gentlemen, ladies, bring out
your valuables, please.
ALL:
Oh, no.
Come along, sir.
Come along.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Come along, madam.
Now...
Is that all
you've got?
Yes.
Well, he's got
much more than you,
so you better have
some of his.
You got a lot of these.
Oh, sorry.
Pick them up
in a moment.
There's about, ooh, what,
nine down there.
So you must have about--
Oh, well, he's still
got lots--
You've got what? You've got
more than he started with.
So if I give you
some of those...
Uh, well, now, look.
If I give you that--
Uh, have you got
a bit of jewelry? Yes.
If I give you that one...
and you have some of
his coins...
Is that another box?
Were you trying to hide it?
Well--
Ooh, that's nice.
I'll have that.
Right. Now,
I've got a tiara.
You've got one.
You've got one in the box.
Anyone else
got a tiara?
Take your hat off.
Oh, honestly, it's
absolutely pointless
trying to do this
if you're going to cheat.
It really is
awful of you.
I thought you should
have won.
I mean, judicially,
you swept the board.
All right, he had posture.
But where was he
in the summing-up?
-Oh, shut up, Melford.
-[SOBS]
There's always
next year.
[♪♪♪]