[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Monty Python's Flying Circuses.
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
Book at Bedtime.
Tonight, Jeremy Toogood
reads Redgauntlet
by Sir Walter Scott.
Hello.
[CLEARS THROAT]
"The sunsuit--
he... The sunseeit...
The sun-- The sunset!
The sunset...
...was-- w-was-- was...
The sunset was...
...die-- deeing--
dying-- dying...
over the...
hile-- heel--
he-- heels--
halls-- hills!
hills...
of-- of slow--
Solway Firth.
The love piper--
The-- The lone piper!
The lone piper on the ba...
bat-tle-lyments...
...of Ed--
embing...
embingunder...
en-- Endingburger...
En... Em....
Edinburgh! Edinburgh...
castle was sil-- silow--
siluted-- si-- sill..."
"The sunset was dying
over the hills of Solway Firth.
The lone piper
on the battlements
of Edinburgh Castle
was silhouetted against
the crim... Crimsey...
Crimson.
Against the crimson strees...
Stre..."
-Streaked.
-Streaked?
"Crimson-streaked sky.
In the shadows
of Coriginu...
Coriginu?"
"Cran-- Crangrim.
Crangrim."
Cairngorm.
Oh, Cairngorm.
"In the shadows
of Cairngorm,
the lud...
Laird."
ALL:
Laird. Laird.
"The Laird of...
Of, um..."
"Laird of Monteur.
Montreaux!"
Montrose!
Montrose, Montrose.
"The Laird
of Montrose..."
"Galopped?"
"Galloped..."
-[PLAYING BAGPIPES]
-ANNOUNCER: The lone piper
on the battlements
of Edinburgh Castle.
[SCREAMS]
Next.
MAN [SCOTTISH ACCENT]:
Here, on top of
Edinburgh Castle,
in conditions
of extreme secrecy,
men are trained for
the British army's first
kamikaze regiment:
The Queen's own
McKamikaze Highlanders.
So successful
has been the training
of the kamikaze regiment
that the numbers
have dwindled from 30,000
to just over a dozen
in three weeks.
What makes these young
Scotsmen so keen to
kill themselves?
The money's good.
And the water-skiing.
[SCREAMING]
Attention!
All right, sergeant major,
at ease.
-Now, how many chaps
you got left?
-Six, sir.
-[SCREAM]
-Six?
Five, sir.
All right, good luck, Johnson.
Jolly-good show.
Well, I've come here
to tell you we got a job
for your five lads.
-[SCREAM]
-Uh, four, sir.
-For your four lads.
-Good luck, Taggart.
Thank you, sarge.
Now, this, uh, mission's
gonna be dangerous and tough.
We're gonna need every lad
of yours to pull his weight.
Now, which--?
Which four are they?
These three here, sir.
-Okay, off you go, Smith.
-Right!
-Uh, Sergeant major?
-Sir!
You don't think it might
be a good idea
to stop the training
for a bit?
They gotta be trained!
It's a dangerous job.
-[SCREAM]
-Yes, I realize, but--
MacPherson, you're next.
Off you go.
-Aye!
-See, what is worrying me--
I'll make it
a good'un, sir!
Good lad,
MacPherson.
Eh, MacPherson, um...
This mission is very dangerous.
We're gonna need both
the chaps you've got left.
-[SCREAM]
-Both of who, sir?
What's this
man's name?
Uh, this one, sir?
This one's MacDonald.
-MacDonald.
-Go ahead.
No, hang on to MacDonald.
Hang on to him.
I don't know
whether I can, sir.
He's in a state of
Itsubishi Kyoko McSayonara.
What's that?
It's the fifth state
a Scotsman can achieve, sir.
He's got to finish himself
off by lunchtime,
or he thinks he's let down
the emperor, sir.
Can't we get him
out of it?
Oh, I don't know
how to, sir.
Our kamikaze instructor,
Mr. Yashimoto, was so good
he never left
Tokyo airport.
There must be someone else
who could advise us.
Good morning.
Kamikaze, please.
Yes. Would you go
through, please?
Thank you.
[SCREAMS]
All right, sergeant major,
no time to lose.
Beg your pardon, sir?
No time to lose.
No what, sir?
No time.
No time to lose.
Oh, I see, sir. Uh, no time...
to lose, sir. Heh.
Yes, that's right. Yes.
Yes. No time to lose, sir.
Right.
Funny, sir. I've never come
across that phrase before:
"No time to lose."
Huh, 42 years I've been
in the regular army,
and I've never heard
that phrase.
It's in perfectly
common parlance.
-In what, sir?
-Oh, never mind.
Right, um, no time to lose.
Eventually, yes, sir.
What?
Well, like you said, sir.
We'll be able to make time,
eventually,
without to lose, sir, no.
Look, um... I don't think
you've quite got the hang
of this phrase,
sergeant major.
-Morning.
-[CLEARS THROAT]
No time to lose.
Now then, how were you
thinking of using this phrase?
Uh...
Well, I was-- I was thinking
of using it like, uh:
Ah... "Good morning, dear.
What is in no time to lose?"
Yes, well, you've not quite got
the hang of that, have you?
♪ No time to lose
No time to lose ♪
Uh, you want to use this phrase
in everyday conversation.
-Is that right?
-Uh, yes, that's right. Yes.
Yes, good.
[CLUCKING]
M-my wife and I have...
My wife and I have
never had a great deal
to say to each other.
In-- In the old days we used
to find things to say, like:
"Pass the sugar," or...
"That's my flannel."
But in the last
10 or 15 years,
there just hasn't seemed
to be anything to say.
Anyway, I saw your phrase
advertised in the paper,
and I thought:
"That's the kind of thing
I'd like to say to her."
Yes, well, what we'd
normally suggest
for a beginner
such as yourself,
is that you put your alarm clock
back 10 minutes in the morning,
so you can wake up,
look at the clock
and use the phrase
immediately.
-Shall we try it?
-Yes.
All right,
I'll be the alarm clock.
When I go off, look at me
and use the phrase, okay?
[IMITATES TICKING]
[IMITATES RINGING]
No!
Uh... time to lose.
No. "No time to lose."
No time to lose.
-No time to lose.
No. "To lose."
Like Toulouse in France.
"No time Toulouse."
No. "No time Toulouse."
"No. No time Toulouse."
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
No-time Tolouse.
[READS]
MAN:
All right, you yellow-bellied
sidewinder...
go for your guns.
Anyway, um... no time to lose,
sergeant major.
Look out, sir.
-MacDonald!
We'll have to
hurry, sir.
Now, MacDonald, put that down.
Put that down, MacDonald.
He's reached...
He's reached the sixth
plane already, sir.
Right. Here are the plans,
sergeant major. Good luck.
Thank you, sir!
And, uh, good luck
to you, MacDonald.
-Thank you, sir.
-Right. Come on.
No time to lose.
Very good, sergeant major.
Yes, excellent.
ANNOUNCER:
So it was that on
a cold November morning,
RSM Urdoch
and Sapper MacDonald,
one of the most
highly-trained
kamikaze experts
the Scottish Highlands
had ever witnessed,
left on a mission,
which was to--
Oh, I can't go on
with this drivel.
All right, MacDonald,
no time to lose.
-[SCREAMING]
-MacDonald!
[TIRES SCREECH]
[MacDONALD CHOKES]
In we go.
[GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
That's the mission.
Here's the method.
RSM Urdoch will
lull the enemy
into a false sense
of security
by giving them
large quantities of money,
a good home
and a steady job.
Then, when they're upstairs
with the wife,
uh, Sapper MacDonald will hurl
himself at the secret documents,
destroying them and himself.
Well, that's the plan.
The time is now 1942 hours.
I want you to get to bed,
have a good night's rest,
and be on parade
early in the morning.
Thank you for listening, and
thank you for a lovely supper.
"And... A-a-and-- And sue... So.
So, so, so...the--
The in-- intripted--"
-Intrepid.
-Intrepid. Yeah, intrepid.
"Intrepid RSM Urdoch
and super..."
-Sapper.
"Sapper Mac-- MacDonald..."
-ALL: Made.
-"Made-- Made-- Made--
-Made their why--"
-ALL: Way.
"Way to-- Towawa--"
Towards!
"Towards... Towards
the-- The Roos-- Roosty?
-Roosty..."?
-Russia?
ALL:
Russian!
"Russian bolder."
ALL: Border!
"And so-- And so, RSM Urdoch
and Sapper MacDonald made their
way towards the Russian bolder."
ALL:
Border!
MAN:
It's not the Russian bolder.
[CLANG]
[GRUNTING]
[MUMBLING]
[CELESTIAL TUNE PLAYING]
[GRUNTING]
[MUMBLING]
[CELESTIAL TUNE PLAYING]
-[MUMBLING]
-[DING]
[GRUNTING]
[PEACEFUL MUSIC SOUNDS]
[RICHARD STRAUSS' "ALSO SPRACH
ZARATHUSTRA" PLAYING]
[MUSIC FALTERS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[COMIC MUSIC PLAYING]
Penguins. Yes, penguins.
What relevance do
penguins have
to the furtherance
of medical science?
Well, strangely enough,
quite a lot.
A major breakthrough, maybe.
It was from such
an unlikely beginning
as an unwanted fungus
accidentally growing
on a sterile plate,
that Sir Alexander Fleming
gave the world penicillin.
James Watt watched an ordinary
household kettle boiling,
and conceived the potentiality
of steam power.
Would Albert Einstein
ever have hit upon
the theory of relativity
if he hadn't been clever?
All these tremendous
leaps forward
have been taken in the dark.
Would Rutherford
ever have split the atom
if he hadn't tried?
Could Marconi
have invented the radio
if he hadn't by pure chance
spent years
working at the problem?
Are these amazing
breakthroughs ever achieved,
except by years and years
of unremitting study?
Of course not.
What I said earlier about
accidental discoveries
must have been wrong.
Nevertheless, scientists
believe that these penguins,
these comic, flightless,
web-footed little bastards,
may finally, unwittingly,
help man to fathom
the uncharted depths
of the human mind.
Professor Rosewall
of the Laver Institute.
Hello.
Here at the Institute,
Professor Charles Pasarell,
Dr. Peaches Bartkowicz
and myself
have been working
on the theory,
originally postulated
by the late Dr. Kramer,
that the penguin is
intrinsically more intelligent
than the human being.
The first thing that
Dr. Kramer came up with
was that
the penguin has
a much smaller brain
than the man.
This postulate formed
the fundamental basis
of all of his thinking
and remained with him
until his death.
[GRUNT]
Now, we've taken this theory
one stage further.
If we increase
the size of the penguin,
until it is the same
height as the man,
and then compare
the relative brain sizes,
we now find that the penguin's
brain is still smaller.
But, and this is the point,
it is larger than it was.
For a penguin to have
the same size of brain as a man,
the penguin would have to be
over 66-feet high.
This theory has become known
as the "waste-of-time theory,"
and was abandoned in 1956.
Hello again. Standard IQ tests
gave the following results:
The penguins scored badly
when compared with primitive
human sub-groups
like the Bushmen
of the Kalahari,
but better than
BBC program planners.
The BBC program planners'
surprisingly high total here
can be explained away
as being within the ordinary
limits of statistical error.
One particularly dim
program planner
can cock
the whole thing up.
These IQ tests
were thought to contain
an unfair cultural bias
against the penguin.
For example, it didn't
take into account
the penguin's extremely poor
educational system.
To devise
a fairer system of tests,
a team of our researchers
spent 18 months in Antarctica
living like penguins...
and subsequently dying
like penguins,
only quicker...
Proving that the penguin
is a clever little sod
in his own environment.
Therefore, we devised tests
to be given to the penguins
in the fourth set.
I do beg your pardon.
In their own environment.
-MAN: Net!
-Shh!
What is the next number
in this sequence?
Two, four, six...
[PENGUIN SHRIEKS]
Did he say "eight"?
[SIGHS]
What is...?
ROSEWALL:
The environmental barrier
had been removed,
but we'd hit another:
the language barrier.
The penguins could not
speak English,
and were therefore
unable to give the answers.
This problem was removed in
the next series of experiments
by asking the same questions
to the penguins
and to a random group
of non-English-speaking humans
in the same conditions.
What is
the next number?
Two, four, six...
Hello?
The results of these tests
were most illuminating.
The penguins' scores
were consistently equal
to those of the
non-English-speaking group.
[SQUAWKS]
These enquiries led to
certain changes at the BBC...
[SHRIEKING]
...while attendances
at zoos boomed.
ROSEWALL:
Soon these feathery
little hustlers
were infiltrating important
positions everywhere.
[GRUNTS]
[KICKING, SQUAWKING]
[GLASS BREAKS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[GASP]
[KICKING, GROANING]
[SHRIEKS]
[GASP]
[KICKING NOISES]
-[CROWD CHEERING]
-[GASP]
[SHRIEKING]
[SHRIEKS]
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYS]
[IN RUSSIAN]
We must study them in conditions
of absolute secrecy.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Look out!
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYING]
-[GLASS BREAKS]
-[MAN SCREAMS]
[TICKING NOISE]
He hasn't gone off.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Yes, my general!
What?
[RINGING]
[TICKING]
[SINGING]
[CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
And welcome to
Spot the Looney,
where, once again,
we invite you to come with us
all over the world
to meet all kinds of people
in all kinds of places,
and ask you to...
"Spot the Looney!"
Our panel this evening,
Gurt Svensson,
the Swedish mammal abuser
and part-time radiator.
Good evening.
Dame Elsie Occluded,
historian, wit, bon viveur,
and rear half
of the Johnson brothers.
Good evening.
And Miles Yellowbird,
up high in banana tree,
the golfer and inventor
of Catholicism.
Good evening.
Ha. And we'll be inviting
them to: "Spot the Looney."
[BUZZES]
Ha-ha, yes, quite right.
A viewer
from Preston there
who's pointed out correctly
that the entire panel
are loonies.
Five points to Preston there and
on to our first piece of film.
It's about mountaineering.
And remember,
you have to spot the looney.
NARRATOR: The legendary south
face of Ben Macdui,
dark, forbidding...
[CHEERFUL MUSIC SOUNDS]
[BUZZ]
Ha-ha. Yes, well done.
Mrs. Nesbitt of York spotted
the looney in 1.8 seconds.
On to our second round.
And it's photo time.
We're gonna invite you
to look at photos
of Tony Jacklin,
Anthony Barber,
Edgar Allan Poe,
Katy Boyle, Reginald Maudling,
and a looney.
All you have to do is
spot the looney.
[BUZZ]
Now, I must ask you please
not to ring in until you've
seen all the photos.
-[CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
-[PHONE RINGS]
[WHISTLE]
Ha-ha. Yes, you're right.
The answer was,
of course, number two.
Uh, I'm afraid there's been
an error in our computer.
The correct answer should,
of course,
have been number four,
and not Katy Boyle.
Katy Boyle is not a looney.
She is a television
personality.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
And now it's time for:
Spot the Looney:
Historical Adaptation.
And this time it's the
thrilling medieval romance,
Ivanhoe.
A stirring story
of love and war,
violence and chivalry,
set amidst the pageantry
and splendor of 13th-century
England.
All you have to do is
spot the looney.
[BUZZING]
[BELLS RINGING]
Yes, well done,
Mrs. L. of Leicester,
Mrs. B. of Buxton,
and Mrs. G. of Gatwick.
The looney was of course
the writer:
Sir Walter Scott.
I didn't write that!
Sounds more like Dickens.
You bastard!
Was Sir Walter Scott
a looney?
Or was he the
greatest flowering
of the early 19th-century
romantic tradition?
The most underestimated
novelist of the 19th century?
Or merely a disillusioned
and embittered man--
Excuse me, can I
borrow that, please?
-Here.
-Thank you.
These trees behind me now were
planted over 40 years ago
as part of a policy
by the then-Crown Woods,
who became the Forestry
Commission in 1924.
-Excuse me.
-The Forestry Commission
systematically replanted
this entire area. Shh.
That's 40,000 acres
of virgin forest.
By 1980 this will have risen to
200,000 acres of soft woods.
In commercial terms,
a coniferous cornucopia,
an evergreen El Dorado,
a tree-lined treasure trove...
-[MURMURS]
-No!
...a fat, fir-coned future
for the financiers.
-But what of the cost--
-It's mine!
Go away!
--in human terms?
Who are
the casualties of--?
For this was
Sir Walter Scott's country.
In many of
his finest romances,
such as Guy Mannering
or Redgauntlet--
-Give that back!
-No.
--Scott showed himself
to be not only a f--
The spruces and firs
of this forest
will be used
to create-- Aah!
And also a writer
of humor and--
Britain's timber resources
are being used up
at the rate of over--
One man who knew Scott
was Angus Tinker.
TINKER:
Much of Scott's greatest work,
and I'm thinking here
particularly of Heart of
Midlothian, and, uh,
Old Mortality, for example.
--was concerned with
preserving the life and
conditions of a--
Forestry research here has shown
that a wholly synthetic
soft-timber fiber
can be created,
leaving the harder trees:
the oaks,
the beeches, the larches,
and the pines, and even some
of the deciduous hardwoods.
-This new soft-timber
fiber would--
-Can I have that back?
--totally replace the plywoods,
hardboards and chipboards,
at present
dominating the, uh--
In the Waverley novels,
Scott was constantly concerned
to protect a way of...
[THUD]
...safeguarding
nationalist traditions
and aspirations, within
the necessary limitations
of the gothic novel.
Scott explored
the torturous,
and at times,
self-destructive--
Developments in
reinforced timber--
Scott lived in Abbotsford,
in the heart of the country--
Maplewood and rosewood--
A subjugated country,
as Scotland--
An increase in
the Canadian timber--
Which were recovering
from the effects
of two unsuccessful
Jacobite rebellions--
For wood
adhesives--
In Rob Roy
and also in--
The decline
in hard--
Scott was at pains
to emphasize the--
[TIRES SCREECH]
[CRASH]
"Theend.
The ned."
-MAN: Thend.
-"The end." Ah.
ALL:
The end.
"The end."
[♪♪♪]
[BUZZ]
[APPLAUSE, CROWD CHEERING]
[BUZZING]
[MOUTHS WORDS]
ANNOUNCER:
Next week on
Book at Bedtime:
Jeremy Toogood will be reading
Anna Sewell's Black Bue--
But... Black Beut...
Black Bottom...
Black Bub-- Beautum...
Black Butty...
ANNOUNCER 2: Tomorrow night,
comedy returns to BBC TV
with a new series of
half-hour situation comedies
for you to spot the winners.
Ronnie Thompson stars
in Dad's Doctor,
the daffy exploits
of the RAMC training school.
He's in charge of a group
of mad medicos,
and when they run wild,
it's titty jokes galore.
Newcomer Veronica Papp
plays the girl
with the large breasts.
Week two sees the return
of the wacky exploits
of the oddest couple
you've ever seen.
Yes, Dad's Pooves.
The kooky, oddball,
laugh-a-minute
fun-a-plenty world
of unnatural
sexual practices.
Week three brings
a change of pace
to the new comedy schedules.
With Reg Cuttleworth,
Trevor Quantas,
and Cindy Rommel as Bob in:
On the Dad's Liver
Bachelors at Large.
Keeping the buses running
from typical bed-sit land
in pre-war Liverpool.
That's followed by
The Ratings Game.
The looney life
of a BBC program planner,
with the accent on repeats.
Edie Phillips-Bong
plays Kevin Vole,
the program planner
with a problem,
and his comic attempts
to pass the time.
Week six sees the return
of Up the Palace...
the zany exploits
of a wacky queen.
And that's followed by
Limestone, Dear Limestone,
the wacky days
of the late Pleistocene era,
when much of Britain's rock
strata was being formed.
All this and less
on Comedy Ahoy.
But now, BBC Television
is closing down for
the night.
Don't forget to
switch off your sets.
Good night.