[♪]
The golden age of ballooning
can be said to begin
in 1783...
[METAL CLANGING]
...when the Montgolfier
brothers made their
first ascent
in a fire balloon.
On the eve of that--
Come on, come on.
--momentous ascent,
the brothers
took one last look
at their craft
as it stood on the fields
of Annencay.
This is a great moment
for us, Joseph.
It is a great moment
for France.
Ah, oui.
The first ascent
in a hot-air balloon
by the Montgolfier
brothers, 1783.
I can see us now...
just after Montesquieu
and just before Mozart.
I think I'll go and wash.
Good luck.
Oh, it's quite easy really.
I just slap a little
water on--
No, no, no, no.
Good luck for tomorrow.
Oh, I see.
Yes. You too.
Yours has been
the work.
Let us hope
for a safe ascent.
And, uh, don't use
my flannel.
You know...when you showed me
the plans in Paris,
I could not believe
that we should be
the first men
who would fly.
Yes, it's wonderful.
I'm so excited
I could hardly wash.
Yes. I, too, have had
some difficulty washing
these past few days.
Still, what is washing,
when we are on the verge
of a great scientific
breakthrough?
Jacques?
Yes, Joseph?
I've not been washing
very thoroughly
for many years now.
What do you mean?
Y-you must have been
washing your face.
Oh, yes, my face.
I've washed my face.
But my legs...
my stomach, my chest...
they're filthy.
Well, uh, I don't wash
my stomach every day.
Ah, but you wash
far more than me.
You are the cleaner
of the Montgolfier brothers.
This is nothing,
Joseph--
Monsieur
Montgolfier,
a Mr. Parfitt
to see you, sir.
Eh, ah, no, no, no.
Uh, Bartlett.
A Mr. Barklit
to see you, sir.
No. Bart-lett.
With a T.
A Mr. Barrat-elett
to see you, sir.
Bartlett.
Barkit.
Barklit.
Bartlett.
A Mr. Bart-lett
to see you, sir.
I don't wanna see anyone,
O'Toole. Tell him to go away.
Thank you, sir.
Well, it's
getting late.
I must go
and have a wash.
Uh, what will you be washing?
Oh, just my face and neck.
Perhaps my feet, and
possibly--
But no. No.
Lock up the plans,
Joseph.
Tomorrow they will make us
the toast of France.
The first ascent by
the Montgolfier brothers
in a balloon.
Just after Ballcock
and just before Bang.
What a position.
ANNOUNCER:
So on June 7th, 1783,
the Montgolfier brothers
had a really good wash.
Starting on his face
and arms,
Joseph Michel Montgolfier
went on to scrub his torso,
his legs and his naughty
bits,
before rinsing his whole
body.
That June night,
he and his brother between
them
washed 17 square feet
of body area.
They used a kilo and a half
of carbolic soap
and nearly 14 gallons
of nice hot water.
It was indeed
an impressive sight.
Next week on
The Golden Age of Ballooning,
we examine the work
of Glashire and Coxwell,
the English balloonists
who ascended to a height
of seven miles in 1862
without washing.
There is also a book called
The Golden Age of Ballooning
published by the BBC
to coincide with the series.
It's in an attractive
hand-tooled binding,
Is priced 5 pounds,
and failure to buy it will make
you liable to a 50 pound fine
or three months in prison.
There's also a record
of someone
reading the book of
The Golden Age of Ballooning,
a crochet-work bedspread
with the words
"The Golden Age of
Ballooning" on it,
available from the BBC,
price 18 pound,
or five months imprisonment.
And there are matching
toilet-seat covers
and courtesy mats
with illustrations
of many of
the balloons mentioned.
Also available is
a life-sized model frog
which croaks the words:
"Golden Age of Ballooning,"
and an attractive
Bakelite case
for storing motorway
construction plans in,
made in the shape of a
balloon.
And now, another chance
to see episode two
of the award-winning series
The Golden Age of Ballooning.
[♪]
Oh, Joseph. All you
think about is balloons.
All you talk about
is balloons.
Your beautiful house is full
of bits and pieces of
balloons.
Your books are
all about balloons.
Every time
you sing a song,
it is in some way obliquely
connected with balloons.
Everything you eat
has to have the word "balloon"
incorporated in the title.
Your dogs are
all called Balloon-o.
You tie balloons to your
ankles in the evenings.
I don't do that.
Well...no,
you don't do that.
But you do duck down
and shout:
"Hey, balloons,"
when there are none about.
Oh, your whole life
is becoming
obsessively balloonic,
you know?
Ohh! Why do I
have to hang
from this bloody gasbag
all day?
Don't I mean
anything to you?
Oh, ma chérie,
you mean more to me
than any heavier-than-air
dirigible.
Oh, there you go again!
Don't waggle!
Oh.
I've run your bath
for you, Joseph.
Uh, oh, I'm so sorry,
I didn't realize, uh...
It's all right.
We've done the difficult bit.
Don't forget
we have our special guest
coming this evening.
Oh?
Don't tell me
you've forgotten already.
The man who is giving us
thousands of francs
for experiments.
What man?
Louis XIV.
Isn't he dead?
Evidently not.
All right, I'll be round.
Oh, and Joseph?
Yes, Jacques?
You will...wash, won't you?
Yes, of course.
[DOOR OPENS]
His Royal Majesty
Louis XIV of France.
And
Mr. Bartlett.
[♪]
Your Majesty,
it is a great privilege.
Welcome to our humble abode.
It's, eh, very nice
to be here.
O'Toole.
O'TOOLE: Sir?
Claret for
His Majesty, please.
There's a Mr. Bartlett
outside again, sir.
Not now. We have
the king of France here.
Yes, sir.
Hm.
[EXHALES]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Your Majesty, you had a--
A pleasant journey, I trust?
Yes, yes. Oh, definitely,
yes, yes.
Oh, aye. Aye. Mm.
You have come from Paris?
Where?
Eh, from Paris?
You have traveled from Paris?
Oh, yes, yes, yes. We've come
from, eh-- From, uh, Paris.
Yes, oh, yes. Yes, we've, uh,
just come from, eh...
Eh...Paris, yes.
O'TOOLE: Sir?
Yes, O'Toole?
Which one is
the claret, sir?
The claret
is in the decanter.
The wooden thing?
No, no.
The glass thing.
The glass decanter
with the round glass stopper.
Oh, yes, behind the door.
No, no.
On the sideboard.
The sideboard?
The sideboard, yes.
Look, you go into
the salle à manger --
the dining room, right?
--and the sideboard's
on your left by the wall.
Beside the master's
portrait.
Oh. Above
the mirror, sir?
No, no, no, no. The mirror's
on the other side.
It's opposite the mirror.
But that's
the table, sir.
No, you don't go as far
as the table. Oh, look--
You go into
the room, right?
On your right is the door
to the orangery,
straight ahead of you
is the door to the library,
and to your left...
is the sideboard.
Ah, yes, I see, sir.
And the claret is on top
of the sideboard, to the left.
On the left.
Yes.
As one looks at it, sir?
I see, sir. Thank you.
O'Toole.
Yes, sir.
Will you please tell Monsieur
Joseph our guest is here.
Yes, sir.
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Ah!
I'm, uh, sorry
about that, Your Majesty.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Apparently, sir, there's
a plan to build a canal
between the two Egyptian--
Not now, O'Toole.
Well, eh,
Mr. Montgolfier,
let's not beat
around the bush.
My, eh-- My-- My dukes and I
are very busy men.
What we'd like to do
is see the, uh, plans
of your proposed balloon,
if that's at all possible.
Certainly. I have them
here ready prepared.
Oh, great, hen.
Now, what we'd like to do
is, eh...take these,
uh, back with us
for the Royal Archives
of, eh--
France.
France, aye.
Well, it is indeed a great
honor that I cannot refuse.
Right. Okay,
let's get 'em.
JOSEPH: Just a moment!
JACQUES: Joseph.
That man is not Louis XIV.
Joseph, are you
out of your mind?
I've been looking it up
in my bath.
Louis XIV died in 1717.
It's now 1783.
Answer me that.
Did I say Louis XIV?
I'm sorry, I meant Louis XV.
Louis XV.
He died in 1774.
All right.
Louis XVI.
Listen to me,
smart-arse...
when you're king
of France,
you've got better things to do
than go around all day
remembering
your bloody number.
[BONES SNAP,
GRUNTING]
All right. You wanna
argue about numbers?
No, no.
Boys, get hold of these plans
for the Royal Archives.
We've gotta get back to, eh...
Paris.
Paris. By tonight.
come on, let's move.
I got as far as
the sideboard, sir.
Stop them,
stop them. Oof!
Ohh!
No news on the canal,
I'm afraid, sir,
but apparently in India...
[SCREAMS]
...they're thinking of
building a railway
between the towns
of Lahore...
ANNOUNCER:
Will Louis XIV get away
with the Montgolfiers'
precious plans?
Is 16 years of work
to be stolen
by this suspect sovereign?
Is France really in the grip
of a Glaswegian monarch?
Watch next week's episode
of The Golden Age
of Ballooning now.
[♪]
So now that the government
has collapsed
and shown itself incapable
of providing any kind
of unifying force,
I feel that we do need
the kind of stability
and the breathing space
that a military presence
would provide.
Lord Interest?
Yes, I-I agree
the army should take over,
but I think it should
not interfere
with the program
of street executions,
which I feel have been
the shot in the arm
that the British economy
so desperately needed.
Yes, the Montgolfier brothers'
plans did indeed turn up,
six months later
and a long way from Paris,
at the court of
King George III of England.
[♪]
"Titty was very worried.
"Where could Mary be?
"He looked everywhere.
"Under the stones
and behind the bushes.
"And Mr. Squirrel
helped him
"by looking up
in the trees.
And Mr. Badger helped him
by looking under the ground--"
[KNOCK AT DOOR]
"And so, Your Majesty,
we, the Commons
do herein crave
and, eh--"
Your Majesty,
Louis XVIII is here.
Who is Louis XVIII?
He is the king of France,
Your Majesty.
Uh, this is a great moment
to have, sir.
There is no Louis XVIII.
MAN: Psst.
[MUTTERS]
Tell him to stop mucking
about, Louis XVII's out here.
He craves Your Majesty's
pardon.
He has had a long journey here
and miscounted.
He is Louis XVII.
Louis XVI
is dead already?
MAN: No, I don't--
Oh, don't you
tell me-- I know my name.
I know about the numbers.
I know this country...
If he doesn't
know the bloody--
[BONE CRACKS, GROANING]
Your Majesty, I'm Louis XVI--
Oh, Christ.
Your Majesty,
I'm Louis XVI,
as you so rightly say,
and I don't wanna muck about.
I've got a wee
proposition,
which could make the name
of George IV
the most respected
in Europe.
George III.
Aye, Geo-- George III.
Sorry. Where can we talk?
Did you see that?
[GROANING]
We shall have a state banquet
at St. James's Palace.
No, I don't wanna
hang about. Take it or leave.
I gotta get back to...
DUKE: Paris.
Paris, by tonight,
you know.
Must you leave us,
Louis?
Yeah, I'd rather just
sell the plans
and nip off,
Georgie boy.
Well, all right.
We shall buy the plans,
if you will undertake
to disengage your troops
in America.
Do what?
And I shall give you
10,000 pound for the plans.
Ten thousand pounds?
Right. All right, well,
we'll, uh--
We'll, uh, disengage
the, um, you know...
Like you said,
we'll disengage 'em.
Tell you what, hen, I'll put
a duke onto it, okay? Right.
Oh, it's worst thing
you can do to anybody.
You asked for it, sonny.
Well, you could've broke
my nose.
I'll break it your--
North, please!
NORTH: Well, you saw it.
It was right
on the bone.
North, will you send
for the Duke of Portland?
We have a financial matter
to discuss.
Well,
it really hurt.
No, d-- I think it's better
if you give the money to us.
You know, we're going back.
We've got a bag.
No, no-- Don't--
Don't worry, Louis.
We shall talk
to your Monsieur Necker.
Ah, well-- A-- Actually, we'd
rather you didn't, you know.
We've been having a wee bit
of trouble with him recently.
Monsieur Necker?
The man who introduced
so many valuable reforms,
and proved so popular,
despite his opposition
to Mirabeau's policy
of issuing assignats?
Uh, aye, yeah.
But, eh, the trouble is
he's been drinking
a bit recently.
Fourteen lagers with his
breakfast, that sort of thing.
Well, very well,
Louis.
Just a moment!
Oh, Christ.
What are you doing?
I am Joseph
Montgolfier,
the inventor
of the fire balloon.
The man before you
is an impostor.
Oh, no, I am not.
Honestly.
No, no, no. Not you,
Your Majesty. This man.
This Louis, the so-called
king of France man.
Which number did he give you
this time, Louis XXIII?
I got it right!
Yeah, I bet you took
a few guesses.
Listen, you spotty
Sassenach pillock.
Your Majesty,
the Ronettes are here.
And Mr. Bartlett.
♪ George III ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
Mmph! Oh, dear.
I'm not supposed
to go mad until 1800!
♪ George III ♪
Oh.
Joseph has been gone
for six months now.
We have heard
nothing.
He can look after himself.
Oh. But he had only on
a towel, you know.
Antoinette...from now on,
there is only one
Montgolfier brother.
But Louis XIV
has the plans.
Oh, you must wait
until Joseph returns.
The plans
are here, chérie.
Let me put my tongue
in your mouth.
What do you mean?
We're supposed to be
French, aren't we?
No, no, no. I mean,
what are the plans
which Joseph
after is chasing?
Please, let me put it
in a little way.
The plans!
I take it out if you
don't like it.
No, listen--
Are you sure the claret
was on the left
of the sideboard,
sir?
Yes, O'Toole,
it's always been there.
Well, I'll look for
one more month, sir.
Please let me put
my tongue--
No, no.
By the way, sir,
Mr. Bartlett
has gone, sir.
He said he couldn't
wait any longer.
Thank you, O'Toole.
Not at all, sir.
I've enjoyed being in it.
Right.
Thank you, sir.
Mademoiselle.
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
By the way, sir,
Mr. Bartlett has gone, sir.
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
He said he couldn't
wait any longer, sir.
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
Thank you,
O'Toole.
Not at all, sir,
I've enjoyed being in it.
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
Right.
Thank you, sir.
Mademoiselle.
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[♪]
ANNOUNCER:
George III was arranged
and composed by Neil Innes.
He is available from the
BBC, price 4 pound,
or eight months
imprisonment.
That was episode three
of The Golden Age
of Ballooning.
May I remind you that
there's still time to get
your Golden Age of
Ballooning suppositories
direct from the BBC,
price 4.50 or 19 pound
for a set of six.
Well, in a moment the BBC
will be closing down
for the night.
But first,
here is a party political
broadcast
on behalf
of the Norwegian Party.
[SPEAKING NORWEGIAN]
[BUZZING]
ANNOUNCER:
That broadcast
will be discussed later
by Lord George-Brown,
ex-foreign secretary,
Mr. Sven Olafson,
the ex-Norwegian
minister of finance,
Sir Charles Ollendorff,
ex-chairman
of the Norwegian
Trades Council,
Mr. Hamish McLavell,
the mayor of Wick,
the nearest large town
to Norway,
Mrs. Betty Norday, whose
name sounds remarkably
like Norway,
Mr. Brian Waynor, whose name
is an anagram of Norway,
Mr. and Mrs. Ford, whose name
sounds like fjord,
of which there are
a lot in Norway,
Ron and Christine Boslow--
[♪]
NARRATOR:
Ferdinand von Zeppelin was
born in Konstanz in 1838,
the brother of Barry
Zeppelin,
the least talented
of the 14 Zeppelin brothers.
[♪]
[BLOWING]
Hmm.
Hm.
[BLOWING]
Meanwhile,
for Ferdinand von Zeppelin,
the year 1908 was a year
of triumph.
[SYMPHONIC MUSIC PLAYING]
Herr Zeppelin,
it's wonderful.
It's put ballooning
right back on the map.
It's not a balloon.
Do you hear?
It's an airship!
An airship, do you hear?!
Well,
it's very nice anyway.
Tell me, uh, what is
the principle of this balloon?
It's not a balloon, you
stupid, thickheaded,
Saxon git!
It's not a balloon!
Balloons is
for kiddy-winkies.
If you want to play
with balloons, get outside!
[SCREAMING]
"Yorkshire pudding.
A type
of thick pancake,
eaten with large--"
[CRASHING]
I hear you are to name
the balloon after Bismarck.
Bismarck? Of course I'm not
calling it after Bismarck.
It's a Zeppelin!
It's nothing to do
with bloody Bismarck!
Surely he gave you
some money for it.
Get outside!
[SCREAMING]
[SLOWLY]
"Zabaglione.
"A sort of cream
mouse--
Mousse
--of Italian origin."
[CRASHING]
Ferdinand, that was
a minister of state
you just threw out
of the balloon.
It's not
a balloon!
It's an airship!
All right, I'm sorry.
All right,
go and have a look!
No, I'm fine here,
thank you.
[MEN SCREAMING]
"Zucchini.
Italian mallows--"
[CRASHING]
"Zingara.
"A garnish
of finely chopped
or shredded lean ham--"
[CRASHING]
"Tongue...
...mushrooms
and truffles."
[CRASHING]
"Zakuski.
"A Russian hors d'oeuvre
served--"
[CRASHING]
"With tiny pieces
of sliced--"
Oh, look.
It's the chancellor.
Oh.
Prince Von Buelow? Here?
Yeah.
Coming here?
No, no. He is here.
Oh! I must go and
put my old uniform on.
He won't notice,
Helmut.
He's dead.
Dead? Here?
Ja, in our sitting room.
This is our sitting room,
dear.
Ja, well,
you know what I mean.
The drawing room.
Ja. Well, it's a kind of
sitting room.
Well, it's, mmm...
Look.
Which one
is Von Bu%low?
Here, look.
Oh, ja.
Und-- Und Admiral Tirpitz.
Oh, ja, ja.
And von Muller and Reichner.
Oh, ja.
And-- And-- And Hollweg.
Oh.
And von Graunberg.
This isn't
Graunberg.
This is Graunberg.
Oh, yeah?
This is, uh,
Moltke.
Oh, ja.
He's a lot older
than I thought. Oh, ja.
He's a clever
man, ja.
And Zimmermann.
Ja.
And-- And--
And Klimt.
Oh, Klimt, ja.
Oh.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Uh, what shall we do,
Helmut?
We must-- We must
ring the government.
This is the government,
Helmut.
Oh, dear.
It is a great honor
to have so many members
of the government
dead in our sitting room.
Drawing room.
Ja, well...
There are no dead government
members in our sitting room.
Ja, but you know what
I mean.
Well, it's...
Perhaps, eh, I should make
a little speech or something.
Uh, no, not a speech,
Helmut, no.
Shall we make them
a cup of tea?
No, it would be-- It would
be a waste of tea.
We must do something.
So many important people
in our drawing room.
Must do something.
Uh...
We could...
sort them out.
And make a little
list. Ja.
Oh, j a, ja, ja.
Good. We could put the
ministers for internal affairs
over against the wall...
Ja.
...and those for internal,
here by the clock.
And sort them out
alphabetically?
Nein, nein, nein. We just
put the cleanest by the door.
Oh, ja.
Ja.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Very good.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY,
GRUNTING]
No, no, no, that is--
That is von Buelow
He must go
over here.
But that is
my reading chair.
He is the Reichskanzler
of Germany, Helmut.
All right.
But I think he would
have been better up against
the clock, you know.
No, he would not look
nice under the clock.
I did not say under the clock.
I said against the clock.
Well, then we could not
see the clock.
Put the minister
for the colonies under there.
He's small.
The colonies
are internal affairs.
He must go against
the wall.
Education.
Ah!
[GRUNTING]
Soon we'll be able
to make a list.
Oh, ja, ja.
Wait a minute. Who's
that by the cat litter?
I don't know. I've never
seen him before.
He is not a member
of the government.
Get him out of here.
Put him in the drawing room.
He's in the drawing room,
my dear.
Ja, well, you know what I
mean.
Put him in the sitting room.
Ja, ja.
It's all the same.
I must put him
in the sitting room
if he's in
the drawing room.
NARRATOR: Count Ferdinand von
Zeppelin's behavior on that
flight in 1900
had incredible,
far-reaching consequences.
For one of the falling
ministers,
the talented
Herr von Meintlitz,
architect of the new German
expansionist farm policy,
fell on top of an old lady
in Nimwegen,
killing her outright.
Her daughter, Alice,
suffered severe
cerebral damage
from the talented minister's
heavy briefcase...
but was nursed back to life
by an English doctor,
Henderson.
Eventually, they married.
And their eldest son,
George Henderson,
was the father
of Mike Henderson,
producer and director of
The Golden Age of
Ballooning.
[♪]
ANNOUNCER: ...Mr. and
Mrs. Rita Trondheim,
Reginald Bosankway,
who would be next to Norway
in a rhyming dictionary
if it included proper names,
and if he pronounced
his name like that.
[♪]