[COIN CLINKS]
[♪]
Oof!
Yes, this looks
the sort of thing.
May I just try it?
Certainly, madam.
Ooh!
Sorry, so sorry.
Yes, that's fine.
Is that on account, madam?
WOMAN:
Yes.
Hello?
[RINGS]
[SQUAWKS]
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I thought you were
someone else.
Oh, I see, yes.
I'm-- I'm sorry, sir,
can I help you?
Uh, yes-- Yes, as a matter
of fact you can, actually.
I-- I was interested
in the possibility of pur--
Can I ask you
who you thought I was?
What?
Who did you think I was,
just then, when you thought
I was somebody?
Oh, it's no one
you'd know, sir.
Well, I might know them.
Well, it's possible,
but I think it's unlikely.
I know quite a lot--
He's hardly likely to move
in your circle, sir.
Why, is he very rich?
Oh, no, I didn't mean that,
sir.
Is he a lord, or something?
Oh, no. Not at all.
This is very easy to settle.
What is his name?
What?
Well, um--
Yes?
Michael Ellis.
Who?
I see.
Do you know him, sir?
Oh, Michael Ellis. Um...
Michael Ellis--
You don't.
Well, I don't remember
the name.
I think you would
remember him, sir.
Why do you say that?
Well, would you remember a man
6-foot, 9-inches high, 40-ish,
and he's got a scar from
here to here,
and absolutely no nose?
Oh, I think I do remember
somebody like that.
Well,
that's not Michael Ellis.
He's a small man
about this high,
with a high-pitched voice.
Right, I'm not gonna buy
an ant from you now.
Oh, no. Please?
I know you've
not been trained.
I demand another assistant.
Oh, no, come on.
I want another assistant.
All right. I'll get
another assistant.
Thank you.
Hello, sir,
can I help you, sir?
No, I want
a different assistant.
I am, sir.
I'm Mr. Abanazar, sir.
Don't be silly.
Oh, no, please,
please let me help you.
No, I want another assistant.
Come on.
If you don't give me
another assist--
No, no,
I'll be very good, sir.
Good morning, sir.
How are you, sir?
Bit parky outside, isn't it?
Very nice suit
you've got there, sir.
You had a close shave
this morning.
Right, I'm going.
No, no, no, please!
I'll get another assistant.
All right.
Whoooo!
It's not him.
Oh.
I don't want him.
Oh, please,
give him a chance.
No.
Yes, sir. Can I be
of any assistance?
Oh, come on, don't try that.
I'm sorry, sir,
try what?
You know what I mean.
I'm afraid I don't, sir.
You were down there with a
silly mask on, going "whooo!"
I don't think I was, sir.
All right, get the manager.
There seems to be some sort
of a misunderstanding, sir.
Manager!
This is the manager, sir.
What?
Yes, I'm the manager.
Manager.
It's a smashing store.
Can't recommend it too highly.
Well lit, rat-free.
It's a joy to manage.
Manager.
Oh, yes.
Freshest haddock in London,
second floor.
Third floor, Ribena.
Ants here.
Manager!
Television and flame throwers
over there,
our dinner-wagon
exhibition--
Manager!
Quick!
Yes, sir?
Can I help you, sir?
Yes, I want to complain about
the assistants on this counter.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that,
sir. Which ones?
Well, they're hiding now.
Sir?
They're hiding, down there,
behind the counter.
I see, sir.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, there's nobody
down here, sir.
Well, they-- They must've
crawled through here,
crawled along and made their
escape through soft toys.
Yes, of course.
They were wearing masks and
going "whoo!", making noises.
And one of them pretended
to be the manager.
Sir?
He went, "Oh, yes,
I'm the manager.
Smashing store to manage,
this.
Freshest haddock in London."
I think I've got it, sir.
I think I've got it.
It's rag week. Heh.
Rag week?
Yes, you know,
for charity, sir.
Oh, I see.
Some local college
or university?
No, no, it's the store's
rag week, sir.
The store's rag week?
Yes. The senior staff
don't join in much.
It's for the trainees,
really.
Not very good
for business, is it?
Oh, it's for charity.
People are awfully good
about it, you know.
I see, yeah.
Right, sir.
Well, I'll get you
a senior assistant.
Ants, was it?
Yes, please, yes.
Mr. Snetterton?
Could you look after--?
I don't want him!
Oh, please,
give me a chance.
No!
All right.
Mr. Hartford.
Yes, good morning, sir.
Can I help you?
Yes, please.
I'm interested in buying
an ant.
Ah, yes.
And, uh, what price were
you thinking of paying, sir?
Oh, well, I hadn't actually
got as far as that.
Well, sir, they start
about half a P,
but they can go
as high as 3P,
or even 3 and a half P
for a champion.
Uh, inflation, I'm afraid.
Well, I should think one about
1 and a half P, please.
You'll get a serviceable
little animal for that, sir.
Quite frankly, the half-P ones
are a bit on the mangy side.
What, uh--?
What length was sir
thinking of?
Oh, uh...medium?
Medium. Medium,
medium, medium, medium.
Yes, here we are.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now, um, that one there
is an Ayrshire.
And that one there is a
King George bitch, I think.
And that one killing the
little flitbat is an Afghan.
That's a nice one.
Oh, well, let's see how
you get on with him, eh?
Ah, yes, he likes you.
He's taken to you.
What do you feed them on?
Uh, blancmange.
Blancmange?
I'm sorry, I don't know
why I said that.
No, you don't feed them
at all.
Well, what do they live on?
They don't. They die.
They die?
Of course they do,
if you don't feed them.
I don't understand.
Well, you let them die.
Then you buy another one.
It's much cheaper
than feeding them.
You have a constant variety
of little companions.
I see.
That's the advantage
of owning an ant.
Well, I'll take this one.
Oh, dear, I've dropped it.
Never mind.
Here's another one.
Thank you.
Is there anything else
I'll need?
Yes, sir, you'll need
an ant house.
This is the, uh,
model we recommend, sir.
Won't it get out of there?
Yes.
Then what's the point
of having the cage?
Well, none at all really.
Then some little pieces
of cage furniture,
which will keep him
entertained.
There's an ant-wheel.
And there's
a little ant-swing.
Here, sir, here's
a very nice one here,
a little ladder.
He can run up, ring the bell,
that's a trick
he can learn.
Will he live long enough?
Not really, no.
But it's best to have one.
And, um, here's a two-way
radio he can play with.
And then of course
you'll need, uh, the book.
The book?
Uh, yes, yes. The, uh--
The book on ants.
I see.
So, sir, that is,
if I may say so, 184 pounds,
one and a half P, sir.
Well, will you take a check?
Yes, sir, if you don't mind
leaving a blood sample
and a piece of skin
off the back of the scalp
just here, sir.
Sorry, it's just for
identification, you know?
Can't be too careful.
Oh, I think
I'll put it on account.
I should, sir.
Much less painful.
Uh, there we are.
Anyway, sir, you know what
they say about an ant.
A friend for life, eh?
Well, a friend
for its life anyway.
Now, then, uh--
Ah. Here we are.
His name's Marcus.
Right.
If the little chap should go
to an early grave, sir,
give us a ring and we'll stick
a few in an envelope,
all right?
Thanks very much, indeed.
Not at all.
Thank you, Mr. Ellis.
Shhh!
What did you say?
I said, thank you, Mr. Ellis.
It's not him.
Why did you say I was
Mr. Ellis?
Who?
No, no,
he didn't say that.
Yes, I heard him say,
"Thank you, Mr. Ellis."
No, no, he said,
"I'm jealous."
What?
"I'm jealous of your ant."
Goodbye. Goodbye.
CLERK 2:
Bye-bye. Bye.
I don't care
who Michael Ellis is.
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Excuse me, I was in the
ant counter a minute ago--
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[BELL DINGING]
MAN [OVER PA]:
Will Mr. Michael Ellis please
go straight
to the manager's office.
I'll repeat that.
Will Mr. Nigel Mellish please
go straight
to the manager's office.
What you got now?
I bought an ant, Mother.
Oh, devil.
What do you want one
of them for?
I'm not gonna
clean it out.
You said you'd clean
the tiger out,
but do you?
No, I suppose you've
lost interest in it now.
Now it'll be "ant, ant, ant"
for a couple of days,
then all of a sudden:
"Oh, Mum,
I've bought a sloth
or some other odd-toed
ungulate like a tapir."
No, it's really different
this time, Mum.
I'm really gonna look
after this ant.
That's what you said
about the sperm whale.
Now your papa's having
to use it as a garage.
Well, he didn't
feed it properly.
Where are we gonna get
44 tons of plankton
from every morning?
Your papa was dead vexed
about that.
They thought he was mad
in the deli.
Well, at least he's got
a free garage.
Right, no good to him.
His Hillman
smells all fishy.
[TIGER GROWLING]
Oh, blimey,
there's the tiger.
He'll be wanting
his mandies.
Are you giving
that tiger drugs?
Course I'm giving it drugs.
It's illegal.
You try telling that
to the tiger.
Well, I think
it's dangerous.
Listen, before
he started fixing,
he used to get through four
Jehovah's Witnesses a day.
And he used to eat
all of them,
except for the pamphlets.
Well, he's not dim.
[GROWLING]
MUM:
All right.
Well, I think I'll go watch
one of the televisions.
Come on, Marcus.
Oh, by the way,
Michael's been on the phone
all day for you.
Michael?
Yeah, you know, Michael.
Michael. Michael Ellis.
Yeah, he's been
on the phone all day.
He, uh, came round twice.
What's he look like?
Oh, I didn't see him.
The orange-rumped agouti
answered the door.
Only useful animal
you ever bought, that.
Where is he now?
He's upstairs
forging prescriptions
for the sodding tiger.
No, no, no,
where's Michael Ellis now?
Oh, I don't know.
He said
it wasn't important, anyway.
All right,
here I come.
[♪]
Hello, and welcome
to the University of the Air.
And first this afternoon,
Part 17 of our series
on animal communications.
This afternoon
we look at recent discoveries
in the field of intraspecific
signaling codes
in the family formicidae.
That's a stroke of luck,
Marcus.
Turn that bloody thing off!
...bring you the latest news
of the extraordinary
Michael Ellis saga.
Apparently Michael Ellis--
Hey, I was watching that.
Bloody thing.
It's upsetting the tiger.
[TIGER GROWLS]
Oh, Christ.
[CLATTERING]
End of the announcement.
And now,
back to University of the Air
and our series for
advanced medical students,
Elements of Surgical
Homeopathic Practice.
Part 68, "Ants."
Oh, we're in luck again,
Marcus.
Hello, formicidophiles.
Well, before all the
blood and guts
you're waiting to see,
let's have a look at the
anatomy of the little ant.
The body of the ant is divided
into three sections:
The head, the thorax
and the abdomen.
They're enclosed in a hard,
armor-like covering
called the exoskeleton,
which provides some protection
from other nasty little
insects.
But unfortunately,
not from the dissector's
scalpel.
See, nothing to it.
He's not such a toughie.
And his legs,
they help him carry
hundreds of times
his own weight,
but look at this:
You're not so strong
compared to me.
Four, five, six. Ha!
I didn't know ants
had six legs, Marcus.
I assure you they do,
Mr. Ellis.
Hey, you've got two legs
missing.
And that's a false feeler,
Marcus.
Blimey.
I'm taking this ant back,
Mother,
he's got two legs missing.
Mrs. McWong's been
on the phone.
The polar bear's been
in her garden again.
I'll get it on the way back
from the store.
Well, mind you do.
His droppings are enormous.
Oh, and by the way,
while you're out,
get us another couple
of tellies, would you.
Here's 180 quid.
Second floor.
Stationery, leather goods,
nasal injuries,
cricket bats, film stars,
dolphinariums.
Third floor.
Cosmetics, books,
Irish massage,
tribal headgear, ants.
But not complaints
about ants.
Oh, where do I go to complain?
Straight on, then left,
then right past the thing,
then up the little stairs,
then right past the bit
where it's gone all soft,
then down the wobbly bit,
left past the nail,
past the brown stain
on the wall to your right,
and it's the door
marked "exit,"
straight ahead of you
on the left.
Thank you.
Fourth floor,
kiddies' vasectomies.
I don't want you.
Oh, something wrong
with your little ant friend?
No, I'm not gonna tell you.
Oh, has he got
something missing
in the leg department?
No.
Yes, sir.
No, no, no.
Oh, it's all right, sir.
It's for the sack race
later on, sir.
No, no. I want to speak
to the general manager.
I want to complain.
You want the Toupee Hall
in that case, sir.
The what?
The Toupee Hall, Mr. Ellis.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me the way
to the Toupee Hall, please?
Sorry?
Ah, the Toupee Hall.
The what?
The Toupee Hall.
Oh, the Toupee Hall.
Gladys, where are toupees now?
Yes?
Toupees?
This gentleman wants one.
A toupee?
Mmm.
Well, no, actually.
I think they're in
surgical appliances now.
Oh, that's right, yes,
you go left at artificial
limbs and hearing aids,
right at dentures,
and it's on your left,
just by glass eyes.
It doesn't say "toupees"
to avoid embarrassing people,
but you can smell them.
Thank you.
You can see the join.
Yes, you can.
WOMAN:
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
It's so nice to see such a
large turnout this afternoon.
And I'd like to start off by
welcoming our guest speakers
for this afternoon,
Mr. Wadsworth--
Wordsworth.
Sorry, Wordsworth.
Mr. John Koots,
and Percy Bysshe.
Shelley!
Oh, just a little one,
medium dry.
And Alfred Lord.
Tennyson.
Tennis ball.
Son.
Sorry. Alfred Lord,
who is evidently
Lord Tennisball's son.
And to start off,
I'm going to ask Mr. Wadsworth
to recite his latest offering,
a little pram entitled:
"I Wandered Lonely as a Crab."
And it's all about ants.
I wandered lonely as a cloud
Oh.
That floats on high
O'er vales and hills
When all at once I saw a crowd
A host of golden worker ants
[APPLAUSE]
Thank you, thank you,
Mr. Bradlaugh.
Now, Mr. Bysshe--
Shelley.
Oh, just a little.
--is going to read
one of his latest psalms
entitled "Ode to a Crab."
Well, it's not about crabs,
actually.
It's called "Ozymandias."
It's not an ode.
I met a traveler
In an antique land
Who said, six vast
And trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert.
And on the pedestal
These words appear:
My name is Ozymandias
King of ants
ALL:
Ooooh!
Look on my feelers, termites
And despair!
I am the biggest ant
You'll ever see.
ALL:
Ooh!
The ants of old weren't
Half as bold and big
And fierce as me
[WILD APPLAUSE]
Thank you. Thank you,
Mr. Amontillado.
I'd like to ask one or two
of you at the back
not to soil the carpet.
There is a restroom upstairs,
if you find the poems
too exciting.
Good afternoon.
Next, Mr. Dennis Keat will
recite his latest problem:
"Ode to a Glass of Sherry."
My heart aches
And a drowsy numbness
Pains my senses
As though an anteater I'd seen
ALL: Oh!
A nasty long-nosed brute
[ALL YELLING]
With furry legs
And sticky, darting tongue
I seem to feel its cruel jaws
Crunch, crunch
There go my legs
Snap, snap, my thorax too
My head's in twain
There goes my brain
Swallow, swallow
It's true,
don't you see, it's true!
It happens.
It's happened!
Please.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I do apologize for that last--
Well, I hesitate
to call it a pram,
but I had no idea.
And talking of filth,
I have asked
you once about the carpet.
Now, I do appreciate that last
poem was very frightening.
But, please.
Now, before we move on to tea
and pramwiches,
I would like-- I would like
to ask Arthur Lord Tenniscourt
to give us his latest
little plum, entitled
"The Charge of the
Ant Brigade."
Half an inch
MAN:
The queen, the queen!
[FANFARE PLAYING]
My loyal subjects.
We are here today on a
matter of national import.
My late husband and we
are increasingly disturbed
by recent developments
in literary style
that have taken place here
in Germany-- England.
There seems to be an
increasing tendency
for the ant--
Uh, the ant--
The-- The ant to become
the dominant--
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Theme.
Theme among poetry
here in Germany.
We are not, uh--
Entertained.
From now on,
ants is verboten.
Instead it's skylarks,
daffodils,
nightingales,
light brigades and--
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Well, we must away now,
or we shall be late
for the races.
God bless you alles.
[FANFARE PLAYING]
MAN:
Psst!
Electric kettles
over here, sir.
Don't worry, sir,
you're amongst friends
now, sir.
Mr. Bradford, Mr. Crawley.
These are our fitters, sir.
We've had a lot of experience
in this field,
and we do pride ourselves.
We offer the best
and most discreet service
available.
I don't know whether
you'll believe this, sir,
but one of us is actually
wearing a toupee
at this moment.
Well, you all are,
aren't you?
Have you got one?
Yeah, but I thought you--
I didn't know you.
I thought it was me.
I thought it was me!
So did I.
That is good.
Oh!
It is, yeah.
Actually, I only came in here
to ask where the manager's
office was.
Just a minute,
someone told you
we all had toupees?
No.
Oh, yeah.
How did you know?
Well, it's pretty obvious,
isn't it?
What do you mean,
obvious?
His is undetectable.
Well, it's a different color,
for a start.
Is it?
Of course it isn't.
It doesn't fit in
with the rest of his hair.
It sticks up in the middle.
Well, it's better than yours.
Yes.
I'm not wearing one.
[ALL LAUGH]
Not wearing one.
Why'd you come here in, then?
They told me to find
the manager's office here.
Oh, no, not again.
Bit lame, isn't it?
It's the truth.
Manager's office.
I mean, look at it.
Where did you get that, eh?
Mac Fisheries?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Dreadful, isn't it?
Nylon?
It's not, it's real, look.
Oh, anyone can do that.
Come on, get it off.
Look, do you want
a proper one?
No, I don't need one.
There's no need
to be ashamed.
We've all owned up.
I'm not wearing one.
Don't you see,
this is something
you've got to come
to terms with.
I am not wearing a toupee.
They just told me
to come in here
to find the manager's office,
to complain about my ant.
Complain about an ant?
Look, this is
for your own good.
Ow!
MAN:
All right. Take a seat.
You see, it ought to have
a safety catch.
I mean-- Ooh!
I mean, what if this fell
into the wrong hands?
Yes, madam. I'll speak
to the makers personally.
Oh, would you?
It would put my mind
at ease.
Thank you.
[FLAMETHROWER FIRING]
WOMAN:
Sorry, oh, sorry.
Next?
He's still molesting her.
Yes, yes, I'll see you
in a moment, sir.
I've got a complaint to make.
Ah, take a seat.
I'm sorry it's on fire.
Oh, not at all.
I got used to this out east.
Oh, where were you out east?
Oh, Norway, Sweden.
Places like that.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry,
my suit seems
to keep catching fire.
Extinguisher?
Oh, no, thank you.
I think we'd better
let it run its course.
I was just thinking, uh,
Norway is not very east,
is it?
No, I should have said,
"When I was out north."
Yes, sir. Are there
many fires in Norway?
Oh, good Lord, yes.
The place is a constant blaze.
Wooden buildings,
do you know.
Yes.
Mmm.
No, I lost my wife
in Norway.
Oh, I am sorry to hear that.
Why, did you know her?
No. No, I don't.
Oh, she wasn't
a favorite of mine.
No, we were out strolling
across a fjord one day
when one of the local matadors
came out of his tree house
and flung a load of old
scimitars and guillotines out
that he'd got cluttering up
his wine cellar.
And apparently, a rather large
proportion of them
landed on my wife,
causing her to, uh, snuff it
without much more ado.
Yes, yes, well, look.
[PA CHIMES]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Here is an important
announcement
about Michael Ellis.
It is now the end
of Michael Ellis week.
From now on,
it is Chris Quinn week.
What a rotten ending.
Well, it is one
of our cheapest, sir.
Well, what else have you got?
Well, there's the long,
slow pullout, sir.
You know, the camera tracks
back and back and you mix.
[CHIMES RINGING]
No, no, no. Have you got
anything more exciting?
Well, how about a chase?
There he is!
[♪]
Oh, no, no, no.
Walking into the sunset?
What's that one?
You know, two lone figures
silhouetted against
the dying rays
of the setting sun.
[♪]
The, uh-- The music swells,
you've got a lump
in your throat
and a tear in your eye.
Oh, no.
Pity, I rather like that one.
They're all a bit
off the point, you see?
Well,
there is one that ties up
the whole Michael Ellis thing,
but, um...
But what?
Oh, no, nothing, nothing.
Who is Michael Ellis?
How about a happy ending, sir?
Chris!
Thank God you're safe.
No, you wouldn't want that,
would you?
Why wouldn't I want that?
Uh, what about summing up
from the panel? That's cheap.
What?
You know,
the, uh, big match experts.
I think that it was quite
a good show, isn't it?
I think that the, uh--
The Michael Ellis character
was a-- A little overdone.
Well, I don't agree
with that, Malcolm.
Uh, quite frankly,
the only bit I liked
was this bit
with me in it, now.
No?
Slow fade?
No.
Well, uh, how about
a sudden ending?