[♪]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
NARRATOR:
Taking life as it comes.
Sharing the good things
and the bad things.
Finding laughter and fun
wherever they go.
It's with these two
happy-go-lucky rogues
that our story begins.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[CRASH]
For it is they who were run
over by Alex Diamond.
International crime-fighter
and playboy.
Fast-moving, tough-talking
and just one of the hundreds
of famous people
who suffer from lumbago,
the endemic disease
about which no one
knows more
than this man,
Dr. Emile Konig.
Doctor, surgeon,
proctologist,
and selfless fighter
against human suffering
whose doorbell
was the one above
the hero of our story tonight.
Rear Admiral Humphrey De Vere.
Yes, this is the story
of Rear Admiral
Humphrey De Vere,
or rather,
the story of his daughter.
For it was her courage,
foresight and understanding
that enabled us
to probe beneath
the sophisticated veneer
of the Royal Arsenal
Women's College, Bagshot,
and learn the true history
of this man.
Len Hanky. Chiropodist,
voyeur, hen-teaser.
The man of whom the chairman
of Fiat once said:
[IN ITALIAN]
[PHONE RINGS]
Si.
NARRATOR:
Yes, tonight we examine
the career of Gino Agnelli.
The man who started
from nothing
to build up one of
the greatest firms in Europe.
And whose telescope
was bought from the shop
part-owned by a man
who, at the age of 8,
stole a penknife
from the son
of this man's brother's
housekeeper's
dental hygenist's uncle,
the Reverend Charlie
"Drooper" Hyper-Squawk Smith.
The cleft-palated
RAF chaplain
who, single-handed, shot down
over 500 German chaplains.
This is the story of the men
who flew with him.
It really is.
Morning, squadron leader.
What ho, Squiffy.
How was it?
Top-hole. Bally Jerry
pranged his kite
right in the
how's-your-father.
Hairy blighter, dicky-birdied,
feathered back on his Sammy,
took a waspy, flipped over
on his Betty Harpers,
and caught his can
in the Bertie.
Afraid I don't quite
follow you,
squadron leader.
It's perfectly
ordinary banter, Squiffy.
Bally Jerry pranged his kite
right in the
how's-your-father.
Hairy blighter, dicky-birdied,
feathered back on his Sammy,
took a waspy, flipped over
on his Betty Harpers,
and caught his can
in the Bertie.
I'm just not understanding
banter at all well today.
Give us it slower.
Banter's not the same
if you say it slower, Squiffy.
Hold on, then. Wingco!
Yes?
Bend an ear to the squadron
leader's banter for a sec?
Can do.
Jolly good.
Fire away.
Bally Jerry pranged his kite
right in the
how's-your-father.
Hairy blighter, dicky-birdied,
feathered back on his Sammy,
took a waspy, flipped over
on his Betty Harpers,
and caught his can
in the Bertie.
No, I don't understand
that banter at all.
Something up
with my banter, chaps?
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Hah. Bunch of monkeys
on the ceiling, sir!
Grab your egg and fours and
let's get the bacon delivered.
Do you understand that?
No, didn't get
a word of it.
Sorry, old man, we don't
understand your banter.
You know, bally ten-penny
ones dropping in the custard.
Um, Charlie Choppers
chucking a handful.
No, no, sorry.
Say it a bit slower,
old chap.
Slower banter, sir?
Rather.
Um, sausage squad
up the blue end.
No, still don't get it.
Um, cabbage crates
coming over the briny?
ALL:
No, no, no.
NARRATOR:
But by then it was too late.
The first cabbage crates
hit London on July the 7th.
That was just the beginning.
Five shillings a dozen?
That's ordinary cabbages,
is it?
And what about the bombs?
Good Lord,
they are expensive.
Sir!
Yes, what is it?
News from
the Western Front, sir.
Yes?
Big enemy attack
at dawn, sir.
Yes?
Well...
the enemy were all wearing
little silver halos, sir,
and they had fairy wands
with big stars on
the end and--
They what?
And they had spiders
in matchboxes, sir.
Good God.
How did our chaps react?
Well, they were
jolly interested, sir.
Some of them--
I think it was the
4th Armored Brigade. They--
They...
Yes?
Well, they went and had a look
at the spiders, sir.
Oh, my God!
Well, thank you, Shirley.
Sir!
Get me
the prime minister.
Sir!
Not that quickly.
Sir.
Gentlemen, it's now quite
apparent that the enemy
are not only fighting
this war on the cheap,
but they're also
not taking it seriously.
Bastards.
First they drop cabbages
instead of decent bombs--
The crates
were probably expensive.
Quiet, critic!
And now they're doing
very silly things in one
of the most vital areas
of the war.
What are we going to do,
Shirley?
Well, we've got to act fast
before it saps morale.
We're gonna show
these Chinese--
Germans.
These Germans.
We're gonna show them
that no British soldier
will descend to their level.
Anyone found
trivializing this war
will face
the supreme penalty
that military law
can provide.
That was all right,
I think?
Seemed to go quite well.
Sapper Walters,
you stand before this court
accused of carrying on the war
by other than warlike means.
To wit, that you did,
on April the 16th, 1942,
dressed up as a bag
of dainties,
flick wet towels at the enemy
during the
important offensive.
Well, sir--
Shut up.
Colonel Fawcett
for the prosecution.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Sir, we all know--
Shut up.
I'm sorry?
Carry on.
Sir, we all know
the facts of the case.
That Sapper Walters,
being in possession
of expensive
military equipment,
to wit, one Lee-Enfield
.303 rifle
and 72 rounds
of ammunition
valued at 140 pounds
three shillings and sixpence,
chose instead
to use wet towels
to take an enemy command post
in the area of Basingstoke.
Basingstoke?
Basingstoke in Hampshire?
Uh, no, no, no, sir, no.
Oh, I see, carry on.
The result of his action
was that the enemy--
Basingstoke where?
Basingstoke
in Westphalia, sir.
Oh, I see. Carry on.
The result of Walters'
action was that the enemy
received wet patches
upon their trousers
and in some cases,
small, red strawberry marks
upon their thighs.
I didn't know there was
a Basingstoke in Westphalia.
It's on the map, sir.
What map?
The map of Westphalia
as used by the army, sir.
Well, I've certainly
never heard
of Basingstoke in Westphalia.
It's a municipal borough,
27 miles
north-northeast of
Southampton.
Its chief manufactures--
Southampton in Westphalia?
Yes, sir. Bricks, clothing.
Nearby are remains
of Basing House,
burned down
by Cromwell's cavalry--
Who--? Who compiled this map?
Cole Porter, sir.
Cole Porter,
who wrote "Kiss Me, Kate"?
No, alas not, sir.
This was the Cole Porter
who wrote
"Anything Goes," sir.
I shall seek to prove
the man--
It's the same one.
♪ In olden days
A glimpse of stocking ♪
I beg your pardon?
♪ In olden days
A glimpse of stocking ♪
♪ Was looked on
As something shocking ♪
♪ Now heaven knows
Anything goes ♪
No, this one's,
uh, different, sir.
How did it go?
What, sir?
How does
your "Anything Goes" go?
Can I go home now?
Shut up! Come on!
Sir, really,
I think this is--
Come on, how does
your "Anything Goes" go?
♪ Anything goes in ♪
♪ Anything goes out ♪
♪ Fish, bananas, old pajamas
Mutton, beef and trout ♪
♪ Anything goes in-- ♪
No, that's not it. Carry on.
With respect,
I shall prove that the man
before you in the dock
being in the possession
of the following:
One pair of army boots,
value, 3 pounds 7 and 6,
one pair of serge trousers,
value, 2 pounds 3 and 6,
one pair of gaiters, value,
68 pounds 10 shillings, one--
Sixty-eight pounds
10 shillings
for a pair of gaiters?
They were special gaiters,
sir.
Special gaiters?
Yes, sir, they were made
in France, sir.
One beret costing
14 shillings--
What was special about them?
They were made
of a special fabric, sir.
The buckles were made of
empire silver instead
of brass.
The total value
of the uniform was--
Why was the accused
wearing special gaiters?
They were a presentation pair,
sir, from the regiment.
The total value
of the uniform--
Why did they present him
with a special pair
of gaiters?
Sir, it seems to me totally
irrelevant to the case
whether the gaiters were
presented to him or not.
The court will be able
to judge that for themselves.
I want to know why
the regiment
presented the accused
with a special pair
of gaiters.
He used to do things
for them, sir.
The total value
of the uniform--
What things?
He used to oblige them, sir.
The total value--
Oblige them?
Yes, sir. The total value
of the uniform--
How did he oblige them?
What, sir?
He, um, he used to make them
happy in little ways, sir.
The total value
of the uniform could--
Did he touch them at all?
Sir! I submit that this
is totally irrelevant.
I want to know
how he made them happy.
He used to ram things
up their--!
All right! All right!
No need to spell it out.
What has the accused
got to say?
What, me?
Yes. What have you got to say?
What can I say, sir?
I mean, how can I encapsulate
in mere words
my scorn
for any military solution?
The futility of
modern warfare,
and the hypocrisy by which
contemporary government
applies one standard
to violence within
the community and another
to violence perpetrated
by one community upon another?
I'm sorry, but my client
has become pretentious.
I will say
in his defense--
We haven't finished
the prosecution!
Shut up! I'm in charge
of this court. Stand up.
Sit down! Go "moo."
ALL:
Moo.
See? Right, now,
on with the pixie hats.
And order in
the skating vicar.
And...
♪ Anything goes in
Anything goes out ♪
♪ Fish, bananas, old pajamas
Mutton, beef and trout ♪
♪ Anything goes in
Anything goes out ♪
♪ Fish, bananas, old pajamas
Mutton, fish and trout ♪
ANNOUNCER:
Yes! Coming to
this cinema soon.
The tender,
compassionate story
of one man's love
for another man in drag.
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Thrill to the excitement of
a night emission over Germany.
When the pilot, Jennifer,
has to choose
between his secret love
for Louis,
the hot-bloodedly bisexual
navigator,
and Andy,
the rear gunner,
who, though quite
assertive with girls,
tends to take
the submissive role
in his relationships
with men.
And sensational Mexican
starlet Rosetta Nixon
plays the head
of bomber command
whose passion for sea birds
ends in tragedy.
With Ginger
as the half-man,
half-woman parrot
whose unnatural instincts
brought forbidden love
to the aviary.
And Roger as Pip,
the half-parrot,
half-man, half-woman,
three-quarter badger,
ex-bigamist,
Negro preacher for whom
banjo playing was difficult.
And he never mastered it,
though he took courses
and went to banjo college,
ah, and everything.
Don't miss it!
Coming to your cinema soon.
Only five minutes
from this restaurant.
But now...
It's...
[♪]
Bloody repeats.
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
Ahh!
Yes. Repeats
or war films.
It really makes you
want to micturate.
People on television
treat the general public
like idiots.
Well, we are idiots.
Oh, no, we are not!
Well, I am.
How do you know
you're an idiot?
Oh, I can show you.
How?
Look.
[WHOOPING]
You see,
the public are idiots.
You might as well just
show them
the last five miles of the M2.
They'd watch it, eh?
At last they done been put
on something interesting.
Oh, most interesting.
Our figures show conclusively
that these motorways
are extremely popular.
I mean, last time
we showed a repeat
of the Leicester Bypass,
our ratings gave us
97, 300, 912
and ITV naught.
So I do feel
that we ought to give
B roads their own series.
I'm sorry, we just can't
give you a bigger budget.
Budgie?
No, he's left I think.
Why not?
Well, we're only one slice
of the cake, you know.
Wouldn't mind a slice of cake.
Nice chocolate cake,
delicious.
I had a budgie once, you know.
Lovely little budgie.
Amusing little chap. Used
to stick his head in a bell.
What was his name, now?
Uh, Joey? Uh, Xerxes?
We could repeat them.
Reheat them?
No, repeat them.
You don't reheat cakes.
Not chocolate cakes.
What, repeat the cakes?
Mr. Heath.
What?
That was the name
of the budgie.
Good Lord,
the bar's open.
Oh, great.
Oh, no. No, it isn't.
I was looking at the
little hand
that goes round awfully fast.
Blast.
I've got it.
We can retitle the repeats.
What, give them
different names?
Wouldn't that mean
retitling them?
Brilliant!
Right. All we need
is new titles.
And they must be damn new.
How about Dad's Navy?
Good, good, good.
Up Your Mother
Next Door.
Even better.
Doctor at Bee.
What?
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Someone's knocking at
the door.
Quite like it.
Bit long, though, I think.
Far too long.
I Married Lucy.
Hasn't that been done?
Oh, yes, a long time ago,
though.
They'd never remember it.
Doctor at Three.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
I think someone's knocking
at the door.
That's even longer.
I Married a Tree.
And Mother Makes Tree.
Doctor at Cake.
Look, I'm not
absolutely certain,
but well, I do rather get
the impression
there is someone knocking on
the door at this very moment.
That's ridiculous.
Half the program gone.
Stop playing games!
I Married a Cake.
I Married
Three Rabbit Jelly Molds.
Prefer cake.
Especially chocolate cake.
MAN:
Open the sodding door!
No, no. You can't say
"sodding"
on television. No, no.
You're supposed to knock!
Sorry, sir, but there's
trouble at Studio 5.
You're in, uh, Security,
are you?
Yes, sir.
Well, you're not allowed
to suggest program titles.
It's the World War series
in Studio 5.
They're not taking it
seriously anymore.
You're not allowed
to suggest program titles.
Look!
Ahh!
Mind me war wound!
That's it!
That's the one.
Very good title.
Very good.
♪ Fish, bananas, old pajamas ♪
God! Bloody
World War II series.
I hate them.
Ooh, always the same,
so damn predictable.
Depressing,
miserable.
Day after day
after day after day.
Oh. Oh, evening star,
if only we could
have a decent day tomorrow.
Oh, this weather's so wretched
and awful and filthy and--
[SNORING]
[RATTLING]
What? What? What's going on?
What the hell is going--?
Now I can't even sleep.
[BUZZING]
What--?
What are they doing?
[BUZZING, CLANGING]
[GASPS]
What was that? What was it?
What is going on?
Oh, I can't stand it.
[NOISE FADES]
Oh...
[SNORING]
[CLOCK RINGING]
Oh! All right, that does it.
That does it!
[GRUMBLING]
What a lovely day.
Oh, I think
I'm gonna just...
[YAWNS, SNORES]
[AIRPLANE HUMMING]
[♪]
I say.
Yes, Daddy?
Croquet hoops look damn
pretty this afternoon.
Frightfully damn pretty.
They're coming along
awfully well this year.
Yes, better than your
Aunt Lavinia's croquet hoops.
Oh, dreadful tin things.
I did tell her
to stick to wood.
Yes, you can't beat wood.
"Gorn."
What's "gorn," dear?
Nothing, nothing,
I just like the word.
It gives me confidence.
Gorn. Gorn. It's got a sort
of woody quality about it.
Gorn. Gorn.
Much better than "newspaper"
or "litter bin."
Oh, frightful words.
Perfectly dreadful.
Uh, "newspaper," "litter bin."
Dreadful tinny sort of words.
[SCREAMS]
Tin, tin, tin.
Oh, dear, don't say
"tin" to Rebecca,
you know how
it upsets her.
Sorry, old horse.
Sausage.
There's a good woody sort
of word, "sausage."
[CHUCKLES]
Gorn.
Antelope!
Where?
On the lawn?
No, no, Daddy,
just the word.
Don't want antelope
nibbling the hoops.
No, no, "antelope." Sort of
nice and woody type of thing.
Don't think so,
Becky, old chap.
No, no. "Antelope,"
"antelope,"
tinny sort of word.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, sorry,
old man.
Really,
Mansfield.
Well, she's got to come
to terms with these things.
Seemly, prodding,
vacuum, leap.
Ooh, hate "leap."
Perfectly dreadful.
Sort of PVC sort of word,
don't you know.
Lower-middle.
Bound.
Now you're talking.
Bound, vole, recidivist.
Bit tinny.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, sorry, Becky,
old beast.
Oh, dear. I suppose she'll
be gorn for a few days now.
Caribou.
Splendid word!
No, dear,
nibbling the hoops.
Caribou gorn.
Intercourse.
Later, dear.
No, no, no.
The word "intercourse."
Good and woody.
Intercourse.
Pert, pert thighs.
Botty, botty, botty.
Oh, erogenous zone.
Oh, concubine.
Erogenous zone.
Loose woman.
Erogenous zone--
Oh.
Oh, thank you, dear.
Uh, you know,
it's a funny thing, dear,
all the naughty words
sound woody.
Really, dear?
How about "tit"?
Oh, dear, I hadn't thought
about that.
Tit, tit. Oh, that's very
tinny, isn't it? Tit, tit.
Uh, tinny,
tinny, tinny.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, dear.
Ocelot.
Wasp.
Yowling.
Oh, dear,
I'm bored.
I'd better go
and have a bath, I suppose.
Oh, really, must you, dear?
You've had nine today.
All right, I'll sack
one of the servants.
Simpkins! Nasty, tinny sort
of name. Simpkins!
I say, mater, cabbage crates
coming over the briny.
Sorry, dear,
don't understand.
Uh, cow-catchers creeping up
on the conning towers.
No, sorry, old sport.
Um, caribou nibbling
at the croquet hoops.
Yes, Mansfield shot one
in the antlers.
Oh, jolly good show.
Is Becca about?
No, she's
"gorn orff."
Oh, what a super woody sort
of phrase, "gorn orff."
Yes, she's gorn orff because
Mansfield said "tin" to her.
Oh, what rotten luck.
Yeah, well,
whole afternoon to kill.
Better have a bath,
I suppose.
Oh, Gervaise,
do sing me a song.
Oh, okay.
Something woody.
♪ For she's going
to marry Yum Yum ♪
Oh, crikey.
Old song's finished her off.
What's "urp"?
Oh, I'm afraid
Mrs. Vermin Jones
appears to have passed on.
Dead, is she?
Afraid so.
What a blow for her.
What I want to know,
Mrs. Elizabeth III,
is why they show us
crap like this
when there's bits
of the Leicester Bypass
what have never
been shown. Biscuit?
Oh, thank you.
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
MAN: Appearing on the M2
were 4,281 Vauxhall Vivas
2,117 Vauxhall Vivas
deluxe--
Bloody repeats.
Repeats or war films.
Makes you want to--
MAN:
Hello and welcome
to Show Jumping from--
Oh, motocross.
--just about to go into
a jump-off against the clock.
The slight pause
is for the stewards
who are repairing
The Sound of Music.
Captain Phillips on Streuth
caught one of the nuns
at the start of
what would've been
a fine, clear round.
It's a formidable obstacle,
this Sound of Music.
Eight nuns high,
they're ready now and singing.
[BELL SOUNDS]
And there's the bell.
She's got 1.07 seconds
to beat,
but she needs
a clear round to win
as she comes towards
The Sound of Music--
Quite exciting.
Beautifully taken.
And now she needs
to pick up speed
for Oklahoma!,
but not too much.
This is where Alan Jones
knocked down poor Jud.
You notice how you never
actually see the horses jump?
Superb.
Superb show jumping.
She's coming up to the
black-and-white minstrel show.
Watch this.
♪ .--music and dance ♪
And she's taken it.
She's over the minstrels.
She just flicked
Leslie Crowther with her tail.
The time's good,
and now she turns
before coming
into the final jump.
This is a tough one.
It's Ben-Hur.
Forty-six chariots,
6000 spectators,
400 slaves, lions--
I bet we don't see
this one.
We interrupt show jumping
to bring you a news flash.
The Second World War has now
entered a sentimental stage.
This morning
on the Ardennes front
the Germans started
spooning at dawn.
But the British Fifth Army
responded
by gazing deep
into their eyes,
and the Germans are now
reported to have gone all coy.
♪ When does a dream begin? ♪
♪ Does it start with a
Goodnight kiss? ♪
♪ Is it conceived
Or simply achieved? ♪
♪ When does a dream begin? ♪
♪ Is it born
In a moment of bliss? ♪
♪ Or is it begun
When two hearts are one? ♪
♪ When does a dream exist? ♪
♪ The vision of you
Appears somehow ♪
♪ Impossible to resist ♪
♪ But I'm not
Imagining seeing you ♪
♪ For who could have
Dreamed of this? ♪
♪ When does a dream begin? ♪
♪ When reality is dismissed? ♪
♪ Or does it commence
When we lose all pretense? ♪
♪ When does a dream begin? ♪