[♪♪]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
It's just that everywhere
I go, it's the same old thing.
All anyone wants me to say is,
"To be, or not to be."
That is the question:
Whether 'tis nobler
in the mind
to suffer
The slings--
Yes.
It's either that or
O, that this too too solid
flesh should melt--
Would melt
Thaw and resolve itself
into a dew!
Or that the Everlasting
had not fix'd
His canon 'gainst
self-slaughter!
Yes, all that sort of thing.
I'm just getting really fed--
Do the bit about
"Alas, poor Yorick!"
No. I'm sick of it.
I want to do something else.
I want to make something
of my life.
No, I don't know that bit.
I want to get away
from all that. Be different.
Well, um,
what do you want to be?
A private dick.
A private dick?
Yes, a private dick.
Why do you wanna be
a private dick?
Why does anyone
want to be a private dick?
Fame, money,
glamour, excitement, sex.
Oh, it's the sex, is it?
Well, that's one
of the things, yes.
What's the sex problem?
There's no problem.
Come on. You've got this girl
on the bed. She's ready for it.
No, it's nothing to do
with that.
Oh, no, come on. There she is,
she's all ready for it.
She's a real stunner,
got great big tits,
she's really well-stacked.
You've got her legs
up against the mantelpiece.
All right, Mr. Butler,
I'll take over.
[GRUNTS]
Morning, Mr. Hamlet.
My name's Natal.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Now, what seems to be
the problem?
I was telling
the other psychiatrist--
Uh, he's--
He is not a psychiatrist.
He said he was a psychiatrist.
Well, yes, um,
he is a kind of psychiatrist,
but he's, um--
He's not a proper
psychiatrist.
Uh, he-- He's not, uh,
fully qualified
in, um, quite the sort of way
that, uh, we should want.
Anyway, the problem,
I believe, is basically
sexual, is it?
I asked him that!
Get out!
Now then, you've, uh--
You've got the girl
on the bed.
Been having a feel up,
tongue down her throat.
She got her legs
up on the mantelpiece--
Out, please! Out, please!
I'm talking to a patient--
[GROANS]
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
We have a lot of trouble here
with bogus psychiatrists.
One of the risks
in psychiatry.
Unfortunately, they do tend
to frighten the patient
and can cause real and
permanent damage
to the treatment.
But I assure you
that I am a completely
bona fide psychiatrist.
Here's my diploma in
Psychiatry from the
University of Oxford.
Uh, this here shows
that I'm a member
of the British Psychiatric
Association,
a very important body indeed.
Here's a letter
from another psychiatrist
in which he mentions
I'm a psychiatrist.
This is my Psychiatric
Club tie,
and, as you can see,
the cufflinks match.
I've got a copy
of Psychiatry Today
in my bag,
which I think
is pretty convincing.
And a letter from my mother
in which she asks
how the psychiatry's going.
I think you'll realize
the one person you can't fool
is your mother.
So if you'd like to ask me
any questions about
psychiatry,
I bet I can answer them.
No, it's all right.
Okay.
You've got the girl on the
bed, you've had a few drinks,
her feet on the mantelpiece--
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
Yes, what is it?
WOMAN:
There's a proper
psychiatrist here.
Oh, my God. Okay, thank you.
Right, thank you very much
for answering the questions.
We'll try not
to trouble you again, sir.
Right. You've got the girl
down on the bed,
you got her legs
up on the mantelpiece...
[BABBLING]
Well, well done, Mr. Hamlet.
You've done extremely well
in our disorientation tests.
Oh. Oh.
I'm sorry it might have
confused you a little,
but we do this
to try and establish
a very good
doctor-patient relationship,
you see? We do it
to sort of, as it were,
to break down the barriers.
All right?
Yes, fine.
Good.
You've got her legs up on
the mantelpiece.
She's really--
Ah-ah.
On behalf of
the Psychiatric Association,
I should like to say
that we are taking firm action
to clamp down on the
activities of bogus
psychiatrists.
In fact, in many areas
of modern psychiatry,
computers are now
being increasingly used
for the first basic diagnosis,
and this has gone a long way
towards eliminating the danger
of unqualified impostors.
Your tongue's down
her throat,
she's got her legs
on the mantelpiece--
Out!
[♪♪]
Good evening,
and welcome to Nationwide,
the program where we do
rather wet things nationally,
and also give you a chance
to see some rather wet items
for the regions.
Well, everyone is talking
today about the
Third World War,
which broke out this morning.
But here on Nationwide,
we're going to get away
from that for a bit
and look instead
at the latest theory
that sitting down regularly
in a comfortable chair
can rest your legs.
It sounds very nice,
doesn't it, but can
it be done?
Is it possible or practical
for many of us
in our jobs and with the sort
of busy lives we lead
to sit down
in a comfortable chair
just when we want?
We sent our reporter
John Dull to find out.
Well, here I am on London's
busy Westminster Bridge,
seeing just how much time
sitting down can take.
Well, I arrived here by train
at about 8:50.
It's now 9:05,
so I've been here
for approximately 12 minutes.
And if it's any encouragement,
I must say that my legs
do feel rested.
Is this your chair?
Uh...
Well, no, it's a--
It's a prop.
It's been stolen.
What?
This belongs
to a Mrs. Edgeworth of Pinner.
She's standing over there.
Hoo.
Oh, well,
it's nothing to do with me.
I mean, it's just a prop
which the BBC--
Oh!
Got her name on the bottom.
Well, um, perhaps you'd better
give it back to her.
You don't believe
I'm a policeman, do you?
Yes, I do.
What am I wearing on my head?
A helmet.
A policeman's helmet.
Yes.
You see that?
That little number there?
Yes.
That is a Metropolitan Area
Identification Code.
No helmet is authentic
without that number.
I see.
Kids' helmets,
helmets you get at toy shops,
helmets you buy at Christmas,
none of them has that number.
None of them is authentic.
Hang on.
Oh, could I--?
Hang on!
But--
Oh!
[BRAKES SQUEAL]
Mind you, I didn't join
the police force
just to wear the helmet,
you know.
Oh, yeah?
That just happens to be
one of the little perks.
COP:
There are plenty of jobs where
I could have worn a helmet
but not such a nice helmet.
This helmet, I think,
beats even some
of the more elaborate helmets
worn by the czar's
private army,
the so-called
Axi red warriors.
You know about them?
Well, no, I don't.
Ah. Their helmets
used to look like--
You got any paper?
Well, only these scripts,
but--
All right.
Hey!
[WHISTLING]
I'll have that.
I say.
Now, then.
Their helmet was not unlike
the bobby's helmet
in basic shape.
It had an emblem here,
and three gold--
And in those days
it really was gold.
That's part of the reason
why the czar was so unpopular.
Three gold bands
surmounted by a golden eagle
on the apex here.
Pretty nice helmet, eh?
Yes.
I think
the domed helmet wins
every time
over the flattened job,
you know.
Even where
they're three-cornered or--
You want something to eat?
Well, no. I mean, really--
Hang on.
Uh...
You can't park here, you know.
We're not parked.
We're not.
Not parked? What's that, then?
BOTH: That's our lunch.
Right.
I'm taking that in
for forensic examination.
Why?
Because it might have been
used as a murder weapon,
that's why.
Now clear off.
Yeah, not bad.
Could be worse.
Beer?
No. No, no, please.
Honestly. Please.
[CRASHING, GLASS SHATTERING]
[ALARM RINGING]
Now, then, the Chaldeans,
who used to inhabit the area
in between the Tigris
and Euphrates rivers,
their helmet was of the
modular, restrained
kind of type.
They had a...
[MAN MOANING]
[SIREN BLARING]
Oh, Robert,
tell me I'm beautiful.
You are, you are.
Oh, Robert,
do you mean that?
Of course I do.
Oh.
You're not just saying it
because I asked you to?
Of course not.
Oh, Robert.
Robert.
Yes?
Are you sure
it doesn't put you off?
What?
My father wanting
to come and live with us.
[SCOFFS]
No, of course
I don't mind your father
coming to live with us.
He wouldn't just
be living with us.
W-what do you mean?
Well, he finds it very
difficult to get to sleep
on his own,
so I said
he could sleep with us.
He wants to put his bed
in our room?
No, no, of course not.
Oh, good.
Our bed is plenty big enough
for three.
What?
He'd just get into bed
and go to sleep.
I'm not having that.
Oh, Robert,
I thought you loved me.
Well, I do, but, uh--
Well, he wouldn't look.
He's bound to peek.
No, no, he wouldn't, honestly.
No, no, no!
You young couple just carry
on. Take no notice of me.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I don't want to feel as though
I'm getting in the way.
Oh, no, Dad,
you're not.
No, no.
Good.
[SIGHS]
Well, I think
I'll get to sleep.
Are you sure?
Oh, yes, I'm a bit tired
after the wedding.
Bob, what about you?
Oh, yes. All right, yes.
Oh, well,
I seem to be OC lights.
Good night, darling.
Good night.
[SLOW RUSTLING]
[RAPID RUSTLING]
[SAW BUZZING]
[CLANGING]
[WOOD KNOCKING]
Father? Father,
what are you doing?
I'm making a boat.
What?
It's--
It's the Cutty Sark.
It's a model I've been making
in the dark for some
years now.
Well, wouldn't it be better
with the light on?
No, no, I'm making it
in the dark, that's the point.
Oh, dear. It's not as accurate
as I thought.
That's not the Cutty Sark.
Well, it hasn't got
its sails on yet.
Oh, well, I'll, uh--
I'll have a look at it
in the darkroom
in the morning.
Good night.
[COIN ROLLING]
[♪♪]
MAN:
Will you shut up in there?
[CHATTER]
[LOUD BANGING]
Shut up!
Shut--
[CHATTER STOPS]
That's better.
HAMLET [ON TV]:
I am myself indifferent
honest
but yet I could accuse me
of such things
that it were better
my mother had not borne me.
O fair Ophelia!
Nymph, in thy orisons
Be all my sins remember'd.
So anyway,
you've got the girl
on the bed,
her legs are on
the mantelpiece--
Out!
We're hit. Jump.
[SNORING]
Good God, sir,
look at that.
Quiet. You'll wake him.
Sorry, sir.
[WHISPERING]
We'll try to reach the city
walls before he wakes up.
Yes, sir.
Shh. Quiet.
Sorry. Sorry, sir.
[BREAKS WIND]
Ooh. Sorry, sir.
Too late.
[ROARING]
BOTH:
We're saved!
[BELL DINGS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
That was a great fight, Champ,
a great fight, you hear?
Oh, boy, what a fight, Champ.
What a great fight!
You nearly had him, Champ,
you nearly had him.
Where's his head?
I got it in here,
Mr. Gabriello.
You were great, Champ,
do you hear? You were great!
He's got a nasty cut
over his eye.
Yeah, I think it was
a mistake, him wearing
spectacles.
Get that sewn onto his body
in time for the
press pictures.
Okay, Mr. Gabriello.
Oh, wasn't he great, my boy?
He was great,
Mr. Gabriello.
The way he kept on fighting
after his head came off.
He was better when the head
came off, Mr. Gabriello.
He was really dodging the guy.
If he could've lasted till
the end of that first minute,
he would've had
the Killer worried.
Sure, Mr. Gabriello.
Oh, he was great.
Did you see his left arm?
No.
Okay, we'll look around the
hall after everyone's gone.
Do you realize,
Mr. Gabriello,
some of those guys out there
paid over $2000
for a ringside seat?
And where does the head land?
Right at the back.
That's justice.
Oh, boy.
What do you want?
This your boy's head?
No, no, we got his head.
He ain't hurt that bad.
Hey, that's Gerry Marinello.
He fought the Killer
last week.
Okay, give it to me.
I'm seeing his trainer
tomorrow, I'll give it to him.
Oh!
Hey, Mr. Gabriello,
the press is still outside.
You ready for 'em?
How's the Champ?
Well, the head's on okay,
but there's still
a left arm missing.
Okay, well, keep the dressing
gown kind of loose, okay?
Okay, boys, come on in.
Hey, Mr. Gabriello,
Mr. Gabriello.
Did you expect your boy
to last the full 28 seconds?
This boy has never
let me down.
He's the pluckiest goddamn
fighter I ever trained.
Were you worried
when his head came loose?
No, we was expecting that.
I told him to expect it,
and he did. He ain't stupid.
Can we have a word
with the Champ?
Yeah, okay,
but keep the questions simple.
Hey, Champ, how you feeling?
I said keep the questions
simple.
People are saying
the kid ought to be buried.
His head's come off
in the last six fights.
There's no question
of burying the kid.
He's just reaching the top.
Shouldn't he stay
in the hospital?
No, he ain't going
to no hospital.
He's got the return fight
next week.
COMMENTATOR [ON RADIO]:
And there's Frank Sinatra
leaving the ring.
Behind him is George Raft,
another great boxing fan.
Martin Bormann,
acknowledging the applause.
And with him, of course,
is Gus Himmler,
who did an awful lot
for the sport in his country
in the early 1940s.
And here comes
the Champ now.
He really seems in
good shape to meet the
Killer once again.
Before an audience,
some of them will have paid
$920,000 million
for the privilege of seeing
this boy get beaten up.
And there's the bell.
[SCREAMS]
ALL:
Quiet!
COMMENTATOR:
Left and a right jab
that's taken half the
Champ's shoulder off.
Here's the Killer with
a right, another left
a bash with a hammer,
and a smack with a thud
into the skull.
There's a gaping hole right
through the Champ's
body now.
Now the Killer's
working on the cut eye
with a series
of beautifully placed
punches.
And the head's coming loose!
The Champ must try
and keep his head on.
Killer kicked him
in the groin,
bitten half
his left buttock off.
The referee's stepped in
with a warning.
What a plucky fighter
this Champ is.
He's fighting as well
as I've ever seen him.
Must be losing blood at the
rate of a pint a second now.
It's everywhere.
Certainly,
those who paid $1.5 million
for those ringside seats
are really getting
their money's worth.
They're covered in it.
And his head's off!
His head that's come off
in so many fights
is off in the 31st second.
It's rolled away
down to the left.
But what's happening?
The Killer's being talked to
by the referee.
There's the Champ,
body racing round the ring,
trying to find his opponent.
And the Killer
has been disqualified!
The Killer has been
disqualified.
This great fighter,
who has killed more than 50
people in his boxing career,
has at last been defeated
by this courageous, headless
little southpaw from
New York.
And there's a great roar
here as the referee
raises the arm
of the new World Heavyweight
Champion.
What a pity the rest of his
body isn't here to see it.
ANNOUNCER:
Well, here in London it's
12:30 and time for
The Robinsons.
An everyday story
of blah-dee-blah-dee-blah.
[CLEARS THROAT]
♪ Da-dee-da-dee-da-dee-da
Da-dee-da-dee-da ♪
And so on.
[WATER DRIPPING]
WOMAN 1:
Mrs. Robinson.
WOMAN 2:
Morning, Mrs. Non-Robinson.
WOMAN 1: Been shopping?
WOMAN 2: No, been shopping.
WOMAN 1: What did you buy?
WOMAN 2:  A piston engine.
WOMAN 1:
What did you buy that for?
WOMAN 2: It was a bargain.
Bloody rubbish.
I wanted to listen to that.
Morning, Mrs. Gorilla.
Morning, Mrs. Non-Gorilla.
Have you been shopping?
No, been shopping.
Did you buy anything?
A piston engine.
What'd you buy that for?
Oh, it was a bargain.
Ooh. Mm.
WOMAN:
Tweet, tweet tweet.
Come on, little birdies.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[WOMAN CHIRPING]
Come on, little birdies.
[CHIRPING]
Come and see
what mummy's got for you.
Little birdies.
[CHIRPING]
Tweety, tweety, tweety.
Tweety, tweety.
Ooh, look at this.
Tweety, treaty.
Nice one. Come on, come on.
[CHIRPING]
Tweet. Tweet, tweet.
Come on, little birdies.
Oh, hello, Mrs. Smoker.
Hello, Mrs. Non-Smoker.
What, you been shopping then?
No, I've been shopping.
Oh. What'd you buy?
A piston engine.
What'd you buy that for?
It was a bargain.
How much do you want
for it?
Three quid.
Done.
Right.
Thank you.
How do you cook it?
You don't cook it.
You can't eat that raw.
Ooh. I never thought
of that.
O day and night,
but this is wondrous strange!
And therefore as a stranger
welcome it.
There are more things
in heaven and earth, Horatio,
than are dreamt of
in your philosophy.
But come,
the time is out of joint.
O cursed spite,
That ever I was born
to set it right!
Let's go together.
[♪♪]
Hello, and welcome to
A Room in Polonius's House.
Tonight is European Cup night.
One result in already
from Munich.
The European Cup,
first round, second leg,
Bayern Munchen 4397,
Wrexham 1.
So Wrexham going through there
on aggregate.
Well, now it's time
for racing,
so let's go straight over
to Epsom and Brian McNulty.
Well, over here at Epsom,
there are chances aplenty
for those who want to make
a good start in, um...
Dentistry.
It's a well-off suburb,
so most people have
their own teeth.
And surgeries are opening at
the rate of four or
five a week.
Well, it's only 44 minutes
from the West End
on the train.
And it's not too built up,
so you can have a nice garden.
And the people of Epsom
are a very nice class of
person.
Well, here in High Street,
Epsom,
there are ample opportunities
for all kinds of
redevelopment.
As you can see behind me now,
there are a high number
of low-density consumer units
still not fully maximizing
site value.
This could be
radically improved
by a carefully planned
program of demolition.
And of course, most of
the occupants are
elderly folks,
so they wouldn't put up
much of a fight.
Good afternoon.
In fact, there's still
a few minutes to go
before the main race
on the card this afternoon,
the Queen Victoria Handicap.
So let's have a quick word
with the winner of
the last race,
one of the season's top
jockeys, Ronnie Mau-Mau.
Good afternoon, Ronnie.
Afternoon, Brian.
A very fine ride there,
Ronnie.
Well, a fine horse, Brian.
You know, you can't go wrong.
Fancy your chances
for the Derby?
Oh, very definitely,
very definitely, indeed.
Certainly, Brian.
Well, let's see
if a colleague of yours
agrees.
Let's have a word with Desmond
Willet. Afternoon, Des.
Afternoon, Brian.
No chance, no chance at all.
No, no, I think
you're wrong there, Des.
With the right kind of going,
he's going to be in there.
No chance,
there's no chance.
Well, in fact, I can see
last season's top jockey,
Johnny Knowles.
Good afternoon, Johnny.
JOHNNY:
Hello, Brian.
Uh, could we have a box
for Johnny, please?
Thank you.
Hello, Brian.
That's better.
There you are.
Three very well-known faces
from the racing world.
Thanks very much for coming
along this afternoon, lads.
ALL:
Not at all.
And best wishes for the Derby.
Thank you, Brian.
Thanks very much.
Well, in fact, I hear
they're ready for us now
at the start of the main race
this afternoon.
So let's go right away
and join Peter at the start.
PETER:
Well, they're under
starter's orders
for this very valuable
Queen Victoria Handicap.
And they're off.
And Queen Victoria is the
first   to go with a clean
jump off,
followed by Queen Victoria,
Queen Victoria
and Queen Victoria.
It's Queen Victoria
and Queen Victoria
making the early running
on the inside.
And at the back,
Queen Victoria
already a couple lengths
behind the leaders.
Queen Victoria now moved up
to challenge Queen Victoria.
Queen Victoria
losing ground.
Queen Victoria tucked in
neatly on the stand side.
Queen Victoria still
the back marker
as they approach
the halfway mark.
Making ground,
passing Queen Victoria
with Queen Victoria
and Queen Victoria
still well placed as they
approach the first fence.
And at the first fence
it's Queen Victoria
ahead of Queen Victoria,
Queen Victoria in
third place.
Queen Victoria in the rear
as they--
Well, a very exciting race
there at Epsom.
And now over to the European
Cup at Barcelona,
where the latest news
is that Miguel Otana,
the burly Real Madrid striker,
was sent off for breaking wind
in the 43rd minute.
He'd already been cautioned
for pursing his lips
earlier on
and now he's off.
So let's see a playback
of that, Brian.
Yes. Uh, well, as you can see,
there's Otana now.
Uh, he gets the, uh--
The through ball from Gomez
and, uh, he makes no attempt
to play the ball.
He quite deliberately
lets off.
And, uh, to my mind,
he was within the box
and the referee had no option
whatsoever
but to send him off.
Jimmy?
Good evening.
What do you make of that?
Well, the referees
really are clamping down
these days.
Only last week, the Belgian
captain was sent off
for having a Sony
radio-cassette player.
And Gonerelli,
that huge Italian defender,
was sent off in Turin for
having his sitting and
dining room
knocked through
to form an open living area.
Hamlet?
Good evening.
Got the girl on the bed,
legs up--
Out! Out! Come on,
come on, out.
[CANNON FIRES]
Wait. I'm getting
out of here.
[LAUGHS]
I got away.
Ha-ha-ha.
[SQUAWKING]
Missed.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
Missed. Missed again.
Heh-heh-heh.
Oh, wait a minute.
Wait, wait.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
[♪♪]
Let four captains
Bear Hamlet, like a soldier,
to the stage.
For he was likely,
had he been put on,
to have proved
most royally...
[♪♪]
[BREAKS WIND]
And then...