[♪♪]
Let's bring them out!
Any old iron!
Let's bring them--
Oh, thank you.
Any old iron!
Thank you.
Right! Thanks!
Any old metal!
[CLEARS THROAT]
We are here today to witness
the opening of a new box
to replace the box
which used to stand
on the corner of
Ulverston Road
and Sandwood Crescent.
Owing to a program
of road-widening
being carried out
by the borough council,
the Ulverston Road box
was removed
leaving the wall box
in Esher Road
as the only box for the people
of the Ulverston Road area.
This new box
will enable the people
of the Ulverston Road area
to post letters,
postcards and small packages
without recourse
to the Esher Road box
or to the box outside the
post office at Turner's Parade
which many people
used to use
but which has now been
discontinued
owing to the opening
of this box
and also to the reorganization
of box distribution
throughout the whole area
which comes into force with
the opening of the new boxes
at the Wyatt Road post office
in July.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
NARRATOR:
A perfectly ordinary morning
in a perfectly ordinary
English suburb.
Life goes on
as it has done for years.
But soon,
this quiet pattern of
life was to change
irrevocably.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[WHISTLES]
The commonplace routine
of a typical Monday morning
would never be the same again.
For into this quiet little
community came Mr. Neutron.
Mr. Neutron,
the most dangerous
and terrifying man
in the world.
The man with the strength
of an army,
the wisdom of all
the scholars in history.
The man who had the power
to destroy the world.
No one knows what strange and
distant planet he came from,
or where he was going to.
Wherever he went,
terror and destruction
were sure to follow.
Mr. Neutron.
The man whose incredible power
has made him the most
feared man of all time,
waits for his moment
to destroy
this little world utterly.
Then there's Stanley.
He's our eldest.
He's a biochemist in Sutton.
He's married to Shirley.
Shirley, who used to be
the hairdresser?
Yes, that's right.
I think she's a lovely person.
Mind you,
my husband doesn't.
He thinks she's a bit flash.
Hm!
I hate her. I hate her guts.
They come down weekends.
You'll be able
to meet them then.
I'd love to.
Hairdressing is very
interesting.
Oh, yes,
and very important too.
If you don't care for your
scalp, you get rabies.
Then there's Kenneth.
He's our youngest.
He's a bit of a problem.
At least,
my husband thinks so.
Nasty little piece of work,
he is. I hate him.
Mind you, the one
we don't hear
much about now is Karen.
She married a Canadian.
Uh, he's a dentist.
Uh, they live in Alberta.
Two lovely children.
Gary, who's 3,
Leslie, who's 6.
Leslie looks like
the spitting image of Karen.
Do you want to see a photo?
Oh, yes, please.
All right.
They're a couple of little
bastards. I hate them.
They've got eyes
like little pigs,
just like their mother.
She's a disaster.
A really horrible-looking
person, she is.
I thought that one
would stay on the shelf,
but along comes
this stupid dentist git.
He's a real creepy little
bastard, he is. I hate him.
This is a nice area.
It's like a bloody graveyard.
I hate it.
It's handy for the shops and
convenient for the West End.
Oh, if you like going
to the West End.
I think it's a stinking dump.
Meanwhile, in Washington
at the headquarters
of F.E.A.R.,
the Federal Egg
Answering Room--
In reality,
a front name for F.E.E.B.L.E:
The Free World Extra-Earthly
Bodies Location
and Extermination Center.
All was not well.
Good God!
Get me the supreme commander
of land, sea and air forces,
immediately.
[♪♪]
[SNIFFS]
[BUZZES]
Hello?
CARPENTER: This is
Carpenter from F.E.A.R.
You mean F.E.E.B.L.E.?
Yes, sir.
What is it?
Mr. Neutron is missing, sir.
Mr. Neutron? Oh, my God.
Okay.
Surround the entire city.
Send in four waves
of armed paratroopers
with full ground-to-air
missile support.
Alert all air bases.
Destroy all roads.
We'll bomb the town flat
if we have to!
Sir, he's not in Washington,
sir.
Okay, okay. Hold everything.
Hold everything!
Hold it, hold it.
Lay off, lay off. Lay off.
Where is he?
We don't know, sir.
All we know is
he checked out of his hotel
and took a bus to the airport.
All right.
I want a full-scale red alert
throughout the world.
Surround everyone
with everything we've got.
Mobilize every fighting unit
and every weapon
we can lay our hands on.
I want...
I want three full-scale
global nuclear alerts
with every army,
navy and air force unit
on eternal standby.
Right, sir.
And introduce conscription.
Yes, sir.
Right.
[♪♪]
[SNIFFS]
NARRATOR:
So the world was
in the grip of F.E.A.R.
A huge and terrifying crisis
generated by one man.
Easily the most dangerous man
the world has ever seen,
honestly.
Though still biding his time,
he could strike at any moment.
Could he be stopped in time?
You've got a bit of work
to do there, then.
Yes, it is a problem.
Mrs. Ottershaw
never used to bother.
Then, of course,
she was very old. She was 206.
But I must be going.
If you need a hand,
I'll send Frank round.
He could do with a bit
of exercise.
[CACKLES]
Fat old bastard.
[♪♪]
[BUZZES]
Yes?
CARPENTER:
Captain Carpenter here, sir.
Uh, we've been on red alert
now for three days, sir,
and still no sign
of Mr. Neutron.
Have we bombed anywhere?
Have we shown him we
got teeth?
Oh, yes, sir. We've bombed
a lot of places flat, sir.
Good, good. We don't want
anyone to think we're chicken.
Oh, no. They don't think that,
sir.
Everyone's really
scared of us, sir.
Of us?
Yes, sir.
Of our power?
Oh, yes, sir.
They're really scared
when they see those
big planes come over.
Wow, I bet they are.
Ho-ho-ho! I bet they are.
I bet they're really scared.
Oh, they are, sir.
Do we have any figures
on how scared they are?
Uh, no. No figures, sir.
But they sure were scared.
Ah!
But it's not working?
No, sir.
Okay.
We'll try another tactic.
We'll try and outsmart
this Neutron guy.
Yeah, there's one man I know
who could nail him.
One guy? That won't
frighten anyone, sir.
He's the most brilliant man
I ever met.
We were in the CIA together.
He's retired now.
He breeds rabbits
up in the Yukon.
What's his name, sir?
His name is Teddy Salad.
Salad, as in... ?
Lettuces, cucumber, radishes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Where do I find him, sir?
The Yukon.
Oh, and Carpenter?
Yes, sir?
Make sure you get
a decent disguise.
[♪♪]
[CHIMES]
Oh, uh, hello.
My name's Carpenter.
I'm from the U.S. government.
Are you from the Army?
No. No, no, no.
I'm, uh-- I'm from the ballet.
The U.S. Government Ballet.
The ballet?
The ballet's coming here?
Uh, well, maybe.
Oh, that's great.
We love the ballet.
Last year, some of us
from Yellow River,
we go to a party to go and see
the ballet in Montreal.
Look, I-- I was, uh,
wondering--
Oh, we had a marvelous time.
It was, uh, Margot Fonteyn
dancing Les Sylphides.
Oh, it was beautiful.
Look, do you know--?
Do you know how old she is?
Who?
Margot Fonteyn.
No.
She's 206.
Oh.
Well, look, I hear there's
a U.S. ballet organizer
round these parts
by the name of Teddy Salad.
You mean the special agent?
Well, uh...
He's an ex-CIA man.
He's not a ballet dancer.
[ALL LAUGH]
Oh, uh, well,
I just want to see
him on some ballet business.
Oh, well, you could try
the store.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, could you get us
Lionel Blair's autograph?
NARRATOR:
While precious time
was being lost in Canada,
the seconds were ticking away
for the free world.
Already, Neutron,
who, you will remember
is infinitely the most
dangerous man in the world,
he really is,
was gathering allies together.
Try having an omelet
for your evening meal.
Perhaps with yogurt
and grapefruit.
Oh, I've tried that.
I once got down to 56 stone.
But I couldn't stay like that.
I had to take potatoes
wherever I went.
I used to go out to the cinema
with three hundredweight
of King Edwards.
I'd eat them all before
I got out of the toilet.
I had to go on to bread.
What about salad?
Teddy Salad?
No, no, no. Salad.
As in lettuces, radishes,
cucumber.
WAITER:
Don't like it?
No, I-- I didn't want
to eat a salad.
I wanted to find out
about a man called Salad.
You're the first person
to order a salad
here for two years.
All the Eskimos eat in here
is fish, fish, fish.
We are not Eskimos.
Where's our fish?
We've finished our fish.
What fish you want today, huh?
Bream.
Bream? Where do I get bream
this time of year?
You bloody, choosy
Eskimo pests.
We are not Eskimos.
Why don't you like
a nice plate of cannelloni?
ALL: Ugh!
That's not fish.
Oh, I've had my lot
of the Arctic Circle.
I wish I was back in Oldham.
[SPEAKING SLOWLY]
Do any of you Eskimos
speak English?
We are not Eskimos.
I am.
ALL: Shh!
WAITER: Haddock!
ALL: Where?
Do any of you know a man
called Salad?
What, salad as in... ?
Lettuce, cucumbers,
tomatoes, yeah.
Like you have on your plate?
Yeah, that's right.
No, I'm afraid not.
Where's our fish?
What does this Teddy Salad do?
Oh, uh, he-- He's a--
He's a hen-teaser.
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
No, the only Teddy Salad
we know is a CIA man.
Oh, uh, he-- He might know.
ALL: Gunga, gunga,
where's our fish?
Where will I find him?
Oh, he lives up
at Kipper Sound.
Thanks a lot.
ALL: ♪ Fishy, fishy, eye-yo ♪
Um, are you in
international spying too?
Uh, no. No, no, no, no.
I'm, uh-- I'm with the, uh--
The, uh--
The U.S. Ballet Force.
Who are you with?
MI6. But not a word
to the Eskimos.
ALL:
♪ Fishy, fishy, eye-yo ♪
Here's your bloody fish.
Thank you, Anouk.
I'm not an Eskimo!
[♪♪]
CARPENTER:
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hi. I'm Carpenter
of the U.S. Ballet.
Hey, great to have you around.
The last decent ballet we got
around here was Ballet Ramben.
Thursday, they did
Pétrouchka.
Then on Saturday,
they did Fille Mal Gardée.
I thought it was a bit slow,
but--
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It sure is,
uh, nice to see you,
Mr. Salad.
I ain't Salad.
What?
You want Teddy Salad?
Yeah.
CARPENTER:
I don't see anyone.
The one on the end,
on the right.
That's Salad.
CARPENTER:
That's a dog.
No, only bits of it.
What do you mean?
Listen.
Teddy Salad's
the most brilliant agent
the CIA ever had, all right?
Right.
That's how he made his name.
Disguise.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
He had to slim down
to one and a half pounds
to get into that costume.
And 18 inches off each arm
and over 3 feet off each leg.
The most brilliant surgeon
in Europe stuck that tail on.
What about the head?
All of the head was removed
apart from the eyes
and the brain
in order to fit
into the costume.
That's incredible.
Do you want to talk to him?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, uh,
let's move over
to those trees, there.
You never know
who might be watching.
Mr. Salad?
There's a Mr. Carpenter
to see you.
What's he saying?
Do you have a bone?
Here. It's all part
of the disguise.
Okay, Teddy,
here's the bone.
All right, you've got
his trust, now.
You can talk to him.
Sir. Sir. Mr. Salad?
Sir, I've come direct
from the commander of land,
sea and air forces.
There's a pretty dangerous
situation, sir.
Mr. Neutron is missing.
The general says
you're the only one
who'll know where to find him.
What's he saying?
Uh, he wants to go walkies.
Walkies?
Yeah, he--
He's right into it today.
Do you mind taking him
for walkies?
NARRATOR:
While Carpenter took
the most brilliant agent
the CIA ever had for walkies,
events in the world's capitals
were moving fast.
[♪♪]
[PLAYING]
[BUZZES]
SECRETARY:
Secretary of state to see you,
prime minister.
Uh, very well, show him in.
Prime minister.
Oh, do take a seat.
Oh!
Prime minister, we just had
the supreme commander
of U.S. Forces on the phone.
Apparently, they want
a full-scale red alert.
They what?
They want a full-scale
red alert.
Every troop moving--
It's all right,
don't worry about Giuseppe.
He's English, really.
I see.
Well, the whole structure
of world peace is threatened--
Uh, your anniversary, signor?
Uh, no, no, no, Giuseppe.
Not now.
Uh, you mean
this isn't the lady?
No, no.
Oh, signor, my mistake.
Quite fine. But what we--
I play for you "My Mistake."
♪ My mistake ♪
♪ I have made my mistake ♪
♪ What a dreadful mistake ♪
♪ Is this mistake that
I make ♪
♪ My mistake ♪
Giuseppe, do you mind
playing over there?
Oh, very well, signor.
But I play only for you
and your beautiful companion.
♪ My mistake ♪
Well, look,
this Mr. Neutron is located
somewhere in the London area.
We must find him
and exterminate him.
The Americans say if we don't,
they will.
What?
The Americans say
if we don't, they will!
That he doesn't know what?
They'll bomb the entire
London area!
We'd better get out of here!
SECRETARY OF STATE:
They won't bomb here.
Are you sure?
Sure.
Right.
When are they gonna start?
Apparently they haven't got
Neutron yet. But when they do,
they're going to send in--
What?
They're going to send in
waves of bombers!
What? What?!
Four hundred fifty-two
bombers!
Ah, did he tell you anything?
No, no, no.
We chased sticks,
we chased a few reindeer.
Oh, you been chasing reindeer,
have you?
You're a naughty boy, eh?
Look, we haven't got
much time.
He hasn't given me
any information yet.
Okay. Look, tell you what,
then. Let's eat.
You give him
one of your meatballs,
he'll tell you anything, okay?
Okay.
Wait a minute. He's trying
to tell us something.
Carpenter.
Yeah. Carpenter.
Yes, Mr. Salad?
Can you hear me?
Yup, yup. It's--
It's just it's so
goddamn painful in here.
What's the problem?
It-- It's Mr. Neutron, sir.
He's gone missing.
The supreme commander
wants you to take charge.
I-- Oh, God. I...
I-- I...
Yes, Mr. Salad?
I... I gotta go walkies again.
[BUZZES]
SECRETARY:
Still no sign
of Captain Carpenter, sir.
Or Mr. Neutron.
Okay. We'll bomb Neutron out.
Get me Moscow, Peking,
and Shanklin, Isle of Wight.
NARRATOR:
And so the great powers
and the people of Shanklin,
Isle of Wight,
drew their net
in ever-tightening circles
around the most dangerous
threat to peace
the world has ever faced.
They bombed Cairo, Bangkok,
Cape Town,
Buenos Aires, Harrow,
Hammersmith,
Stepney, Wandsworth
and Enfield.
But always,
it was the wrong place.
MAN [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]:
Sorry, Enfield.
We apologize for any
inconvenience
caused by our bombing.
Sorry.
NARRATOR:
But what of Mr. Neutron
the most fearfully dangerous
man in the world?
The man who could destroy
entire galaxies
with his wrist.
The man who could tear
fruit machines apart
with his eyeballs.
He had not been idle.
In fact, he had fallen in love
with the lady
who does for Mrs. Entrail.
Oh, hello, Mr. N.
Terrible about Enfield,
isn't it? It's all gone.
So is Staines. Lovely shops
they used to have in Staines
and Stanmore, you know,
where the AA offices were.
I don't know where we'll pay
our AA subscriptions to now.
Do you know where we'll pay
our AA subscriptions to now?
I didn't know you were
a member
of the AA, Mrs. S-C-U-M.
Oh, yes.
Ever since the corsair
broke down in Leytonstone.
They towed it all the way
to Deauville, FOC.
Yes, you know, FOC,
"free of charge."
Well, my husband Ken,
K-E-N, he said--
Oh, forget about your husband,
Mrs. S-C-U-M.
Or may I call you Mrs. S?
Well, you can call me Linda,
if you like.
No, I'd rather call you
Mrs. S.
Oh.
And you can call me Mr. N.
Well, that's what I was
calling you.
Mrs. S, there is something
I have to tell you.
Yes, Mr. N?
I have just won a Kellogg's
Corn Flake competition.
Oh, Mr. N, that's wonderful.
I got the ball
in exactly the right place.
The prize is 5000 pounds
in cash
or as much ice cream
as you can eat.
Five thousand pounds?
I was thinking
of taking the ice cream.
Oh-- Oh, no. No.
It's been so hot recently.
No, well, you couldn't eat
that much ice cream, Mr. N.
Mrs. S, I can eat enormous
quantities of ice cream
without being sick.
Oh, no, no.
Take the 5000 pounds.
Please take the 5000 pounds.
I was thinking,
if we got married...
Oh, yes?
...we could use
the 5000 pounds
to buy a spoon...
Oh, we could buy
a lot more than that.
...and then fill up
with ice cream.
Oh, forget about the
ice cream.
We need the money.
We need nothing.
For there is something
I have not told you,
Mrs. S-C-U-M.
Oh, please,
call me Mrs. S.
No, I would rather go back
to calling you Mrs. S-C-U-M,
Mrs. S-C-U-M.
I am the most powerful man
in the universe.
Oh.
There is nothing I cannot do.
Mr. N.
I want you to be my helpmate.
As Tarzan had his Jane,
as Napoleon had his Josephine,
as Frankie Laine had
whoever he had,
I want you to help me in my
plan to dominate the world.
Oh, Mr. N.
That I should be so lucky.
You're not Jewish, are you?
Another time was when
I was in Cairo.
I was disguised
as a water hydrant.
The whole top part of my head
had been removed, and...
Please, Mr. Salad. You must
tell us where Neutron is.
...and I functioned.
Do you hear?
I really worked.
I could put out a fire.
Please, Mr. Salad.
Mind you, it hurt a bit.
Please, Mr. Salad,
there isn't much time.
Where is Neutron?
Okay. Give me another meatball
and I'll tell you.
[MR. SALAD CHOMPING]
Mm!
Okay. Listen carefully.
I won't repeat this,
you understand?
Yes, yes. Quick.
I know where Neutron is
right now.
I know the exact address
and the exact house
and the exact road.
Okay, where is he?
He's not in America.
No.
He's not in Asia.
He's not in Australia.
No.
He's in--
Yes?
Europe.
You wanna know where
in Europe?
Yes!
Okay, okay. I'll tell you.
He's in England, in London,
at number 19--
That's the Yukon.
What's left?
SECRETARY [OVER PHONE]:
Only Ruislip, the Gobi Desert,
and your office, sir.
Okay. Let's start
with my office.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
[WHISTLING]
[EXPLOSION]
I will take you away
from all this, Mrs. S-C-U-M.
Oh, Mr. N, I'd follow you
anywhere.
We will have two weeks
in Benidorm.
Oh, yes. Yes.
And I will make you the most
beautiful woman in the world.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Oh, Mr. N, you have made
my heart sing.
Late in life's pageant
it may be
but you have made roses bloom
anew for me.
Life's rich harvest is being--
Shut up, Mrs. S.
We must hurry.
Oh. I-- Well-- I-- I--
I'd better leave a note for
Ken. He'll be expecting it.
[EXPLOSION]
NARRATOR:
Has Mr. Neutron escaped
in time?
Is the world
utterly destroyed?
How can Mr. Neutron
and his child bride survive?
Will his mighty powers
be of any avail
against the holocaust?
Stay tuned to this channel.
Hello. Uh, well, in fact,
what happens is
that they are saved
by Mr. Neutron's mighty powers
just as the last bomb
falls on Ruislip.
However, the Earth has been
blown off its axis.
And in a
dramatic and dangerous
and expensive sequence
it spins off into space.
There are
appallingly expensive
scenes of devastation
and horror.
And the final, incredibly
expensive climax is reached
as thousands of ape monsters
in very expensive costumes
descend from the sky
onto these--
Plug up a whole city, which
had to be specially built,
and fling them all into the
sea, very expensively.
And we can see those very
expensive scenes right now.
[♪♪]
Just after the credits
have gone through.
Incidentally, these are
going to be some of the most
expensive and lavish scenes
ever filmed by the BBC.
In conjunction
with Time-Life, of course.
These are some
of the technical people
who have been involved
in filming
these very expensive scenes.
The sound.
Very expensive sound.
Expensive
visual effects there.
Expensive production
assistant, expensive designer.
Cheap director.
Well, you can see those very
expensive scenes right now.
MAN:
Oh, come on. You can give us
another minute,
Mr. Cotton, please.
[♪♪]
Good evening.
Last week, we learned
how to saw a lady in half.
This week, we're gonna
learn how to
saw a lady in three bits
and dispose of the body--
Whoa!
[SCREAMS]
Look, if you can put on
rubbish like that
and Horse of the Year Show
you can afford us another
minute, Mr. Cotton, please.
I mean, look at this load
of old...
ANNOUNCER:
"World Domination" T-shirts
are available from the BBC
World Domination Department,
Cardiff.