ANNOUNCER:
There now follows
a party political broadcast
on behalf of the
Liberal Party.
SPORTSCASTER:
Pratt, back to Pratt.
Pratt again,
a long ball out to Pratt.
And now Pratt is on the ball,
a neat little flick
back inside to Pratt,
who takes it nicely,
and zips it through
on the far side to Pratt.
Pratt with it, but passes
instead to Pratt.
Pratt again--
Oh, and well intercepted by
the swarthy little number
nine, Conchito Maracon.
This 21-year-old halfback,
remarkably stocky
for 6-foot-3-inches.
Square-shouldered,
balding giant,
hair flowing in the wind,
bright-eyed, pert,
young for his age, but oh,
so old in so many ways.
For a 39-year-old, you
wouldn't expect such speed.
Normally considered slow,
he's incredibly fast
as he wanders aimlessly
around sweeping up,
taking the defense
to the cleaners.
Who would've thought,
though many expected it
this remarkable,
45-year-old,
9'4" dwarf of a man,
who is still only 17
in some parts of the world,
would ever really be--?
There was a goal
there apparently.
And now it's Pratt.
Back to Pratt.
Pratt again,
a long ball out to Pratt.
Pratt inside.
Chips it through, far post.
Pratt inside, back again--
MAN:
I really like this Ano-Weet.
It really unclogs me.
Oh, do be careful.
Sorry, Mum.
MAN:
I mean, a lot of the others
say they unclog you,
but I never had a single
bowel movement
with them Recto-Puffs.
Now, if we--
Oh, sorry, Mum.
If we lived in Rhodesia,
there'd be someone
to mop that up for you.
Don't be so bleeding stupid.
If you lived
in bleeding Rhodesia
you'd be out at bleeding
fascist rallies
every bleeding day.
You're a bleeding racist,
you bleeding are.
Language.
Well, he gets on my
sodding wick.
That's better.
The stuff I liked was
that stuff
they gave me before the war.
What was it? Wilkinson's
Number Eight Laxative Cereal.
That went through you
like a bloody Ferrari.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Now, who's that
at this time of day?
If it's the man
to empty the Elsan,
tell him
it's in the hall.
Right, dear.
And make sure you hold it
the right way up.
Dad?
Yeah?
No, no, my dad.
Oh.
Dad?
Dad, why is Rhodesia called
Rhodesia? Oh, sorry, Dad.
No, no, thank you very much.
No. No, I'm sorry. No,
thank you very much indeed.
No. Thank you for calling.
Not today, thank you.
Good morning.
DAD: Who was that?
A Liberal Party candidate,
darling.
What have you done now?
I'm sorry, Mum.
I was just washing up.
Do go and sit down.
Mum?
Mum, do you know why
Rhodesia's called Rhodesia?
Yeah, do you
remember Go-Eazi?
They were hopeless.
Little black pellets,
tasted foul and stuck inside
you like flooring adhesive.
Well, I'm off.
What time are you coming back?
Three a.m.
I think it's disgusting,
you a Member of Parliament.
I heard you in the hall
last night.
I heard you snogging away.
We was not snogging.
Sure. Sounded like
snogging to me.
I could hear his great wet,
slobbering lips going at you.
And his hand going--
Dad.
Yeah?
No, not you.
Just mind your language.
Sorry, Mum.
I've run out of beans.
We was talking.
We was not snogging.
Talking about snogging,
I'll bet.
If you must know,
we was talking
about council rehousing.
Would it mean going to live
in Hollywood?
I've run out of beans.
Where to rehouse
his right hand,
that's all he was
interested in.
And has Faye Dunaway
definitely said yes?
He is the chairman
of the housing subcommittee.
Snogging subcommittee.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Ralph, do answer that door,
will you?
Beans.
Shut up.
Yes, Mum.
If it's the man from
Probbo-Rib,
tell him it's in the bed.
All right.
Sorry, Mum.
Postman.
Beans.
Shut up.
A very good try there
by the Garibaldi family
of Droitwich, in
Worcestershire. Professor.
Well, I can't make up my mind
about this family.
I don't think there was
the sustained awfulness
that we really need.
I mean,
the father was appalling.
Appalling, yes.
He was dirty,
smelly and distasteful,
and I liked him very much.
But, uh...
Lady Organs.
Well, they were
an unpleasant family,
certainly, but I don't think
we had any of the really gross
awfulness we're looking for.
Harsh words there
for the Garibaldi family
of Droitwich,
in Worcestershire.
Present holders of the
East Midlands Most Awful
Family Award
lower-middle-class section.
But unable--Unable today
to score more than 15
on our disgustometer.
With the scores all
in from the judges,
the Garibaldis are
number three,
and a surprise at number two:
The Fanshaw-Chumleighs
of Berkshire.
Absolutely super.
My little man at Poirier's
was telling me
I could have my whole
body lifted for 5000 pounds.
Absolutely super.
[ALL CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Put that down there.
Well,
some of the wonderful behavior
that made the
Fanshaw-Chumleighs
the second-most-awful family
in Britain, 1974.
But the winners, by a clear
10-point margin, once again,
the awful Jodrell family
of Durham.
Unfortunately, we can't show
you some of the performance
that won them the award.
But I assure you, it was
of the very highest standard.
Was it not, Lady Organs?
Oh, yes, superb.
I mean, Mr. Jodrell, you know,
the old grandfather
who licks the--
Yes. Yes, we do.
He's superb. His gobbing
is consistent and accurate,
and his son's a dirty,
foul little creature.
And those frightful scabs
which Mrs. Jodrell--
Yes, well, thank you
very much, Lady Organs.
And from all of us,
well done to the Jodrells.
And to all of you,
without whom,
of course, and not forgetting
who made it all possible.
We'll be back. Until then
good night, and I wish you
a safe journey home.
Thank you for watching. It
was great fun. I enjoyed it,
and I hope you watching
at home have enjoyed it too.
The Jodrells win every bloody
year. It makes you vomit.
Dad?
Yes?
Get your stinking feet
off the bread.
I'm only wiping
the cat's doos off.
Mum?
Shut your gob, Douglas.
I want more Corn Blasters.
Shut up and eat what you got.
[MEOWING]
Some fat bastard at the door.
Shut up.
A strong hive of bees
contains approximately
75,000 bees.
Each honeybee
must make 154 trips
to collect one teaspoonful
of honey. Hello, sir.
What do you want?
Would you like to buy
some of our honey, sir?
What are you doing in here?
Which would you like?
The Californian
Orange Blossom,
the Mexican, the New Zealand
or the Scottish Heather?
He can't eat honey.
It makes him go plop-plops.
Oh, come on. Please, try some.
All right, I'll have
some Icelandic honey.
No, there is no such thing.
You mean you can't make
any honey at all?
No. No, we must import it all.
Every bally drop.
We are a gloomy people.
It's so crikey cold
and dark up there
and there's only fish to eat.
Fish and imported honey.
Oh, strewth.
Well, why do you have a week?
Listen, buster, in Reykjavík,
it is dark for eight months
of the year,
and it's cold enough
to freeze your wrists off.
And there's only
golly fish to eat.
Administrative errors
are bound
to occur in
enormous quantities.
Look at this.
It's all a mistake.
It's a real pain
in the sphincter.
Icelandic Honey Week? My life.
Well, why did you come in here
trying to flog the stuff then?
Listen, cowboy,
I got a job to do.
It's a stupid, pointless job,
but at least it keeps me
away from Iceland. All right?
The leg of the worker bee
has four tiny--
Get out of here.
[♪♪]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
ANNOUNCER [READING]:
Well, Mr. Cotton,
you have what
we in the medical profession
call a naughty complaint.
Now, my advice to you
is to, uh, put this paper bag
over your head--
It's got little holes there.
See,
little holes for your eyes?
--and, uh, to ring this bell,
and to take this card
along to a hospital. Okay?
And I shall inform all
your relatives and friends
and anyone else that I happen
to bump into. Okay?
Cash, wasn't it?
Thank you very much.
Get out.
[RINGING]
Dirty little man.
Hippocratic oath.
Hippocratic...
Oh, it's not in there.
Jolly good.
Very useful. Next.
[GRUNTING]
Ah, yes, you must be
Mr. Williams, is that so?
Well, do take a seat.
W-what seems to be
the trouble?
I've just been stabbed
by your nurse.
Oh, dear. Yes, well,
I probably better have a
look at you then.
Look, uh, could you
fill in this form first?
Sh-she just stabbed me.
Yes. Sh-she's
an unpredictable sort.
Look, uh, you seem to be
bleeding rather badly.
You better hurry up
and fill this in.
Couldn't I fill it in later,
doctor?
No, no. You'd have bled
to death by then.
Can you hold a pen?
I-I'll try.
Yes, jolly good.
You know,
it's a hell of a nuisance,
all this damn paperwork.
Really, it is.
It's a real nightmare,
this paperwork.
It really is a hell
of a nuisance.
Uh, something ought to be
done about it.
Do I have to answer all
the questions, doctor?
No, no, no. Just, uh, just
fill in as many as you can.
No need to go into too much
detail, you know.
I-I don't know why we bother
with it all, really.
It's such a nuisance.
It really is such a--
Well, let's see
how you've done then.
Oh, yes.
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
That's not very good, is it?
Look, surely you knew
number four.
It's from The Merchant
of Venice. Even I knew that.
Sorry about the carpet.
Oh, don't worry about that.
Look at this.
Look at this, number six.
It's the Treaty of Versailles.
Didn't you know that?
Oh, my God.
And number nine,
Emerson Fittipaldi.
Really. Virginia Wade?
You must be mad.
Um, doctor, I've just
shot another patient.
There's no point
in your seeing him.
You didn't kill him, did you?
Afraid so.
Oh, you mustn't kill them,
nurse.
Oh, I'm sorry, doctor.
It was just on the spur
of the moment.
Rather silly, really.
I'm sorry
about the carpet, doctor.
Mr. Williams, I-I'm afraid
I can't give you any marks
so I won't be able to
recommend you for hospital.
I tell you what,
I'll stop the bleeding,
but strictly speaking,
I shouldn't even do that.
On marks like these.
I mean, really, it's not--
There--There are no more
patients now, doctor.
Oh, well,
let's go for lunch then.
Uh, what about, uh... ?
Ah, yes.
Look, Mr. Williams,
we're just popping out for
a bite of lunch
while, uh, we've got
a spare moment, you know.
Look, have another bash at
the form, and try and answer--
If at least you can answer
the questions on history,
then we can give you
some morphine
or something like that, okay?
Thank you, doctor. Thank you.
Dear Sir, I wish to protest in
the strongest possible terms.
Yours sincerely,
Brigadier N.F.
Marwood-Git, bracket, retired.
Read that back,
will you, Brian?
"And when he had
built up Cedron,
"he sent horsemen there,
"and an host of footmen
to the end that, issuing out,
"they might make outroads
upon the ways of Judea,
as the king commanded them."
Good. Pop it in an envelope
and bung it off.
It's no good
bottling things up, Brian.
If you feel them,
you must just say them or
you'll just go mad.
Oh, yes, indeed.
As the book of Maccabees said:
Yea, as the flea
is like unto an oxen,
so is the privet hedge
liken unto a botanist,
black in thy sight, O Lord.
Right. Look, why don't you
just nip out for lunch, Brian?
Yea,
as Raymond Chandler said:
"It was one of those days
when Los Angeles
felt like a rock-hard fig."
Brian, let's stop
this pretending, shall we?
Yea, as Dirk Bogarde said
in his autobiography--
Brian, let's stop
all this futile pretense.
I've--I've always been
moderately fond of you.
Well, to be quite--
Quite frank, brigadier, one--
One can't walk
so closely
with a chap like you for--
For so long
without feeling something
deep down inside.
Even if it isn't anything--
Anything very much.
Well, splendid, Brian.
Well, uh,
I don't suppose there's
much we can do, really.
Not on television, no.
No.
They, uh...
They are a lot more permissive
these days than
they used to be.
Ah, yes, but, uh,
not with this sort of thing.
No.
I suppose they've got
to draw the line somewhere.
Yes.
Well, take a letter, Brian.
Dear Sir, I wish to protest--
[SINGING OPERA]
[METAL SQUEAKING]
[SINGING STOPS]
[SINGING CONTINUES]
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER:
There now follows an appeal
on behalf of extremely
rich people
who have absolutely nothing
wrong with them.
Hello. I'd like to talk
to you tonight
about a minority group
of people
who have no mental
or physical handicaps,
and who, through no fault
of their own,
have never been deprived,
and consequently
are forced to live
in conditions
of extreme luxury.
This often-ignored minority
is very rarely brought
to the attention
of the general public.
The average man in the street
scarcely gives a
second thought
to these extremely
well-off people.
He quite simply fails
to appreciate the pressures
that vast quantities of money
just do not bring.
Have you at home ever
had to cope with this problem?
[♪♪]
Or this?
I know it's only human to say,
"Oh, this will never
happen to me."
And of course, it won't.
So I'm asking you, please,
please, send no contributions,
however large,
to me.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
A party political broadcast...
All right, I'll go.
on behalf of the
Liberal Party.
♪ Everything goes up ♪
♪ Everything goes down ♪
♪ Fish bananas all--♪
Hello, madam.
Oh, hello.
You must have come about--
Finishing the sentences, yes.
Perhaps you'd like to--?
Come through this way.
Certainly.
Oh, nice place you've
got here.
Yes, well, we--
Like it?
Yes, we certainly--
Do. Good.
When did you first start?
Finding it difficult--?
To finish sentences, yes.
Well, it's not me, it's my--
Husband?
Yes, he--
Never lets you finish
what you start?
I'm starting to feel--
You'll never finish
a sentence again.
Exact--
--ly. It must be awful.
It's driving me--
To drink?
No, roun--
--ound the bend?
Yes.
May I... ?
Take a seat.
Thank you. You see,
our method is to reassure
the patient by re-creating
normal--
Conditions?
Yes. Then we try
and get them into a position
where they suddenly find
that they're completing
other people's sentences...
Themselves.
Spot on, Mrs...
Smith?
Good. Well,
try not to overdo it to--
Begin with.
Just keep it to one or two--
Words.
To start,
otherwise you may find that--
I'm taking on too long
a sentence
and getting completely...
Stuck. Good. Yes.
Well, that's about--
--it for now, so--
Thanks very much for calling.
Oh, not at all.
And, uh--
Just like to say--
Thank you very much
for coming along.
Not at all.
And good--
--bye, Mr.--
Vernon.
WOMAN: Carl?
Yes, dear?
I've just had another baby.
Oh, no. How many is that now?
Twelve since lunch.
Oh, there's another one.
[♪♪]
[MACHINE DRILLING]
This is Stonehenge.
And it's from here
we go to Africa.
Well, here it is at last,
the goal of our quest.
After six months and three
days, we've finally caught up
with the legendary
walking tree of Dahomey,
Quercus nicholas parsonus.
Resting here for a moment
on its long journey south.
It's almost incredible,
isn't it,
to think that this huge tree
has walked over 2000 miles
across this inhospitable
terrain to stop here,
maybe just to take in water
before the 2000 miles
on to Cape Town where
it lives.
It's almost unimaginable,
I find,
[QUIET TRICKLING]
uh, the thought of
this mighty tree strolling
through Nigeria,
perhaps swaggering a little,
as it crosses the border
into Zaire,
hopping through the tropical
rain forest,
trying to find a-a quiet grove
where it can, uh,
jump around on its own.
Sprinting up to Zambia
for the afternoon,
then nipping back--
Oh, super.
Well, I've just been told
that this is, uh,
not, in fact,
the legendary walking tree
of Dahomey.
This is one of Africa's
many stationary trees.
Arborus bamber gascoignes.
In fact, we've just, uh,
missed the walking tree.
It left here at 8:00
this morning.
Uh, it was heading off
in that direction,
so we'll just see if we can go
and catch it up.
Come on, boys.
Well, we're still
keeping up with it,
but it's setting a
furious pace.
Early this morning,
we thought we'd spotted it,
but it turned out to be
an Angolan sauntering tree,
Amazellus robin ray,
out walking
with a Gambian sidling bush.
So on we go.
It's gonna be difficult.
The walking tree can achieve
speeds of up to 50 miles
an hour,
especially when it's
in a hurry.
Super. Well,
Rupert has spotted something.
This could be it.
A walking tree on the move.
Come on.
But what Rupert
had in fact discovered
was something very different.
The Turkish little rude plant.
This remarkably smutty
piece of flora
was used by the Turks
to ram up each other's--
Ah, no. In fact,
it was something
even more interesting.
Yes, there it was,
over the other side
of the clearing,
the legendary
puking tree of Mozambique.
No, what they had come across
was a tribe lost to man
since time immemorial.
The legendary Batsmen
of the Kalahari.
ANNOUNCER:
Primitive customs
still survive here
as if the march of time
had passed them by.
But for all the mumbo jumbo
and superstition,
the Batsmen of the Kalahari
are formidable fighters,
as we can see
in this rare footage of them
in action
against Warwickshire.
Warwickshire had dismissed
the Kalahari Batsmen for 140.
And then it was
their turn to face
this extraordinary
Kalahari attack.
Pratt was the first to go,
but Pratt and Pratt
put on a second-wicket
stand of naught,
which was broken by O'Dinga,
in his most hostile move.
That's B. Pratt,
hit wicket, naught.
But Pratt and Z. Pratt dug in
and took the score to a half
before Z. Pratt ran away.
[YELLING]
But out came M.J.K. Pratt
to play a real
captain's innings.
He'd taken his own score
up to naught
when he mistimed a shot
of Bowanga and was lbw.
Typical of Umbonga's
hostile opening spell
was his dismissal
of V.E. Pratt,
who offered no resistance
to this delivery.
And he was caught behind.
But by lunch, the situation
had changed dramatically.
And so with the
tension colossal
as we come up to
the last ball,
that's all from us.
[♪♪]
Good evening.
Over 400,000 million pounds
were wiped off the value
of shares this afternoon,
when someone
in the stock exchange coughed.
Sport. Capital punishment
is to be reintroduced
in the first
and second division.
Any player found tackling from
behind or controlling the ball
with the lower part of the arm
will be hanged.
But the electric chair remains
the standard punishment
for threatening the goalie.
Referees chairman,
Len Goebbels said:
"At last the referee
has been given teeth."
Finally, politics. The latest
opinion poll published today
shows Labor ahead
with 40 percent,
the AA, second with
38 percent,
and not surprisingly,
Kentucky Fried Chicken
running the Liberals
a very close third.
And now back to me. Hello.
And now it's time to go over
to Hugh Delaney at Paignton.
Hello,
and welcome to Paignton.
Because it's from Paignton
we take you straight back
to the studio.
Hello. And it's from here
we go over there.
Well, we're already here,
so let's go over there.
Welcome back.
And now it's time for
part eight of our series
about the life and work
of Ursula Hitler,
the Surrey housewife
who revolutionized
British beekeeping in
the 1930s.
ANNOUNCER:
That was a party political
cast on behalf of
[LAUGHING]
the Liberal Party.