[dramatic music]
[dramatic music continues]
[music stops]
[music resumes]
[inspirational orchestral music]
[music stops]
[mariachi music]
[wind howling]
[bird screeching]
[galloping sound]
Whoa, there!
Halt!
Who goes there?
It is I, Arthur,
Son of Uther Pendragon,
from the Castle of Camelot,
king of the Britons,
defeater of the Saxons,
sovereign of all England.
Pull the other one.
I am, and this is
my trusty servant, Patsy.
We have ridden the length
and breadth of the land
in search of knights
who will join me
in my court at Camelot.
I must speak
with your lord and master.
-What? Ridden on a horse?
-Yes.
-You're using coconuts!
-What?
You've got two empty halves
of coconut,
and you're banging them
together.
So? We have ridden since
the snows of winter
covered this land.
Through the Kingdom of Mercia.
Where did you
get the coconuts?
We found them.
Found them? In Mercia?
The coconut is tropical.
What do you mean?
Well, this is a temperate zone.
The swallow may fly
south with the sun,
or the house martin
or the plover
may seek warmer climes
in winter,
yet these are not strangers
to our land.
Are you suggesting
coconuts migrate?
Not at all.
They could be carried.
What?
A swallow carrying a coconut?
It could grip it by the husk.
It's not a question
of where he grips it.
It's a simple question
of weight ratios.
A five-ounce bird could not
carry a one-pound coconut.
It doesn't matter.
Will you go and tell your master
that Arthur from the court
of Camelot is here?
Listen, in order to maintain
air-speed velocity,
a swallow needs
to beat its wings
43 times every second,
right?
-Please!
-Am I right?
I'm not interested.
It could be carried
by an African swallow.
Oh, yes!
An African swallow, maybe.
Not a European swallow.
That's my point.
Oh, yeah.
I agree with that.
Will you ask your master
if he wants
to join my court at Camelot?
But then, of course,
African swallows
are non-migratory.
Oh, yes.
So, they couldn't bring
a coconut back, anyway.
Wait a minute! Supposing two
swallows carried it together?
No, they'd have to have it
on a line.
Simple. They'd just use
a strand of creeper.
What, held under
the dorsal guiding feathers?
Well, why not?
-[people sobbing]
-[bell dings]
Bring out your dead!
[coughing]
Nine pence.
Bring out your dead!
-Bring out your dead!
-[cat snarls]
-Here's one.
Nine pence.
-I'm not dead!
-What?
Nothing.
Here's your nine pence.
I'm not dead!
-Here. He says he's not dead.
-Yes, he is.
-I'm not!
-He isn't?
He will be soon.
He's very ill.
I'm getting better!
No, you're not. You'll be
stone dead in a moment.
I can't take him like that.
It's against regulations.
I don't want to go on the cart.
Don't be such a baby.
-I can't take him.
-I feel fine.
-Well, do us a favor.
-I can't.
Can you hang around a couple
of minutes? He won't be long.
Got to go to the Robinsons'.
They've lost nine today.
-When's your next round?
-Thursday.
I think I'll go for a walk.
You're not fooling anyone,
you know.
Look, isn't there something
you can do?
I feel happy!
-[man grunts]
-Thanks very much.
Not at all.
See you on Thursday.
Right.
-Who's that, then?
-I don't know. Must be a king.
Why?
He hasn't got shit all over him.
-Old woman!
-Man!
Man, sorry. What knight
lives in that castle over there?
-I'm 37.
-What?
-I'm 37. I'm not old.
-I can't just call you "man."
You could say "Dennis."
I didn't know you
were called Dennis.
Well, you didn't bother
to find out, did you?
I did say sorry about the
"old woman," but from behind--
What I object to
is that you automatically
treat me like an inferior.
-Well, I am king.
-King? Very nice.
How did you get that?
By exploiting the workers!
By hanging on to outdated
imperialist dogma
which perpetuates
the economic and social
differences in our society!
If there's ever going to be
any progress--
Dennis, there's some
lovely filth down here. Ooh.
How do you do?
How do you do, good lady? I am
Arthur, King of the Britons.
-Whose castle is that?
-King of the who?
-The Britons.
-Who are the Britons?
We all are. We're all Britons.
And I am your king.
Didn't know we had a king.
I thought we were
an autonomous collective.
You're fooling yourself.
We're living in a dictatorship.
A self-perpetuating autocracy
in which the working class--
There you go!
Bringing class into it again.
That's what it's all about.
If only people--
Please! Please, good people.
I am in haste.
Who lives in that castle?
-No one lives there.
-Then who is your lord?
-We don't have a lord.
-What?
I told you. We're an
anarcho-syndicalist commune.
We take it in turns
to act as a sort of executive
officer for the week.
Yes.
But all the decisions
of that officer
have to be ratified
at a special biweekly meeting.
Yes, I see.
By a simple majority in the case
of purely internal affairs.
Be quiet!
By a two-thirds majority
in the case of--
Be quiet!
I order you to be quiet.
"Order"?
Who does he think he is?
-I am your king!
-Well, I didn't vote for you.
-You don't vote for kings.
-How did you become king then?
The Lady of the Lake,
her arm clad in the purest
shimmering samite,
held aloft Excalibur
from the bosom of the water,
signifying,
by divine providence,
that I, Arthur,
was to carry Excalibur.
That is why I'm your king!
Listen. Strange women
lying in ponds
distributing swords, is no basis
for a system of government.
Supreme executive power
derives from a mandate
from the masses.
Not from some
farcical aquatic ceremony.
Be quiet!
You can't expect to wield
supreme executive power
just 'cause some watery tart
threw a sword at you.
Shut up!
I mean, if I went around
saying I was an emperor
because some moistened bint
had lobbed a scimitar at me,
they'd put me away!
Shut up!
Will you shut up?
Now we see the violence
inherent in the system.
Shut up!
Come and see the violence
inherent in the system!
-Help, I'm being repressed!
-Bloody peasant!
What a giveaway.
Did you hear that?
That's what I'm on about.
Did you see him repressing me?
You saw it didn't you?
[screaming]
[both scream]
-[gurgling]
-[thud]
You fight with the strength
of many men, Sir Knight.
I am Arthur,
King of the Britons.
I seek the finest
and the bravest knights
in the land to join me
in my court at Camelot.
You have proved yourself worthy.
Will you join me?
You make me sad.
So be it. Come, Patsy.
None shall pass.
-What?
-None shall pass.
I have no quarrel with you,
good Sir Knight,
but I must cross this bridge.
Then you shall die.
I command you, as King
of the Britons, to stand aside.
I move for no man.
So be it!
[screaming]
Now, stand aside,
worthy adversary.
-'Tis but a scratch.
-"A scratch"? Your arm's off.
-No, it isn't.
-Well, what's that, then?
-I've had worse.
-You liar.
Come on, you pansy!
Victory is mine.
We thank thee,
Lord, that in thy--
-Come on, then.
-What?
Have at you.
You are indeed brave,
Sir Knight,
-but the fight is mine.
-Oh, had enough, eh?
Look, you stupid bastard!
You've got no arms left.
-Yes, I have.
-Look!
Just a flesh wound.
-Look, stop that.
-Chicken! Chicken!
I'll have your leg. Right!
-Right! I'll do you for that.
-You'll what?
Come here.
What are you going to do?
Bleed on me?
-I am invincible!
-You're a loony.
The Black Knight always
triumphs. Have at you!
Come on, then.
All right,
we'll call it a draw.
-Come, Patsy.
-Oh, I see.
Running away, eh?
You yellow bastards!
Come back here
and take what's coming to you!
I'll bite your legs off!
♪ Pie Jesu Domine ♪
♪ Dona eis requiem ♪
-A witch!
-We found a witch!
-We got a witch!
We've got a witch!
Burn her! Burn her!
[shouting continues]
We have found a witch.
May we burn her?
Burn her! Burn her!
How do you know
she is a witch?
She looks like one.
Bring her forward.
-I am not a witch.
-But you are dressed as one.
-They dressed me up like this.
-We didn't!
And this isn't my nose.
It's a false one.
-Well?
-Well, we did do the nose.
The nose?
And the hat.
But she is a witch.
Burn her! Burn her!
Did you dress her
up like this?
-No! No!
-No!
-Yes. Yes.
-Yes.
-A bit. She has got a wart.
-A bit.
What makes you think
she is a witch?
Well,
she turned me into a newt.
A newt?
I got better.
-Burn her anyway.
-Burn her!
Quiet! There are ways of telling
whether she is a witch.
Are there? What are they?
Tell us.
Do they hurt?
Tell me,
what do you do with witches?
Burn them! Burn them!
And what do you burn apart
from witches?
More witches!
-Wood.
-So, why do witches burn?
-'Cause they're made of wood?
-Good.
So, how do we tell
whether she is made of wood?
Build a bridge out of her.
Ah, but can you not
also make bridges out of stone?
Oh, yeah.
Does wood sink in water?
-No.
-It floats! It floats!
Throw her into the pond!
-What also floats in water?
-Bread.
-Apples.
-Very small rocks.
-Cider. Cherries.
-Gravy. Mud.
-Churches.
-Lead.
A duck!
Exactly.
So, logically...
If she...
weighs the same as a duck...
she's made of wood.
And, therefore...
-A witch!
We shall use my largest scales.
Right. Remove the supports!
-A witch!
-It's a fair cop.
-Burn her!
Who are you, who are so wise
in the ways of science?
I am Arthur,
King of the Britons.
My liege.
Good Sir Knight, will you come
with me to Camelot,
and join us
at the Round Table?
My liege,
I would be honored.
-What is your name?
-Bedevere, my liege.
Then I dub you Sir Bedevere,
knight of the Round Table.
[narrator] The wise Sir Bedevere
was the first to join
King Arthur's knights.
But other illustrious names
were soon to follow.
Sir Lancelot the Brave.
Sir Galahad the Pure.
And Sir Robin, the Not-quite-
so-brave-as-Sir-Lancelot,
who had nearly fought
the Dragon of Angnor,
who had nearly stood up to
the vicious Chicken of Bristol,
and who had personally
wet himself
at the Battle of Badon Hill.
And the aptly named
Sir Not-appearing-in-this-film.
Together they formed a band
whose names and deeds were to be
retold throughout the centuries.
The Knights of the Round Table.
That, my liege, is how we know
the Earth to be banana-shaped.
This new learning
amazes me, Sir Bedevere.
Explain again
how sheep's bladders
may be employed
to prevent earthquakes.
-Certainly, sir.
-Look, my liege!
-Camelot.
-It's only a model.
Shh.
Knights, I bid you welcome
to your new home.
Let us ride to Camelot!
♪ We're knights
of the Round Table ♪
♪ We dance
whene'er we're able ♪
♪ We do routines
and chorus scenes ♪
♪ With footwork impeccable ♪
♪ We dine well here
in Camelot ♪
♪ We eat ham
and jam and spam a lot ♪
♪ We're knights
of the Round Table ♪
♪ Our shows are formidable ♪
♪ But many times
We're given rhymes ♪
♪ That are quite unsingable
We're opera mad in Camelot ♪
♪ We sing from
the diaphragm a lot ♪
-♪ In war we're tough
and able ♪
-[snarls]
♪ Quite indefatigable ♪
♪ Between our quests
We sequin vests ♪
♪ And impersonate Clark Gable
It's a busy life in Camelot ♪
♪ I have to push the pram
a lot ♪
No, on second thoughts,
let's not go to Camelot.
-It is a silly place.
-Right.
[voice] Arthur. Arthur.
King of the Britons.
Oh, don't grovel. If there's
one thing I can't stand,
it's people groveling.
-Sorry.
-And don't apologize!
Every time I try to talk
to someone it's "sorry this,"
and, "forgive me that,"
and, "I'm not worthy."
-What are you doing now?
-I'm averting my eyes, Oh Lord.
Don't. It's like those miserable
psalms. They're so depressing.
-Now, knock it off!
-Yes, Lord.
Right.
Arthur, King of the Britons.
Your knights of the Round Table
shall have a task
to make them an example
in these dark times.
-Good idea, Oh Lord!
-Course it's a good idea!
Behold, Arthur,
this is the Holy Grail.
Look well, Arthur,
for it is your sacred task
to seek this Grail.
That is your purpose, Arthur.
The quest for the Holy Grail.
[solemn music]
-A blessing from the Lord.
-God be praised!
[bugle music]
[gasps]
Halt!
Hello!
[in French accent]
Hello. Who is it?
It is King Arthur, and these are
my knights of the Round Table.
Whose castle is this?
This is the castle of my master,
Guy de Loimbard.
Go and tell your master
that we have been charged by God
with a sacred quest.
If he will give us food
and shelter for the night,
he can join us in our quest
for the Holy Grail.
Well, I'll ask him, but I don't
think he'll be very keen.
He's already got one, you see.
What?
He says
they've already got one!
-Are you sure he's got one?
-Oh, yes. It's very nice.
I told him
we've already got one.
[snickering]
Well...
can we come up and have a look?
Of course not!
You are English-types.
-Well, what are you then?
-I'm French.
Why do you think I have
this outrageous accent,
you silly king?
-What are you doing in England?
-Mind your own business.
If you will not show us
the Grail,
we shall take
your castle by force.
You don't frighten us,
English pig-dogs!
Go and boil your bottoms,
sons of a silly person.
I blow my nose at you,
so-called Arthur King.
You and all your
silly English k... nights.
-What a strange person.
-Now look here, my good man--
I don't want to talk
to you no more,
you empty-headed,
animal food-trough wiper.
I fart
in your general direction.
Your mother was a hamster,
and your father
smelt of elderberries.
Is there someone else up there
we could talk to?
No. Now go away, or I shall
taunt you a second time.
Now, this is your last chance.
I've been
more than reasonable...
-Fetchez la vache!
-Quoi?
Fetchez la vache!
[mooing]
If you do not agree to
my commands, then I shall--
Jesus Christ!
-Crikey!
-Ow!
Right! Charge!
[knights] Charge!
Run away! Run away!
-Fiends! I'll tear them apart.
-No, no.
Sir, I have a plan, sir.
[sawing]
[clattering]
-[loud noise]
-[cat snarls]
[construction sounds]
[metallic object clatters]
[man speaks French]
-[man 1] Un cadeau.
-[man 2] What?
-[man 1] A present.
-[man 2] Un cadeau.
-[man 1] Oui, oui, allons-y.
-[man 2] What?
-[man 1] Let's go.
-[man 2] Oh.
[indistinct muttering]
[door shuts]
What happens now?
Well, now, Lancelot, Galahad,
and I wait until nightfall,
and then leap out of the rabbit,
taking the French by surprise.
Not only by surprise,
but totally unarmed!
Who leaps out?
Lancelot, Galahad, and I...
leap out of the rabbit...
and...
[groans]
Um... Look. If we built
this large, wooden badger...
Run away!
[all] Run away!
[French men laugh]
History for Schools.
Take 8. Action!
Defeat at the castle
seems to have utterly
disheartened King Arthur.
The ferocity
of the French taunting
took him
completely by surprise.
And Arthur became convinced
that a new strategy was required
if the quest for the Holy Grail
were to be brought
to a successful conclusion.
Arthur, having consulted
his closest knights,
decided that
they should separate,
and search
for the Grail individually.
Now, this is what they did.
[knight screams]
Frank!
[narrator]
The tale of Sir Robin.
So, each of the knights
went their separate ways.
Sir Robin rode north, through
the dark forest of Ewing,
accompanied
by his favorite minstrels.
♪ Bravely bold Sir Robin
Rode forth from Camelot ♪
♪ He was not afraid to die
O, Brave Sir Robin ♪
♪ He was not at all afraid
To be killed in nasty ways ♪
♪ Brave, brave, brave
brave Sir Robin ♪
♪ He was not
in the least bit scared ♪
♪ To be mashed into a pulp ♪
♪ Or to have his eyes gouged
out and his elbows broken ♪
♪ To have his kneecaps split
And his body burned away ♪
♪ And his limbs
all hacked and mangled ♪
♪ Brave Sir Robin ♪
♪ His head smashed in
And his heart cut out ♪
♪ His liver removed
And his bowels unplugged ♪
♪ His nostrils raped,
his bottom burned off ♪
♪ And his penis-- ♪
That's enough music
for now, lads.
Looks like there's
dirty work afoot.
Anarcho-syndicalism
is a way of preserving freedom.
Dennis, forget about freedom.
Don't drop that mud.
Halt! Who art thou?
He is brave Sir Robin
Brave Sir Robin...
Shut up!
Um... nobody, really.
I was just passing through.
What do you want?
-To fight and--
-Shut up!
Um, ooh, nothing.
Nothing, really.
Just to pass through,
good Sir Knight.
I'm afraid not.
Ah. Well, actually, I am
a knight of the Round Table.
You're a knight
of the Round Table?
I am.
In that case,
I shall have to kill you.
Shall I?
-I don't think so.
-What do I think?
-I think, kill him.
-Let's be nice to him.
-Oh, shut up.
-But...
And you!
Get the sword out.
I want to cut his head off!
-Cut your own head off.
-Yes, do us all a favor.
-What?
-Yapping on all the time.
You're lucky
you're not next to him.
What do you mean?
-You snore.
-Ooh, I don't.
Anyway,
you've got bad breath.
Well, it's only because
you don't brush my teeth.
Oh, stop bitching,
and let's go and have tea!
All right! We'll kill him first,
and then have tea and biscuits.
-Yes.
-Not biscuits.
All right! Not biscuits.
But let's kill him anyway.
Right.
-He's buggered off!
-So he has! He's scarpered.
♪ Brave Sir Robin ran away ♪
No!
♪ Bravely ran away, away ♪
I didn't.
♪ When danger
reared its ugly head ♪
-♪ He bravely turned
his tail and fled ♪
-No!
♪ Yes, Brave Sir Robin
turned about ♪
-I didn't!
♪ And gallantly
he chickened out ♪
-♪ Bravely taking to his feet ♪
-I never did!
♪ He beat a very
brave retreat ♪
-Ooh lies!
♪ Bravest of the brave,
Sir Robin ♪
I never!
♪ Pie Jesu Domine ♪
♪ Dona eis requiem ♪
[excited screaming]
Wee!
[gasps]
Ooh ooh.
[narrator] The tale
of Sir Galahad.
[thunderclap]
[distant scream]
[animal roars]
[angelic choir singing]
Open the door!
In the name of King Arthur,
open the door!
[door creaks closed]
Hello!
Welcome, gentle Sir Knight.
Welcome to the Castle Anthrax.
-The Castle Anthrax?
-Yes.
It's not a very good name,
is it?
Oh, but we are nice,
and we will attend
to your every, every need!
You are the keepers
of the Holy Grail?
-The what?
-The Grail. It is here?
Oh, but you are tired,
and you must rest awhile.
Midget! Crapper!
-Yes, O Zoot?
-Prepare a bed for our guest.
-Oh thank you, Zoot.
-Thank you.
Away, away, varletesses!
The beds here are warm
and soft, and very, very big.
Well, look, I--
What is your name,
handsome knight?
Sir Galahad the Chaste.
Mine is Zoot. Just Zoot.
Oh, but come.
No! Please, in God's name,
show me the Grail.
Oh, you have suffered much.
You are delirious.
Look, I have seen it.
It is here.
Sir Galahad!
You would not be so ungallant
as to refuse our hospitality.
Well, I...
Oh, I'm afraid our life must
seem very dull and quiet,
compared to yours.
We are but eight score
young blondes and brunettes,
all between 16
and 19 and a half,
cut off in this castle,
with no one to protect us.
Oh, it is a lonely life.
Bathing, dressing, undressing,
making exciting underwear.
We are just not used
to handsome knights.
Nay. Come. You may lie here.
-Oh, but you are wounded!
-No, it's nothing!
You must see the doctors
immediately. Please, lie down.
Well, what seems
to be the trouble?
They're doctors?
Uh, they have a basic
medical training, yes.
Oh, come, come,
you must try to rest.
Dr. Piglet! Dr. Winston!
Practice your art.
Try to relax.
Are you sure
that's absolutely necessary?
We must examine you.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Please. We are doctors.
Look, this cannot be!
-I am sworn to chastity!
-Back to your bed at once!
Torment me no longer.
I have seen the Grail.
-There's no Grail here.
-I have seen it.
-I have seen--
-[women] Hello.
Oh.
Hello.
[women] Hello.
Zoot!
No. I am Zoot's
identical twin sister, Dingo.
Oh, but excuse me--
-Where are you going?
-I seek the Grail.
I have seen it
here in this castle!
No! Oh, no!
Bad, bad, Zoot!
-What is it?
-Wicked, bad, naughty Zoot!
She has been setting light
to our beacon,
which, I've just remembered,
is Grail-shaped.
It's not the first time
we've had this problem.
It's not the real Grail?
Wicked, bad, naughty, evil Zoot.
She is a bad person,
and must pay the penalty.
Do you think this scene
should have been cut?
We were so worried
when the boys were writing it.
But now we're glad.
It's better than some of
the previous scenes, I think.
At least ours
was better visually.
At least ours was committed.
It wasn't just a string
of pussy jokes.
-Get on with it.
-Yes. Get on with it!
Get on with it!
-I am enjoying this scene.
-Get on with it!
[sighs]
Oh, wicked, wicked Zoot!
She must pay the penalty.
And here in Castle Anthrax,
we have but one punishment
for setting alight
the Grail-shaped beacon.
You must tie her down on a bed,
and spank her.
[girls] A spanking!
A spanking!
You must spank her well,
and after you've spanked her,
you may
deal with her as you like.
-And, then, spank me.
-And me!
-And me.
Yes. You must give us
all a good spanking!
A spanking! A spanking!
And, after the spanking,
the oral sex.
The oral sex!
Well, I could stay
a bit longer.
-Sir Galahad!
-Oh, hello.
-Quick! You are in great peril.
-Why?
-No, he isn't!
-Silence, foul temptress!
-She's got a point.
-We'll cover your escape!
-Look, I'm fine!
-Wait, Sir Galahad!
I can tackle
this lot single-handed!
Yes, let him tackle us
single-handed!
[girls shout]
No, Sir Galahad. Come!
No, really. I can cope.
I can handle this lot easily!
-Yes, let him handle us easily.
-Go! Quick!
Wait! Please! I can defeat them!
There's only 150 of them!
Yes! He'll beat us easily.
We haven't a chance.
[girls shout]
[door shuts]
Oh, shit!
-You were in great peril.
-I don't think I was.
Yes, you were.
You were in terrible peril.
Look, let me go back in there
and face the peril.
No, it's too perilous.
It's my duty as a knight to
sample as much peril as I can.
No, we've got to find
the Holy Grail. Come on!
Let me have
just a little bit of peril?
No. It's unhealthy.
-I bet you're gay.
-No, I'm not.
[narrator] Sir Lancelot
had saved Sir Galahad
from almost
certain temptation.
But, they were still
no nearer the Grail.
Meanwhile,
King Arthur and Sir Bedevere,
not more than
a swallow's flight away,
had discovered something.
That's an unladen
swallow's flight, obviously.
They were more than two laden
swallow's flights away.
Four, if they had a coconut
on a line between them.
I mean, If the birds were--
Get on with it!
Oh, anyway,
on to Scene 24,
which is a smashing scene,
with some lovely acting,
in which Arthur
discovers a vital clue.
There aren't any swallows,
but I think you can hear
a st--
[narrator screams in agony]
[cackling]
And this enchanter of whom you
speak, he has seen the Grail?
[continues cackling]
Where does he live?
Old man, where does he live?
He knows of a cave.
A cave which no man has entered.
And the Grail.
The Grail is there?
There is much danger.
For beyond the cave
lies the Gorge of Eternal Peril,
which no man has ever crossed.
But the Grail.
Where is the Grail?
Seek you the Bridge of Death.
The Bridge of Death
which leads to the Grail?
[cackling]
Ni! Ni! Ni!
Who are you?
We are the knights
who say "Ni"!
No! Not the knights
who say "Ni"?
-The same!
-[man] Who are they?
We are the keepers
of the sacred words.
"Ni," "Peng," and "Neee Wom"!
Those who hear them
seldom live to tell the tale.
The knights who say "Ni"
demand a sacrifice.
Knights of Ni,
we are but simple travelers
who seek the enchanter
who lives beyond these woods.
-Ni! Ni! Ni!
-[knights groan]
[silence]
We shall say "Ni" again to you,
if you do not appease us.
-What is it you want?
-We want...
a shrubbery.
A what?
-Ni! Ni! Ni!
-[knights groan]
Please! Please! No more!
We will find you a shrubbery.
You must return
with a shrubbery,
or else you will never pass
through this wood...
alive.
Knights of Ni,
you are just and fair.
-We will return
with a shrubbery.
-One that looks nice.
-Of course.
-And not too expensive.
-Yes.
-Now...
go!
[humming]
-[loud thud]
-Oh! God!
-Hm. Hm!
-[thudding continues]
-[grumbling]
-[man screams]
-[clattering]
[grunting]
Stop that!
Stop that! Stop that!
Go on, clear off!
Go on, go away!
Do it! Go away!
And you, clear off!
[grunts]
-[church bell rings]
-Huh. Bloody weather.
[narrator] The tale
of Sir Lancelot.
One day, lad,
all this will be yours.
-What, the curtains?
-No, not the curtains, lad.
All that you can see,
stretched out over the hills
and valleys of this land.
That'll be your kingdom, lad.
-But, Mother.
-Father, lad, father.
But, Father,
I don't want any of that.
Listen, lad.
I built this kingdom
up from nothing.
When I started here,
all there was was a swamp.
Other kings said I was daft
to build a castle on a swamp.
But I built it all the same,
just to show them.
It sank into the swamp.
So, I built a second one.
That sank into the swamp.
So, I built a third one.
That burned down,
fell over,
then sank in the swamp.
But the fourth one stayed up.
And that's what
you're gonna get, lad.
The strongest castle
in these isles.
But I don't want any of that.
-I'd rather--
-Rather what?
-I'd rather just...
-[theatrical music]
-Sing!
-Stop that.
-[music stops]
-You're not going
into a song while I'm here!
Now, listen, lad.
In 20 minutes,
you're getting married to a girl
whose father owns the biggest
tracts of open land in Britain.
-But I don't want land.
-Listen, Alice.
-Herbert.
We live on a bloody swamp,
we need all the land we can get.
-But I don't like her.
-Don't like her?
What's wrong with her?
She's beautiful, she's rich.
She's got huge...
tracts of land.
I know, but I want the girl
that I marry to have...
-A certain special something.
-[theatrical music]
Cut that out! Cut that out!
-[music stops]
You're marrying
Princess Lucky,
so you'd better
get used to the idea!
Guards!
Make sure the prince
doesn't leave this room
until I come and get him.
Not to leave the room,
even if you come and get him.
-[hiccups]
-No. Until I come and get him.
Until you come and get him,
we're not to enter the room.
No, you stay in the room
and make sure he doesn't leave.
-And you'll come and get him.
-Right.
We don't
need to do anything,
apart from just stop him
entering the room.
-No. Leaving the room.
-Leaving the room, yes.
-All right?
-Right. If...
-lf we're...
-Yes, what is it?
-If...
-Look, it's quite simple.
You just stay here and make sure
he doesn't leave the room.
-All right?
-[hiccups]
-Oh, I remember.
Can he leave the room with us?
No, you just keep him in here,
and make sure--
Yes! We'll keep him in here,
obviously.
But if he had to leave
and we were with him--
No. Keep just him in here!
-Until you, or anyone else--
-Not anyone, just me.
-Just you... get back.
-Get back.
-Right?
-Right.
We'll stay here
until you get back.
-And make sure he doesn't leave.
-What?
-Make sure he doesn't leave.
-The prince?
Yes, make sure he doesn't leave.
Oh, yes, of course!
I thought you meant him!
It seemed a bit daft me having
to guard him when he's a guard.
-Is that clear?
-Quite clear. No problems.
Right.
-Where are you going?
-We're coming with you.
No, I want you to stay here,
and make sure he doesn't leave.
I see, right.
But, Father...
Shut your noise, you,
and get that suit on.
[theatrical music]
-And no singing!
-[music stops]
-[hiccups]
-Go and get a glass of water.
-Well taken, Concorde!
-Thank you, sir, most kind.
And again!
Over we go! Good, steady!
Now, the big one!
Come on, Concorde!
[object thuds]
Message for you, sir.
Concorde!
Concorde, speak to me!
"To whoever finds this note.
I have been imprisoned
by my father,
who wishes me to marry
against my will.
Please, please come
and rescue me.
I am in the tall tower
of Swamp Castle."
At last! A call!
A cry of distress!
This could be the sign
that leads us to the Holy Grail!
Brave, brave Concorde,
you shall not have died in vain!
Uh, I'm not quite dead, sir.
You shall not have been mortally
wounded in vain!
I think
I could pull through, sir.
Oh, I see.
I think
I'm all right to come with you.
No, sweet Concorde! Stay here.
I will send help as soon as
I have accomplished a daring
and heroic rescue
in my own particular...
[sighs]
-Idiom, sir?
-Idiom!
-No, I feel fine, actually, sir.
-Farewell, sweet Concorde!
I'll just stay here,
shall I, sir?
Yeah.
[women giggle]
[classical music]
[indistinct chatter]
-Morning.
Oh.
Ha haa!
Hey!
[screams]
You're not allowed
to enter the room--
[groans]
Fair one,
behold your humble servant,
Sir Lancelot of Camelot.
I have come to take--
I'm terribly sorry.
You got my note!
-Well, I got a note.
-You've come to rescue me?
-Well, no, you see--
-I knew someone would.
I knew that somewhere out there,
-there must be someone...
-[theatrical music]
-Stop that! Stop that!
Stop it! Stop it!
-[music stops]
Who are you?
-I'm your son.
-No, not you.
I'm Sir Lancelot, sir.
He's come to rescue me,
Father.
-Let's not jump to conclusions.
-Did you kill all those guards?
Uh... Oh, yes. Sorry.
-They cost 50 pounds each.
-I'm awfully sorry.
Don't be afraid of him,
Sir Lancelot.
I've got a rope all ready.
You killed
eight wedding guests and all!
Well, you see,
I thought your son was a lady.
I can understand that.
-Hurry, Sir Lancelot! Hurry!
-Shut up!
You only killed
the bride's father, that's all.
Well, I really didn't mean to.
Didn't mean to? You put your
sword right through his head!
Oh, dear. Is he all right?
You kicked the bride
in the chest! It's going
to cost me a fortune!
I can explain,
I was in the forest,
riding north from Camelot,
-when I got this note.
-Camelot?
-Are you from Camelot?
-Hurry, Sir Lancelot!
I'm a knight
of King Arthur, sir.
Very nice castle, Camelot.
Very good pig country.
-Is it?
-Hurry! I am ready!
Would you like to come
have a drink?
That's awfully nice of you.
I am ready!
I mean,
to be so understanding.
You see,
when I'm in this idiom,
I sometimes
get a bit carried away.
-[prince grunts]
-[wet thud]
[sobbing]
Now, this is the main hall.
We're gonna have all this
knocked through and made into--
-There he is!
-[King] Oh, bloody hell.
Hold it! Hold it, please!
Sorry! You see what I mean,
I just get carried away.
I'm really most awfully sorry.
Sorry, everyone.
-He's killed the best man!
-[people shout]
Hold it, please, hold it!
This is Sir Lancelot
from the court of Camelot,
a very brave
and influential knight.
And my special guest
here today.
-Hello.
-He killed my auntie!
No, please! Please!
This is supposed
to be a happy occasion!
Let's not bicker and argue
about who killed who.
We are here today to witness
the union of two young people
in the joyful bond
of a holy wedlock.
Unfortunately, one of them,
my son Herbert,
-has just fallen to his death.
-[people groan]
But I don't want to think
I've lost a son, so much as...
gained a daughter.
For, since the tragic death
of her father--
He's not quite dead!
[people gasp]
Since the near fatal wounding
of her father--
He's getting better!
For, since her own father,
who, when he seemed
about to recover,
suddenly felt the icy
hand of death upon him.
-[man groans]
-Oh, he's died!
I want his only daughter
to look upon me
as her own dad, in a very real,
and legally binding sense.
And I feel sure
that the merger--
the union between the Princess
and the brave but dangerous
Sir Lancelot of Camelot...
-What?
-Look, the dead prince!
-He's not quite dead!
-I feel much better.
You fell out of the tall tower,
you creep!
No, I was saved
at the last minute.
-How?
-Well, I'll tell you.
-[music starts]
-Not like that! Not like that.
♪ He's going to tell
He's going to tell ♪
Quickly, sir, come this way!
No, it's not right for my idiom.
I must escape more...
[sighs]
-Dramatically, sir?
-Dramatically.
-♪ But he's here
with us today ♪
-[crash]
♪ What a wonderful escape ♪
[cheering]
[Lancelot] Excuse me, could
somebody give me a push, please?
[cat snarls]
Old crone!
Is there anywhere in this town
where we could buy a shrubbery?
-Who sent you?
-The knights who say "Ni"!
[groans] No! We have
no shrubberies here.
If you do not tell us where
we can buy a shrubbery,
my friend and I will say...
We will say "Ni."
[groans] Do your worst!
Very well. If you will not
assist us voluntarily...
-Ni!
-No!
Never. No shrubberies.
-Ni!
-Noo!
No, no, no.
No, it's not that, it's "Ni."
-Noo.
-No, no. "Ni."
You're not doing it properly.
-Ni.
-That's it! You've got it.
-Ni! Ni! Ni!
Are you saying "Ni"
to that old woman?
Um... Yes.
Oh, what sad times are these
when passing ruffians
can say "Ni"
at will to old ladies.
There is a pestilence upon
this land. Nothing is sacred.
Even those who arrange
and design shrubberies
are under considerable
economic stress
at this period in history.
-Did you say "shrubberies"?
-Yes.
Shrubberies are my trade.
I am a shrubber.
My name is
Roger the Shrubber.
I arrange, design,
and sell shrubberies.
-Ni!
-No, no, no, no. No!
Oh Knights of Ni, we have
brought you your shrubbery.
-May we go now?
-It is a good shrubbery.
I like the laurels particularly.
But there is one small problem.
What is that?
We are now no longer
the knights who say "Ni."
-Ni!
-Shh!
We are now
the knights who say
"Ekke Ekke Ekke Ptang
-Zoo Boing Arouza"!
-Ni!
Therefore,
we must give you a test.
What is this test, oh Knights
who until recently said "Ni"?
Firstly, you must find...
another shrubbery!
-[knights babble]
-Not another shrubbery!
Then, when you have found
the shrubbery,
you must place it here
beside this shrubbery.
Only slightly higher,
so you get the two-level effect
with a little path running down
the middle.
A path! A path!
Then, when you have found
the shrubberies,
you must cut down the mightiest
tree in the forest
with...
-a herring!
-A herring! A herring!
-We shall do no such thing.
-Oh, please.
Cut down a tree with a herring?
It can't be done.
[knights scream]
-Don't say that word.
-What word?
I cannot tell.
Suffice to say,
it's one of the words
the Knights of Ni cannot hear.
How can we not say the word
if you don't tell us what it is?
-He did it again.
-What? "Is"?
No, not "is"!
You wouldn't get very far
in life not saying "is."
My liege, it's Robin.
♪ He's jacking it in
and packing it up ♪
♪ And sneaking away
and buggering off ♪
♪ And chickening out
and pissing a pot ♪
♪ Yes, bravely he is
throwing in the sponge ♪
-Robin.
-My liege.
-It's good to see you.
-Now he's said the word!
Surely, you haven't given up
your quest for the Holy Grail?
-♪ He is sneaking away and-- ♪
-Shut up!
-No, far from it.
-You said the word again.
-I was looking for it...
-[screams]
...uh, here in this forest.
-No, it is far from this place.
-[screams] Stop saying the word!
-The word we cannot hear!
-Oh, stop it!
-He said "it" again!
-That's it!
I've said "it." I've said "it."
I've said "it" again!
And there again,
that's three "its"!
[narrator] And so Arthur
and Bedevere and Sir Robin
set out on their search to find
the enchanter of whom the old
man had spoken in Scene 24.
Beyond the forest
they met Lancelot and Galahad,
and there was much rejoicing.
[men] Yay!
[wind howling]
In the frozen land of Nador,
they were forced
to eat Robin's minstrels.
And there was much rejoicing.
[men] Yay!
A year passed.
[shivering]
-Winter changed into spring.
-Nice.
Spring changed into summer.
Summer changed
back into winter,
and winter gave spring
and summer a miss
and went straight
on into autumn.
Ah.
[grunts]
Until one day.
[all gasp]
Knights...
forward!
[explosion]
What manner of man are you
that can summon up fire
-without flint or tinder?
-I...
am an enchanter.
-By what name are you known?
-There are some who call me...
-Tim.
-Greetings, Tim the Enchanter!
Greetings, King Arthur.
-You know my name?
-I do.
You seek the Holy Grail.
That is our quest. You know
much that is hidden, oh Tim.
Quite.
Yes, we are looking
for the Holy Grail.
Our quest
is to find the Holy Grail.
Yes, it is.
-And so we're looking for it.
-Yes, we are.
-We have been for some time.
-Ages.
So, anything you could do
to help would be...
very... helpful.
Look, can you tell us where--?
Fine, I don't want to waste
any more of your time,
but I don't suppose
you could tell us
where we might find a...
find a... a, uh...
A what?
A g... A g...
A Grail?
Yes, I think so.
[all] Yes.
Yes!
-Oh. Thank you.
-Splendid!
Look, you're a busy man--
Yes, I can help you
find the Holy Grail.
Oh, thank you.
To the north, there lies a cave.
The Cave of Caerbannog.
Wherein, carved in mystic runes,
upon the very living rock,
the last words
of Olfin Bedwere of Rheged...
[thunderous explosion]
...make plain the last resting
place of the most Holy Grail.
Where could we find
this cave, oh Tim?
Follow!
But follow only
if ye be men of valor.
For the entrance to this cave
is guarded by a creature
so foul, so cruel,
that no man yet has fought
with it and lived.
Bones of full 50 men lie
strewn about its lair.
So, brave knights,
if you do doubt your courage
or your strength,
come no further,
for death awaits you all
with nasty, big, pointy teeth.
What an eccentric performance.
[horse whinny sounds]
They're nervous, sire.
Then we'd best leave them here
and carry on, on foot.
Dismount!
[deep breathing sound]
Behold the Cave of Caerbannog!
-Right, keep me covered.
-What with?
-Just keep me covered.
-Too late.
There he is!
-Where?
-There.
What, behind the rabbit?
It is the rabbit.
-You silly sod!
-What?
You got us all worked up.
That's no ordinary rabbit.
That's the most foul, cruel
and bad-tempered rodent
you ever set eyes on.
You tit! I soiled my armor
I was so scared!
Look, that rabbit's got
a vicious streak a mile wide.
-It's a killer!
-Get stuffed.
-He'll do you up a treat, mate!
-Yeah?
-You manky Scots git!
-I'm warning you.
-What's he do? Nibble your bum?
-He's got huge, sharp...
It can leap about...
Look at the bones!
Go on, Bors, chop its head off.
Right. Silly little bleeder.
One rabbit stew coming right up.
-Look!
-[rabbit squeaks]
-Jesus Christ!
-I warned you!
-I've done it again.
-I warned you.
But did you listen to me?
No, you knew it all, didn't you?
Oh, it's just a harmless
little bunny, isn't it?
Well, it's always the same.
I always--
-Oh, shut up!
-Do they listen to me? Oh no.
-Charge!
-[men shout]
[men scream]
Run away! Run away!
[laughs]
-Right. How many did we lose?
-Gawain.
-Ector.
-And Bors. That's five.
-Three, sir.
-Three. Three.
We better not risk
another frontal assault,
that rabbit's dynamite.
Would it help to confuse it
if we run away more?
-Shut up and change your armor.
-Let us taunt it.
It may become so cross
that it will make a mistake.
Like what?
Well...
-Have we got bows?
-No.
-We have the Holy Hand Grenade.
-Yes, of course!
The Holy Hand Grenade
of Antioch.
It's one of the sacred relics
Brother Maynard
carries with him.
Brother Maynard!
Bring up the Holy Hand Grenade.
[religious choir chanting]
How does it...
How does it work?
-I know not, my liege.
-[Arthur] Consult the Book
of Armaments.
Armaments chapter 2:
verses 9-21.
"And St. Attila raised the hand
grenade up on high, saying,
'O Lord,
bless this thy hand grenade,
that with it thou mayest
blow thine enemies
to tiny bits, in thy mercy.'
And the Lord did grin
and the people did feast
upon the lambs and sloths
and carp and anchovies
and orangutans
and breakfast cereals
and fruit bats and--"
Skip a bit, Brother.
"And the Lord spake, saying,
'First shalt thou take out
the Holy Pin,
then shalt thou count
to three, no more, no less.
Three shalt be the number
thou shalt count,
and the number
of the counting shalt be three.
Four shalt thou not count,
neither count thou two,
excepting that thou
then proceed to three.
Five is right out.
Once the number three, being
the third number be reached,
then lobbest thou
thy Holy Hand Grenade of Antioch
towards thy foe,
who, being naughty in my sight,
shall snuff it."'
-Amen.
Right.
One, two, five!
-Three, sir!
-Three!
[deep breathing]
There! Look!
-What does it say?
-What language is that?
Brother Maynard,
you're our scholar.
It is Aramaic!
Of course. Joseph of Arimathea!
-Of course.
-What does it say?
It reads, "Here may be found
the last words
of Joseph of Arimathea.
He who is valiant
and pure of spirit
may find the Holy Grail
in the Castle of Aaargh."'
What?
"The Castle of Aaargh."
What is that?
He must have died
while carving it.
-Oh, come on!
-Well, that's what it says.
Look, if he was dying,
he wouldn't bother
to carve "Aaargh."
He'd just say it.
That's what's carved
in the rock.
-Perhaps he was dictating it.
-Oh shut up!
-Does it say anything else?
-No!
Just "Aaargh."
-Aaargh.
Do you suppose
he meant the Camargue?
-Where's that?
-In France, I think.
Isn't there a St. Aaargh's
in Cornwall?
No, that's St. Ives.
-Oh, yes. St. Ives.
-St. Ives.
Ooooh!
No, "Aaargh."
At the back of the throat.
No no no,
"Ooh," in surprise and alarm!
-You mean a sort of an "Ah!"
-Yes, that's right.
-Aaah!
-Oh!
My God!
[roars]
It's the legendary
Black Beast of...
Aaah!
That's it! That's it!
Run away! Run away!
[all scream]
Keep running.
-Shh. Shh.
-We've lost him.
-[beast roars]
-[men scream]
[narrator] As the horrendous
Black Beast lunged forward,
escape for Arthur and his
knights seemed hopeless.
When, suddenly, the animator
suffered a fatal heart attack.
The cartoon peril was no more.
The quest for the Holy Grail
could continue.
[liquid bubbling]
There it is!
-The Bridge of Death.
-Oh, great.
Look! There's the old man
from Scene 24.
What's he doing here?
He is the keeper
of the Bridge of Death.
He asks each traveler
five questions.
-Three questions.
He who answers
the five questions--
Three questions.
...three questions,
may cross in safety.
What if you get
a question wrong?
Then you are cast
into the Gorge of Eternal Peril.
Oh, wacko.
Who's going to answer
the questions?
-Sir Robin?
-Yes?
Brave Sir Robin, you go.
Hey!
I've got a great idea.
Why doesn't Lancelot go?
Yes, let me go, my liege.
I will take him single-handed.
I shall make a feint
to the northeast--
No. Hang on! Hang on!
Just answer
the five questions--
Three questions.
...three questions,
as best you can.
And we shall
watch and pray.
I understand, my liege.
Good luck, brave Sir Lancelot.
God be with you.
Stop!
Who would cross
the Bridge of Death,
must answer me
these questions three.
Ere the other side he see.
Ask me the questions,
Bridgekeeper. I'm not afraid.
What is your name?
My name is
Sir Lancelot of Camelot.
What is your quest?
To seek the Holy Grail.
What is your favorite color?
-Blue.
-Right. Off you go.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
That's easy.
Stop!
Who approacheth
the Bridge of Death,
must answer me
these questions three.
Ere the other side he see.
Ask me the questions,
Bridgekeeper. I'm not afraid.
-What is your name?
-Sir Robin of Camelot.
-What is your quest?
-To seek the Holy Grail.
What is the capital of Assyria?
I don't know that!
[screaming]
Stop!
-What is your name?
-Sir Galahad of Camelot.
-What is your quest?
-I seek the Grail.
What is your favorite color?
Blue.
No! Yellow!
[screaming]
[chuckles]
Stop!
What is your name?
It is Arthur,
King of the Britons.
-What is your quest?
-To seek the Holy Grail.
What is the air-speed velocity
of an unladen swallow?
What do you mean?
An African or European swallow?
I don't know that.
[screaming]
How do you know
so much about swallows?
You have to know these things
when you're a king, you know.
[uptempo organ music]
Lancelot!
-Lancelot!
[chatter over police radio]
Lancelot!
[angelic music]
The Castle Aargh.
Our quest is at an end.
God be praised.
Almighty God,
we thank thee,
that thou hast vouchsafed
to us the most holy--
-[thudding sound]
-[sheep bleats]
Jesus Christ!
Hello, stuffy English knights
and Monsieur Arthur King,
who has the brain of a duck,
you know.
So, we French fellows
outwit you a second time.
How dare you profane this place
with your presence?
I command you, in the name
of the Knights of Camelot,
to open the doors
of this sacred castle,
to which God himself
has guided us.
How you English say?
One more time, I unclog
my nose in your direction,
sons of a window-dresser!
So, you think you could
out-clever us French folk
with your silly knees-bent,
running about,
advancing behavior.
I wave my private parts
at your aunties.
You cheesy lot of second-hand,
electric donkey-bottom biters!
In the name of the Lord,
we demand entrance
to this sacred castle!
No chance,
English bed-wetting types.
I burst my pimples at you,
and call your door-opening
request a silly thing!
You tiny-brained wipers
of other people's bottoms.
If you'll
not open this door,
we shall take this castle
by force!
In the name of God
and the glory of our--
-[men laugh]
-Right! That settles it!
Yes, depart at this time, and
don't be approaching any more,
or we fire arrows
in the tops of your heads,
and make castanets
out of your testicles already.
Walk away, just ignore them.
And now remain gone,
illegitimate-faced bugger-folk!
And, if you think you got
a nasty taunting this time,
you ain't heard nothing yet,
stuffy English k-nights!
-[men taunt]
-[blows raspberry]
[taunting continues]
-We shall attack at once.
-Yes, my liege.
Stand by for attack!
[military drumming]
[drumming stops]
French persons!
[French soldiers
continue taunting]
Today the blood of many a
valiant knight shall be avenged.
In the name of God,
we shall not stop our fight
till each one of you lies dead,
and the Holy Grail
returns to those
whom God has chosen!
Charge!
[soldiers shouting]
[police siren blares]
Yes, they're the ones, I'm sure.
Right, come on. Get back.
Get back right away.
-Put him in the van.
-Get a blanket over that one.
Come on, back! Right back!
That's an offensive weapon,
that is.
[police shout]
All right, sonny, that's enough.
Just pack that in.
[man] Christ!
[uptempo organ music]
[music ends]