(CROWD CHEERING)
(ORCHESTRAL OVERTURE PLAYING)
CHOIR: (SINGING)
♪ Lovely Spam! Lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely Spa-a-a ♪
♪ A-a-a-m ♪
♪ Lovely Spam! Lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely Spam!
Spam, spam, spam, spam! ♪
♪ Always look on
the bright side of life ♪
the bright side ♪
♪ Of life! ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
(THEME FROM
2001: A SPACE ODYSSEY)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(FLAMENCO MUSIC PLAYING)
-Ole!
-(SNICKERS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Senoras, senores y senoritas,
buenas noches.
-ALL: Buenas Noches.
-(WHOOPING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
ALL: (SHOUTING) Llama!
(ALL CHEERFULLY SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
-Ole!
-ALL: Ole!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(COOING)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Who would have thought
40 years ago,
we'd all be sitting here
doing Monty Python?
ALL: Aye, aye.
In them days, we was glad
to have the price of
a cup of tea.
-Cup of cold tea.
-Aye.
Without milk or sugar.
-Or tea.
-In a cracked cup and all.
Oh, we never used
to have a cup.
We used to have to drink it
out of a roll of newspaper.
Best we could manage
was to suck on
a piece of damp cloth.
But you know we were happy
in those days,
although we were poor.
-Because we were poor.
-Right.
My old dad used to say to me,
"Money doesn't buy you
happiness, son."
-He was right.
-Oh, aye.
I was happier in those days
and I had nothing.
We used to live in this tiny,
old chumble-down house,
with great big holes
in the roof.
You were lucky
to have a house.
There were 26 of us
in one room.
No furniture,
half the floor were missing.
We were all huddled
in one corner
for fear of falling.
You were lucky
to have a room.
We used to live in corridor.
Oh...
We used to dream
of living in a corridor.
Would have been
a palace to us.
We used to live in an old
water tank on a rubbish tip.
Got woke up every morning
by having a load
of rotting fish
dumped all over us.
House. Ha!
Well, when I say "House,"
it was only a hole
in the ground,
covered by a sheet of
tarpaulin, but it was
a house to us.
We were evicted
from our hole in the ground.
We had to go
and live in the swamp.
You were lucky
to have a swamp.
There were 150 of us
living in a shoe box,
in the middle of road.
-Cardboard box?
-Aye.
You were lucky.
We lived for three months
in a rolled-up newspaper
in a septic tank.
We used to have to get up
at 6:00 in the morning,
clean the newspaper,
go to work down at the mill,
14 hours a day,
week in, week out,
for six pence a week.
When we got home,
our dad would thrash us
to sleep with his belt.
Luxury.
We used to get up
out of the swamp
at 3:00 in the morning,
drain the swamp,
eat a hard-boiled twig,
work 19 hours at mill
for a shilling a year,
and when we got home, our dad
would flog us to sleep
with a cat-o'-nine-tails
if we were lucky. Ha!
Paradise.
We had it tough.
We used to have to get up
out of shoe box
in middle of night,
and lick road clean
with our tongues.
We had to eat half a handful
of freezing cold gravel,
work 24 hours a day
at mill for four pence
every six years,
and when we got home,
our dad would slice us in two
with bread knife.
Right.
I had to get up in the morning
at 10:00 at night,
half an hour before
I went to bed.
Eat a lump of cold poison,
work 29 hours a day down mill,
and pay mill owner for
permission to come to work,
and when we got home,
our dad would kill us
and dance about on our graves
singing hallelujah.
Aye.
You try and tell
the young people of today that,
-and they won't believe you.
-No.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Wasn't that terrific, ladies
and gentlemen? Really great.
Now, the next item
on the program is...
I can't stand it, man.
Really, I've had it
with this idiot.
Every night, making me say
the most annoying...
Really terrific act.
Now, the next item on the...
MOUTH: Mouth's gone...
It's gone away.
Gonna find someone
a bit cooler, maybe?
I mean, it can't be that hard.
I got experience... (MUTTERS)
Know how he feels...
(CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
(MUFFLED GRUNTS)
Welcome aboard,
British-er pig.
Aye, Fritz, the tables
seem to have turned, old chap.
Greetings, capitalist pig,
very sorry,
but must inform you
that you are now our prisoner.
(SHIP HORN BLARES)
(CROWD WHISTLING)
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
You look and smell divine.
Welcome to Monty's Musical,
the show that leaves you
wanting less.
And, a very big hand please,
for Terry Gilliam.
Here's a little number
I tossed off recently
in the Caribbean.
♪ Isn't it awfully nice
to have a penis? ♪
♪ Isn't it frightfully good
to have a dong? ♪
♪ It's swell to have a stiffy
It's divine to own a dick ♪
♪ From the tiniest
little tadger ♪
♪ To the world's
biggest prick ♪
♪ So, three cheers for your
willy or John Thomas ♪
♪ Hooray for your one-eyed
trouser snake ♪
♪ Your piece of pork
Your wife's best friend ♪
♪ Your Percy or your cock ♪
♪ You can wrap it
up in ribbons ♪
♪ You can slip it
in your sock ♪
♪ But don't take it out
in public or they'll stick
you in the dock ♪
♪ And you won't
a-come a-back ♪
Thank you very much, indeed.
Thank you so much.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Thank you.
I'd like to thank the Navy,
and here they are.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
♪ Isn't it awfully nice
to have a penis? ♪
♪ Isn't it frightfully good
to have a dong? ♪
♪ It's swell to have a stiffy ♪
♪ It's divine to own a dick ♪
♪ From the tiniest
little tadger ♪
♪ To the world's
biggest prick ♪
♪ So three cheers for
your willy or John Thomas ♪
♪ Hooray for your one-eyed
trouser snake ♪
♪ Your piece of pork
Your wife's best friend ♪
♪ Your Percy or your cock ♪
♪ You can wrap it
up in ribbons ♪
♪ You can slip
it in your sock ♪
♪ But don't take it
out in public ♪
♪ Or they'll stick
you in the dock ♪
♪ And you won't come back ♪
♪ It's fun to own
your own vagina ♪
♪ It's great to have
your friendly thatch ♪
♪ Your minge,
your twat your kitty cat ♪
♪ Your nest, your nasty
or your snatch ♪
♪ It's great to have
a monkey furrow ♪
♪ Your finger pie
your lunch box
or your catch ♪
♪ Your camel toe
your bearded clam ♪
♪ Your bottom
at the front ♪
♪ Your monkey minge
your muffin ♪
♪ Or your
old Sir Berkeley Hunt ♪
♪ Your honey pot
your hairy friend ♪
♪ But never call it "cunt" ♪
♪ Or we won't come back ♪
♪ Isn't it awfully nice
to own a bottom ♪
♪ Isn't it frightfully good
to have an arse ♪
♪ It's swell to own a tushy
it's divine to have a scut ♪
♪ From the skinniest
little buttocks ♪
♪ To the world's largest butt ♪
♪ Three cheers
for your posterior or anus ♪
♪ Hooray for your
lovely sit-upon ♪
(WHISTLES)
♪ Your fundament, your fanny ♪
♪ Your cheeky little dear ♪
♪ Your rump,
your haunch your hams ♪
♪ Your stern,
your fanny or your rear ♪
♪ But be careful
how you handle it
or you'll be caught I fear ♪
♪ And you won't come back ♪
♪ Isn't it awfully nice
to have a penis... ♪
♪ It's fun to own
your own vagina ♪
♪ It's great to have
your friendly thatch ♪
♪ It's swell to have a stiffy
It's divine to own a dick ♪
♪ Your kitty cat ♪
♪ Your nest, your nasty
or your snatch... ♪
♪ So, three cheers
for your willy... ♪
♪ It's great to have
a monkey furrow ♪
♪ Your finger pie,
your lunch box
or your catch... ♪
♪ Your piece of pork,
your wife's best friend ♪
♪ Your Percy or your cock ♪
♪ Your bottom at the front ♪
♪ Your monkey minge
your muffin ♪
♪ But don't take it
out in public ♪
♪ Or they'll stick
you in the dock ♪
♪ And you won't come back ♪
♪ No, sir!
No, you won't come back ♪
♪ No, sir! ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
Company, by the right...
Dress!
Company, camp it, hup!
♪ My goodness me! ♪
♪ I'm in a bad temper today
all right! ♪
♪ Two, three, damn, damn ♪
♪ Two, three
I'm vexed and ratty ♪
♪ Two, three,
and hopping mad ♪
♪ Stamp, stamp
Get her, whoops ♪
♪ I've got your number, ducky ♪
♪ You couldn't afford me,
dear ♪
♪ Two, three,
I'll scratch your eyes out ♪
♪ Two, three, meow ♪
♪ Two, three ♪
♪ Don't come the Rear Admiral
bit with us, dear ♪
♪ We all know where you've
been you Royal Naval fairy ♪
♪ Two, three, left,
right, left, right ♪
♪ Mother's kissing us tonight ♪
♪ Whoops, don't
look now, girls ♪
♪ The captain's just minced in
with that dolly little seaman ♪
♪ Two, three, ooh ♪
♪ Two, three, hello sailor! ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
Company, today,
you go off to war,
and my God,
I wish I was coming with you.
When I first went to fight,
I had two arms.
Two good arms, but when
the time came to give them,
I gave them,
I gave them gladly.
I sang and laughed
as they sawed them off,
because I believed
that there was a future
for mankind
if men were prepared
to give their limbs.
And not just men,
but their women folk, too,
and our children,
and our children's
children's limbs,
children's limbs.
And what about our pets?
Why should the little
bastards get off...
MAN: Right. Stop that sketch.
I think it's silly.
Now, nobody likes a good laugh
more than I do.
Except perhaps, my wife,
and some of her friends.
Oh, yes, and Captain Johnson.
Come to think of it,
most people like a good laugh
more than I do.
But that's beside the point.
Now, let's have a good, clean,
healthy outdoor sketch.
Get some air into your lungs.
Ten, nine, eight,
and all that.
There are pages
in history's book,
which are written
on the grand scale.
Events so momentous,
that they dwarf man
and time alike.
And such was
the Battle of Pearl Harbor,
re-enacted for us now
by the women of the
Batley Townswomen's Guild.
Miss Rita Thurbanks, you
organized this reconstruction
of the battle of
Pearl Harbor, why?
Well, we've always been
extremely interested
in modern drama.
We were, of course,
the first Townswomen's Guild
to perform Camp on
Blood Island,
and last year, of course,
we did an extremely
popular re-enactment
of Nazi war atrocities.
And so, this year, we thought,
we'd like to do something
in a lighter vein.
ANNOUNCER: So, you chose
the battle of Pearl Harbor?
Yes, that's right, we did.
ANNOUNCER: Well, I can see
you're all ready to go,
so, I'll just wish you
good luck in your
latest venture.
Thank you very much,
young man.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
the World of History
is proud to present
the premiere of
the Batley Townswomen's Guild
re-enactment of the Battle
of Pearl Harbor.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(ALL YELLING)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
(MAN CHUCKLES)
That's it!
We're not about to allow
this sort of smut to be
showing on screen.
A Michelangelo to see you,
Your Holiness.
What?
Michelangelo,
the famous Renaissance artist,
whose best known
works include,
the celebrated statue of David
without any underpants.
In 1514...
Yes, yes, they've got it now,
they've got it now.
-What? What?
-Go away.
I was just trying
to be informative.
Go away.
Oh... (INHALES DEEPLY)
Right. Exits.
-Good evening, Your Holiness.
-Good evening, Michelangelo.
Now, I want to have
a word with you
about this painting of yours,
the Last Supper.
-Oh, yeah?
-I'm not happy with it.
Oh, dear. It took me hours.
Not happy at all.
-Is it the jelly
you don't like?
-Jelly?
I mean, they do add
a bit of colour, don't they?
I know what it is.
You don't like the kangaroo.
-What kangaroo?
-Never mind,
I'll paint him out.
I never saw a kangaroo.
Well, he's at the back
with the llama.
Doesn't matter, I'll make him
into one of the Disciples.
Ah.
-Okay?
-That's the problem.
-What is?
-The Disciples.
Are they too Jewish?
I made Judas the most Jewish.
No, it's just that
there are 28 of them.
-Too many?
-Well, of course
it's too many.
Yeah, I know, but I wanted
to give the impression
of a real Last Supper,
you know
not just like a last snack
or a final meal.
But a real mother
of a Last Supper.
There were only 12 Disciples
at the Last Supper.
Well, maybe, some
of their friends dropped by
after dinner for a drink.
No friends.
-Waiters?
-No waiters.
-Cabaret.
-No cabaret.
You see, I like the crowd,
it helps to flesh out
the scene.
I could lose a few, I suppose.
Look, there were only
12 Disciples...
I've got it.
We'll call it,
The Last But One Supper.
What?
Well, if there was a last one,
there must have been
a one before that.
So, this will be
the Penultimate Supper.
The Bible doesn't say
how many people were
there now, does it?
-No, no.
-Well, there you are, then.
Well, look, look,
The Last Supper
was a significant event
in the life of our Lord.
The Penultimate Supper
was not,
even if they had
a mariachi band
and a conjurer.
Now, I commissioned
a Last Supper from you,
and a Last Supper I want,
with 12 Disciples,
and one Christ!
One?
Yes, one!
Now, will you tell me
what in God's name
possessed you to paint this
with three Christs in it?
-It works, mate.
-Works?
Yeah, it looks great.
The fat one
balances the two skinny ones.
There was only one redeemer!
I know that,
we all know that.
I want one...
But what about a bit
of artistic license?
I want one Messiah.
I'll tell you what you want,
you want a bloody
photographer,
that's what you
bloody well want.
Not an artistic creator.
I'll tell you what I want.
I want a Last Supper
with 12 Disciples, one Christ,
no steel bands,
no trampoline acts,
no kangaroos,
by Thursday lunch,
or you don't get paid.
Bloody fascist.
Look, I'm the head of the
fucking Catholic Church, I am,
so, watch it.
You know what
makes that special?
Yes.
♪ There are Jews in the world
there are Buddhists ♪
♪ There are Hindus
and Mormons ♪
♪ And then ♪
♪ There are those
who all follow Mohammed ♪
♪ But I've never been
one of them ♪
♪ I'm a Roman Catholic ♪
♪ And have been since
before I was born ♪
♪ And the one thing
they say about Catholics is ♪
♪ They'll take you as soon
as you're warm ♪
♪ You don't have to be
a six-footer ♪
♪ You don't have
to have a great brain ♪
♪ You don't have to have
any clothes on ♪
♪ You're a Catholic
the moment Dad came ♪
♪ Because ♪
♪ Every sperm is sacred ♪
♪ Every sperm is great ♪
♪ If a sperm is wasted ♪
♪ God gets in a bate ♪
CHOIR:
♪ Every sperm is sacred ♪
♪ Every sperm is great ♪
♪ If a sperm is wasted ♪
♪ God gets quite irate ♪
VIRGIN MARY:
♪ Let the Heathens
spill theirs ♪
♪ On the dusty ground ♪
♪ God shall make them pay ♪
♪ For each sperm
that can't be found ♪
CHOIR:
♪ Every sperm is wanted ♪
♪ Every sperm is good ♪
♪ Every sperm is needed ♪
♪ In your neighbourhood ♪
♪ Hindu, Taoist, Mormon ♪
♪ Spill theirs just anywhere ♪
♪ But God loves
those who treat ♪
♪ Their semen with more care ♪
♪ Every sperm is sacred ♪
♪ Every sperm is boss ♪
♪ If a sperm is wasted ♪
♪ God can get quite cross ♪
♪ Every sperm is holy ♪
♪ Every drop divine ♪
♪ But God needs everybody's ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ And mine ♪
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
♪ Let the pagans spill theirs ♪
♪ On mountain, hill and plain ♪
♪ God shall strike
them down for ♪
♪ Each sperm
that's spilled in vain ♪
♪ Every sperm is sacred ♪
♪ Every sperm is true ♪
♪ Every sperm is needed ♪
♪ Even in O2 ♪
♪ Every sperm is sacred ♪
♪ Every sperm is great ♪
♪ If a sperm is wasted ♪
♪ God gets quite ♪
♪ Irate ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES PLAYING)
Bloody Catholics.
Filling up the bloody world
with bloody people,
they can't afford
to bloody feed.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
What are we, dear?
Protestant
and fiercely proud of it.
Why do they have
so many children?
Because every time
they have sexual intercourse,
they have to have a baby.
But it's the same
with us, Harry.
What do you mean?
Well, we've got two children,
and we've had
sexual intercourse twice.
Ah.
That's not the point,
we can have it whenever
we want.
-Really?
-Oh, yeah.
Because we don't believe
in all that papist clap trap,
we can take precautions.
What, you mean lock the door?
No. I mean as members of
the Protestant Reformed
Church,
that successfully challenged
the autocratic power
of the papacy
in the early part
of the 16th century,
we can wear little
rubber devices
to prevent issue.
What do you mean?
I could, if I wanted,
have sexual intercourse
with you.
Oh, yes, Harry.
And thanks to Martin Luther
and his friends,
I could wear a sheath.
-What, a dress?
-No, no.
A rubber sheath
over my own fella
to ensure that
when I came off,
-you would not be impregnated.
-Ooh!
Oh, yes, that's what being
a Protestant's all about.
It doesn't stop
with a simple condom, no.
I could wear French ticklers.
You what?
French ticklers,
crocodile ribs,
black mambos,
wafer thin condoms.
Designed not only to protect,
but enhance the stimulation
of sexual congress.
Have you got one?
Have I got one?
Well, no.
But I could go
down the road any time
and walk into Boots
with my head held high,
and say, "Mr Boot,
I want you to sell me
a condom.
In fact, I think
I'll have a Mexican tickler.
For, I am a Protestant,
and that is best thing
to be because that is
what God wants."
You people really piss me off!
I'm sorry I invented you.
It was a really bad idea.
Sex, sex, sex,
that's all you bloody humans
think about.
That, and trying to blow smoke
up my arse
with endless prayers.
It's so boring.
Now, this is supposed to be
a funny show, so, for my sake,
get on with it.
ANNOUNCER:
And, welcome to Munich
for the 27th City Olympiad,
an event held traditionally
every 3.7 years,
which, this year,
has brought
together competitors
from over four million
different countries.
And here we are at the start
of the first event
of the afternoon,
the second semi-final
of the 100 yards
for people with no sense
of direction.
Now, I'll just give you
the competitors.
Lane one, Kolomovski of Poland
Lane two, Zatapatique
of France.
Lane three, Gropovich
of the United States.
Next to him,
Drabble of Trinidad.
Fernandez of Spain,
and in the outside lane,
Bormann of Brazil.
(GUNSHOT)
And now, over to the swimming.
And you join us here
at the Bundesabsurd pool,
just in time to see the start
of the 200 meters freestyle
for non-swimmers.
Watch for the tough
Australian champion,
Ron Barnett in
the second lane.
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Well, we'll be bringing you
back here
the moment they start
fishing the corpses out,
but now over to Hans Clay
for the start of the marathon
for incontinence.
Well, we've got an enormous
entry for this event.
Forty-four competitors
from 29 different countries,
all of them with
the most superbly
weak bladders.
Not a tight
sphincter in sight.
Ready to embark, nevertheless,
on the world's longest race,
and they're just aching to go.
On your marks! Get set!
(GUNSHOT)
And they're off, they're off.
And now, the high jump.
Katerina Ovelenskij
for the Soviet Union.
But what a jump! What a jump!
That will probably
be a record!
And here we are
at the 3,000 meter
steeple chase
for people who think
they're chickens.
There's Samuelsson
of the United States
and over there,
is Klaus of East Germany.
He's been
a Rhode Island Red now
for the last three Olympics.
And there's the referee
trying to get them going...
Where is the leader?
Abe Seagull of Canada,
he went off,
got a very good start
and then settled down
on the water jump,
and has now gone loopy.
Now, we're back
with the marathon
for incontinence once again.
There's Polinski
of Poland in the lead,
and now, Brewer
of Australia has taken over.
Brewer has overtaken him,
but he's gone
to spend a penny.
There goes Burt
to spend a penny
and there goes
Gurdich of Austria,
and so now it's
Alvarez of Cuba,
followed by the plucky
Norwegian, Borg.
They're in and out
like yo-yos, boys!
And there's MacDonald!
MacDonald is coming back,
but he can't hold...
Here's Immacuvich.
Immacuvich of Yugoslavia
is taking...
And he can't hold it either.
Well, well, these must be some
of the weakest bladders
ever to represent
their countries.
And now,
let's have a look back
at what's going on
down on the stage.
-Ah, Mr Anchovy.
-Hello.
-Do sit down.
-Thank you.
-Take the weight off the feet?
-Yes, yes, yes.
Lovely weather
for the time of year?
Enough of this gay banter.
Now, Mr Anchovy,
you asked us to advise you
what was the best job in life,
as your profession.
-That is correct.
-Right.
Now, I have the results here
of the interviews,
the aptitude test
that you did last week
and I think we've managed
to build up
a pretty clear picture
of the sort of person you are.
I think I can say without fear
of contradiction
that the ideal job for you
is chartered accountancy.
But I am a
chartered accountant.
Good for you.
Well, back to the office,
then. Well done.
No, you don't understand.
I've been
a chartered accountant
for 20 years.
I want a new job.
Something exciting
that will let me live.
Accountancy is quite exciting,
isn't it?
Exciting? No, it's not.
It's dull, dull, dull.
My God, it's dull.
It's deadly dull,
and tedious
and boring and stuffy
and desperately dull.
Ah, yes, Mr Anchovy,
but you see, your report here
says that you are
an extremely dull fellow.
Our experts describe you
as appallingly dull,
unimaginative, timid,
lacking in initiative,
spineless, easily dominated,
no sense of humour,
tedious company
and irrepressibly drab
and awful.
And whereas,
in other professions,
these would be considerable
drawbacks,
in chartered accountancy
they're a positive boon.
But I came here to find
a new job, a new life,
a new meaning to my existence.
Can't you help me?
Well, do you have any idea
what you want to do?
-Yes, I have.
-Ah.
Lion taming.
Lion taming?
Yes, it's a bit of a jump,
isn't it?
You know,
chartered accountancy
to lion taming in one go,
you don't think it might
be better to work your way
towards lion taming?
Say, via insurance
or something like that?
-Oh, no, no.
-No?
I don't want to wait.
Nine o'clock tomorrow,
I want to be in there, taming.
(STUTTERS) Yes, but do you
have any qualifications?
I've got a hat.
-A hat?
-Yeah, a hat.
A lion tamer's hat.
A hat with "Lion Tamer"
written on it.
I bought it at Harrods.
-Ah, I see.
-Yeah, yeah.
It lights up at night saying,
"Lion Tamer"
in big red neon letters,
so you can tame
them after dark,
-when they're less stroppy.
-Yes, yes.
And during the day
you can turn it off
and claim reasonable
wear and tear
as allowable
professional expenses
-under paragraph 335 B...
-Mr Anchovy,
if I now ring up Bertram Mills
and say,
"Look, I've got a 45-year-old
chartered accountant here
who wants to become
a lion tamer,"
their first question
is not going to be,
"Does he have his own hat?"
You see, they're more likely
to ask about
your experience with lions.
(SNICKERS) Well, I've seen
them at the zoo.
Yes, well, that's a start.
Yes, small brown
furry creature,
with short stumpy legs
and great long curved noses.
I don't know
what all the fuss is about.
I could tame one of those.
They look pretty tame
to start with.
Now these,
these lions of yours,
how tall are they?
Well...
Well, about so high.
They don't frighten me.
And do they, by any chance,
eat ants?
Got it.
Well, I think what
you've got there, Mr Anchovy,
-is an anteater, not a lion.
-What?
You see, a lion
is a huge savage brute,
about five feet tall,
ten feet long,
weighing about 500 pounds.
They run 40 miles an hour
and they have huge,
very sharp pointed teeth,
and nasty, vicious,
razor-sharp claws
that could rip your belly open
before you could say,
"Jack Robinson,"
and they look like this.
(ROARING)
(GASPS) Oh!
Oh, shit.
(SHUDDERS)
Um...
Actually, I quite like
your idea perhaps,
of making the transition
to lion taming
via easier stages.
-You know,
maybe via insurance.
-Or banking.
-Banking.
Banking.
There's a man's life.
Banking, travel,
excitement, adventure,
decisions affecting
people's lives.
So, shall I call the bank?
-Eh... Yeah.
-Yes?
No, no, no. No, look...
Just give me a couple of weeks
to think about it,
because it's a big,
it is a big decision.
-Maybe, I'll just...
-Yes, yes, yes.
-Or maybe three weeks.
-Give it a month.
-A month. Yeah.
-Well...
-Um...
Can I tell you something?
Yes?
I never really wanted
to be a lion tamer.
I wanted to be...
A systems analyst.
Systems...
And then I got this postcard
from my aunt in Canada
and it looked wonderful.
I realized the one thing
I wanted was to be
a lumberjack.
Leaping from tree to tree
as they float down
the mighty rivers
of British Columbia.
The giant redwood.
The larch.
The mighty Scots pine.
With my best girl by my side,
we'd sing, sing, sing.
♪ Oh, I'm a lumberjack
and I'm okay ♪
♪ I sleep all night
and I work all day ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
and he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
and he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees,
I eat my lunch ♪
♪ I go to the lavatory ♪
♪ On Wednesdays I go shopping ♪
♪ And have
buttered scones for tea ♪
♪ He cuts down trees,
he eats his lunch ♪
♪ He goes to the lavatory ♪
♪ On Wednesdays
he goes shopping ♪
♪ And has
buttered scones for tea ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
and he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
and he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees,
I skip and jump ♪
♪ I like to press
wild flowers ♪
♪ I put on women's clothing ♪
♪ And hang around in bars ♪
♪ He cuts down trees,
he skips and jumps ♪
♪ He likes to press
wild flowers ♪
♪ He puts on women's clothing ♪
♪ And hangs around in bars? ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
and he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
and he works all day ♪
♪ I cut down trees,
I wear high heels ♪
♪ Suspendies and a bra ♪
♪ I wish I'd been a girlie ♪
♪ Just like my dear Papa ♪
♪ He cuts down trees,
he wears high heels ♪
♪ Suspendies and a bra? ♪
-Disgusting.
-(ALL GROANING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SOBBING)
Oh, Bevis!
And I thought
you were so butch.
♪ He's a lumberjack
and he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
and he works all day ♪
♪ He's a lumberjack
and he's okay ♪
♪ He sleeps all night
and he works all day ♪
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
WOMAN: Ooh!
(CHUCKLES)
Mm.
Oh, yeah.
(SQUEALS)
Oh, yes.
(SCREAMS)
Charles Atlas, with his
world's most perfectly
developed body.
Tired of being pushed around?
Would you like to do
some pushing around instead?
Would you like a body
that can't fail
to attract women?
To be the envy of other men?
I must get one of those.
Just give me your skinny,
scrawny, little body
for just 15 minutes a day.
I've heard that one before,
ducky.
Let me slap 50 pounds
of He-Man muscles on you.
Thick Herculean arms,
a deep massive chest,
atomic powered legs,
shoulders a yard wide
and right in the privacy
of your own home.
What's my secret?
It's dynamo tension.
Muscles pulling against
muscles, the natural way.
Here's living proof.
And there's no need
to stop there.
So, don't delay.
Send today
for my gigantic, free,
78-page muscle
building course.
(KNOCKING)
MAN: Postman.
And start building a body
you can be proud of.
Yes.
(LAUGHS)
Huh?
Yes.
ANNOUNCER:
Good afternoon and welcome
to a packed Olympic Stadium
in Munich
for the second leg
of this exciting final
of International Philosophy.
And over to your commentator,
Juan Stoppa.
JUAN STOPPA:
And here come
the Germans now,
led by their skipper,
"Nobby" Hegel.
They must surely
start favourites
this afternoon.
They've certainly attracted
the most attention
from the press
with their team problems.
And let's now
see their line-up.
The Germans playing,
Four-Two-Four.
Leibniz in goal.
Back four, Kant, Hegel,
Schopenhauer and Schelling.
Front runners Schlegel,
Wittgenstein,
Nietzsche and Heidegger,
and the midfield duo
of Beckenbauer and Jaspers.
Beckenbauer, obviously,
a bit of a surprise there.
And here come the Greeks,
led out by their veteran
centre half, Heraclitus.
Let's look at their team.
As you'd expect,
it's a much more
defensive line up.
Plato's in goal.
Socrates a front runner there,
and Aristotle as sweeper.
Aristotle very much
the man in form.
One surprise is the inclusion
of Archimedes.
Well, here comes the referee,
Kung Fu Tsu Confucius
and his two linesmen,
St Augustine
and St Thomas Aquinas.
And as the two skippers
come together to shake hands
we're ready for the start
of this very exciting final.
The referee, Mr Confucius,
checks his sand...
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-And... they're off.
Nietzsche and Hegel there.
Karl Jaspers number seven
on the outside.
Wittgenstein there with him.
There's Beckenbauer.
Schelling's in there.
Heidegger covering.
Schopenhauer.
And now it's the Greeks.
Epicurus, Plotinus number six.
Aristotle.
Empedocles of Acragas,
and Democritus with him.
There's Archimedes.
Socrates, there he is,
Socrates.
Socrates there, going through.
There's the ball.
And Nietzsche there.
Nietzsche...
Number 10 in this German side.
Kant moving up on the outside.
Schlegel's on the left.
The Germans moving very well
in these opening moments.
Well, there you are.
And we'll be returning
to the match
sometime in the second half,
but right now it's time for...
MAN: Philosophy.
Hello there. How you doing?
How are you? How you doing?
ALL: G'day, Bruce.
G'day, ladies and Bruce's.
It's very nice to be here
in the Oz arena.
O2, mate. It's a two.
I'm sorry, mate.
Thank you very much.
-So patriotic.
-Sorry.
We're all philosophy
professors
from the University
of Woolamaloo, Australia.
ALL: Australia, Australia,
Australia.
We love you.
I teach Hegelian philosophy.
Bruce here teaches
Aristotelian philosophy.
And Bruce here teaches
classical philosophy
and all of these
other Bruce's are in charge
of the sheep dip.
ALL: Sheep, sheep, sheep,
we love you.
This is the wattle,
the emblem of our land.
You can stick it in a bottle,
you can hold it in your hand.
-Amen.
-Amen, amen.
Bloody thirsty work this,
Bruce, I think I'll get...
Why don't you have
a chilly then, mate.
In fact,
they look a bit thirsty.
They look like
they could use a drink.
Throw them a drink
out there, mate.
-Throw them some of...
-Are you thirsty?
-Good old Australian beer.
-Who's going to...
Throw them out, yeah.
Chuck them, mate.
Chuck them. Good, there.
Now the reason we do this,
ladies and Bruce's,
is we find over here,
your English beer
is a little like
making love in a canoe.
How's that at?
It's fucking close to water.
I love it!
Oh.
-Good evening.
-Good evening, dickhead.
-How are you, Punk Bruce?
-I'm good.
Now Punk Bruce here
has brought on Guest Bruce,
who tonight
has agreed to dress
like a prat for charity.
All right.
So what's your name, Bruce?
My name is Roger.
-Roger?
-Roger McGough.
You're fucking Eddie Izzard,
aren't you?
I fuck him on Tuesdays
and Wednesdays.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah, he's in
disguise tonight.
And what's your
charity, Bruce?
My charity, Bruce,
I'm raising money,
or I've been giving money
to the Monty Python
Retirement Fund.
-Yeah.
-Excellent. Right...
Thank you.
And so for...
'Roo Bruce, leave him alone.
You randy little kanga.
-It's all right.
-Sorry about that, Bruce.
Have you got
another monologue or...
No, no, I'll just say
I've paid 40 million
Australian dollars
to do this, so...
-Okay, very nice indeed.
-Check's in the post.
Thank you, Bruce.
Right, I'm sorry
about our marsupials,
they shag worse
than a bloody carpet,
-some of them.
-(BRUCE LAUGHS)
Anyway, let's try
and raise the chain a little
by singing
a little intellectual song.
-Are you ready?
-Good idea, Bruce.
♪ Immanuel Kant was
a real pissant ♪
♪ Who was very rarely stable ♪
♪ Heidegger, Heidegger
was a boozy beggar ♪
♪ Who could think you
under the table ♪
♪ David Hume could
out-consume ♪
♪ Schopenhauer and Hegel ♪
♪ And Wittgenstein
was a beery swine ♪
♪ Who was just as sloshed
as Schlegel ♪
Hang on a second,
Bruce's, hang on.
I think this lot are in
a bit of a playful mood,
this crowd here.
-Yeah, I think they're...
-BRUCE: Yeah.
ALL: Yeah.
-Pissed as parrots
half of them.
-Yeah.
And I bet some of them have
been smoking their home-grown
English little wacky weed.
Yeah, they might as well
smoke daffodils, mate.
Might as well, mate.
How do you tell
an English batsman?
They're the ones
in the pavilion.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Did you hear about
the pommy bastard
that took Viagra
instead of his sleeping pill?
No, what happened?
He ended up having 40 wanks!
(ALL LAUGHING)
-I love Aussie humour.
-Right.
Well, why don't you guys
give us a bit of a hand
and we'll sing along
to this one, right?
Feel like that?
All right, I'll...
I've got the words here.
They're in my pocket.
I just find it's always
a bit tight down there. Ooh!
Whoa, that's not it.
-Don't pull that out, Bruce.
-Here we are.
Here we are. Got them all
written out in my own
fair hand.
-So I'll make it easy for you.
-All right, so here we go.
All right?
♪ Immanuel Kant
was a real pissant ♪
♪ Who was very rarely stable ♪
♪ Heidegger, Heidegger
was a boozy beggar
who could... ♪
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
It's not working, Bruce.
I think it's my handwriting,
Bruce.
I bet it is.
They're a typical
O2 audience, Bruce.
They don't know whether
to titter or twitter.
(SCOFFS)
-Left my mobile on vibrate.
-Oh, dear.
That's funny, Bruce.
My Sheila has a vibrator
which she can switch on
to phone.
(LAUGHS)
Think about it.
Thank you very much.
Doesn't know if she's coming
or going.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Disgusting.
-Let's raise the tone.
-Now, have we got anything.
Punk Bruce,
can you give us a hand?
I can give her a hand here.
Oh, oi, oi!
Stop that, Bruce. You, oi!
Straight off. Off.
-Oh, go on, fuck off.
-Get off her, mate.
Bugger off to Barcelona
and bite Luis Suarez.
Now, Punk Bruce,
have you got anything
to help us put the words up
for these poor people?
-How's that, Bruce?
-Oh, yeah.
BRUCE 1: Now you can see that.
BRUCE 2: Very nice.
Very good. All right.
Now we've got
no excuse, all right?
It's almost the intermission,
so here we go.
♪ Immanuel Kant
was a real pissant ♪
♪ Who was very rarely stable ♪
♪ Heidegger, Heidegger
was a boozy beggar ♪
♪ Who could think you
under the table ♪
♪ David Hume could
out-consume ♪
♪ Schopenhauer and Hegel ♪
♪ And Wittgenstein
was a beery swine ♪
♪ Who was just as sloshed
as Schlegel ♪
♪ There's nothing Nietzsche
couldn't teach ya ♪
♪ About the raising
of the wrist ♪
♪ Socrates himself
was permanently pissed ♪
♪ John Stuart Mill
of his own free will ♪
♪ On half a pint of shandy
was particularly ill ♪
♪ Plato they say
could stick it away ♪
♪ Half a pint of whisky ♪
every day ♪
♪ Aristotle, Aristotle
was a bugger for the bottle ♪
♪ Hobbes was fond of his dram ♪
♪ And Rene Descartes
was a drunken fart ♪
♪ I drink therefore I am ♪
♪ Yes, Socrates himself
is particularly missed ♪
♪ A lovely little thinker
But a bugger
when he's pissed ♪
-Yay!
-(WHOOPING)
Thank you. You're brilliant.
You're brilliant.
Well, right now we're going
back to the Olympic Stadium
for the closing minutes
of the Philosophy final
and I understand
that there's still no score.
ANNOUNCER:
Well, there may be no score,
but there's certainly no lack
of excitement here.
As you can see Nietzsche
has just been booked
for arguing with the referee.
He accused Confucius
of having no free will
and Confucius he say,
"Name go in book."
And this is Nietzsche's
third booking in four games.
(WHISTLE)
And who's that?
It's Karl Marx.
Karl Marx is warming up.
It looks as though
there's going to be
a substitution
on the German side.
Obviously,
manager Martin Luther
has decided on all-out attack,
as indeed he must,
with only two minutes
of the match to go.
And the big question is,
who is he going to replace?
Who's going to come off?
It could be Jaspers,
Hegel or Schopenhauer,
but it's Wittgenstein.
Wittgenstein who saw
his Auntie only last week.
And here's Marx. Let's see
if he can put some life
into this German attack.
Evidently not.
Honestly.
Well now,
with just over a minute left
a replay on Tuesday
looks absolutely vital,
and there's Archimedes,
and I think he's had an idea.
Eureka!
COMMENTATOR:
Archimedes out to Socrates.
Socrates back to Archimedes.
Archimedes out to Heraclitus,
he beats Hegel.
Heraclitus has a little flick.
Here he comes,
on the far post.
-Socrates is there.
Socrates heads it in!
-(CROWD CHEERING)
Socrates has scored,
the Greeks are going mad.
The Greeks are going mad,
Socrates scores.
Got a beautiful cross
from Archimedes,
the Germans are disputing it.
Hegel is arguing
that the reality
is merely an a priori adjunct
of non-naturalistic ethics.
Kant, via the
categorical imperative,
is holding that ontologically,
it exists only
in the imagination,
and Marx is claiming
it was offside.
But Confucius has answered
them with the final whistle.
It's all over.
Germany, having trounced
England's famous midfield trio
of Bentham, Locke and Hobbes
in the semi-final,
have been beaten
by the odd goal.
And let's see it again.
There it is. Socrates.
Socrates heads it and Leibniz
doesn't have a chance.
And just look at those
delighted Greeks.
There they are,
"Chopper" Sophocles.
Empedocles of Acragas.
What a game he had.
And Epicurus is there,
and Socrates,
the captain, who scored
what was probably the most
important goal of his career.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-Mr Hilton.
-Yes.
You are sole owner
and proprietor
of the Whizzo
Chocolate company?
I am.
Constable Parrot and I
are from the Scotland Yard
Hygiene Squad.
Oh, yes?
Want to have a word with you
about this box
of chocolates you manufacture
called the Whizzo
Quality Assortment.
Ah, good, yes.
If I could begin
at the beginning.
Number one is cherry fondue.
Now this is extremely nasty,
but we can't prosecute you
for that.
Agreed.
Next, we have crunchy frog.
Ah, yes?
Well, am I right in thinking
there's a real frog in here?
-Yes, a little one.
-(STAMMERS)
Is it cooked?
-No.
-What? A raw frog?
We use only the finest
baby frogs,
dew-picked and flown
from Swaziland.
Cleansed in the finest quality
spring water,
lightly killed
and sealed in a treble
milk chocolate envelope
and lovingly frosted
with glucose.
That's as maybe,
it's still a frog.
Well, what else would it be?
Well, don't you even
take the bones out?
If we took the bones out
it wouldn't be crunchy,
would it?
Constable Parrot
ate one of those.
Would you excuse me
a moment, sir?
-Not right at the moment...
-(FARTING)
(CONTINUES FARTING)
Why didn't you say
why you wanted to be excused?
-Hmm?
-(GROANS)
Uh, it says, "crunchy frog"
quite clearly.
Well, people won't expect
there to be a frog in here.
They're bound to think
it's some form of mock frog.
Mock frog?
We use no artificial additives
or preservatives of any kind.
In future though,
you will replace
the description "crunchy frog"
with the words "crunchy, raw,
unboned, uncooked,
real, dead frog,"
if you want
to avoid prosecution.
What about our sales?
Fuck your sales,
we have to protect
the general public.
Now what's this one?
Number five,
ram's bladder cup.
We use choice juicy chunks of
fresh Cornish ram's bladder.
Emptied, steamed and flavoured
with sesame seeds,
whipped into a fondue
and garnished with mouse poo.
-Mouse poo?!
-(GAGGING)
It doesn't say anything
about mouse poo on the box.
Uh, yes, it does,
on the bottom of the box,
after monosodium glutamate.
Well, this is hardly
good enough.
In future,
you must put on this box
a large red sticker
with the words,
"Warning, contains mouse poo."
Our sales would plummet.
Well, why don't you move into
more conventional
areas of confectionary,
like lime cream
or strawberry delight?
I mean, look at this lot.
Um...
Anthrax ripple.
Cockroach cluster.
Flip...
Uh...
Take the box.
-Take the box.
-No.
Take it.
And what's this one?
Spring Surprise.
Ah, that's our specialty.
Covered in darkest rich
smooth chocolate.
When you pop it
into your mouth,
stainless steel bolts
spring out
and punch straight through
both cheeks.
Well, where's the pleasure
in that?
(SOBBING)
Pull yourself together,
Constable.
Sorry, Sir.
Or you'll be
a Constable Ex-Parrot.
Where are we?
Can you remember?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Uh...
Oh, yes!
As you were saying,
"Punch straight through
both cheeks."
Well, where's the pleasure
in that?
That's me speaking now.
Where's the pleasure in that,
when people pop a choccy
in their mouth,
they don't want
their cheeks lacerated.
In any case, this is an
inadequate description
of the sweetmeat.
I must ask you to accompany me
to Scotland Yard.
Uh, it's a fair cop.
And don't talk
to the audience.
Why not?
It's contrary to Section 28
of the Sketch Comedy Act.
Oh, right.
Hello and welcome
to another edition of
Blood Devastation Death,
War and Horror.
Later in the program
we'll be talking to a man
who does gardening.
But my first guest tonight
is a man who speaks
entirely in anagrams.
Tahts sey crreoct.
Do you enjoy it?
Sey, sey, I stom certainly od.
Yeah, and what's your name?
Uh, Hamrag, Hamrag Yattlerot.
Well, Graham,
nice to have you on the show.
Uh, where do you hail from?
Bumcreland.
Uh, Cumberland?
Staht it sepricely. (CHUCKLES)
Lovely part of the world.
And I believe you're working
on an anagram version
of Shakespeare.
Sey, sey, tahtsi crreoct.
Ta the nimute I'm rowking on
'The Mating of The Wersh.'
By William Shakespeare?
Nay, by Malliwi Rakessheape.
(CHUCKLES)
Of course, and what else?
Uh, Twelfth Thing,
The Chamrent of Venice,
Two Nnetlemeg of Verona.
Ah, have you,
have you done Hamlet?
-Thamle.
-Huh?
"Beot, or bot neot.
Tath is the nestiquo."
And what is your
latest project?
Ring Kichard the Thrid.
I'm sorry?
"A shroe, a shroe!
-"My dingkom for a shroe."
-Oh!
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Of course, Ring Kichard,
yes, yes.
But surely
that's not an anagram.
That's a spoonerism.
If you're going to split hairs
I'm going to piss off.
(GUITAR STRUMMING)
The world today
seems absolutely crackers.
With nuclear bombs
to blow us all sky high.
There's fools and idiots
sitting on the trigger.
It's depressing
and it's senseless
and that's why...
♪ I like Chinese ♪
♪ They copy
everything they sees ♪
♪ Ah, but they're up
on the moon ♪
♪ So, they'll do
as they please ♪
♪ I like Chinese ♪
♪ They're still
a little Communise ♪
♪ But Americans
don't need to fret ♪
♪ For China has bought
all their debt ♪
♪ I like Chinese food ♪
♪ The waiters never are rude ♪
♪ Think of the many things
They've done to impress ♪
♪ There's Maoism, Taoism ♪
♪ I Ching and chess ♪
♪ So, I like Chinese ♪
♪ I like Chinese ♪
♪ I like their
tiny little trees ♪
-CHORUS: That's Japanese.
-Oh, yes.
♪ Their Zen, their ping pong ♪
♪ Their yin and yang-ese ♪
♪ I like Chinese thoughts ♪
♪ The wisdom
that Confucius taught ♪
♪ If Darwin is anything
to shout about ♪
♪ The Chinese
will survive us all ♪
♪ Without any doubt ♪
♪ So, I like Chinese ♪
♪ I like Chinese ♪
♪ I like their teas
and their tai chi's ♪
♪ Their calligraphy,
as you can see ♪
♪ They all dance with ease ♪
♪ I like Chinese ♪
♪ Their food
is guaranteed to please ♪
♪ A 14, a seven ♪
♪ A nine and lychees ♪
Altogether now.
(AUDIENCE SINGING ALONG)
♪ I like Chinese ♪
Oh, yeah.
Thank you very much, O2.
(GRUNTS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
-(ALL EXCLAIMING)
-It's the intermission.
-Ooh!
I like the intermission.
(EXCLAIMS) Ooh!
-It's the best bit. I like it.
-Shopping!
I always look forward
to the intermission.
I can go to the toilet.
I so want to go to the toilet.
Oh, Is there only one.
Yes, one for 16,000.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Sit on my face and tell me
that you love me ♪
♪ I'll sit on your face
and tell you I love you too ♪
♪ I love to hear you oralize ♪
♪ When I'm between
your thighs ♪
♪ You blow me away ♪
♪ Sit on my face
and let my lips embrace you ♪
♪ I'll sit on your face
and then I'll love you truly ♪
♪ Life can be fine
if we both 69 ♪
♪ If we sit on our faces
in all sorts of places ♪
♪ And play till
we're blown away ♪
♪ Sit on my face
and tell me that you love me ♪
♪ I'll sit on your face
and tell you I love you too ♪
♪ I love to hear you oralise ♪
♪ When I'm between
your thighs ♪
♪ You blow me away ♪
♪ Sit on my face
and let my lips embrace you ♪
♪ I'll sit on your face
and then I'll love you truly ♪
♪ Life can be fine
if we both sixty-nine ♪
♪ If we sit on our faces
in all sorts of places ♪
♪ And play till
we're blown away ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
And that concludes
tonight's broadcast
of Spam Lake,
part of a new series
of ballet for the radio.
And now we present
the first episode
of a new radio drama series
The Death
of Mary Queen of Scots,
Part I, The Beginning.
MAN: You are
Mary Queen of Scots?
-WOMAN: I am.
-(CLANKING)
(MARY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
-WOMAN: Oh, no!
-(PUNCHING)
(CLATTERING)
Oh, dear!
(SCREAMING)
Oh!
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
Episode two of The Death
of Mary Queen of Scots
can be heard on Radio 4
almost immediately.
-(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
-(CLATTERING)
(GUNSHOTS)
MARY: (SHRIEKING) Oh!
MAN ON RADIO:
I think she's dead.
MARY: No, I'm not.
-(SCREAMING)
-(PUNCHING)
(CLATTERING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
That was episode two
of The Death of Mary
Queen of Scots,
adapted for radio
by sticking a large nail
through it.
And now, Radio 4 will explode.
Oh!
We'll have to watch
the telly then.
Yes, we will.
What's on the television?
Looks like a penguin.
No, I didn't mean
what's on the television set,
I meant what program?
Oh... Oh.
-Sort of funny, that penguin
being there, isn't it?
-Mmm.
What's it doing?
Standing.
I can see that!
If it lays an egg,
it'll fall down the back
of the television set.
We'll have to watch that.
Unless it's male.
Oh, I never thought of that.
It looks fairly butch.
Perhaps it's from next door.
Penguins don't come
from next door.
They come from the Antarctic.
Burma!
Why did you say Burma?
-Oh, I panicked.
-Oh!
Perhaps it's from the zoo.
Which zoo?
How would I know
which bloody zoo?
I'm not David
bloody Attenborough!
How does David
bloody Attenborough
know which zoo it came from?
He knows everything.
Oh.
I wouldn't like that.
It would take all the mystery
out of life.
Anyway,
if it came from the zoo,
it would have
"Property of the zoo"
stamped on it.
No, it wouldn't.
They don't stamp animals
"Property of the zoo."
You can't stamp
a huge Siberian tiger,
"Property of the zoo."
They stamp them
when they're small.
What happens when they molt?
Siberian tigers don't molt.
No, but penguins do!
There, I've run rings
around you, logically.
(LAUGHS)
Oh.
Intercourse the penguin.
Well, it's just gone
8:00 o'clock
and time for
the penguin on top
of your television set
to explode.
How did he know
that was gonna happen?
It was an inspired guess.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, he knows everything,
that Michael Palin.
Yes, and he's been
everywhere too.
-You ever watch any
of those travel? Travel...
-(YAWNS)
(YAWNING)
If you're going
to be rude about me,
I'm going to switch you off.
And now, it's time
for Home Beautiful
with Professor D.P. Gumby
to give you some hints
on the often-forgotten art
of flower arranging.
-(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
-(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(APPLAUSE)
Good evening!
AUDIENCE: Good evening!
Tonight, flower arranging.
First, take a bunch
of flowers.
Mmm!
Pretty begonias.
Irises.
Freesias.
Chrysanthemum...
Mmm...
Mums, mums.
Then,
arrange them nicely in a vase.
Get in, get in, get in!
Oh, get in there.
Oh, get in, get in,
come on little flowers.
Oh, no.
No! No! My brain hurts!
MAN: Case adjourned.
Oh, I had a bitch of a morning
in the High Court.
-Oh, me too, love.
-(GROANS)
I could stamp me little feet,
the way those QCs carry on.
Oh, don't I know it, love?
-Objection here,
objection there.
-(CHUCKLES)
And that nice policeman
giving his evidence so well.
Beautiful speaking voice.
-And what a body.
-Yes.
Well, at the end
all I could do
was bang my gavel.
You what, love?
-I did me
"Silence in court" bit.
-Oh.
Oh, yes.
If looks could have killed,
that prosecuting counsel
-would have been
in for 40 years.
-(LAUGHS) Oh.
How did your summing up go?
(CROWD CHEERING)
Um...
I did it in me butch voice,
you know,
"What the jury
must understand,"
and they loved it
I bet they did.
I can see little foreman
of the jury eyeing me.
-Really?
-Oh, yes, cheeky devil.
-Made me want to turn
Queen's evidence. (CHUCKLES)
-Ooh!
I know what they mean
by a well-hung jury.
-Anyway, I finished up
really serious.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
"The actions
of these vicious men
are a violent stain
upon the community
and the full
penalty of the law
is scarcely sufficient
to deal with their
ghastly crimes,"
and I waggled me wig.
You waggled your what?
-I waggled me wig. Oh!
-Oh!
-Ever so slightly.
-Hmm.
-Stunning effect.
-I bet it was.
Anyway, (SNIFFLES)
I gave him three years.
Only took ten minutes.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Tell me, did you handle
the Cleese divorce?
(AUDIENCE MEMBER SHOUTS)
Which one?
He's had four wives.
Really?
Is he a Muslim?
No.
It's just the way he walks.
Oh.
Tell me, what do
you usually give
for sex in a public toilet?
(SIGHS)
About ten quid.
-Oh!
-Yeah.
-All in?
-Mmm.
Now, ladies and gents,
here it is,
the show you've been
waiting for,
the show you've heard
so much about.
This is the show
that gives you what you want
the way you like it,
-so move right up front
for Full Frontal Nudity
-(SCATTERED CLAPPING)
MAN: Stop the crap.
Get on with the show
Oh, yes. Ooh!
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, yes. Oh...
Oh...
Kevin, that's my seat.
MAN: What? Will you sit down?
-Get out of the way.
-Uh, excuse me.
MAN: (CHUCKLES)
Yeah, that's better. Mmm.
Yes.
Oh-oh! (CHUCKLES)
-Look at them. What?
-(BELL CLANGING)
Get your choc
ice cream, sweeties.
MAN: (GRUNTS) I'm not hungry.
Hmm. That's better.
-Oh, yes, here we go,
here we go.
-(BEEPS)
MAN ON PA:
Will the owner
of a Ford Cortina,
registration OYR 312...
MAN: Shut up.
MAN ON PA:
Please remove his vehicle?
MAN: Oh, and we're back.
-Oh, yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
-(TRAIN HOOTING)
-Ooh, yeah.
-(CARS HONKING)
(HONKING)
Oh, God, I'll have to
come back tomorrow.
Albatross!
(CHEERING)
Uh, two choc ices, please.
I haven't got any choc ices,
I've just got this albatross.
Albatross!
Uh, what flavour is it?
(STAMMERS) What? Well...
It's a bloody sea bird,
it's an albatross.
It's not any bloody flavour.
-Oh.
-Albatross!
Everything's got a flavour.
All right,
it's bloody sea bird flavour,
it's bloody albatross
bloody flavour.
Albatross!
Do you get wafers with it?
Course you don't get
fucking wafers with it!
It's an albatross!
You're disgusting.
You're not even
a proper woman.
Don't you oppress me, mate.
You should be ashamed
of yourself.
Racist!
-Racist!
-Whoa-whoa!
Racist!
Stormy petrel on a stick.
-Oh.
-Gannet in a basket.
(APPLAUSE)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Evening, squire.
Eh, good evening.
Is your wife a goer, eh?
Know what I mean,
know what I mean,
nudge, nudge,
know what I mean, say no more?
I beg your pardon?
Your wife, does she go, eh?
Does she, does she go, eh?
Well, she sometimes
has to go, yes.
I bet she does,
I bet she does, say no more,
say no more, know what I mean,
nudge, nudge.
Eh, I'm afraid
I don't quite follow you.
Ooh! Follow me, follow me,
that's very good, very good.
A nod's as good
as a wink to a blind bat.
Are you selling something?
Selling!
Very good, you're wicked,
you are.
You are a wicked one,
aren't you, eh, yeah?
You know what I mean?
Say no more, wicked, eh?
Say no more.
What?
Is your wife interested
in sport, eh?
Well, eh...
She likes sport, yes.
I bet she does,
I bet she does.
As a matter of fact,
she's very fond of cricket.
Oh! Likes games, eh?
She likes games.
I knew she would,
I knew she would.
She's been around a bit, eh?
Been around, been around, eh?
Well, she has travelled.
She's from Purley.
Whoa!
Purley? Say no more,
say no more,
say no more, say no more!
Well?
Is your wife interested
in photography?
Photography?
"Photographs, eh?",
he asked him knowingly.
Photography?
Snap, snap, grin, grin,
wink, wink,
nudge, nudge, say no more.
Oh, holiday snaps?
They could be, they could be
taken on holiday, you know?
Swimming costumes.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Dressing up.
(BOISTEROUS LAUGHTER
AND CHEERING)
Candid photography,
if you know what I mean,
you know?
Behind the scenes bit.
No, we don't have a camera.
Oh, still... Whoa, eh?
Whoa, eh? Whoa, eh?
Whoa...
Look, are you
insinuating something?
Oh, no! No! No!
Yes.
Well?
Well, I mean, you're a man
of the world, squire,
you know,
you've been around a bit,
you know, been around.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, like, you know,
you've... You've done it.
You've slept with a lady.
Yes.
What's it like?
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
♪ Blackmail! ♪
ERIC IDLE: Evening, squire.
Is your wife a goer, eh?
Know what I mean,
know what I mean,
nudge, nudge, say no more.
Does she, eh, does she go?
Oh, I bet she does.
♪ Oh, eh? Nudge, eh? Oh, eh? ♪
♪ Wink, wink, eh? ♪
♪ A nod's as good as a wink
to a blind bat ♪
♪ Say no more! ♪
♪ Nudge, nudge, wink, wink
Nudge, nudge, wink, wink ♪
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
♪ Nudge, nudge, wink, wink,
Nudge, nudge, wink, wink ♪
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
IDLE: ♪ Whoa, eh? Whoa, eh? ♪
♪ Whoa, eh? ♪
♪ Is your girlfriend
interested
in photography, eh? ♪
♪ Whoa, eh? ♪
♪ "Photographs, eh",
he asked him knowingly ♪
♪ Candid, you know,
candid photography, eh? ♪
♪ Say no more! ♪
♪ Snap, snap, grin, grin,
wink, wink, ♪
♪ Nudge, nudge, grin, grin,
that's better! ♪
♪ Nudge, nudge, wink, wink,
Nudge, nudge, wink, wink ♪
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
♪ Nudge, nudge, wink, wink,
Nudge, nudge, wink, wink ♪
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
IDLE: ♪ Whoa, eh? Whoa, eh? ♪
♪ Whoa, eh? ♪
ALL: ♪ Blackmail! ♪
♪ Blackmail! ♪
MICHAEL PALIN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Blackmail.
Live from the
Tower Backroom, Blackpool.
Please, welcome your host
for tonight,
here's Nobby.
♪ Blackmail ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
Hello and welcome
to Blackmail,
the show people
can't wait to be off.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
And first we go north
to Preston in Lancashire
and Mrs Betty Teal.
Now, Mrs Teal,
this is for £500,
and it's to stop us
revealing
-the name of your lover
in Bolton.
-Whoa!
So, Mrs Teal, £500
by tomorrow, please,
and your husband Trevor
and your lovely children
Diane, Janice
and little Juliette,
who's having a difficult time
in school at the moment,
need never know the name
of your lover in Bolton.
-(ORGAN PLAYING)
-Whoa ho!
What a hunk.
Now, a politician,
a freemason, an ex-guardsman
and a prominent supporter
of the English
folk dance movement.
Well, he's been getting into
a bit of a dance of his own.
On last week's program,
he had the chance
to pay up and hush it up,
but he thought he knew better.
Well, we've got news for him.
He thinks
he's at a crack addict's
conference in Broadstairs.
In fact, he's here backstage
at our Blackmail studios.
Bring him on!
Hey! Sir Norman Barry Castle.
Welcome to Blackmail.
Well, you elected
not to pay up,
so here you are now
in front of our
studio audience of 15,000,
our global audience
of fifty million,
paying the price
of our right
to know everything about you.
(ORGAN PLAYING)
Well, your career's in ruins,
but the good thing is
that your wife
is gonna stand by you
and she's here
in the studio tonight.
Is she with us?
Can we see her there?
-Oh, lovely, thank you.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Thank you for coming along.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-(KISSES)
Behind every strong man,
there's a stronger woman.
You bastard.
Well, that's what they all say
but he should have...
-kept it in his pants.
-ALL: Kept it in his pants.
Well, thank you, Sir Norman.
-Now it's telephone time,
so bring on the golden phone.
-(ORGAN PLAYING)
Last week, we showed you
this photograph
of three middle-aged
car enthusiasts
and asked them
to send in £30,000
to stop us revealing the name
of the two girls
from the garage,
the make of car
in which they did it
and the type of engine oil
they used
-for lubrication. Well...
(CHUCKLING)
-(CHEERING)
We've heard nothing from them,
so it's time to...
-fill in the puzzle!
-ALL: Fill in the puzzle!
Let's see more.
Okay, boys,
you're on Blackmail
and it's now £40,000 each.
Well, they're either
very brave or very rich.
Let's see which it is.
£400,000 now, unless we hear
from James or Richard or...
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello, hello.
Ah, hello, Jeremy, yeah,
how are you?
Yeah, yeah, I know.
I'm sure you didn't,
no, no, no.
We don't morally censure,
we just want the money.
If your check's in the mail,
you won't be
in The Daily Mail.
Thanks for playing Blackmail.
Thanks. (CHUCKLING)
You too, Jezza.
Lovely man.
-Deeply flawed.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
And, now,
what is it time for now,
Veronica?
I'm A Celebrity Or Am I?
Your chance to play the game
where we bring on
a mystery contestant
and you have to tell us
whether you think
he's a celebrity
or a mere non-entity,
so here he comes...
Celebrity or non-entity?
Let's start the clock.
(CLOCK TICKING)
The famous legs,
are those Simon Cowell's legs?
Are these legs you recognize?
Looks pretty ordinary to me.
Could just be an ordinary guy
off the street.
-Could be a celebrity.
-ALL: Five, four, three,
two, one.
Off with the bag. Oh, my God!
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-Oh, wow!
Oh...
International Man of Mystery
himself.
This is a great moment,
but Mike, Mike...
-Yes.
-We're both Mike
so I can Mike...
-Yes.
-I can Mike with you.
-You're on Blackmail...
-Yes.
What's gone wrong?
You mean, what's gone right?
-Oh, did I?
-I'm on stage with you, sir.
Oh, well, we want you
to confess, you know?
Because Blackmail,
we know
you've been in trouble,
so if there's anything
you wanna share
with the audience,
now's your time.
I wanna share how incredibly
honoured I am
to be on stage
with Monty Python,
the greatest comedy troupe
in the history
-of the English language.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Okay.
And...
There may be photographs
of me with German Shepherds.
Ah! Wow, yeah.
He's too nice a guy.
Thank you for coming
on the show, Mike.
Oh, that's it? Okay.
Thank you and thank you all,
girls, from Blackmail.
-See you next week! Okay!
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(BLACKMAIL TRACK PLAYING)
Good evening and welcome
to another edition
of Science Today,
where we look
at science today,
and today we have
with us Anne Elk,
Mrs Anne Elk.
-Miss.
-(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
-Miss Anne Elk.
-Miss. Yes.
Sorry.
Miss Elk,
you have a new theory
about the brontosaurus.
Can I just say at this point,
Chris,
that I have a new theory
about the brontosaurus?
Mmm-hmm.
Exactly.
-What is it?
-Where?
-Your new theory?
-Oh, oh, what is my theory?
-Yes.
-Oh, what is my theory
that it is.
Well, Chris,
you may well ask me
what is my theory.
-I am asking
what is your theory.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Well done, Chris.
-Thank you.
-Spot on.
My word, yes.
Well, Chris, eh, what is it,
that it is,
this theory of mine?
Well, this is what it is.
My theory, which belongs to me
and which I own, is mine.
Yes, I know it's yours,
but what is it?
-Where?
-Your theory.
-Oh, what is my theory?
-Yes.
Ah... This is it.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(COUGHING)
Here is my theory
and what it is, too.
(CLEARING THROAT AND COUGHING)
(PROLONGED COUGHING)
"My theory, by Anne Elk,
(COUGHING)
brackets, Miss, brackets..."
(CLEARING THROAT)
(PROLONGED COUGHING)
The next thing that I will say
will be my theory.
(COUGHING)
Here it comes.
(CLEARING THROAT)
You ready, Chris?
Yes.
My theory begins now.
(COUGHING)
All brontosauruses are thin
at one end
and then much thicker
in the middle
and then thin
at the far end again.
-That is my theory
and what it is,
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
-and it belongs to me too
and it's mine.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(MOUTHING)
-That's it, is it?
-Spot on, Chris.
Well, this theory of yours
certainly seems to have hit
the nail on the head.
Thank you, Chris, thank you.
-Next week sees the opening...
-Thank you very much.
-Of a new wasp...
-Thank you.
And thank you for asking me
to the studio.
You're very welcome.
-Next week sees
the opening of a...
-(CLEARING THROAT)
-of a new wasp farm
near Redditch...
-(COUGHING)
-That is going to...
Next week sees the opening...
I have another theory.
Really?
Called, "My Second Theory"
or "Miss Anne Elk,
bracket, Miss, second theory,
number two." (CLEARING THROAT)
-Would you like to hear it?
(CLEARING THROAT)
-Yes, all right.
(PROLONGED COUGHING)
(BREATHING IN DEEPLY)
(EXHALING)
My second theory states
that dentists can make
your teeth dance.
-Really?
-Look.
Yes, mothers,
it's time once again
for Conrad Poohs
and his dancing teeth.
(FARTING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
Trouble at mill.
Oh, no. What sort of trouble?
One of crossbeam's
gone out of skew on treadle.
Pardon?
One of crossbeam's
gone out of skew on treadle.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
One of the crossbeams has gone
out of askew on the treadle.
Well, what on earth
does that mean?
Well, I don't know.
Mr Wentworth just told me
to come in here
and say there was trouble
at mill, that's all.
I didn't expect a kind
of Spanish Inquisition.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
Our chief weapon is surprise,
surprise and fear.
Fear as well.
Our two weapons are fear
and surprise and ruthless...
Our three weapons are fear
and surprise
and ruthless efficiency
and an almost
fanatical devotion to...
Four, our four...
The... I'll come in again.
I didn't expect a kind
of Spanish Inquisition.
-(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
-Ha!
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
Amongst our weaponry
are such diverse elements as
fear, surprise,
ruthless efficiency,
an almost fanatical devotion
to the Pope
and nice red uniforms.
No, I can't do this,
I can't say this.
-You'll have to say it.
-What?
The bit about
our chief weapons. Ah!
I couldn't do that.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Nobody, um...
Expects.
Nobody expects the Spanish...
-Inquisition.
-I know, I know.
Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition.
-In fact, those...
-Our chief weapons are...
-Our chief weapons are, uh...
-Surprise.
-Surprise and...
-Stop there, stop there. Good.
Surprise, fear,
ruthless efficiency,
fanatical devotion
to the Pope.
-Cardinal Fang...
-Yes, love?
(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
Read the charges.
(SIGHING)
Eh, fourteen ducats
for a complete massage on...
No, no, no,
the charges against her.
Oh... (CHUCKLING)
(CLEARING THROAT)
You have hereby been charged
that you did on diverse dates
commit heresy against
the Holy Church
by word, thought and deed.
With full relief, 22 ducats...
Yeah, no, that's enough,
that's enough. So... Oh-ho...
How do you plead?
Innocent.
(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
-Innocent!
-Very well.
Cardinal Biggles...
Fetch the rack.
-(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
-(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
Eh, tie her to the rack.
(GROANS)
(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
So...
How do you plead?
-Innocent.
-(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
Cardinal,
give the rack a turn.
-I, uh...
-I know, I know you can't,
I didn't want to say anything,
I just wanted to ignore
your crass mistake.
-I, uh...
-It makes it all
seem so stupid.
Shall I, uh...
Just pretend,
pretend for God's sake.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
So, old woman, you are accused
of heresy on three counts.
Heresy by thought,
heresy by word,
heresy by deed
and heresy by action.
Four, four, four counts.
Do you...
confess?
I don't understand
what I'm accused of.
(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
Then we shall
make you understand.
Cardinal, take her
to the comfy chair.
-(LAUGHING SINISTERLY)
-(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
So you think
you can survive the rack.
You will not survive
the comfy chair.
So, old woman,
you have one last chance.
Confess the heinous sin
of heresy,
reject the works
of the ungodly...
Two, two last chances,
and you shall be...
Three, three last chances.
Confess.
-Confess. Confess.
I confess! (SOBBING)
No, not you.
Oh...
I have one last weapon
in my armoury.
If you do not talk...
I will show you...
the fridge.
Oh! Not the fridge!
Cardinal, go to the fridge
and get her...
a large glass of...
cold milk.
(LAUGHING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDS AND CHEERS)
♪ Whenever life gets you down,
Mrs Brown... ♪
♪ And things
seem hard or tough ♪
♪ And people are stupid,
obnoxious or daft ♪
♪ And you feel
that you've had quite enough ♪
♪ Just remember
that you're standing ♪
♪ On a planet that's evolving ♪
♪ And revolving
at 900 miles an hour ♪
♪ That's orbiting at 19 miles
a second, so it's reckoned ♪
♪ The sun that is the source
of all our power ♪
♪ The sun and you and me ♪
♪ And all the stars
that we can see ♪
♪ Are moving
at a million miles a day ♪
♪ In an outer spiral arm,
at 40,000 miles an hour ♪
♪ Of the galaxy
we call the Milky Way ♪
♪ Our galaxy itself
contains 500 billion stars ♪
♪ It's a hundred thousand
light years side to side ♪
♪ It bulges in the middle ♪
♪ Six thousand light
years thick ♪
♪ But out by us it's just
a thousand light years wide ♪
♪ We're 40,000 light years
from Galactic Central Point ♪
♪ We go round
every 200 million years ♪
♪ And our galaxy is only
one of millions and billions ♪
♪ In this amazing
and expanding universe ♪
♪ The universe itself keeps
on expanding and expanding ♪
♪ In all of the directions
it can whizz ♪
♪ As fast as it can go at the
speed of light you know ♪
♪ 12 million miles a minute ♪
♪ And that's the
fastest speed there is ♪
♪ So remember
when you're feeling
very small and insecure ♪
♪ How amazingly unlikely
is your birth ♪
♪ And pray that
there's intelligent life ♪
♪ Somewhere out in space ♪
♪ 'Cause there's bugger
all down here on earth ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Now there are many reasons why
I find that song
scientifically inaccurate.
It's pathetic really.
The statement that
the sun is the source
of all our power.
Well, take geothermal energy.
That comes from the heat
of the earth's core.
That's generated,
at least in part,
by the radioactive decay
of uranium.
Uranium was formed
in supernova explosions.
Then the statement
that the earth orbits
at 19 miles a second.
Well, that'd be okay
if the earth's orbit
was circular,
but in fact it's elliptical,
so it's better to say
that the earth sweeps out
equal areas in equal times.
Kepler knew that back in 1609.
Then the statement
that space time expands
at the speed of light.
Well, there was a period
of expansion,
exponential expansion
between 10 to the minus 36
and 10 to the minus 32 seconds
after the Big Bang
called inflation, in which...
(SCREAMING)
STEPHEN HAWKING:
I think you are
being pedantic.
♪ Just remember
that you're standing ♪
♪ On a planet that's evolving ♪
♪ And revolving
at 900 miles an hour ♪
♪ That's orbiting at 19 miles
a second, so it's reckoned ♪
♪ The sun that is the source
of all our power ♪
♪ The sun and you and me ♪
♪ And all the stars
that we can see ♪
♪ Are moving
at a million miles a day ♪
♪ In an outer spiral arm
at 400,000 miles an hour ♪
♪ In a galaxy we call
the Milky Way ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SHRIEKING)
(ALARM RINGING)
♪ Work, work, money, money
Work, work, money, money ♪
♪ Work, work, funny money
Funny money, work, work ♪
♪ Work, work, hurry, hurry
Work, work, worry, worry ♪
Worry hurry, work, work ♪
♪ Morning, morning, morning ♪
♪ Morning, Jill
Morning, Jack ♪
♪ Can't complain
keep coming back ♪
♪ Morning, morning, morning ♪
♪ Morning Jim
Morning, Fred ♪
♪ Work all day
until you're dead ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Money is the fruit of sin ♪
♪ Money is the root
of everything ♪
♪ Wear a suit,
they'll let you in ♪
♪ Morning, morning, morning ♪
♪ What's the point
and what's the use ♪
♪ Work until you reproduce ♪
♪ Boring, boring, boring ♪
♪ Work all day,
earn your bread ♪
♪ Till you finally
drop down dead ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Money is the fruit of sin ♪
♪ Money, money, money
can drive you mad ♪
♪ End up in the loony bin ♪
♪ Work, work, money, money
Work, work, money, money ♪
♪ Work, work, funny money
Funny money, work, work ♪
♪ Work, work, hurry, hurry
Work, work, worry, worry ♪
Worry hurry, work, work ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Money is the fruit of sin ♪
♪ Money is the root
of everything ♪
♪ Pay up or we'll do you in ♪
♪ Work hard every single day ♪
♪ Work, work,
work your life away ♪
♪ Don't question what,
Don't question why ♪
♪ Just keep working
till you die ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Money is the fruit of sin ♪
♪ Money is the root
of everything ♪
♪ The Grim Reaper's coming in ♪
♪ Life is a silly walk
in the park ♪
♪ A knife in your throat
held after dark ♪
♪ Life is a terrible joke,
a lark ♪
♪ A spoken word
then it all goes dark ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Money is the root of sin ♪
♪ Funny money loot
will make you rich ♪
♪ Life's a bitch
and you can't win ♪
♪ Money is the root of evil ♪
♪ Never, never question why ♪
♪ Money is the fruit of evil ♪
♪ Work all day until you die ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
-Oh!
-(CHUCKLES) Hello.
Good afternoon, sir.
Have you come for an argument?
Um...
Or would you like a blow job?
Pardon?
Ah, you've come
for an argument.
-(CHUCKLES)
-What was the other option?
-Oh, nothing... Nothing.
-Oh.
-It's just a special offer.
So have you been here before?
No, this is my first time.
-(CLEARS THROAT)
-I see. Well would you like
to have just one argument?
Or were you thinking
of taking a course?
Well, what is the cost?
It's one pound
for a five-minute argument,
but only eight pounds
for a course of ten.
Well, I think I'll take
the five minutes
and see how it goes
from there.
-Fine. Let's see.
-(CHUCKLES)
Uh, yes, try Mr Barnard.
Thank you. Thank you.
Such nice people.
-What do you want?
-Well I... I...
And don't give me that,
you snotty-faced heap
of parrot droppings.
Shut your festering gob,
you tit.
Your type makes me puke.
You vacuous, stuffy,
malodorous, old pervert.
Look, I came here
for an argument.
Oh, I'm sorry, this is abuse.
Oh.
Oh, you want next door.
Oh, I see. Thank you.
Not at all.
Stupid dick!
Hello. Is this the right room
for an argument?
I've told you once...
-No, you haven't.
-Yes, I have.
-When?
-Just now.
-No, you didn't. You didn't.
-Yes, I did.
-Yes, I did. Yes, I did.
-You didn't. You didn't.
Oh, I'm sorry. Is this
the five-minute argument
or the full half-hour?
-Oh, just the five minutes.
(CLEARS THROAT)
-Just the five minutes.
Thank you very much.
Anyway I did.
You most certainly did not.
Now, let's get one thing
absolutely clear.
I most definitely told you.
-No, you didn't.
-Yes, I did.
No, you didn't.
Look, this isn't an argument.
-Yes, it is.
-No, it isn't.
-Just contradiction.
You contradicted me just then.
You did...
I did not.
Never. No, no, no, no, no.
(SCOFFS)
This is futile.
No, it isn't.
Yes, it is.
I came here for
a good argument.
No, you didn't.
You came here for an argument.
But an argument
isn't just contradiction.
-Yes, it is.
-No, it isn't.
An argument is a connected
series of statements
intended to establish
a proposition.
Look, if I argue with you,
I must take up
a contrary position.
Yes, but that's
not just saying,
-"No, it isn't."
-Yes, it is.
-No, it isn't.
-No, it isn't, no, it isn't.
-Yes, yes, yes, yes, it is.
Argument
is an intellectual process.
Contradiction is just
the automatic gainsaying
of anything
the other person says.
-It is not.
-It is.
-Not at all.
-Now, look, I...
-(BELL DINGS)
-Thank you, good morning.
What? What?
That's it.
The five minutes is up.
That was never
five minutes just now.
-I'm afraid it was.
-No, it wasn't.
I'm sorry, I'm not allowed
to argue any more.
Oh, this is ridiculous.
If you want me
to go on arguing
you'll have to pay
for another five minutes.
-But that was never
five minutes just now.
-(WHISTLES)
Oh, this is ridiculous.
There you are.
-Ah, thank you very much.
Very good.
-(CLEARS THROAT)
Well?
What?
That was never
five minutes just now.
I told you, I'm not allowed
to argue unless you pay.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
-I just paid.
-No, you didn't.
-I did. I did. I did. I did.
-You did not. You did not.
Look, I don't want
to argue about that.
Well, I'm very sorry
but you didn't pay.
A-ha!
If I didn't pay,
why are you arguing?
Ha-ha! Got you.
-No, you haven't.
-Yes, I have.
If you're arguing
I must have paid.
Not necessarily.
I could be arguing
in my spare time.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ I've got two legs,
From my hips to the ground ♪
♪ And when I move them
They walk around ♪
♪ And when I lift 'em
They climb the stairs ♪
♪ And whoo! When I shave 'em
They ain't got hairs! ♪
♪ I've got two legs
with my feet... ♪
Oh, God! (GROANS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(BELL CHIMING)
-Good morning.
-Morning.
What have you got then?
Well, there's egg and Spam,
egg, bacon and Spam.
Egg, bacon, sausage and Spam.
Spam, bacon, sausage and Spam.
Spam egg. Spam,
Spam, bacon and Spam.
Spam, Spam, Spam,
egg and Spam.
Spam, baked beans,
Spam, Spam, and Spam.
Or lobster thermidor
aux crevettes
with a mornay sauce
garnished with truffle pate,
brandy and a fried egg on top,
and Spam.
Have you got anything
without Spam in it?
Well, there's Spam, egg,
sausage and Spam.
That's not got
much Spam in it.
I don't want any Spam.
Why can't she have egg, bacon,
Spam and sausage?
That's got Spam in it.
Yeah, but not as much as Spam,
egg, bacon, Spam and sausage.
Look. Can I just have
egg, bacon,
Spam and sausage,
without the Spam?
Ugh!
What do you mean..."ugh"?
You can't have egg, bacon,
Spam and sausage
without the Spam.
Why not?
Well, it wouldn't be
egg, bacon, Spam
and sausage, would it?
I don't like Spam.
Oh, don't make a fuss, dear.
I'll have your Spam,
I love it.
I'm having Spam, Spam,
Spam, Spam, Spam,
Spam, Spam, baked beans,
Spam and Spam.
-Baked beans are off.
-(GROANS) Oh.
Well can I have Spam instead?
You mean Spam,
Spam, Spam, Spam...
(CHORUS SINGING)
♪ Spam! Spam! Spam! Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely Spam!
Wonderful Spam! ♪
♪ Spam! Spam! Spam! Spam! ♪
-TERRY JONES: Shut up!
-(METAL CLANKING)
♪ Lovely Spam!
Wonderful Spam! ♪
Shut up!
♪ Lovely Spam!
Wonderful Spam! ♪
Shut up!
♪ Lovely Spam!
Wonderful Spam! ♪
Shut up!
Bloody Vikings!
Racist bastard.
(ALL SINGING)
♪ Finland, Finland, Finland ♪
♪ The country
where I quite want to be ♪
♪ Pony trekking or camping ♪
♪ Or just watching TV ♪
♪ Finland, Finland, Finland ♪
♪ That's the country for me ♪
♪ Spam! Spam! Spam! Spam! ♪
♪ Oh, Spam ♪
♪ Lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Oh, lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely Spam!
Wonderful Spam! ♪
♪ Lovely spam!
Wonderful spam! ♪
Wonderful spam... ♪
♪ Lovely Spam! ♪
♪ Spam! Spam! Spam! ♪
I wish to register
a complaint.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hello, miss.
What do you mean,
"miss"?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I have a cold.
(INHALES)
I wish to make a complaint...
Sorry, we're closed for lunch.
Never mind that...
I wish to
complain about this parrot
what I purchased
not half an hour ago
from this very boutique.
Oh, yes, the Norwegian Blue?
What's wrong with it?
I tell you
what's wrong with it.
It's dead!
That's what's wrong with it.
No, no. He's resting.
Look, my lad,
I know a dead parrot
when I see one.
And I'm looking
at one right now.
No, no, he's resting.
Remarkable bird,
the Norwegian Blue, isn't it?
Beautiful plumage.
The plumage
don't enter into it.
He's stone dead.
No, no.
He's resting.
All right then,
if he's resting,
I'll wake him up.
Hello, Mr Polly Parrot,
I've got a lovely fresh...
There, he moved.
No, he didn't,
that was you hitting the cage.
I never.
Hello, Polly!
This is your 9:00 o'clock
alarm call.
Wakey! Wakey!
Pfft!
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Where were we?
You say... "And now that's
what I call a dead parrot."
Now that's what I call
a dead parrot!
(APPLAUSE)
No, no.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-"No, no" I say. It's stunned!
-(CHUCKLES)
Stunned?
Yeah, stunned!
You stunned it
just as it was waking up,
Norwegian Blues stun easily.
Listen, my lad, I've...
(SNORTS)
I've had enough of this.
That parrot
is definitely deceased.
And when I purchased it,
not half an hour ago,
you assured me
that its total lack
of movement
was due to it being tired
and shagged out
following a prolonged squawk.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Well, he's probably pining
for the fjords.
Pining for the fjords?
What kind of talk is that?
Look, why did he fall
flat on his back
the moment I got him home?
The Norwegian Blue
prefers kipping on his back.
Remarkable bird, isn't it?
Beautiful plumage.
Look, matey,
I took the liberty
of examining that bird
when I got it home
and I discovered
the only reason
it had been sitting
on its perch
in the first place
was that it had been
nailed there.
Well, of course,
it were nailed there!
If I hadn't nailed
that bird down,
it would have muscled up
to those bars,
ripped them apart with its
immensely strong beak...
And "voom."
-"Voom?"
-"Voom."
Matey, this parrot
wouldn't "voom"
if you put 40,000 volts
through it.
It's bleeding demised!
No.
No, no, he's...
He's pining...
-He's not pining!
-(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
He's passed on.
This parrot is no more.
He has ceased to be.
He has expired
and gone to meet
Dr Chapman.
-This...
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
This is a late parrot...
It's a stiff, bereft of life.
It rests in peace.
If you hadn't nailed it
to the perch,
it would be pushing up
the daisies.
It's run down the curtain
and joined
the choir invisible.
It has breathed its last.
Its metabolic processes
are a matter of interest
only to Victorians.
-He has...
-(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
He has kicked the bucket.
This is an ex-parrot.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
-Well I'd better
replace it, then.
-(EXHALING)
I was listening
to the wireless
this morning...
Very interesting, apparently,
the editor of the Daily Mail,
Mr Paul Dacre
has just received
an arsehole transplant.
-Ah...
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Yeah.
(HOOTING)
I heard that...
I heard that too.
-The arsehole rejected him,
I hear.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
-Really?
-Yeah.
I've been round the back,
I've had a look...
We're right out of parrots.
I see, I see,
I get the picture...
But...
I have got a selection
of cheeses.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Amazingly enough.
A selection of cheeses?
-Yeah.
-Really?
What you have got?
You name it, I've got it.
Brie?
-No.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
-Camembert?
-No.
-Bresse bleu?
Stilton?
No.
-Lancashire cheese?
-No.
-Red Leicester?
-Double Gloucester?
-No.
Stinking Bishop?
-Don't you call me names.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
It's the name of a well-known
West Country cheese,
you should know that,
-you run a pet shop.
-Oh.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Caerphilly?
No.
You don't have any Caerphilly?
-Wensleydale?
-Yeah.
(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Well, I'll have a pound
of Wensleydale cheese, please.
Oh, sorry, I thought you were
talking to me. (LAUGHING)
That's my name,
Arthur Wensleydale.
(LAUGHING)
-Gruyere?
-No.
-Emmental?
-Jarlsberg?
-No.
Armenian String Cheese
with cumin seeds?
-Not much call for it
round here, squire.
-(LAUGHING)
Zimbabwean
rhinoceros milk cheese?
Cat's eaten it.
-Tell you what.
-What?
You haven't asked me
about Cheddar.
-Cheddar?
-Yeah, Cheddar.
You know...
Is it worth it?
-Could be.
-All right, I'm game.
Do you have...
Honestly expecting the answer
"No," any Cheddar?
No.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Do you want to come back
to my place?
-I thought he'd never ask.
-Oh.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(EXPLOSION)
(HOOTING)
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little...
(GNAWING AND CHOMPING)
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little...
(GNAWING AND CHOMPING)
(BURPING)
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little...
Wait a minute, buckaroos,
this has gone far enough.
-No, no, no.
-(CHOMPING)
Get it away. Get it away.
Get it away.
(TRUMPETS PLAYING)
(FLUTE PLAYING)
Good evening
ladies and gentlemen,
it's truly a real
honourable experience
to be here this evening.
A very wonderful and warm
and emotional moment
for all of us,
and I'd like to sing a song
for all of you.
(APPLAUDING)
♪ It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ All the children sing ♪
♪ Hark, hark,
those church bells ring ♪
♪ It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ The snow
falls from the sky ♪
♪ But it's nice and warm,
and everyone ♪
♪ Looks smart and wears a tie ♪
♪ It's Christmas
It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ Hip hip hip hip hip hooray ♪
♪ Every single day ♪
♪ Is Christmas day ♪
♪ It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ So welcome everyone ♪
♪ Every day is just the same ♪
♪ There's tons
and tons of fun ♪
♪ It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ You've won life's lottery ♪
♪ For heaven's
just like Vegas ♪
♪ And it's absolutely free ♪
♪ It's Christmas
It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ Hip hip hip hip hip hooray ♪
♪ Every single day ♪
♪ Is Christmas day ♪
♪ It's Christmas
It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ Hip hip hip hip hip hooray ♪
♪ Every single day ♪
♪ Is Christmas day ♪
Round number two!
♪ It's Christmas
It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ Hip hip hip hip hip hooray ♪
-♪ Every single day ♪
-(HOOTING)
♪ Is Christmas day ♪
♪ It's Christmas
It's Christmas in Heaven ♪
♪ Hip hip hip hip hip hooray ♪
♪ Every single day ♪
♪ Is Christmas day ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
BOISTEROUSLY)
(CHEERING CONTINUES
ENERGETICALLY)
Ladies and gentlemen,
eh, tonight this show
is going live
all around the world,
-amazingly enough.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Including North America,
South America,
Europe, Africa,
the Middle East,
Asia and Australia.
On TV and film,
so wherever you're watching,
would you please all join us,
all the way around the world,
in saying farewell to us
by singing this little ditty.
(GUITAR PLAYING)
♪ Some things in life are bad ♪
♪ They can really
Make you mad ♪
♪ Other things just make you
swear and curse ♪
♪ When you're chewing
on life's gristle ♪
♪ Don't grumble ♪
-♪ Give a whistle ♪
-(FLUTE PLAYING)
♪ And this'll help things
turn out for the best... ♪
♪ And... ♪
♪ Always look on
the bright side of life ♪
Come on!
♪ Always look on
the bright side of life ♪
♪ If life seems jolly rotten ♪
♪ There's something
you've forgotten ♪
♪ And that's to laugh
and smile
and dance and sing ♪
♪ When you're feeling
in the dumps ♪
♪ Don't be silly chumps ♪
♪ Just purse your lips
and whistle
That's the thing ♪
♪ And always look
on the bright side of life ♪
♪ Always look on
the bright side of life ♪
♪ For life is quite absurd ♪
♪ And death's the final word ♪
♪ You must always
face the curtain
with a bow ♪
♪ Forget about your sin
Give the audience a grin ♪
♪ Enjoy it,
it's your last chance anyhow ♪
♪ So always look on
The bright side of death ♪
♪ Just before you draw
your terminal breath ♪
♪ Life's a piece of shit
When you look at it ♪
♪ Life's a laugh
and death's a joke, it's true ♪
♪ You'll see it's all a show
Keep 'em laughing as you go ♪
♪ Just remember
that the last laugh is on you ♪
♪ And... Always look on
the bright side of life ♪
♪ Always look on
Key change, here we go!
the bright side of life ♪
♪ Always look on
Yeah!
the bright side of life ♪
♪ Always look on
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
BOISTEROUSLY)
Carol! Hey!
Thank you!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!
(THEME PLAYING)