[grunting]
[mimics gunshots]
Hey, Princess.
You looking at me? [shouts]
[woman over PA] All squadrons,
report to training area immediately
for evaluation.
-[whispers] Psst. Anyone seen Catra?
-[mumbles]
[scoffs] Not again.
At attention, cadets. Your simulation
is about to begin. Here's your scenario.
You'll be passing through
the treacherous Whispering Woods
to reach the heart of rebel insurgency,
Bright Moon.
Your mission is to defeat
the Queen of the Princesses
and liberate Bright Moon
in Lord Hordak's name.
-Where is Catra?
-She will be here. I promise.
Mm-hmm. The Whispering Woods
is full of princesses.
Vicious, violent instigators.
They will take you out if given
the chance. Don't give it to them.
Good luck, recruits.
-Watch out!
-Oh, no, no, no!
[shouting]
Come on, this way.
[growls]
[screams]
Aw, dang it.
-Seriously, Kyle?
-Bra-vo.
Seriously, Kyle?
Run!
-[Lonnie] Adora!
-[alarm beeping]
[gasps]
[all grunting]
[yells]
-[alarm beeps]
-[yells]
Hey, Adora. How's it hanging?
Catra.
Did you really show up late
and let us do all the hard parts?
That is low, even for you.
Aw.
You know nothing's too low for me.
[laughing]
Come on,
you look stupid hanging down there.
[woman over PA]
Training exercise successfully completed.
[laughing]
You should have seen your face.
You were like, "Aah, no! Betrayal."
Oh, come on, Catra.
We're senior cadets now.
I can't believe you're still pulling
such childish, immature-- Is that a mouse?
What? Where?
[laughing]
-Are you ever going to not fall for that?
-I don't know.
Are you ever going to let it go?
That was one time.
I know, but for some reason
it's always funny.
[Shadow Weaver] Adora.
Shadow Weaver.
[Shadow Weaver] You have done well.
You've completed your training course
in record time.
Uh, well, that wasn't just me.
You know, Catra did, too.
[Shadow Weaver] Ah, yes.
How someone as unmotivated as you
completed the course
in that time, I'll never know.
Always serving up those pep talks,
huh, Shadow Weaver?
Silence!
Do not be flippant with me, cadet.
-Sorry, Shadow Weaver.
-[Shadow Weaver] Adora, walk with me.
Adora.
Lord Hordak has been watching you.
He thinks you are a fine candidate
for Force Captain.
Really? Force Captain?
Lord Hordak said that about me?
[Shadow Weaver] Yes.
He sees great promise in you.
In fact, he has elected you
the honor of leading a squadron
in the invasion
of the rebel Fortress of Thaymor.
Thaymor?
You mean we're finally seeing active duty?
You are seeing active duty.
But I'll be able
to bring my team along, right?
Your team is not ready.
They'll only slow you down.
Shadow Weaver, with respect,
they've been training hard for this, too.
And Catra, all she wants
is to get out there and prove herself.
Then she should have worked harder
to prove herself to me.
This is what I raised you for, Adora.
Now is your chance
to prove yourself.
I saw talent in you the moment
I found you as an orphan child
and took you in.
Is this not what you've wanted since
you were old enough to want anything?
-Yes.
-With you at the forefront,
we will crush the Bright Moon Rebellion
once and for all.
Do not disappoint me.
[Angella] Send her in.
-Your Majesty.
-I'm told you disobeyed orders
and led the Rebellion into a dangerous
combat situation
after you were ordered to retreat.
I was trying to protect a village
from falling into the Horde's grasp.
You were reckless and put yourself
and the other rebels in danger.
Fighting is supposed to be dangerous!
How are we going to hold our own
against the Horde if we keep retreating?
Pretty soon, we won't have
anything left to defend.
I'm growing tired of your back-talking,
Commander Glimmer.
Why did you even make me a commander
if you won't let me fight?
That's enough! You're grounded!
-[scoffs] Mom!
-You heard me.
-You never let me do anything!
-We're not having this discussion tonight.
You are embarrassing me
in front of my royal court!
Oh, I'm embarrassing you?
Go to your room!
I'm going!
[sighs]
-[grunts]
-What'd she say? Hey, what's this?
Hey! Give it back.
No way. You've been promoted?
Well, kind of.
I mean, yeah, I guess. Heh.
-But it's not a big deal.
-Are you kidding? That is awesome.
We're gonna see the world and conquer it.
Adora, I need to blow something up.
[purring]
-Um...
-What?
Shadow Weaver says you're not coming.
What? My time was just as good
as yours today.
What is her problem with me?
I mean, you are kind of disrespectful.
Why should I respect her?
She's bitter that she doesn't have
any real power
that doesn't come from Hordak
and everyone knows it.
I guess it sure must be easy being
a people pleaser like you.
I am not a pe--
Catra, wait!
[sighs]
Look, I'm sorry.
I didn't even think you wanted
to be a Force Captain.
I don't. Here, take your stupid badge.
Come on, Catra.
This is what I have been working for
my entire life.
I was hoping you could be,
I don't know, happy for me.
Ugh, whatever. It's not like I even care.
I just wanna get out of this dump
at some point before I die of boredom.
I wonder what's even outside
the Fright Zone anyway.
Why don't we go find out?
[Catra] I take it all back.
You're officially awesome.
I can't believe
you actually stole a skiff.
Borrowed.
Please don't make me regret this.
I've always wanted to drive one
of these things. Here, give me.
Whoa, there.
Save us enough fuel to get back.
That is a problem
for future Adora and Catra.
-I'm driving.
-I want it.
[Catra] Can't have it!
[both shouting]
-Let me.
-Give me. I'm doing it.
-I want it.
-No, I've got it.
Catra!
What is it?
I think this must be the Whispering Woods.
They say there are strange,
old monsters in there,
and the trees move
when you're not looking.
Every Horde squadron they've sent in there
has never come out again.
Let's go in.
Wait, what? [yells]
[Catra] Woo-hoo!
[shouting, then laughing]
[both shouting]
Catra, slow down!
Catra, tree! Tree!
-[grunts]
-Adora!
[yelling]
[grunts]
[groaning]
Catra?
Huh?
Whoa.
Cool.
[gasps]
[female voice] Balance must be restored.
Etheria must seek a hero.
[baby crying]
Adora, Adora.
Hey, Adora?
Adora!
-Catra? What happened?
-You fell out of the skiff
-after you drove it into a tree.
-No, you drove it into a tree.
Ah, up for debate. Let's go.
-Wait. Where is it? Where'd it go?
-What?
There was a sword. It was right here.
I tried to touch it,
but it got really bright.
Are you brain damaged?
Don't be brain damaged.
Oh, Shadow Weaver's gonna kill me.
I'm not brain damaged.
It was here, I saw it.
Well, there's nothing here now.
So, come on, let's go.
[Glimmer] "Dear Mom,
I know you'll never read this,
but I have to say it somewhere.
I feel like you...
don't respect me."
[shrieks]
[groans]
Watch it! You almost hit me!
-Hey, Glimmer!
-Shh!
Bow, what are you doing here?
What did you say? Come down here!
I can't, I'm grounded.
What?
[whispering] I'm grounded.
-I'm... grounded.
-[shouts]
-[groans] I'm so mad at my mom.
-Is this about the siege on Elberon?
I was just trying to defend
another one of our villages
from falling into the Horde's clutches!
She stationed me all the way out there
because it's too remote
to ever get attacked,
but then it did, and it was my one chance
to prove that I can do this.
But she acts like I can't do anything
because I'm just a princess.
[grumbles]
That doesn't make any sense.
Everyone here is a princess.
I'm, like, the only one
who's not a princess.
[groans] Tell that to my mom.
-Hey, where does this go?
-Bottom drawer.
Anyway, your mom might have a point.
Only reason you got out of there
is because of your teleportation powers,
and, let's face it,
they don't always work that well.
Looking for support here, Bow!
I'm just saying,
if you wanna prove yourself,
it's gonna take more than running
recklessly into any old battle.
Luckily, I've got just the thing.
Check this out.
I detected a piece of First Ones tech
in the Whispering Woods.
A pretty powerful one, too,
by the size of these readings.
If you find this one and bring it back,
your mom is bound to be impressed.
Did you forget I'm grounded?
[knocking on door]
-[Angella] Glimmer? Are you in there?
-Uh...
Ah!
Glimmer?
Everything's fine, Mom.
Is someone else in there? I heard voices.
No one else is in here.
Can you leave me alone?
I don't appreciate your tone right now,
young lady.
-[Glimmer] What tone?
-That attitude is never gonna help you.
-You can't act that way--
-[Glimmer] That's not fair!
[door slams]
I'm in.
[all snoring]
[grunts]
[female voice] Adora.
Adora.
-Adora!
-[gasps]
-Hey, where are you going?
-Back to the woods.
-There's something I need to figure out.
-What? You're not--
[robot beeping]
What is wrong with you? You've been
acting weird since we got back.
Sure you're not brain damaged?
Look, Catra,
I know I saw something out there.
I just need to get another look.
It feels important somehow.
-Sounds good. Let's go.
-No.
I don't want you getting in trouble
on my behalf.
Just cover for me, okay? I'll be back
before anyone knows I'm gone.
Adora!
Come on, come on!
Ah, please. Tell me we're not lost.
No, this thing is acting up.
Looks like it's being overloaded
by the tech's signal.
We must be getting close!
Uh... I think it's that way.
What makes you say that?
Oh, yeah. That'll do it.
[Adora] What are you doing out here,
Adora? Catra's right, this is crazy.
There's no sword, you just got hit
on the head a little too hard.
You should go back home
and forget about all of this.
[Glimmer]
Bow, just let me lead the way, okay?
[Bow] The light came
from the edge of the forest.
-Yes, you saw the light. It's this way.
-The tracker pad says otherwise.
-It's this way-- [gasps]
-[gasps]
-Horde soldier!
-I see her!
[both yelling]
[gasps]
[grunting]
Bow, catch.
Give me the sword.
[yelling]
Get off.
Stand down. I don't wanna hurt you.
Since when do Horde soldiers
not want to hurt anyone?
[all grunting and shouting]
[Adora] What?
[female voice] Hello, Adora.
Who are you? What's going on?
My name is Light Hope.
I have been waiting a long time for you,
but I could not reach you until you forged
your connection with the sword.
-You sent the sword?
-The sword is meant for you.
Etheria has need of you, Adora.
Will you answer its call?
Will you fight for the honor of Grayskull?
What are you talking about?
What is-- What's Grayskull?
You're not making any sense!
I don't understand!
-You will.
-Wait!
[grunts]
[groaning]
Hey! She's awake.
-What happened?
-Quiet, Horde spy, I ask the questions.
How did you make it this far
into the Whispering Woods?
I just walked in.
And I'm not a spy.
Sure, sure. You just so happened
to find yourself in the Whispering Woods,
like you just so happened
to try and steal our sword.
It's not yours. I found it first.
The Whispering Woods
is under the Rebellion's protection.
You were lucky to make it
as far as you did.
Come on, Bow.
Let's get this spy back to Bright Moon
where she can be interrogated properly.
This is perfect.
Not only do we have First Ones tech
for the Rebellion,
we've also captured a Horde spy.
My mom's gonna be so impressed.
Now come on, on your feet.
[Bow] You positive we're going
the right way, Glimmer?
I know what I'm doing, Bow.
Can you please just trust me for once?
You know I always trust you,
but I'm starting to get
a little freaked out.
I mean,
I pretty much grew up in these woods,
and I've never even seen
this part of them.
I've heard stories
about weird stuff out here.
It's fine, okay?
Just let me figure this out.
Okay! Touchy.
Sorry about her.
Usually she's really nice.
Not much for talking, huh?
I prefer not to swap pleasantries
with my captors.
There. Suit yourself.
You know she's a princess, right?
How can you follow her?
Princesses are a dangerous threat
to everyone on Etheria.
-Is that what Hordak told you?
-I thought it was just common knowledge.
They're violent instigators who don't
even know how to control their powers.
[shouting]
You've never actually met a princess,
have you?
-Well, maybe not in person, but...
-[Glimmer whimpering]
-What happened to this place?
-Don't play dumb with me.
I bet you were part of the raiding party
that did this.
What are you talking about?
The Horde didn't do this.
Oh, yeah?
You're a heartless destroyer,
just like all the rest of your people.
I am not a destroyer.
Hordak says we're doing
what's best for Etheria.
We're trying to make things better.
More orderly.
This is what's best for Etheria?
Ever since the Horde got here,
they've been poisoning our land,
burning our cities,
destroying everything in their path.
And you're a part of it!
How's that for orderly?
This doesn't make any sense.
The Horde would never do
something like this.
Did you really not know any of this?
I mean, your army is called
the Evil Horde.
Who calls us that?
Everybody.
The Horde rescued me when I was a baby
and gave me a home.
They're my family.
You-- you don't know them like I do.
Maybe you don't know them
like you think you do.
[Glimmer shouting]
There's something out there.
Something big.
[Bow] How big?
[ground rumbling]
So, pretty big then.
[screeching]
Watch out!
[grunting and shouting]
[yelling]
[Glimmer yelling]
[Adora] Hey, bug brain!
Come on, Magic Sword.
Oh, where's a blinding flash of light
when you need one? [screams]
[Light Hope] Adora.
Adora.
[baby crying]
Will you fight for the honor of Grayskull?
[echoing] ...honor of Grayskull?
For the honor of Grayskull!