♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Glimmer?
Yeah, I see her, Bow.
Okay. I wanted to make sure
it wasn't just me.
[screams]
[panting]
Huh?
[both grunting]
-Stay where you are!
-What did you do to me?
What do you mean what did I do to you?
I didn't know
being a princess was contagious!
Okay, okay, everyone, calm down!
-Wanna tell us how you did that?
-I didn't do anything.
All I did was pick up the sword,
and then, woosh, I'm in a tiara!
I don't care how she did it.
Me just have to make sure
she never does it again!
[roaring]
[all shouting]
[roars]
Do it again!
Bow!
Do what you did before.
-I don't know what I did before!
-No time. We have to go.
[all grunting and shouting]
[all groaning]
What is this place?
No idea, but in there's gotta be better
than out here.
[grunting]
Everyone, grab on, I can get us in there!
Glimmer, no! You've never teleported
three people before.
-Do you have a better idea?
-[both gasp]
What's written on this door?
It looks like some kind of password.
You can read that?
You can't?
-What's it say?
-Uh, "Eternia."
Oh, come on!
So, Horde soldier, have you always
been able to read First Ones writing?
Wanna tell us what exactly
is going on here?
I told you I don't know.
I just read the word on the door.
Right...
[chuckles] You read a word in a language
that no one's spoken for a thousand years,
and the door just opened
into a mysterious ancient ruin.
Sure.
You think I did this on purpose?
You think I wanted to be a princess?
Princesses are monsters!
Monsters?
-You're the monster!
-Whoa, whoa.
-Glimmer, she did save us.
-I don't care!
We can't trust her, Bow.
Have you forgotten everything
the Horde's done to us?
The people we've lost.
[Glimmer sobbing]
We need to find another way out of here
and get her back to Bright Moon soon.
My mother will know what to do with her.
Hey, so, thanks for saving us
from that bug thing back there
-when you could've escaped instead.
-Okay, well, I didn't save you.
I wanted to get the sword, okay?
Are you sure it's not
because you secretly like us?
[chuckles] Wh--? I don't like you.
You're my captors.
Sure.
Thanks for saving us anyway.
I'm Bow, by the way.
Adora.
"Adora." Ah.
Weird name for a Horde soldier.
Is it?
[whispers] For the honor of Grayskull.
-What are we doing?
-Nothing! I mean, uh...
Look at these carvings.
I think this might be a First Ones ruin.
What's a First One?
You've never heard of the First Ones?
The First Ones
are the original settlers of Etheria.
They disappeared a thousand years ago,
but they left behind a lot of old ruins
and technology. Like this place.
So, what happened to them?
No one knows. They just disappeared.
The Horde didn't tell you about them?
Seems like there's a lot
the Horde didn't tell me.
Ugh. How do we get out of here?
[sighs] It'll take forever
to find a way out at this rate.
[gasps] Hey, you wanna turn on
some lights, Adora?
-I don't know how to do that.
-Maybe there's a magic word.
Ooh, what's the First Ones' word
for "lights"?
-I don't know. I'm not magic.
-[Glimmer] Obviously.
Everyone, stand back.
Uh, Glimmer?
Maybe you should take it easy.
We're a long way from Bright Moon.
It'll be a while until you can recharge.
-Bow!
-You have to recharge your powers?
Can we not talk about this
in front of the Horde soldier?
Now, stand back.
[grunting]
Whoa. [gasps]
-[Glimmer groans]
-Wow, are you okay?
I'm fine, Bow.
Oh, hey! That's you!
What?
That doesn't look anything like me.
No, I mean, the other you.
The scary one in the cape.
That was me?
You can read that inscription, right?
What's it say?
It says...
"She-Ra."
-[Light Hope] Greetings, administrator.
-What is this thing?
What is your query?
Think it's some kind of ancient hologram.
Uh...
Hi. What is this place?
How do we get out of here?
-What is your query?
-She's broken.
She's old. I'm surprised
any of this stuff still works at all.
Administrator not detected.
Lockdown initiated.
-I didn't do it!
-No. No lockdown!
-Adora, you gotta get it to stop!
-What makes you think I can?
-Query not recognized.
-There's gotta be a password or something!
Uh, stop it!
Uh, Eternia!
Eternia!
-Give me the sword.
-What? No!
We need the scary lady in the cape.
I don't know how,
but she's the key to this place,
so maybe she can get us out.
You're a Horde soldier.
I'm not giving you the sword.
[shouting]
Eternia!
Uh, cape!
Uh... She-Ra!
-Hold on!
-Glimmer, no!
[screaming]
Glimmer!
Glimmer?
[groans]
Did it work?
[chuckles]
Yeah, it worked. Barely.
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine. [groans]
I think I used too much power
getting us out of there.
I don't know who could've
predicted that... Oh, right. Me.
-Bow...
-Like an hour ago.
Bow!
Sorry. I'm just glad you're okay.
No more teleporting.
You could really hurt yourself.
I'm fine, okay?
Let's just get back to Bright Moon
so I can recharge already.
-Why are you still here?
-What?
Bow and I are hardly
a crack security team.
You could've escaped at any time.
Why didn't you?
I just-- I wanna figure out
what's happening to me,
and if I go back to the Fright Zone,
then I'll never know.
I never knew where I came from
or who my family was.
Shadow Weaver said it didn't matter
who I was before,
that I was nothing
before Hordak took me in.
There's always been a part of me
that I don't know anything about.
And all of this,
it feels familiar somehow.
I don't know how else to explain it.
Glimmer's mom knows more
about First Ones' tech than anyone.
She'll know what's going on
with you and the sword for sure.
So, if you want your questions answered,
stick with us?
Let's go. There should be a village
a few miles from here.
They'll be able to give us a ride
to Bright Moon.
We've wasted too much time already.
For the last time, where is Adora?
For the last time, I don't know.
You think I keep her on a leash?
I know you're lying.
You two are close. She would
never depart without telling you.
-Then I guess she let us both down, huh?
-Have it your way.
I already know where she is.
-We've been tracking her.
-Uh, then why did you ask me?
Because you are going
to bring her back.
I don't think so. [grunting]
Your insolence will not protect her.
You will do as I ask.
Oh, yeah? Or what?
Or you will suffer the consequences
in her place.
[chattering and laughing]
-Okay. The jacket comes off.
-That? Why?
Because if the villagers see
a Horde soldier, they'll freak out.
So, we gotta fix... all this.
I feel ridiculous.
That's because you need something
to tie it all together.
I don't like it.
The point is, you don't look
like a Horde soldier anymore.
Just try and keep a low profile.
We'll be in and out.
-What is this?
-It's a festival.
You know, like a big party.
You don't have parties
in the Fright Zone?
Oh, right, parties.
I mean, yeah, pfft, of course. I, uh--
I don't know what that is.
Ah!
Did you even hear what I just said?
In and out, Bow!
She has never been
to a party before, Glimmer.
This is serious.
[children cheering]
[all gasp]
[sighs]
So, seriously? No parties ever?
-What do you do on your birthday?
-Huh?
No birthdays?!
How is your life this sad?
[gasps]
What is that?
That would be a horse.
[neighs]
It's majestic.
-You wanna go meet it?
-What? No!
[whining]
Come on, it's okay. See, he likes you.
[gasps] This is the best day of my life.
-Bow...
-Come on, I know you like her, too.
[rumbling nearby]
[people screaming nearby]
What's going on?
It's the Horde!
Why are they here?
The people of Thaymor aren't a threat.
Wait. Did you say Thaymor?
This can't be Thaymor.
-Did you know about this?
-No. I mean,
yes, but there's a mistake.
Thaymor's supposed to be
a heavily fortified rebel fortress,
not a civilian town.
Do you really think that matters to them?
I can get them to stop.
This is a big mistake.
I just need to talk to them.
Get as many people out as you can
and don't let them see you.
I'm sorry.
Adora!
Stop!
-Adora!
-Catra?
They let me drive a tank.
Can you believe it?
Catra, I don't understand.
Why are you here?
Uh, duh, we came to find you.
"Cover for me, Catra.
No one will know I'm gone."
Seriously, did you
just immediately get captured
right after you snuck out or--?
What are you wearing?
Uh...
Bow!
[shouting]
Hey!
Look, there's no time.
We have to put a stop to this.
-What? Why?
-Because this is a civilian town.
Look around! These aren't insurgents,
they're innocent people!
Yeah, sure. Innocent people
who kidnapped a Horde officer.
Come on, let's get you back
to the Fright Zone.
Shadow Weaver is freaking out.
[laughing]
It'd be funny if she weren't
such a terrible person.
Catra, no.
I can't go back.
Not until the Horde
leaves this town alone.
You have to help me!
What are you saying?
I'm saying this is wrong.
They've been lying to us,
manipulating us.
Hordak, Shadow Weaver, all of them.
Duh. You just figured that out?
Manipulation is
Shadow Weaver's whole thing.
She's been messing with our heads
since we were kids.
How could you be okay with that?
Because. It doesn't matter what they do.
The two of us look out for each other.
And soon we'll be the ones
calling the shots.
Now, can we go home already?
[gasps]
I'm not going home, Catra. I can't.
Not after everything I've seen.
Come with me.
You don't have to go back there.
We can fix this.
Are you kidding?
You've known these people for,
what, a couple hours?
And now you're gonna throw everything away
for them?
Ugh. What happened to you?
I don't know.
But I have to do something.
I'm sorry, Catra.
[yells]
[Bow] I think that's all of them.
Glimmer, let's go!
-What are we gonna do?
-There's nothing we can do, Bow.
You're almost out of arrows,
and I'm almost out of magic.
You can't say that. You're Glimmer.
You throw yourself into every fight,
no matter how hopeless.
Ugh. Every decision I've made
in the last day
has almost gotten us killed.
My mom's right,
I'm not ready for this yet.
No. You are not giving up now.
I'm sorry your mom doesn't see
how strong you are, but that's her loss.
You can do this, Glimmer.
And you don't have to do it alone.
You're right.
-We need Adora.
-We do?
Didn't she just sell us out to the Horde?
I don't think she did.
We need to find her.
I think she can help us.
Just trust me.
Okay?
[horse neighing]
Oh, man.
That was a lot stronger than I thought.
Are you okay?
Catra! [yells]
I'm sorry! It was a reflex.
Why are you doing this?
Because you left me.
And if I don't bring you back,
Shadow Weaver's gonna have my head.
So enough
with your weird little identity crisis
and let's go home already.
Or do I need to zap you again? [shrieks]
Glimmer?
[growls]
[grunting]
-Watch out!
-[shouting]
Adora!
[yells]
[groans]
Glimmer? What are you doing?
Why did you save me?
We need you.
We need She-Ra. I should've given
this back to you in the ruin.
You could've saved us there
and I knew that. But I was stupid.
And a jerk, and I almost got us killed,
and I'm sorry.
You're not. I'm the Horde soldier.
How do you know you can trust me now?
I don't. But I hope I can.
I feel like maybe you're here to help us.
For the honor of Grayskull!
[grunting]
[neighing]
It's been an honor
serving beside you, Horsey.
Bow! Are you okay?
Is that Adora?
It's She-Ra.
[officer] Retreat!
[all screaming]
Catra.
You did it.
I did?
You saved us. You saved everyone.
[chuckles] I did it.
I turned against the Horde!
I turned against the Horde.
Why did I do that? I can't go back now.
Where am I supposed to go?
Hey, hey.
It's okay. You're with us now.
So, come on, let's go home.
Best-friends squad!
[horse neighs]
Wait, whose horse was this?