-Hey, we made it.
-[Adora] Whoa.
Welcome to Bright Moon.
[birds chirping
It's so beautiful.
Okay. I just need to go in there,
recharge and deal with my mom.
[groans]
This'll be fun.
Uh, Bow?
Maybe you should take Adora
in the back way?
Oh, yeah. Good call.
What's the back way?
This is the back way?
It might seem weird, but we
totally come in this way all the time.
Oh! Hey, here.
Why don't you put this robe on?
-No reason.
-You're trying to hide me.
What? No!
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[Angella] Glimmer!
-Where have you been?
-Hey, Mom.
All of Bright Moon has been worried sick.
-What were you thinking?
-Mom!
How could you be so selfish
and disobedient?
[groans]
[gasps] Glimmer.
[groaning]
Are you all right?
-I'm fine, Mom.
-Don't think you're not still in trouble.
You didn't even take the time
to charge up before you left?
I didn't think I'd be gone that long.
-Where did you go, anyway?
-Okay.
Bow and I found a piece of super powerful
First Ones tech in the woods.
We knew it would help the Rebellion,
so we went to get it and bring it back,
but we got a little sidetracked.
It was fine though,
I totally had it under control.
And while we were out,
we found something even better!
What did you find?
I can't tell you yet.
But you're gonna love it. I promise!
-Glimmer.
-Ah! Wait here, I'll be right back.
We are not done talking about this,
Glimmer. Glimmer!
Okay, I get it.
I'm guessing the people of Bright Moon
are gonna be less welcoming
of a Horde soldier
than you led me to believe.
-Maybe a little.
-How little?
-Think pitchforks and torches.
-[groans]
It's just that the people of Bright Moon
have been really hurt by the Horde.
Everyone here has lost someone in the war.
You can't blame them
for being a little suspicious.
Sorry.
Hey, it's not your fault.
Once they get to know you,
the people of Bright Moon
are going to trust you
just like Glimmer and I already--
[shrieks]
I'm here! Okay,
my mom's on her way, but no one panic.
-What?
-I said no one panic!
Don't worry, she'll love you.
All you have to do is use the sword
to transform into She-Ra
before she gets here.
Wait, we're jumping straight to She-Ra
with your mom?
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
My mom isn't going to buy,
"Hey, Mom, we found a Horde soldier.
Can we keep her?"
My mom is gonna love She-Ra.
We can ease her
into the Horde stuff later.
Uh, Glimmer, look. I don't know
if I can just turn on She-Ra.
I've only done it when someone was
in danger before,
and it felt a little
out of control last time.
I'm still figuring out
how all of this stuff works.
How hard can it be?
Sword, magic words, poof! She-Ra.
Hey. You're gonna do great, okay?
Bow and I will go buy you some time.
Just hang out here with the sword
and think She-Ra thoughts.
-I believe in you.
-[grunts]
Right. Okay, sword,
it's just you and me now. So...
Let's do this. [chuckles]
For the honor of Gray-- [shouting]
[groans]
[horse neighs, Adora gasps]
Horsey!
Oh! This is much better.
There's actually room to move around here.
Ready to see something cool?
For the honor of Grayskull!
Okay, let's try that again.
[whinnies]
[sighs]
[in deep voice]
For the honor of Grayskull!
[in normal voice]
[whispers] For the honor of Grayskull.
For the honor of Grayskull. [grunts]
-Honor of Grayskull, blah, blah, blah.
-[horse blusters, neighs]
Come on! Glimmer's counting on me.
Don't leave me hanging here.
For the honor of Grayskull!
Horsey, no!
Okay.
[neighing]
Horsey, it's okay!
[crowd shouting]
No! No, wait!
Horsey!
Stop!
Come back!
[woman] Horde soldier.
[chattering]
Horde soldier!
Wait, you don't understand. Stop!
I'm not with the Horde! Just listen!
[grunting and shouting]
[woman 1] Go! Get her!
-[woman 2] Don't let her get away!
-Move!
[yells]
[panting]
For the last time.
What is this grand surprise
that I'm supposed to be so impressed with?
You'll see it in just a minute,
Mom, I promise.
Bow, can you go check and make sure
that the surprise is ready for us?
You got it, Princess.
-I like that boy.
-I know you do, Mom.
You'll like this surprise even more.
[chuckles]
-So... problem.
-What?
[woman] Your Majesty.
A Horde spy has been discovered
on the Bright Moon grounds.
She attacked our troops with a sword
and then fled
with the help of a winged beast.
What did you do?!
[Lonnie] I'm telling you.
This new princess is no joke.
She wiped the floor with our recon squad.
Twelve feet tall at least!
Took out every one of our machines
with nothing but a sword.
-Did you actually see her?
-No. And it's a good thing, too.
-We were lucky to get out of there alive.
-Oh, please.
She's like every other princess:
All sparkle, no substance.
She caught us off-guard. That is all.
Sure. You were the only one
who saw her up close,
and you didn't even land a hit on her.
-What? Did you freeze up?
-[growls]
You think I'm scared of some princess?
I could take her out whenever I want.
I know her secret.
-[scoffs] Oh, yeah?
-[grunts]
And what's that?
[growling]
Hmm. Like I'd tell you.
Easy, Catra.
Adora's not here to protect you anymore.
[panting]
Stupid. You just had to go out there,
even after Bow warned you
about the pitchforks and torches.
[sighs]
[scoffs] What do you want from me now?
Haven't I done enough for you?
For the honor of Grayskull.
[sighs]
-What's wrong with you?
-[metal clanging nearby]
Horsey, is that you?
[humming]
Did you hear something?
Yes, I did, too.
Who's there?!
I, uh, didn't mean to intrude.
Um, but have you seen
a flying horse around here?
Oh, Mara, dearie, is that you?
About time you got here. Come on now,
no time to waste. Let's get going.
Uh, you were waiting for me?
[laughs] We made plans
to go berry-picking today.
I'm sorry, but I think you've mistaken me
for someone else.
I don't know who you are.
No, you don't know Madame Razz,
do you?
You're not quite the same.
This is the wrong time for my Mara,
isn't it?
Now you've got the sword instead.
Wait, what?
Ha! Well, never mind.
You're here now,
and there's berries to be picked.
[Adora] Hey, uh,
you've said something about the sword.
Have you seen it before?
[Razz chuckles]
Don't ask such silly questions, Mara.
You know you bring that sword around here
all the time.
I'm not-- Okay.
How long have you been living
out here in the woods alone?
Alone? Me?
Oh, no. I'm not alone.
I've got Broom here,
and my friend Loo-Kee too,
but he's always hiding.
[chuckles]
[chuckles nervously]
Oh, good, she's got imaginary friends.
Whoa.
Ah! Here we are.
I think I've seen a place
like this before.
This is a First Ones ruin, isn't it?
And the best place to pick fresh berries!
Hey, be careful up there!
That thing's not safe.
[grunting]
[yells]
[chuckles] Oh, dearie me.
That was quite a tumble, eh?
Stars?
Oh. We used to come here
to look at the stars.
Do you remember, Mara?
They're all gone now.
What happened to the stars?
I've seen them before.
I know all of this somehow.
[baby giggling]
What is this?
What's happening to me?
Look, I know you brought me here
for a reason.
If you know something about the sword,
about me, you need to tell me!
I brought you here to pick berries,
and your basket's still empty.
So, come on, silly.
Whoa!
[grunts]
[shouting]
-[Shadow Weaver] Catra!
-What do you want?
Impertinent as always, I see.
With such a grand failure under your belt,
it would benefit you
to show more respect, cadet.
I did what you told me to do.
You are the one who didn't warn us
there would be princesses there.
I gave you a simple task:
bring back Adora.
Instead, your squadron is ravaged,
your war machines destroyed,
and Adora is still missing.
News flash, old lady, if Adora wanted
to come home, she'd be here right now.
Adora's gone. She defected.
And I'm starting to think
she had the right idea.
So maybe it's you who should be showing
a little more respect to me.
[Shadow Weaver] Lies!
I am out of patience
to address your incompetence
and your insubordination, cadet.
You will answer to a higher power,
Lord Hordak himself.
[grumbles] Wait! Will you slow down?
Eh? What's that, dearie?
I don't have my glasses,
you'll have to speak up.
Oh, I know you can hear me. I just--
I need you to tell me what to do!
[laughing] How would Madame Razz know
what you should do?
Look, I left my whole life behind,
looking for answers
about where I came from
and who I'm supposed to be.
The Rebellion hates me,
and I can't go back to the Horde.
And I wanna do the right thing,
but I don't know what that is.
[gasps]
Ah. It's the same old story, dearie.
Wicked people destroy
what they cannot control.
They can't just do this.
Once, the princesses would have
protected us.
But these days, they--
they stay in their castles,
protecting only their own lands.
Meanwhile, the Horde creeps ever closer.
You're very like my Mara, you know?
Brave, loyal, but afraid.
I'm not afraid.
Dearie... [chuckles]
you ran into the woods
and asked the first old lady
you could find what you should do.
No one is going
to make this easy for you, dearie.
Stop waiting for someone
to tell you what the right thing to do is.
You're a smart girl.
What do you think?
I think... this is wrong.
[horse neighing]
-Horsey.
-Huh?
For the honor of Grayskull.
Keep those lines taut.
[grunts]
[neighing]
Turn off your machines
and leave this place now!
It's the Princess. Get her!
[grunting and shouting]
Huh? Uh...
That's my girl.
[laughs]
She-Ra!
Take that, you great lump!
Razzle Dazzle!
Razz, no! You can't be here.
[neighs]
Woo-hoo!
Mara, dear.
Yeah!
[Horde soldiers shouting]
Razzle Dazzle!
[horse whinnies]
Hello, dearie.
Ow.
Swift Wind and I have been talking
while you were asleep.
He thanks you for coming to his rescue.
-Swift Wind?
-That's what he prefers to be called.
Also, he wanted me to make sure
that you know
that "Horsey" was a stupid name.
-How do you feel?
-I'm... I'm okay.
I think I know what I need to do.
If the princesses won't defend Etheria,
then I will.
-I need to get back to Bright Moon.
-Ah, that's the spirit, dearie.
-Will I see you again?
-If you need me,
you will always know where to find me.
Who was that girl?
Um... Any chance I can get a ride back
to Bright Moon, Swift Wind?
Please?
[whinnies]
[laughing]
[Swift Wind neighing]
[Adora] Woo-hoo! [laughs]
[Angella] How could you possibly think
this was acceptable?!
[Glimmer] Mom, you don't understand.
You're not listening!
[Angella] You've shown
remarkably poor judgment!
Allowing a Horde soldier into Bright Moon
without telling me?
Your Majesty, it's not all her fault.
Bow, I think it is time you went home.
Glimmer and I have a lot to discuss.
Mom!
[all gasp]
-It can't be.
-I was trying to tell you. Mom, meet--
She-Ra.
Your Majesty, I've come to pledge myself
to the Rebellion.
But first,
there's something you should know.
[all gasp]
-[woman] She's a Horde soldier.
-Mom, this is Adora.
I know you have no reason to trust me,
Your Majesty.
But I've seen for myself the atrocities
the Horde has committed
against the people of Etheria,
and I'm ready to fight to stop them.
If you give me the chance,
I know I can help the Rebellion
turn the tide of the war.
[Angella] I know the legend of the warrior
the First Ones called She-Ra.
They said she would return to us
in the hour of our greatest need
to bring balance to Etheria.
I never thought
she was anything more than a myth.
And yet you're here now.
And in the uniform
of a Horde soldier, no less.
You would pledge to stand with us
against those you once served?
[sighs] Yes.
Glimmer, you would vouch for her
and take responsibility for her?
Yes.
Then rise.
The Rebellion accepts your allegiance,
She-Ra, Princess of Power.
[all chanting] She-Ra! She-Ra! She-Ra!
-[shouts] Welcome to Bright Moon!
-But for real this time.
[squeaking]
Lord Hordak.
Kneel!
I gave her charge of a simple mission:
To return Force Captain Adora
to the Fright Zone.
Instead, our forces suffered
a humiliating defeat.
[Hordak] Then you mean to tell me
you're still down a Force Captain?
Yes, my lord. But rest assured,
nothing will stop us from finding Adora
and bringing her back.
[Hordak] No. You will elect
another Force Captain
and resume normal operations.
[Shadow Weaver] But, my lord,
Adora is the only viable candidate.
[Hordak] You have Catra.
Was she not your ward as well?
[Shadow Weaver] Catra has been
nothing but a disappointment to me.
[Hordak] If you have failed
to condition her properly,
you have no one but yourself to blame.
-[Shadow Weaver] But, my lord--
-[Hordak] Enough.
I have made my decision.
Rise, Force Captain Catra.
Hmm.