This is awesome!
I can't believe Mom agreed
to let you stay in Bright Moon.
[guards whispering]
Yeah, awesome.
Okay. You've seen the dining hall,
the throne room, the portrait hall.
So, the last stop on our grand tour
is your new room!
Ta-da!
[gasps]
Pretty standard. You got your vanity,
bathroom, crystals, bell pull,
tea nook, more crystals, bed, desk,
and, of course, the waterfall.
-Is the waterfall for showering?
-Ha! Good one, Adora.
"Waterfall for showering." [laughs]
I'm right down the hall
if you need anything. Night.
-Wait--
-[door closes]
Okay. This is different
than the Fright Zone,
but I'm sure I'll get the hang of this
in no time.
[grunts]
Help.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[Adora grunting]
Come on, get flatter!
No! Go back in, go back in!
[shouting]
[whispering] Glimmer? Glimmer?
I think I killed the bed. [shrieks]
[in normal voice]
Ma'am! I mean, Your Majesty. Sir!
[coughs]
So, uh... what are you doing up?
When I feel the cares of the day
weighing upon me, I come here.
-[Adora] Who is that?
-King Micah. My husband.
He built the Rebellion with me.
And he was one of the first casualties
of the Horde.
-Sorry. I didn't know.
-Adora.
My daughter believes you can help us.
Glimmer has vouched for you
despite your background.
And because I greatly love my daughter,
I'm willing to give you a chance.
Do not disappoint her.
[Glimmer snoring]
[yawning]
[both screaming]
[grunts]
-[gasps] Glimmer! Are you okay?
-What are you doing in here?
[sighs] I'm sorry.
I couldn't sleep in my room.
I've never slept
without any other people around before.
And then I ran into your mom,
I think she doesn't like me.
-What? My mom loves you.
-Yeah, sure. She loves She-Ra.
Mom can be a little intense, heh.
But our weekly meeting
with the Rebellion Generals is today.
And you're invited. She wouldn't
have invited you if she didn't like you.
Wow. Heh.
-Come on. Meeting's about to start.
-Uh, the chairs are still empty.
Those are for other Etherian Princesses.
But none of them have been active members
of the Rebellion since I was a kid.
The Rebellion had a big defeat years ago,
and most of the old princesses gave up.
Now all the kingdoms keep to themselves.
And the new princesses do the same.
Other than Spinnerella and Netossa.
Hey, guys!
[whispers]
We're not really sure what they do.
Ah.
[gasping]
What? What? I don't understand.
This is not your chair.
Sorry, first day. Won't happen again.
-What did I do?
-You sat in my dad's chair.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I've asked you here because I received
a distress call from Princess Perfuma.
The Horde is laying siege to her kingdom.
She's asking Bright Moon
for assistance. General?
Perfuma's kingdom, Plumeria,
is located near the front lines.
The Horde has set up camp
in her territory,
cutting off their main supply route.
Bright Moon will provide food
and humanitarian aid.
-I have a better idea. We--
-Fight the Horde?
Glimmer, you propose this idea
every meeting.
No! I was gonna say let's use
aggressive fist-to-face sparkles.
I said, no, Glimmer. Now sit down.
[sighs]
You should send me, Glimmer,
and Bow to lead the relief mission.
Send me as She-Ra.
I'll make sure everyone gets there safely
and protect Bow and Glimmer
if the Horde attacks.
I promise, I won't disappoint you.
[sighs] Very well.
You will deliver food and supplies
to Plumeria.
And under no circumstances
will you engage the Horde.
You leave at dawn.
[shouts] I give up! I give up!
[grunts] Quit playing around, Kyle!
-Where's Catra? She's supposed to be here.
-Not anymore, cadet Lonnie.
-Why aren't you dressed?
-[Kyle shouting]
Oh, Lonnie, Lonnie, sweet dumb Lonnie.
They made you Force Captain?
Congrats, Catra!
[shouting]
Hordak knows a good thing when he sees it.
Now that I'm in charge,
Shadow Weaver won't be the only one...
Uh...
[Kyle grunts]
What do you need, Shadow Weaver?
Ooh, are you giving me my first mission?
You will explain
how you lost Force Captain Adora.
Ugh. I've told you everything I know
about Adora!
I know you're lying. You have to be lying.
What happened to Adora? What did you do?
What did I do?
She left us! She left me!
You ever think Adora's not as loyal
as you thought?
I will learn the truth, Catra,
even if I have to drag it...
[Shadow Weaver shouting]
Out of my way!
[children laughing]
Wow. Mom didn't say anything
about all the plants dying.
I don't think she knows.
Wait, where's Adora?
[grunts]
Are you going to be She-Ra
the entire time we're here?
I told Queen Angella I would.
Besides, people like me better as She-Ra.
[chuckles] Could Adora do this?
[grunting]
Hmm. Yep. Very useful to our mission.
Hey, guys. What is that?
-Must be coming from the Horde camp.
-You're here!
Princess Perfuma. I'm Commander Glimmer.
Ooh, I get a hat.
[gasps]
Oh, my. Everyone, come quick! It's...
Oh, it's...
It's... [shouts]
Look! The universe has heard our pleas
and sent the legendary She-Ra
to help us save our home.
[clears throat]
We've heard about the blockade
and we've come to help.
We brought food and supplies for you.
[whimpers]
Welcome to Plumeria, She-Ra.
Um, Glimmer, what's happening?
Come with me, I'll show you around.
You're gonna love it.
[baby cooing]
Our people have lived here
in tranquility for thousands of years.
We're known for our beautiful flowers,
our majestic trees.
And this is the Heart-Blossom,
the center of our kingdom,
and the source of all my magical powers.
At least this tree is fine.
What happened to everything else?
We're going through a little rough patch,
but I'm sure the universe
will right itself soon.
Everything is dead or dying.
Look, the blight hit
right after the Horde arrived.
We don't know why,
and nothing I do stops it.
Be we don't dwell on the negative.
Look at the positive.
The Heart-Blossom's still healthy,
and the She-Ra is here,
and the celebration's about to begin!
Celebration? [grunts]
[groaning]
[Shadow Weaver] You will not refuse me!
-[Hordak] Shadow Weaver.
-Lord Hordak!
You have disobeyed my orders.
I've done no such thing, Lord Hordak.
My will is your will.
Then explain to me
why you've requisitioned more troops
to look for one missing soldier.
A soldier I ordered you to give up on.
Finding Adora is crucial to the Horde's--
Our mission
is to kill the Whispering Woods
so we can finally march on Bright Moon.
Our mission is to destroy the princesses
and their ridiculous Rebellion.
You are distracted, Shadow Weaver.
Our ground troops
demand your full attention.
The siege on Plumeria
has carried on for too long.
You will give the order to increase power
until victory is achieved.
And never forget,
I gave you your magical power
and at my slightest whim,
I can take it away.
Understand?
Of course, Lord Hordak.
[yells]
No, it's okay.
You need this food more than we do.
Nonsense.
It is our honor to serve the She-Ra.
We are so honored to have you.
-Whoa. That's She-Ra!
-I know. The She-Ra, right?
I'm so happy that
after all these centuries of being gone
you've finally returned.
I said break out the party kale.
And at our hour of greatest need,
just like in the stories.
What stories?
The stories we've been telling
for thousands of years.
She-Ra, the warrior who tamed the beasts
of Beast Island with a single word.
That's nothing.
What about the time She-Ra defeated
a squad of Horde soldiers
on a flying horse?
Or the time she saved Thaymor
from a legion of Horde soldiers?
Or the time she borrowed my toothbrush
and used it to defeat
an army of Horde soldiers.
-Bow, that's not true.
-You're right. It was two armies!
[all cheering]
Hey, calm down!
Give her some space.
One at a time. You first.
-Oh! Thank you for the...
-Windchime.
-[explosion nearby]
We're so excited for you to heal our land
and bring all the plants back to life.
Will you be doing it
before the drum circle or after?
-You want me to heal your land?
-Yes!
Like in the ancient story,
"She-Ra Heals The Forest
And Brings The Trees Back To Life."
I've seen her do way weirder stuff.
This'll be a snap.
Wait, it's not that simple.
Plus, I don't like the look of that smoke.
The Horde's up to something big.
We should investigate.
We?
This is my power.
I grow plants.
We're not strong enough
to go up against the Horde.
All we want is to live peacefully
in our ancestral home.
-And then She-Ra saved the day once again!
-[children laugh]
We need you, She-Ra.
[all chanting] She-Ra! She-Ra! She-Ra!
Yes, healing. That is a thing
I know how to do.
I just need to take Bow and Glimmer
over to those trees for a moment.
I know what I'm doing!
I don't know what I'm doing.
I can't heal anything!
But the stories say
you have healing powers.
They also say I fought the Mantisaur.
I don't even know what that is.
Why don't you just concentrate
really hard?
That seems to work
whenever you need to transform.
Okay.
[grunting]
-Did I do it?
-No, you punched a tree.
-That's kind of the opposite of healing.
-Let me try again. [chuckles]
-[grunts]
-[shrieks]
-Magic blast. Also not healing.
-I'll get it this time.
[grunts]
[screeches]
-Magical transformation?
-Wait, is that what happened to our horse?
[grunting]
[thudding]
It's okay. You'll get it soon.
Soon isn't good enough!
These people expect me to save their land.
I thought I was better as She-Ra,
but I'm useless
no matter what form I take.
[explosion nearby]
-My hat!
-[Perfuma] She-Ra!
Come quickly! Something
absolutely terrible has happened!
The Heart-Blossom is dying.
Please, She-Ra, heal our land.
Oh, come on, do something.
[She-Ra grunting]
No.
-[sighs]
-[all gasping]
-Sorry. I don't know how to heal.
-Who are you? Where's She-Ra?
My name's Adora. I was chosen
to carry the sword of She-Ra,
but I haven't been doing this
for very long, and...
I don't know exactly how it works yet.
She's just a girl!
I never meant to deceive you.
I am She-Ra, I'm just not the same She-Ra.
Then you can't save us?
-[explosion nearby]
-[all gasping]
[all crying]
[Adora] Wait. There might be another way.
I know the Horde. I think they're using
one of their machines to poison your land.
If we wanna save your home,
we have to stop them!
You're not the She-Ra from the stories.
-You were supposed to save us.
-It will be all right. I promise.
We'll rebuild.
We have to believe the universe
will repay the Horde
for their evil deeds eventually.
The universe won't protect you!
You want She-Ra to fix everything,
but won't even try to save yourselves?
At least Adora's trying.
If She-Ra can't save us, no one can.
Right now, we just need to make sure
our people are safe. We leave today.
-Are you okay?
-I just wanted to help.
But all I've done
is disappoint an entire kingdom.
I'm sorry I let you guys down
after you talked me up.
We just wanted everyone to see
what an awesome person you are.
I thought I was being supportive,
but I was actually being terrible!
Adora, She-Ra's not
the reason we like you.
We like you because you're our friend.
[explosion nearby]
You have a plan, don't you?
Yeah. I think I do.
All clear.
Okay, we need to find that machine.
Every Horde camp is laid out the same.
Guard duty's always in half-hour shifts.
So we walk in when the shift changes,
in three, two, one.
-[woman] Shift change!
-[man] Finally!
I swear, boring shifts go by slower.
[gasps]
You were right.
-The Horde is poisoning the land.
-[female guard] Hey!
What are you doing here?
We have security clearance,
password 5-echo-niner.
Now be on your way.
[guard] We haven't used
that password in months.
-Hands up!
-[alarm wailing]
-Adora? What do we do?
-Run!
Hey, the Bright Moon guys left.
"We've gone to the Horde camp
to find the weapon killing your trees.
If we don't make it,
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
I couldn't be the hero you wanted.
Adora."
She's still trying, even though
we were so negative. Glimmer was right.
This is our home,
we can't let her do this alone!
Everyone, She-Ra and our friends
from Bright Moon
are risking their lives
to protect us from the Horde.
We need to help them!
Get the warchimes, we march!
[all cheering]
[all shouting]
-How many soldiers can you take?
-Between one and... zero.
[panting] Whoo.
[panting] I'll take them all,
if you give me a minute.
[soldiers shouting]
[horn wailing]
I always said the universe will repay
the Horde one day.
Well, I guess that day is today!
For the She-Ra!
[all shouting]
Hey.
Ooh. [chuckles]
[grunts]
I've never been so alive!
[grunting and shouting]
For the honor of Grayskull!
For Etheria!
[shouts]
[laughing]
[woman] Ew! Yuck!
[man] Retreat! Retreat!
Thank you so much!
You inspired us to save ourselves.
How can we ever repay you?
Join the Rebellion
and help me reform the Princess Alliance.
Um, are you sure?
Didn't that go horribly the first time?
It went horribly for our parents.
But we have a chance to do it right.
We're clearly stronger together.
Think what all the princesses united
could do.
Would I get to hit more people
with flowers?
Absolutely.
Then you have a deal.
Hey, everyone! Look at us.
We're mighty rebels now!
[all cheering]
Force Captain Catra--
This was brought to me
by retreating soldiers,
retreating because their camp
was attacked by Adora and She-Ra.
Pathetic.
You're still trying to protect her.
Did you think you could keep the truth
from me?
It's just a phase, she's confused.
I'll bring her back in, I swear.
[Shadow Weaver] Oh, yes, you will.
Because until I tell you otherwise,
that is your mission.
And to ensure success,
no matter where Adora goes,
no matter how long it takes,
my shadow spies will find her.
-[gasps]
-Find her and bring her home.
What is this? [chuckles]
Since you've never slept in a room
by yourself before,
Bow and I thought we'd throw a sleepover,
then you won't fell so alone.
We even got you a new bed.
It's wonderful.
We can do this tomorrow too,
since Glimmer's grounded
for ignoring orders.
For one week!
Three weeks less than normal.
And Mom said she'd consider my plan
to recruit new princesses
into the Rebellion!
Thanks, guys.
I might not ever be the perfect hero
everybody wants me to be.
But that's okay. [grunts]
Of course it's okay. Do you have any idea
how annoying you'd be if you were perfect?
-Aw! Best Friend Squad!
-Yeah, we're not calling ourselves that.
-I prefer "The Glimmer Group."
-Nah. We're the Best Friend Squad.
[closing theme playing]