Council, we're looking for plans
to strengthen our defenses
against the Horde.
-Who would like to go first?
-Me, me, me. Me. Me, me.
Who besides Glimmer
would like to go first?
Mom-- Uh, Your Majesty.
You should let me, Bow and Adora continue
our princess recruitment mission.
If we can form a new Princess Alliance,
the Rebellion would actually
stand a chance for once.
The princesses withdrew
from the last alliance.
They chose to focus
on protecting their lands.
So, are we supposed to just give up?
Please, let me try.
All I'm proposing is a diplomatic mission.
So, what do you propose?
Anyone approaching Bright Moon by sea
needs to pass
through the Salineas Sea Gate.
It's controlled by Princess Mermista
now that her father's retired.
With her on our side,
the Rebellion could control the seas.
We need this alliance with her, Mom.
The journey is treacherous, Glimmer.
I'm not sure.
Don't worry, Mom.
With She-Ra, we can conquer anything.
Uh, we're also gonna need a boat.
With She-Ra and a boat,
we can conquer anything.
-And an experienced sea captain.
-[grumbles]
With She-Ra, a boat,
and an experienced sea captain,
we can conquer anything.
[Angella] Very well.
[gasps] Yes.
I mean it, Glimmer.
No violence, and no collateral damage.
Thanks, Mom, you won't regret it.
[sighs]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[grunting]
[laughing]
Go fish.
This is so cool.
Seaworthy is just like I imagined it.
-Everyone here looks like a pirate.
-Focus, Bow.
-We're here to find a sea captain.
-No pirates?
-No pirates.
-Arr.
None of these people look qualified
to sail a ship.
Excuse me. [chuckles]
Uh, we're looking for a sea captain
to take us to Salineas.
[grunting]
[Sea Hawk] I won. Drinks all around.
Put it on my friend here's tab.
Uh, hi.
-We were told you're a sea captain?
-I am the one and only Sea Hawk.
-Has my reputation preceded me?
-Your name is Sea Hawk?
That's the coolest name I've ever heard!
Captain Sea Hawk,
we're interviewing potential captains
to take us to Salineas.
-Would you like to apply for the position?
-[laughing]
Apply for the position?
I am the one and only Sea Hawk.
-I'm offer only.
-Okay.
Just because "Sea" is in your name,
it doesn't tell us anything
about your actual qualifications.
Qualifications? I once ran
the 50-klick Galebreath Gauntlet
in less than 20 klicks.
I maneuvered the Serpentine
with nary a chip in the paint of my bow.
My shanties are considered so desirable,
that sirens fling themselves
into sea at the sound of them.
And because I can tell you're wondering,
my mustache is naturally shiny.
It is shiny.
You're hired. Ow.
Whoa there, kids.
What makes you think you can afford me?
I assure you, Captain Sea Hawk,
money is no object.
Behold my fee.
[gasps]
Money might be an object.
You know what? Fine.
We'll just find another sea captain.
Good luck with that.
You won't find another soul
who knows the treacherous route
to Salineas as well as I do.
I brave it often to visit my close
personal friend, Princess Mermista.
-[gasps] You know her?
-Do I?
[Adora laughing]
Okay. Well, here's the deal.
We go one round, winner takes all.
You win, we leave you alone. I win,
you take us to Salineas. At no cost.
That's a terrible deal.
But I am undefeated at arm wrestling.
Let me show you how it's done, lassie.
[both grunting]
-Go, Adora. Put him in the dirt.
-This is so dumb.
Ha! This is the best you've got?
I once beat a Tyrosaur
with biceps the size of my head
in an arm-wrestling match
that lasted two weeks.
-Ha!
-Yeah! [chuckles]
Well, truth be told, I let you win
so as to, ahem, boost your confidence.
I've been wanting
to go to Salineas anyway.
Come on, kids, with me!
Forward to adventure!
[Shadow Weaver] Adora is in Seaworthy.
I'll give you one more chance
to bring her back.
Uh, didn't Hordak just order you
to stop going after Adora?
And who is going to tell him? You?
Fine. About time you start treating me
like a Force Captain anyway.
I'll bring her back.
Not so fast.
You won't be going alone.
You'll be joined by Force Captain Scorpia.
-Kitty. Just so you know, I'm a hugger.
-Huh? What?
[grunting]
Is this some kind of joke?
[Shadow Weaver] Scorpia will see
that you are kept in line.
Ugh. Okay, whatever.
You're at least
giving me a vehicle, right?
Something like that.
No.
Not boats.
Oh, I just love boats. Don't you?
Wind in your hair, ocean on every side,
miles and miles
from the nearest dry land,
watery death awaiting
at the slightest mishap.
-Man, that's what I call living.
-[shrieks]
Yeah, I'm really gonna need you
to shut up.
Aw. You're seasick?
[groaning]
-Just focus on me, okay? It'll help.
-Put me down!
What is wrong with you?
What are you looking at?
Get back to doing boat things.
Welcome aboard
the Dragon's Daughter, Three.
[scoffs] What happened
to the Dragon's Daughters One and Two?
Tragically, they went down in flames.
-How did that happen?
-I set them on fire.
-Adventure!
-Are we sure about this guy?
He just needs to get us there.
You'll of course  be expected
to earn your keep
by helping out around the ship.
Never fear, I'll teach you
everything you need to know
in shanty form.
Oh!
-What are you doing?
-Oh.
I noticed your mainsail wasn't secured,
so I fixed it.
Tying proper knots is a task
that takes years to master.
-You did these just now?
-Yes.
Sea Hawk is impressed with my knots.
This is the best day of my life.
Excellent work,
even if it is just beginner's luck.
We'll also need to set a lookout.
Come on, Sparkle, we'll sing a shanty duet
and I'll show you
how to climb the ratlines.
Oh! [gasps]
-Wait, how did she--?
-[Adora] I unfurled the jib.
By yourself? Not even a sailor
as experienced as me could do that.
Oh, so what you're saying is,
I'm better at this than you are?
And the name is Glimmer.
Well, you are a strangely
overqualified crew.
-What do you even need old Sea Hawk for?
-Your map?
Can we focus
on our super important mission here?
More sailing, less shanty-ing.
Of course, Shimmer.
A top secret mission from the queen.
I'll get you there straight away.
I'm as excited to see my dearest Mermista
as I know she is to see me.
My name is Glimmer!
Oh!
♪ [singing] I'm Sea Hawk
I am, I am ♪
♪ If you're looking for adventure
I am your man ♪
♪ If you want to ride
On the waves of deepest blue ♪
♪ Through perilous winds
Then I got you ♪
♪ Some say I'm a hero ♪
♪ Some say I'm a man ♪
♪ What I know for sure is ♪
♪ I'm Sea Hawk
I am, I am ♪
[laughs] Adventure.
Something's wrong.
According to the map,
we're way off-course.
[Bow] Yeah!
-[grunting]
-Whoo!
-Let's go. Go, Adora.
-Yes.
-Yeah!
-Best three out of five.
No. No more arm wrestling.
I spotted a ship graveyard in the distance
and we're heading straight for it.
Is anyone worried about this?
[crashing]
What was that?
Aha! We're here.
[gasps, then yells]
The Serpent of the Sea.
I knew he'd be lurking in these waters.
Wait, you brought us here on purpose?
See, I don't just provide transport.
I give you a tale to tell your friends.
Come on, crew,
we're in for a harrowing adventure.
[roaring]
[Adora] For the Honor of Grayskull.
Watch this!
[yelling]
-Is that a normal thing she does?
-Yeah.
-It takes some getting used to.
-Got it. Wait, no.
Let me get this straight.
You steered us into a giant sea serpent
so you could, what, show off?
That was the plan before
your tall friend there stole my thunder!
Unbelievable.
We're trying to save Etheria
and all you care about
is whether or not
we're impressed with you?
I need this mission to go right,
or my mom will never give me another!
[grunts] Just get us to Salineas.
You've wasted enough of our time.
-Okay. Now I got it. We're all good.
-Adora, get in the boat!
-Why have we stopped?
-Sea Gate is blocking our path.
-There's no way past, Force Captain Catra.
-What?
[grunts]
Shadow Weaver didn't bother to mention
that there was a massive gate
blocking the way to Seaworthy?
Didn't you learn
about the Salineas Sea Gate
in Force Captain Orientation?
-There's a Force Captain Orientation?
-[Scorpia] Oh, yes, there is.
-[groans]
-[laughing]
All hands on deck!
We're finding a way through that gate.
Ooh, impressive captain yell.
Where is everyone?
Hmm. Very odd indeed.
If I know the Princess Mermista,
-and I do, something's amiss.
-Halt! Halt! Halt, I say.
Halt.
What's your business in Salineas?
We've come to speak
with Princess Mermista.
Tell her Sea Hawk is with them.
She'll be excited to see me.
-Ew, who let him back in here?
-[Sea Hawk] Princess.
Oh, it's been too long.
I've dreamed of you
night and day since we parted.
Uh-huh. And who are you?
My name is Glimmer of Bright Moon.
We've never met, but our parents
fought in the Rebellion together.
Oh, yeah.
I remember hearing
about the old Princess Alliance.
My dad said it was a total disaster.
I didn't think it was possible,
but your beauty grows greater
with each passing day.
Will you quit it? I'm trying
to talk to my new friend Twinkle.
-Butler, bring us some hors d'oeuvres.
-Ooh, hors d'oeuvres!
-For everyone but Sea Hawk.
-Your guard is also your butler?
I'm a little understaffed right now.
Everybody fled because the gate
is falling apart or whatever.
[all] What?
Yeah, I know, right? It figures
I'd inherit a kingdom that's crumbling,
but it's totally fine. I'm handling it.
It's just kind of inconvenient,
because the Horde won't stop attacking us.
Why is the gate falling apart?
I mean, who knows?
But it's getting weaker every day.
And if the Horde tries to attack us again,
we're pretty much dead.
The Horde is the reason we're here.
We want to rebuild the Princess Alliance.
None of us stand a chance on our own,
but we might be able
to stop them together.
[chuckles] Sure, because that
went so great the first time.
Why should I help Bright Moon?
It's not like they've ever done
anything to help us.
Mermista, if I may.
No. No more shanties.
Why did you bring him here?
He is so annoying!
-I thought you'd said she liked you.
-We have a rich, complicated past.
If by that you mean you got us
kicked out of the Dolphin Social
for challenging the doorman
to a duel, then sure.
I don't recall doing that.
And that time you set our gondola on fire
in the Tunnel of Love.
[chuckling]
That I do recall.
This is First Ones' writing.
And who is she again? What is she doing?
That's Adora. She has a magic sword.
What does it say?
Uh, it's something about the gate.
The First Ones must've built it.
Looks like the gate gets its power
from the Salinean Runestone.
It could be that the gate is failing
because It's losing its connection
to the power source.
-You think you can fix it?
-I can try.
Look, Mermista.
You need our help and we need yours.
If Adora can repair your gate,
will you consider joining us? Please?
[groans] I don't know. I guess.
But he has to leave.
But where am I supposed to go?
Maybe wait with the boat, okay, buddy?
We'll take care of the gate.
[Mermista] I really hope
you know what you're doing.
Uh... Yeah, totally. [chuckles]
I got this.
For the Honor of Grayskull!
Wow. Okay. That's different.
-Is it working?
-[gasps]
Don't distract me.
This is a lot harder than it looks.
[She-Ra grunting]
[yawns] This might take a while.
[groans] Hang on.
-Where are you going?
-[gasps]
I'd really appreciate it
if you'd stop doing that.
-Are you leaving without us?
-It's for the best.
I'm only getting in your way.
It's time for old Sea Hawk
to be where he belongs, alone.
It wasn't always like this.
Where I'm from, I had friends, a crew.
Every day an adventure more daring
than the last.
The fact I kept setting my boats on fire
was considered charming.
But here, I can't even get anyone
to take me seriously.
Yeah. I know a little about that.
I can't get anyone
to take me seriously either.
You? But you're a princess.
Try being the daughter
of an immortal queen
when your powers are sparkles.
-Glitter...
-Glimmer.
...we've just met, but I can tell
you are a brave and powerful soul.
Anyone who'd underestimate you
would live to sorely regret it.
Thanks, Sea Hawk. And you know what?
You still have friends and a crew.
Reporting for duty, captain.
Uh... Adora?
-It's the Horde.
-What?
[shouts]
Keep us going full speed.
I've got something more important to do.
-They're coming right for the gate.
-[groaning]
I just need a little more time.
Keep them busy.
[grunting]
Oh, come on.
[grunting and shouting]
Oh. You're big.
See you.
[yelling]
Gotcha.
Sea Hawk.
Bow, are you all right?
That was amazing!
Thank you for noticing, Bow.
It was amazing.
Nothing's slowing them down.
What do we do?
I think I have a plan.
But no one is allowed to tell my mom
about this.
Sea Hawk, I need your help.
-I need you to do what you do best.
-What?
Set your ship on fire.
Yes.
[grunting]
[Catra laughs] Wow.
You know, the tiara actually gets stupider
the more I look at it.
Catra, how did you find me?
Did you think it'd be that easy
to escape the Horde?
I mean, I always knew you were dumb,
but come on.
What's your plan, insult me
until I decide to rejoin the Horde?
I don't think Shadow Weaver is planning
to give you much of a choice,
but, yeah, something like that.
Check it out. Looks like with you gone,
I got your promotion.
Congratulations.
Seems like only yesterday this was
the thing you wanted most in the world.
And now you're--
[groans] Come on, Adora,
hasn't this all gone on long enough?
I told you before, Catra,
I'm not going back.
[grunting and shouting]
This is what you left me for?
Dress-up games and a light show?
And your new best friends are nowhere
to be seen. When did you get so weak?
Whoo!
-Thanks.
-Yeah, whatever, don't mention it.
[Sea Hawk] Ha-ha!
[both] Adventure!
What the heck?
[all yelling]
Yeah!
[grunting]
[Mermista] Yay, that was cool.
I'm over it, though.
[sighs]
-What do you know? You actually fixed it.
-It's beautiful.
I guess
you're gonna be needing a new ship.
[groans] I suppose
you can have one of mine.
[gasping]
-She's gorgeous.
-Don't set it on fire.
No promises. But, Princess,
if I might ask for one more favor.
[groans] You're always ruining it.
You should think about joining
Glimmer's Princess Alliance.
She is a brave and strong captain.
With her at the helm, she is sure
to lead the Rebellion to victory.
Aw, Sea Hawk. You even got my name right.
-Okay, I'm in.
-Really?
Yeah. The Horde almost destroyed my home.
I wanna help fight them.
Plus, your friend over there can turn
into a 8-foot tall lady with a sword
and I want her on my side.
-Yes, huzzah!
-Yeah! Oh, yes!
-Wow, okay, calm down.
-You won't regret this, I promise.
[singing]
♪ The Best Friend Squad on the seas ♪
♪ We subdued the threat
The threat with ease ♪
♪ We sail the world
Come near or far ♪
♪ We're best friends
We are, we are ♪
[laughs]
[closing theme playing]