[shouting]
[whimpering]
Oh, I got it.
-Don't forget this.
-[both shriek]
[sighs]
Oh, buttered biscuits.
I'll never get used to these things.
[whirring and beeping]
At least I don't have to get lost
in that maze anymore.
A pig.
So cute.
[powering down]
Log. Day 103. 104? No, definitely 103.
First Ones artifact number 58 has yielded
a treasure trove of intact code.
If I can successfully translate it,
it could hold the secrets
of the First Ones.
[alarm ringing]
[groaning]
Oh.
Fascinating. My robots
seem to be responding to the code.
This is remarkable. Could this be
my big step yet towards making ancient
and modern technology
truly compatible? [shouts]
Edit to log.
I'm now going to run.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Princess Entrapta will be a total catch
for the Rebellion.
My mom's gonna be so impressed!
Uh, I'm all for impressing Angella,
but why is Entrapta so important?
She's brilliant inventor.
She makes robots and rehabs old tech
left by the First Ones.
She's a pretty big deal
in the Etherian makers community.
Which I am a part of,
because I dabble in gadgetry myself.
What does any of that mean?
It means if we convince Entrapta
to join the Rebellion,
she'll invent all sorts
of cool junk for us.
And then we'll finally have weapons
that can stand up to the Horde's.
Like my trick arrows!
I'm running low, so I built new ones.
This one is a stun arrow,
this one is an emergency flare.
And this one? This one's just pointy.
And here's my newest one.
Sonic arrow!
[laughs] When will we ever need
a sonic arrow?
-If we have to wake up really early?
-Or if we get separated in a crowd?
[both laughing]
"Separated in a crowd." [groans]
I bet Entrapta will like my arrows.
Must've been a rockslide.
Any loud sound could cause another slide.
We need to be as quiet as--
For the honor of Grayskull!
[echoing]
[groans]
[whimpering]
-Ha! I'm getting the hang of this.
-That was incredibly dangerous.
What the big deal? It worked.
You can't just bust
through everything with magic!
-She-Ra could've caused an avalanche.
-But she didn't, okay?
I spent my whole life without powers.
No way am I gonna stop using them now.
[lightning crashing]
Whoa. She's got lightning!
Something's wrong.
The castle's distress beacon is lit.
They must be under attack.
There's been no report of the Horde
in this area.
Whoa, wait. Be careful!
[beeping]
[gasps]
-Are you okay?
-This place feels wrong. It's nothing.
Hey! Who's there?
Hello? Princess Entrapta?
We're here to, uh, recruit you
for the Rebellion.
[groans]
[shouting]
Okay. We need to be careful.
[panting] Entrapta has traps set up
all over her castle.
[groans]
They're supposed to be really cool.
-[explosion]
-[both gasp]
They're coming. Get out of the square.
-Who's coming? Is it the Horde?
-Hello? Come back!
I'm thinking we should probably move away
from whatever is making that sound.
This way.
[Bow gasps]
-What the...?
-[roaring]
[grunts]
Looks like one of Entrapta's designs.
Why would it attack us?
-All right, stand back.
-Careful. It could be a--
[Glimmer &amp; Adora scream]
Glimmer! Adora! [grunts]
[both grunting]
Bow. He's all alone with those things.
He needs us!
-We have to get out first.
-Come on. I'll teleport us out.
-Uh, is this out?
-Ugh.
[both shrieking]
-Okay, no more teleporting from now on.
-Sounds like a good idea.
-[thud]
-[both gasp]
Not again.
Princesses. I'm saved.
Princess Entrapta?
I mean, so good to see you.
I hope you don't mind,
but we sort of let ourselves in.
And then we let ourselves out
of your cage trap thing. [coughs]
Welcome to Dryl.
Things are usually really fun around here,
but right now it's all kind of deadly.
[grunting] Let me go.
Please keep your voice down, sir.
The robots respond to sound.
-We're just trying to help you.
-Oh, thanks. What's going on?
Why are the robots attacking people?
We don't know!
We're just the kitchen staff.
Miniature cupcake?
Princess Entrapta only eats tiny food.
-[Soda Pop] And delicious fizzy beverages.
-Uh... Thank you?
You'll be safe in here with us.
We've got enough food to last for months.
It's tiny, but still.
The bots will run out of power
eventually, right?
We need to do something.
You can't just hide in here forever.
Oh, yes, we can.
We don't have powers
like the princesses. We can't fight.
-[tracker beeping]
-[all gasp]
Sir, kindly quiet your...
whatever that is.
It's a tracker pad.
It tracks energy signatures from magic.
It'll help me find my friends.
Are those little dot thingies
your friends?
[clanging, robots roaring]
Gonna go with no.
You're lucky I found you.
I designed the castle as a labyrinth.
I'm the only one who can navigate it. Oh!
Which means you can help us
find our friend?
Absolutely. [grunts]
Is she sure about that?
-I think we passed this picture already.
-Oh, isn't it cute?
You might be right.
I usually have my electronic map
to get around,
but, like my bots,
it's sort of evil right now.
-Uh, yeah, about that--
-Why did you invent killer robots?
You're abnormally tall.
Hello! I like your sword.
It's First Ones tech. Can I touch it?
Uh, thank you, yes,
and no, not right now.
-Ahem. About the killer robots?
-They didn't start that way.
Usually, they're super useful.
They do almost everything for me.
Cleaning, filing, basic hygiene.
Ooh, and they're sound-activated.
Here, I'll show you.
Could we maybe not do that?
[robot approaching]
[all shouting]
Isn't it adorable?
[roaring]
[grunts]
It's trying to talk.
Whatever it's saying,
I don't think it's good.
-Make it stop.
-Make what stop?
Bot 329 is attempting to communicate.
[grunting]
Oh, no. Bad bot.
Princess!
[grunting]
[shouts]
[She-Ra grunting]
She-Ra, stop!
Turn it off. Turn it off.
[She-Ra breathing heavily]
[shouts]
[panting]
-The door won't hold much longer.
-Almost done.
-Are you sure about this?
-Uh, you guys?
Now.
[sighs] Here goes nothing.
[shouting]
[laughs]
Shoot it already!
I can't, it's a sonic arrow.
It'll draw more bots.
[whimpering]
Is it over?
I did that?
Hey, I did that.
Nice work. Now let's find my friends.
Come on.
Adora. Wake up.
Please, wake up.
The tall one seems infected, too.
She turned less tall. How does it work?
She's not an it. She's my friend.
And what do you mean, infected?
It's really fascinating.
I've been experimenting with a disc
recovered from a mine.
It was a game changer.
It held more complete First Ones code
than anything I'd ever seen before.
But it seems to have reacted
with the First Ones tech
that powers my bots.
It infected them
with some sort of a virus.
But why would that make She-Ra sick?
Well, I'd have to take her apart
to be sure.
But since her sword is First Ones tech,
it must've spread through that.
First, you're not taking her apart.
She is a person!
Second, if we destroy this disc,
will that turn off the bots
and stop the virus?
Destroy it? The experiment isn't complete!
I think we can safely say
this experiment is a failure.
But what if it's not?
No, you're right, it's a failure.
[grunts]
Glimmer.
There's two of you.
That's nice.
How are you feeling?
Just peachy. Why are we whispering?
-Sound activates the robots.
-What robots?
-The ones that are attacking us!
-Oh, those robots.
-Okay, I'm gonna take a nap.
-No, no, no. Stay awake.
We have to go to Entrapta's lab
and destroy this disc thing,
-and then you'll be all better again.
-Better? I'm fine. I'm She-Ra.
[laughing, then snorts]
Hi, Glimmer.
Come on, we've gotta get to your lab.
She's getting worse.
[grunting]
[shouts]
[grumbles]
[Adora laughs]
Hmm.
Aha!
[gasps]
[grunting]
Oh, we're here. I mean, of course
we're here. We were never lost.
[humming]
[yelling]
Wow. The door is infected, too.
It won't let us in.
That is so smart. And awful.
We're all gonna die.
It's okay, I've got this one.
I'll just teleport into the lab.
Ooh, teleportation.
How does that work? Tell me everything.
Sure. Maybe later, when we're not facing
a robot uprising.
It's a date.
-I'll be back.
-I'm just gonna wait here. Heh.
[robots roaring and Glimmer shouting]
That was not such a great plan.
The lab is very full of robots.
How did they look?
Pretty evil. I couldn't get
anywhere near the disc.
[both screaming]
[all shouting]
Oh, he's kind of cute. [shouts]
[grunts] Uh, guys? A little help?
[screaming]
-[tracker beeping]
-[all shouting]
-Don't say it's more bots.
-No. That's Glimmer teleporting.
I know where Glimmer and Adora are.
Uh-oh. That's not good.
We have to do something.
-We have to save them.
-Oh, no, sir. No, thank you.
It's one thing to fight them off
out of necessity.
But to seek out danger?
-It's madness. Pardon me.
-[groans]
Look, they're princesses,
they have powers.
I make baked goods.
Sure, we don't have powers
like the princesses'.
But that never stopped me
and it doesn't have to stop you.
But you're a master archer.
We're ordinary people.
I'm a master archer who's out of arrows.
But that never stopped me, either.
You each have a skill
that only you can do,
even if it doesn't come
from some magical jewel.
You say you're just ordinary people?
I say you're warriors of the Rebellion!
To the Rebellion!
[both panting]
[gasps]
[robots roaring]
[Glimmer and Entrapta grunting]
Incredible development.
The bots seem to be working together.
Right now, I think that's a bad thing.
We need to find another way into the lab.
The air duct. We can use that.
I don't suppose you have
any other magical powers
that could be useful right now?
I don't have enough energy
to teleport us all.
Not without leaving someone's legs behind.
I'll give up one of mine
if you give up one of yours.
[robots roaring]
[shouting]
-[Bow] Ha, ha!
-Woo-hoo!
It's Bow.
Yay, there's a rainbow.
[grunting]
[chuckles]
-How you doing?
-I'm getting the hang of this.
[grunting and shouting]
-Nice.
-[chuckles]
[Glimmer] Bow.
You're okay. I was so worried.
Big fan of your work, Princess Entrapta.
Maybe not this work exactly,
but your other work.
[chuckles] Hi.
-[Adora] Hi.
-You okay, Adora?
Oh, yeah, sure, I'm totally... [snorts]
Entrapta was experimenting
with First Ones tech
and it infected all her machines
with some kind of virus.
She-Ra's sword got infected,
and made Adora all...
weird.
I teleported into the lab.
But it's full of bots.
Maybe with She-Ra we'd have a chance,
but without her it's hopeless.
We don't need She-Ra.
We can do this together.
[chuckles]
Okay. Where's the disc?
How fascinating.
It has completely protected itself.
-We have to find a way to turn it off.
-Hey, guys, I found the bots.
Adora!
-[screams]
-Shh.
-[Bow] Glimmer!
-We'll get your friends.
You two, get that disc turned off.
Keep them busy.
[all shouting]
[grunting and shouting]
We got your back, princesses.
[groaning]
That's not gonna work.
How do we shut the computer down?
Ha! The power conduit.
[both grunting]
[Bow laughs]
You dumb bots, you're going
the wrong way! Bow, watch out!
Uh, why isn't the computer turning off?
[laughs]
It's running on its own power now.
That's it. We need to get out of here
and burn this place to the ground.
-Experiment officially failed.
-Wait, I have an idea.
[screams]
Now's your chance, sonic arrow.
I believe in you!
[screeching]
[gasps] Where am I? What's happening?
Thanks, former tall one and companions,
for saving our lives.
I would be honored to join your Rebellion
and provide you with weapons.
Thanks, guys. You saved us all back there.
The Rebellion needs regular people now
more than ever.
-We are ready.
-Ha!
So, maybe you had a point before.
What? Sorry, I couldn't hear you.
I think what Glimmer's trying to say
is that you were right,
we can't always rely on our powers.
Oh. Is that
what you were trying to say, Glimmer?
-That I was right?
-Yes.
And my sonic arrow was a good idea?
Yes, it was brilliant,
and you were totally right. Okay?
If you hadn't come,
the bots would've gotten us.
And I didn't know
She-Ra could get sick like that.
-What if it happens again?
-It won't.
We destroyed that evil,
She-Ra-hating disc.
Good. I never wanna feel that way again.
Thanks for saving us, Bow.
All in a day's work
for Bow and his band of Kitchen Knights.
His Baking Brigade.
Pastry Patrol. I'm still working that out.
[both chuckle]
Oh. Look at that rock just staring at us.
Boy, that rock really needs smashing.
And since She-Ra's not sick anymore,
she should probably smash it.
Ha, ha! What? It's practice.
For the honor of Grayskull!
[sighs]
[Entrapta] Log. Day 105. 104? Eh.
The last experiment hit a few bumps,
but it was not a total failure.
I made some important discoveries.
The disc is way more powerful
than I ever imagined.
With a few adjustments, I'm sure
the next experiment will be a success.
[closing theme playing]