[grunting]
[Shadow Weaver] Adora.
[gasps]
[yawning]
Good morning, Glimmer.
[groaning]
It's too early. Five more minutes.
-But it's a beautiful morning.
-Today's canceled.
Go back to bed.
[groans] I can feel you staring at me.
Why is it the one who snores
is the first one to fall asleep?
What? I don't snore.
Adora, do I snore--?
Adora?
[groans]
[gasps]
Sorry. Too early to teleport.
-What are we looking at?
-I don't know.
I heard a noise in the woods last night.
I thought I saw something.
What? Like a bunny? Maybe a butterfly?
-Adora, did you get any sleep at all?
-[gasps] Someone has to stand guard.
Okay. I know you're on edge
because of what happened
with Entrapta's infected robots,
but it's all over now!
You've got to relax. You need a vacation.
Which is why we're going to Mystacor.
[gasps] Mystacor? No way.
Wait, what's Mystacor?
It's a secret, floating kingdom
that's home to all of Etheria's sorcerers.
It's got tranquil gardens,
beautiful beaches, and healing springs.
My Aunt Castaspella just happens
to be head sorceress there.
You'll love it, Adora.
Plus, you won't have to worry
about evil things in the woods.
Mystacor is protected
by an invisibility spell,
so evil can't find it!
It's the safest and most peaceful place
in all of Etheria.
We'll have you relaxing in no time.
You know, I've never relaxed in my life.
-It might--
-We're about to change that. Just wait.
[hissing]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Shadow Weaver. You wanted to see me?
Ah. Force Captain.
How kind of you to join me.
What's up with you?
You're being spookier than usual.
My shadow spies have found Adora.
She's on her way to Mystacor
with her new friends. Mystacor.
This is going to be too easy.
[groans]
Another Adora mission.
Fine. When do I leave?
[Shadow Weaver] The only place
you're headed is outside my door
to stand guard.
I'm going to use my magic
to go after Adora myself.
You will see that I am not disturbed.
Clearly, no one else can be trusted
to bring her back to the Horde,
least of all you. Now go.
I said, go!
[grunts, then panting]
[gasps]
From the farthest regions of Etheria,
I command you, be as one!
[screeching]
We're here.
Uh, we're on a cliff
-overlooking a thousand-foot drop.
-Yes, we are. But not for long.
-[Glimmer laughs] Woo-hoo!
-Woo-hoo!
Uh, guys?
Come on, Adora. Jump.
[grunting]
[shouting]
[gasps, then shouting]
-[grunts]
-Ooh, ouch.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I thought I saw--
[sighs] I'm just stressed.
Hang in there, Adora. Next stop, Mystacor.
[Glimmer laughing]
We rode a flying mountain through clouds.
It never gets old.
Uh, sure, yeah, heh. It was great.
Just so you know,
my Aunt Casta can be a lot.
But don't worry, I know how to handle her.
Is that my Glimmer?
Hi, Aunt Casta.
It's been so long
since you've come to visit.
And Bow.
[Bow grunts]
-And who's this?
-This is my friend Adora.
She's also sometimes
an eight-foot-tall warrior named She-Ra.
-So don't freak out when it happens.
-Hi.
Adora. How nice Glimmer has finally
started making some new friends.
We were all so pleased
when she started bringing Bow around.
I was sure she had made him up
at first. [laughing]
-[clearing throat]
-Oh.
-You've done something to your hair?
-What? Yes. I cut it.
I can see that.
I also see you're not wearing
the sweater I knitted for you.
Don't you like it?
Sure, I like it. It's great.
It's just--
It's a little warm for sweaters right now.
-But you'd tell me if you didn't like it?
-Yes, I'd tell you.
I'm wearing the socks you sent me.
Well, I've always been fond of this one.
So, what brings you all the way
out here to visit your aunt?
Is it once in a blue moon already?
[laughs]
We're on a diplomatic mission, Auntie.
I'm rebuilding the Princess Alliance--
My goodness, then you must be starving.
I'll have a feast prepared.
I'm sure your mother
hasn't been feeding you.
[people laughing]
[gasps] Wow.
You've come at the perfect time.
There's an eclipse this evening.
I'm headed right now
to inspect the Lunarium for the ceremony.
And nothing would make me happier
than to give my favorite niece
and her friends a tour.
Uh... Bow and I have had the tour before.
And we don't wanna get in your way.
It's all right, Glimmer.
Adora hasn't seen it. It'll be fun.
Oh. Well, I guess it's up to Adora, then.
What do you say, my dear?
-Uh... Sure?
-Oh, I like her.
[grumbles]
[gasps] Wow.
The lunar lenses.
We use them in the monthly ceremonies
to renew Mystacor's magic defenses
and keep us shielded
from the outside world.
You will be coming to the Eclipse
Ceremony tonight, won't you?
Aunt Casta, I've seen
the ceremony dozens of times.
And we're all really tired
from travelling.
-Maybe we'll skip it this time?
-Nonsense.
Your friend Adora hasn't seen it,
and it's quite a sight to behold
for a newcomer.
Besides, don't you want to spend
more time with your aunt?
Of course. But we also really wanted
to show Adora the beach.
Well, if the beach
is the only reason you're here,
I really shouldn't keep you, should I?
I certainly don't want to waste your time.
[gasps]
-Auntie, I didn't mean it that way.
-Adora?
Well, someone is enthusiastic.
Ah, yes. The Hall of Sorcerers.
These are the Great Ones
who led Mystacor through the ages.
This is Micah, my brother.
We trained in these very halls together.
Glimmer looks just like him, you know?
He had a beard.
Wait, Glimmer's dad was your brother?
Adora, do you know what aunt means?
No. I was just hoping someone
would eventually explain.
Auntie, we're going to avenge my dad
and make sure that the Horde
never hurts anyone else.
Mom believes in us, and in She-Ra.
Well, if your mother believes,
who am I not to?
She's an angelic being after all,
I'm just a common sorceress.
Ugh. Please, not this again.
She never writes to me, you know?
I send letters, but do I ever get a reply?
-What happened to her?
-Light Spinner.
A scar on Mystacor's past.
She sought power and complete control
above all else, and she was cast out.
Although some say she never really left.
That she's only biding her time,
waiting to exact her revenge.
But those are only children's tales,
of course.
Anyway, on with the tour. Are you hungry?
I've had the dining room redone
since last time you were here, Glimmer.
[gasps, then panting]
-[shrieks]
-[Glimmer] Okay.
Aunt Casta's gone to fix us a big dinner
and now it's finally beach time!
You okay?
It's worse than we thought.
You need warm sand
and calming waves. Stat.
It's time for something more.
So, we just, like, lie here?
Absolutely. Letting your cares melt away.
Didn't you do something like this
to relax in the Horde?
Uh, no. We hit things.
Well, this is so much better. Right, Bow?
[snoring]
Just try it, okay?
[sighs] Okay.
[grunts]
[mimicking bird noises]
[grunts, then sighs] Okay.
[humming and groaning]
-This isn't working for you, is it?
-No. Can I move now?
Yes.
[sighs]
Clearly, we're going to have to take
this relaxation thing to the next level.
-Bow, wake up.
-What?
Come on, we need to show Adora
the steam grotto.
Whoo! Steam grotto.
-Wow.
-Right?
Ah. Ooh. Ah.
Ah.
The pools are full
of magic minerals.
Sorcerers use them to cleanse themselves
of worry and fear
before big ceremonies or spells.
Now, just clear your mind.
Breathe deeply.
Focus on the warmth on your skin.
Let your body go perfectly...
[snoring]
Ah.
[Shadow Weaver] Adora.
[both shouting]
No, no, no! No.
-Help!
-Adora!
-Shadow Weaver's here! I saw her!
-Adora, there's no one else here.
You brought your sword in here?
Are you okay?
-What happened?
-Shadow Weaver was here.
In the grotto.
She was in the Sorceress Hall, too.
-I saw her shadow on the floor.
-What are you talking about?
Who is Shadow Weaver?
Shadow Weaver raised me in the Horde.
She taught me how to read, tie my boots,
and how to subvert the enemy
and be victorious in battle.
-Okay, sure. Mom stuff.
-No. Commanding officer stuff.
-And mom stuff.
-Adora, she isn't here.
She was never here. It's not possible.
But you don't know what she's capable of.
Sounds like this Shadow Weaver
really did a number on you growing up.
But you're okay. You got away from her.
Do you wanna try something else?
We could get massages
or find you something to hit
-if that would work better.
-No. It's okay. I'm okay.
I think I need to be alone. Clear my head.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
[Glimmer] Adora has finally lost it.
Did you see her in here?
I think she's going nuts.
I'm not crazy!
I'm-- I'm not crazy.
[sighs]
You're just a stupid statue.
Pull it together, Adora.
There's no way Shadow Weaver can be here.
[gasps]
[shouts]
For the honor of Grayskull!
-[Catra] Hey, Adora.
-[gasps]
Catra? Where are you?
How did you find me here?
[Catra laughing, footsteps nearby]
[Catra] Nope.
Getting colder.
Whatever you're doing,
I won't let you get away with it.
-Did Shadow Weaver send you?
-[Catra] What do you think?
Shadow Weaver controls us both.
She always has.
Catra, wait.
[Catra laughing]
Catra?
-[Hordak laughing]
-[gasps]
[Hordak] The Horde had
high hopes for you, Force Captain.
Disappointing.
Does the Rebellion truly think
you can save them?
Nothing can stop the Horde,
least of all you.
-Show yourself!
-[Hordak] You will lead them all,
every Etherian,
to their complete and utter annihilation.
Nothing will be left but smoking ruins.
Your new friends buried beneath.
[yells]
[gasps]
What have you done?
[pants] Uh...
-Sorry. I didn't mean-- I thought I saw--
-Adora!
Your friend has destroyed
a thousand years' worth
of sacred writings.
She could've destroyed the lenses
that protect Mystacor.
She didn't mean to. Adora would never--
This is the kind of person
you hang around with?
Auntie, wait.
-Glimmer.
-It's okay, I'll handle her.
The Horde isn't here, Adora.
You need to sleep.
-Promise me you'll try.
-Okay. I'll try.
[knock on door]
-Glimmer. Look, I'm really sorry--
-Save it, Adora.
How could you do this?
I thought you were supposed
to be our friend.
I am your friend.
You've ruined everything I've worked for.
What kind of friend does that?
-Glimmer--
-You know what? Maybe you should just go.
Is Adora coming?
I didn't wanna wake her up.
She needs to sleep.
[gasps]
[grunting]
[both gasping]
[people screaming]
Adora! Come on,
we have to get out of here now!
What's happening?
The protection spell is failing!
We need to go!
Wait, stop! What do you mean, failing?
Where's Glimmer?
Everything that's about to happen
is your fault, Adora.
You're to blame.
[gasps]
[both groaning]
-[Shadow Weaver] Adora.
-Shadow Weaver!
[Shadow Weaver laughing]
[grunts]
[shouting]
The eclipse is nearly over, Adora.
When it is, the shield will be down.
The Horde will conquer Mystacor,
and bring you home to me.
No. I'll stop you!
[Shadow Weaver]
Why? To help these people?
Who are they to you?
They don't understand you.
Just as they did not understand me
when I walked among them as Light Spinner.
-What?
-They feared my dark power.
They'll never accept you.
-Not like I do.
-No, no! You're wrong!
For the honor of Grayskull!
You know deep down what I say is true.
You are the ambitious,
cutthroat, ruthless warrior
I raised you to be.
No.
The princesses don't care about you.
They want to use you for your strength.
Return now to the Fright Zone.
Rule by my side.
[grunts]
[Adora] These are my friends.
They've been kind to me.
-Something you never were.
-I prepared you for greatness.
But you never loved me.
You just played twisted mind games.
I'm none of the things that you say I am.
I'm not like you.
You are bitter and cruel,
and you're the one who used me!
This is who I am.
You hurt my friends,
so now you're gonna pay.
[evil laugh]
[Shadow Weaver] It's too late.
The eclipse will be over in moments.
Mystacor will fall
and it will be your fault.
[grunting and shouting]
[Shadow Weaver yells]
[grunts] Huh?
[Shadow Weaver laughing]
[grunting]
I can give you Etheria.
We can rule together.
You were nothing
before I took you in, Adora!
And you will be nothing without me!
You're weak.
Adora, enough of this.
Come home.
[groaning]
I'm not going back.
You have no power over me anymore.
[grunts]
[Shadow Weaver] No!
[all groaning]
Adora! Are you okay?
[Adora] I'm okay. [chuckles]
Yeah, I think I'm finally okay!
She's gone.
I'm so sorry we didn't believe you!
We've been bad friends.
No, you're not.
This is what Shadow Weaver does.
She manipulates people,
she pushes them apart.
But it's never gonna work on me again.
I'm sorry, it's my fault she was here.
I endangered Mystacor.
Nonsense. You saved Mystacor.
Glimmer has chosen her friends well.
I'll knit you a sweater.
What size are you in the shoulders?
I'm, like, really tired.
-Glimmer?
-Right here, Adora.
Hello? Shadow Weaver?
[chuckles]
You've been going about this
the wrong way, old woman.
If you wanna take down Adora,
you have to go for the heart.
[closing theme playing]