Uh, hey, guys?
I got an invite for the All-Princess Ball,
Winter Wonderland.
-Do you know what this is?
-[both] Princess Prom!
Princess Prom! Princess Prom!
We are going to Princess Prom!
Okay, you've gone crazy, got it.
I'll just come back later.
The All-Princess Ball is a meeting
of all the princesses of Etheria.
And a giant party!
-Dancing, food, fancy dresses.
-Dancing?
It only happens once a decade.
I've been waiting years for this!
Uh... But you know, I'm--
I'm only a princess sometimes.
Are you sure I should even go?
Of course. Every princess is invited.
That includes you.
Oh, yeah. It's all in the invite.
Okay. "Rules for greeting the hostess.
Expected curtsy depth.
Proper stair-descending etiquette"?
The Ball has been going on for centuries.
There's a lot of old etiquette stuff
you gotta do before you can party.
But it's gonna be so fun!
And Princess Frosta is hosting this year
in the Kingdom of Snows.
Her magic is incredibly powerful.
She'd be a huge get for the Rebellion.
[whimpers]
Don't worry. I'll be right there with you,
and so will Bow,
since he's going as my plus one.
Uh... Actually...
Together, the three of us
can handle anything.
-About that...
-It's the best friend squad in action.
-Right, Bow?
-I'm going with Perfuma.
What?
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
I'm sick of this.
Shadow Weaver failed to get Adora,
and if Hordak finds out
she's disobeying him,
she'll take us down with her.
She's obsessed.
We need to think big picture.
It's time for someone new
to take over-- me.
-So, you in?
-I'm hanging out in your room! [chuckles]
Unfortunately, you're the only one
I can trust around here.
Because we're best friends.
Stop being so you and help me think.
I have the beginning of a plan,
but it's not enough.
I need to capture Adora
so Shadow Weaver doesn't demote me.
I need to impress Hordak
so he'll make me the new Shadow Weaver.
How do I do both?
Why don't you try something
at the All-Princess Ball?
Every princess is gonna be there,
so Adora probably will be too.
Ooh! This year's theme
is Winter Wonderland.
-How did you get your claws on this?
-They sent it to me. I'm a princess.
-You're a princess?
-Yeah, you know.
The Horde crash-landed
in my family's kingdom.
We let them stay.
My family gave Hordak
our Runestone, the Black Garnet.
You're a princess?
Oh, man, I thought everyone knew.
I mean, it's covered
in Force Captain orientation.
I'm beginning to think
I shouldn't have skipped that.
Okay, you're a princess
and you're going to a Princess Ball.
Oh, no, I'm not going. No.
No one liked my family,
even before we joined the Horde.
Ah... I never really fit
with the other princesses.
I made them uncomfortable and...
Yeah, they don't like that.
They don't like me.
And that's exactly why you have to go.
How dare those princesses pretend
they're better than you?
Just because you're different?
How dare they abandon people
just because they don't fit in
-with their perfect little lives?
-Yeah!
How dare they take best friends
and turn them into giant sword ladies
who run off with people
clearly inferior to you?
You're telling my whole life
with your words.
Well, time to show those princesses
a thing or two.
You're going, I'm coming as your plus one,
and we are going to make this
a night no one will ever forget.
Super Pal Duo is going to Prom!
She asked and I said yes.
I didn't think it would be a big deal.
It's not. It's fine.
I'm just surprised. I mean,
when did you two even talk about it?
Oh. She was super slick.
[grunting]
-Wanna go to the Ball with me?
-Okay!
[grunting]
-That's super slick?
-I thought it'd be fun.
-And Perfume's cool.
-Yeah, she's fine.
But we always go to events together.
We have all our routine,
we wear matching outfits,
we share inside jokes.
And then we eat ice cream afterwards.
It's our thing.
Well, there's nothing wrong
with a new thing.
Look, I gotta get ready.
We'll hang out with you guys there.
-But I liked our old thing.
-Glimmer!
-Good. No time to waste.
-[shouts]
I've been studying the invite.
Advance prep will be key to success.
I've divided the rules into base parts.
Dance rules, etiquette rules,
rules for greeting the hostess.
[clears throat] I then broke down
the ballroom into quadrants
and I'm familiarizing myself
with targets. Ask me anything.
-Princess Frosta.
-Ruler of the Kingdom of Snows.
First time hosting the ball,
biggest kingdom outside Bright Moon,
neutral in the fight against the Horde.
Allies with the Star Sisters,
who are friends with Mermista,
but not Sweet Bee,
who is dating Peekablue,
as you can tell from the string.
Up means friends, down means frenemies.
And also I made an obstacle course.
I'm feeling good! I've prepared
for any and all possible scenarios.
-I am so ready for this Ball.
-Great! What are you wearing?
I was gonna just go as She-Ra.
She has better hair.
Well, you can't go as She-Ra.
They have a strict no weapons rule.
Neutral ground and all.
You'll have to leave your sword
at the door.
Ugh. How are there
still more parts to this invite?
[gasps] You know what this means?
That clothes aren't important
and I should just keep studying?
It's makeover time!
Whoa.
[pop music playing]
[both laughing]
[laughs]
[shouts]
Yeah!
Huh?
[gasps]
[laughing]
Be careful with it.
Don't just lean it somewhere
with the other swords,
-or it might get confused!
-Adora, come on!
Whoa, heh.
-It's big.
-[pop music playing on speakers]
[Glimmer] The Ball is one
of our most an ancient traditions.
A princess's first Ball
is a huge rite of passage.
-Plus, the Kingdom of Snows is really big.
-Which is why we need Frosta.
If she joins us, all the other princesses
are sure to follow.
[sighs]
Here we go.
[music stops]
Hold for one, two, and three.
That's Frosta? But she's, like, ten.
[crowd gasping]
I'm 11 and three quarters.
Revered hostess. We come into your hall
under the ancient rules of hospitality,
bringing greetings from Bright Moon.
And She-Ra, the legendary warrior.
[crowd chattering]
You are welcome in the Kingdom of Snows
under the ancient rules of hospitality.
Leave conflict at the door.
And please enjoy the Ball.
Thank you, Your-- [shouts] Majesty.
Couldn't have mentioned she was a kid?
You did all that research,
I assumed you knew!
You know what? It's fine.
There's plenty of time still
to win her over.
Come on, let's rock this Ball!
[pop music playing on speakers]
Oh! There's Entrapta! Heh.
Adora! Glimmer!
Are you here to watch
the social experiment, too?
Social experiment?
Different groups are thrown together
and forced to mingle.
Hierarchies form and break.
It's the perfect place
to observe behavior.
And they have tiny food.
Where's Bow? I wanna show him
my new recorder.
He's coming later.
Why didn't he come with you?
Aren't you friends?
-Why would you think we're not?
-There he is! Bow!
They're matching.
That's our best friend thing!
Feelings seem to be getting hurt.
Hey, I'm here too.
Don't make a big thing out of it.
[both laughing]
They're making up their own inside jokes?
What? Is Perfuma his new best friend now?
Not gonna get into
whatever's happening there.
[whispering]
People walk around in circles.
Or that. Look, have you seen--?
[singing]
♪ She's a beauty, can't you see ♪
♪ She's attending this with me ♪
♪ She's my Princess of the Sea ♪
♪ Mermista ♪
Oh, hey, it's my crew.
So, Sea Hawk's your plus one?
No. He is just my ride, okay?
Just my ride.
[laughs] Of course.
[whispers] I am her plus one.
This is the best social experiment
I've ever been to!
-Whatever. Do they have a kelp bar?
-To the buffet!
-Advent-- Oh, hi, Bow.
-[gasps]
-Hey--
-[laughs] That's so funny, Adora!
What a funny inside joke
the two of us just came up with!
The She-Ra, Glimmer.
It's great to see you.
[chuckles] Perfuma was just telling me
about a winged horse
that ate all the apples in Plumeria
and then flew away.
-Sound familiar?
-Sure, whatever. Isn't this fun?
Adora and I are having
such a great time here together.
Just the two of us. Right, Adora?
Okay. Uh, we're gonna say hi to people.
You wanna come?
No, you guys go on. We'll find you later.
I wanna hear the rest
of this hilarious story
that Adora was just telling.
Oh, perfect. Frosta's alone.
I'm gonna try to smooth things over
with her. Coming?
[laughing]
Okay, never mind. I'll just be right back.
Revered hostess.
I've come to apologize for earlier.
I was so rude.
Yes, you were.
But as you're only an honorary princess,
you can't be expected to know better.
Your kingdom is truly beautiful,
Princess Frosta.
-I'm honored to be here.
-[Frosta] Thank you.
And now I expect you're going to ask me
to join your Rebellion?
You know about that?
Of course I do. Princesses talk, you know?
The snow peas and the cookies
are touching. Do it right.
Princess Frosta, the Rebellion needs you.
Your kingdom is the largest
and most powerful.
Your alliance could be the key
to defeating the Horde.
The Horde hasn't threatened us here.
Only because the Kingdom of Snows
is so out of the way
it doesn't matter to Hordak right now.
Joining the Rebellion
is obviously your best bet.
The Kingdom of Snows
has defended itself perfectly well
for thousands of years.
We do not need your help
or your Rebellion.
Please continue to enjoy the Ball.
[all laughing]
[Bow] Perfuma was just telling me
about a winged horse
that ate all the apples in Plumeria!
Where have you been?
[groans] I told you, winning over Frosta.
Actually, scratch that.
Failing to win over Frosta.
Are you okay?
Why does it bother you so much?
It doesn't! Bow can hang out
with whoever he wants. I just...
[groans] I never had
that many friends, okay?
It's always just been me and Bow.
But now, what if he likes
his new friends better than me?
-What if everyone does?
-That's not gonna happen, Glimmer.
Trust me, Bow isn't the type to just leave
his old friends behind, and neither am...
I.
Revered hostess, you can't let them in.
They're from the Horde.
Revered Hostess,
Princess Scorpia was invited,
as per the rules of this Ball.
Rules which I personally have
the utmost respect for.
-You do not!
-[Frosta] Princess Adora.
The rules state clearly
that all princesses
and their chosen guests are welcome.
They're up to something, I can feel it.
You have to--
That's enough!
You look at me and see a child,
but I have worked
too hard to gain respect,
only to throw it away
because you feel they're up to something.
For centuries, the All-Princess Ball
has been neutral ground.
I will not dishonor that legacy.
Scorpia is a princess.
Princesses get plus ones. They stay.
[Adora] Hmm.
[gasps]
[both grunting]
Teenagers.
Really, Adora? I'm shocked.
We're not breaking any rules.
Didn't you read the invite?
I know you're plotting something.
From now to the second the ball ends,
I'll be watching.
Wherever the two of you go, I go.
Suit yourself. Have fun with following us!
[grumbles] Glimmer, you get Scorpia,
I'll take Catra.
[pop music playing]
[woman] Oh!
[crowd gasping]
[sighs]
[chuckles]
[Scorpia] Mm. Mm. Wow, that is good.
Oh, what is--?
I don't even know what's in this.
What? Sir? Garçon? What's in this?
Bow! Wait up!
Glimmer. Hi.
There's something I need to tell you.
I know things between us
have been weird all night.
So, I just wanted to say--
-It's all right. I accept your--
-I forgive you.
You forgive me?
Glimmer, I'm allowed
to hang out with other people.
Bow, don't you see? That's how it starts!
Then suddenly everyone has new friends
and nobody needs me anymore,
-and then I'm all alone!
-What are you talking about?
You have me, plus Adora,
and everyone who joined the Rebellion.
That's what I'm talking about!
It used to be the two of us,
and now everything's changing!
I don't want you to leave me behind.
No one is leaving you behind.
I wanted to hang out with you and Adora
and Perfuma tonight,
but you're the one who keeps
being weird and leaving.
I know change is scary, Glimmer,
but you don't get to take it out on me.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I am going to get my cummerbund,
because it's freezing in here.
We'll talk later, okay?
[gasps]
-Princess Prom. Hour two...
-Don't touch her!
[yells]
You're right. This is a much better
vantage point for my observations.
Hi, Adora.
Have you met my new assistant?
She brought snacks.
She stole my food, and then asked me
to spy on people with her.
Is this what love feels like?
Entrapta, she's from the Horde.
The people the Rebellion are fighting?
The Rebellion you're a part of.
Oh. Well, in that case,
we should keep a better eye on her.
She just walked away.
[groans]
Is that a...? [gasps] Oh, no!
Princess Scorpia is planting heat bombs!
We have to stop her!
[footsteps approaching]
What are you doing? Let me go! Let--
It is my solemn duty as hostess
to now announce,
it is time for the first dance
of the ball.
-[all cheering]
-[shouts]
[pop music playing over speakers]
[groans]
I don't know about you,
but I am having a blast.
Whatever it is you're planning,
it won't work.
You sure?
[sobs] I got into a fight with Bow,
and he won't wanna be friends
with me anymore
and I don't know where Scorpia is!
-What? Glimmer, don't--
-Have you seen Bow?
He went to get his cummerbund,
but that was a while ago.
Right about the same time
that Horde Princess left.
Wait, do you mean Scorpia?
Glimmer, when did you last see Bow?
A while ago. Isn't he with Perfuma?
No. Perfuma says he's been gone
this entire time.
Maybe my plan won't work.
But then again...
maybe it already has.
Say, where's your friend Bow?
[groaning then shouting]
-[crowd gasping]
-Oh, no.
-What did you do to him?
-[laughs] Nothing permanent.
-[woman] How dare she?
-Tell me what you did with him--
[grunting]
Revered hostess, she's got--
Princess Ball is a ceremony of unity.
Violence is strictly forbidden.
-You don't understand.
-I understand perfectly.
As hostess, in accordance with the rules
set down over the centuries,
I hereby revoke your invitation.
You are to leave my kingdom
and never, ever--
[all gasping and shouting]
Remain calm! Stop!
Glimmer! Catra has Bow.
You have to find him now!
Catra. What did you do?
I did nothing. Scorpia, Lonnie, and Kyle,
on the other hand, were very busy.
-It was fun distracting you, though.
-This isn't a game!
People are gonna get hurt.
It's never been a game to me.
I'm after something bigger,
and no one is going to stop me.
[grunting]
Bow? Bow!
Where are you? [gasps]
Get away from him!
[shouting]
-No!
-[thud]
[shouts]
[shouting]
[grunting]
[Sea Hawk] Ooh.
Ha. Trapped.
You wish.
[grunting]
[grunts]
[grunting and shouting]
-Ha!
-[screams]
[both screaming]
Hang on! I can get us out of this.
Oh, Adora, I don't want you to.
[gasps] Catra!
[gasps]
[laughs]
See you later, princess.
[sobbing]