[laughing]
Check this thing out.
You've got to admit, Shadow Weaver,
in a single mission,
I inflicted more damage on the Rebellion
than anyone else.
I succeeded where even you failed.
-Shadow Weaver.
-[Shadow Weaver] My Lord.
I commend you on the capture
of the Princess of Bright Moon.
Queen Angella has been given
until the morning's moonrise
to surrender herself to our forces.
Thank you, Lord Hordak.
I thought you would be pleased
with my work.
You have proven your worth to me. Today.
Your worth? I'm the one who brought back
the Princess of Bright Moon. Not you.
[Shadow Weaver]
You're under my command, Force Captain.
Therefore, anything you manage to do right
is credited to me.
-So I do the work and you get the glory?
-Sometimes that's just the way of things.
[groaning]
Welcome to the Fright Zone, Princess.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Your majesty.
[Angella] I should've never let her
leave this castle.
And now, I'm faced
with an impossible decision.
As leader of the Rebellion,
how can I surrender myself to our enemy?
And yet, as a mother, how do I--?
[sighs]
I'm going to accept Hordak's terms.
Glimmer is all I have.
You can't. We have no guarantee the Horde
will hold up their end of the bargain.
We could end up losing you, too.
A rescue attempt is too risky.
If we had She-Ra we might have a chance,
but without the Sword of Protection...
[sighs] There has to be another way.
We can't just give up.
I can rescue them. I know the Fright Zone.
I'll find a way to get them back.
-How are you going to do that?
-I... I don't know yet.
But I'll think of something, I promise.
I'll bring them home.
[sobbing]
Huh?
What are you all doing here?
We're the Princess Alliance.
And the Horde took one of our own.
-We're ready for our first mission.
-Let's go get our friends back.
[alarm buzzes]
Dinner rations, prisoner.
Ow!
-Hey. What's your name?
-Me? You're talking to me?
Sure. Is that all right?
Uh, I guess, but no one ever talks to me.
I'm Kyle.
Hey, Kyle. I'm Bow.
Can you do me a favor?
Can you tell me
where they're holding the princess?
-Princess?
-She's my best friend.
No one will let me talk to her
or even tell me if she's okay.
Ah, I'm sure she's fine. Maybe.
Or she's not. I don't know.
Do you know where she is?
No, that kind of information
is classified.
-They wouldn't tell me.
-Help me get a message to her.
Uh, uh...
-I better be leaving now.
-No, wait.
-I like your shirt.
-Kyle!
[Adora] Okay. This is the Horde prison.
Glimmer and Bow are being held inside.
Entrapta, this perfume bottle is you.
Perfuma, you're nail polish.
Mermista, lipstick.
Ew, do you know
what that stuff is made of?
I'll be this knife.
I feel like Perfuma should be
the perfume bottle.
That makes the most logical sense.
Maybe I could be a flower.
Could I be this miniature
painted model of Bow?
No. Those represent Bow and Glimmer.
And this one's mine.
Bow made them for us.
Okay, just... Everyone, focus!
Our entry point will be here,
near the Horde's scrapyard.
It's close to the prison
and lightly guarded.
Perfuma and Entrapta
will access the security tower
and wait for my signal
to disable the lights.
Mermista will access the Fright Zone's
sewer system.
She'll swim through the pipes
into the building and open the door.
I'm sorry, Mermista will what?
I know it sounds bad, but you're the one
who can breathe underwater.
[groaning]
Super gross.
[Adora] Sea Hawk and I
will take up position by the entrance.
The two of us will neutralize
any guards on patrol,
Entrapta and Perfuma will regroup
on our position
and the team will enter
when Mermista opens the door.
Excellent plan. Adventure!
[groaning]
[rat squeaking]
Hmm?
[sighs]
[grumbles]
[shrieking]
Mermista should be in place by now.
Adora's signal.
Fright Zone log, day one.
I can barely contain
my excitement! Ha-ha.
Hmm. The Horde's using
an outdated wiring system.
It really would work so much better
if I just consolidated these conduits
-and rerouted the current here...
-Entrapta?
Now would be a good time for those lights.
Oh, right.
[grunting]
[alarm wailing]
-[guard gasps] What happened?
-We go on three.
Ready? One--
Forward!
[grunting and shouting]
I said on three.
I got excited.
-Where's Mermista?
-She must've gotten held up.
Come on. We need to secure the guards.
Entrapta? Entrapta?
[sighs]
[beeping and whirring nearby]
The subject appears to be harvesting
scrap components, possibly for reuse.
-Fascinating.
-Entrapta.
-We're supposed to meet the others.
-I know. I was waiting for you.
Huh. How very considerate. Let's go.
Oh, ha.
[groans]
So we don't get separated.
Psst.
Halt. Who are you?
Me? I'm the inspector.
I'm here to inspect all the things.
Inspector?
Inspector! Oh, of course.
I must have forgotten you were coming.
We're long overdue for an inspection,
I do have to admit it,
but I can assure you we are up to code.
Wha...? How did this happen?
We had a plan.
Actually, you kind of lost me
at that perfume bottle.
Where have you two been?
I tried to get here sooner,
but harmonious teamwork
with Entrapta can be a challenge.
This isn't a game. It's the Horde.
Glimmer and Bow are being held captive
in this building and now Sea Hawk is gone.
Okay. All right, everyone calm down.
Maybe we could try
a simple breathing exercise.
[chuckles] Deep calming breaths. Hmm.
[alarm wailing]
Come on. We're going in.
Could you not?
Huh? What happened to you?
Uh, the sewer happened to me.
We can't waste any more time.
Bow and Glimmer need us.
-Can I get a thank you?
-Thank you.
[shouts]
[chattering nearby]
We need to get to an information port.
I'll hack into the database
and identify the cell block
Glimmer and Bow are being held in.
Hey, where's the geeky princess?
[chuckles nervously] Okay, she is really
putting a crimp in my harmony!
Don't worry.
We'll find Entrapta and Sea Hawk,
and we'll recue Glimmer and Bow.
I don't know. That sounds like a lot.
But you know me,
I'm totally up for anything.
Fright Zone Log, day one continued.
Keypads appear in every corridor
and are capable of giving status updates
on multiple systems.
Wow. Hello there, little guy.
[laughs]
Hello to you, too. [chuckles]
[Glimmer groaning]
[grunting]
[yelling]
I should warn you, Princess.
Any attempt to teleport
through these restraints
will only cause you pain.
[groans]
It seems my Black Garnet
and your powers don't mix.
Besides, your mother will be here soon.
I know all about you and your mind games,
Shadow Weaver.
Adora told me, so, save it.
And, by the way, she's not a fan.
[Shadow Weaver] I'm not playing games.
What I said about Queen Angella is true.
She's coming to surrender herself
in exchange for your safety.
Oh. It's a shame, the toll this Rebellion
has taken on your family.
First, you lose your father and now...
She-Ra will stop you.
There is no She-Ra.
We have the sword.
Not Adora. There will be no one left
to stop the Horde.
In a few hours, Bright Moon will fall
and Etheria will be ours to rule.
[grunting]
[yelling]
Ooh. Tsk, tsk. Careful now.
It would be a shame if we had no princess
to exchange for the queen.
[Glimmer groans]
Well, you Horde types run a tight ship,
I must say.
Everything seems to be up to code.
Yes, indeed, entirely up to code.
You pass with flying colors.
Now, unless you have something else
for me to inspect,
I should get home
to my inspector children.
-You know, you look familiar.
-[gulps]
Perhaps you've seen me in your dreams?
No, that's not it. Princess Prom.
That's where I know you from.
I knew it would come to me.
You were there with that mermaid.
She has a name!
I mean, no, that wasn't me.
You're with the Rebellion.
Now, as a scrupulous inspector,
threats... [clears throat]
normally wouldn't work on me.
But in this case, uh,
perhaps we can reach a compromise?
"Duck"?
Ooh, where?
-Oh! Duck.
-[Scorpia screams]
Hi.
Oh! That was a top-notch rescue.
To be honest, I wasn't sure
which one I was gonna hit.
Okay, I found Bow's cell,
but I can't find Glimmer anywhere.
They must be holding her somewhere else.
This isn't good. [gasps]
-What should we do?
-I am not going back in the sewer.
It's okay. This is my new friend, Emily.
I reprogrammed her.
Where have you been?
-Where have you been?
-It doesn't matter.
We're all together. Let's finish this.
Bow's cell is in section B, level 20.
We'll get him out first
and then figure out where Glimmer is.
Entrapta, can you get us up there?
Yes, I can. I mean, maybe.
I don't know. I'm definitely gonna try.
[laughing]
This is gonna be fun.
Okay. Sea Hawk, Perfuma, you're with me.
I'll keep an eye on this one,
in case she tries
to befriend any more robots.
On to the rescue!
[grunting]
-[Kyle] Bow. Bow!
-Kyle?
I'm supposed to be in the barracks.
Lonnie made me cover her latrine duty.
-What's going on?
-I found out where your friend is.
Shadow Weaver has her
in the Black Garnet chamber.
Oh. That sounds bad.
Uh, yeah. It's pretty bad.
But she's alive, at least.
Shadow Weaver is planning to ransom her
in exchange for the Queen.
-Why are you telling me all this?
-I don't know.
I guess, because you're the first person
who's ever listened to me.
I mean, I'm being held prisoner, so...
I don't know that I have a choice,
but sure!
[all shouting]
[gasps]
Whoops! That's not right.
[grunting]
[grumbles]
Entrapta.
[shouting]
[all shout]
Perfuma.
Hmm? [grunts]
Hang on.
You think you can just come back here?
[grunting and shouting]
-I need to save my friends.
-We were your friends.
[roars]
[Entrapta laughs, Mermista screams]
[grunting]
-[alarm buzzes]
-[Sea Hawk grunts]
[all shouting and grunting]
[grumbles]
-Adora, are you all right?
-Thanks to you.
Great hit, Perfuma.
No one's ever asked for my help before.
People don't think
I can do anything right.
-Mm-hmm. That seems tough.
-[thudding and clanging]
Why am I telling you this?
I shouldn't be here.
I'm gonna get in so much trouble
if I get caught.
No, wait. Um... I mean,
we're just talking. [chuckles]
How much trouble could you get in
for talking?
Oh! You'd be surprised. I get in trouble
for everything around here.
Uh, that doesn't seem fair.
I know! But then I thought
how brave you are
for wanting to save your friend.
And maybe, if I helped you,
I could be your friend too.
Uh, friends, sure, definitely.
We can be friends. [chuckles]
[grunting]
[roars]
[shouts]
Good team, geek Princess.
-Goodbye. Bow!
-[Kyle yelling]
[laughs] We're here to save you.
-Adora.
-Bow. Bow, where's Glimmer?
Shadow Weaver has her
in the Black Garnet chamber.
-Adora, what are we gonna do?
-[alarm wailing]
Come on.
[soldiers shouting nearby]
-Can you get it open?
-I just need a little more time.
[soldiers shouting]
[Entrapta laughing]
This vent system leads
to where you can steal a skiff.
Each chamber needs to be sealed
and purged before you can move on.
The doors will only stay open
for a few seconds, so keep up the pace.
-Adora, what are you doing?
-Don't worry about me.
I'm gonna buy you some time
and find Glimmer. Meet you there, okay?
Adora!
[Bow grunts]
I surrender. Take me to see Shadow Weaver.
[gasps] Glimmer. I'm here.
Don't worry, everything will be okay.
I'll save you.
-What have you done to her?
-[Shadow Weaver] Leave us.
Report to the Force Captain barracks
and pack your things.
Now that Adora is back,
there's no need for you there.
Seriously?
After everything I've done for you,
it's still her you want?
I said, go!
Shadow Weaver,
I'll stay here with you willingly,
but you have to let Glimmer go first.
-Adora, no.
-Glimmer, are you okay?
You are correct, Adora.
You shall stay willingly,
because I am going to wipe your mind.
You'll have no memory of She-Ra
or the time you spent with the Rebellion.
Everything will be as it once was.
As for the princess, once I'm done,
you'll be happy to have her
as your prisoner.
-No. Adora!
-[Adora shouting]
We need to go back for Glimmer and Adora.
We need to do what Adora said.
They'll make it out
and we'll be ready with the skiff.
No princess will be left behind.
[Adora groaning]
[screaming]
[grunting and shouting]
[shouts]
[Shadow Weaver groans]
[panting]
Adora? Are you okay?
Do you know who I am?
[groans]
Glimmer.
[chuckles]
We made it. This way, to the vehicle bay.
[Emily beeping]
-Wait. Emily.
-Entrapta.
No!
[alarm wailing]
[groaning]
-Glimmer, what's happening?
-I don't know.
-I can't teleport.
-What?
Catra.
-What are you doing?
-Take it.
This is not because I like you.
-Catra.
-Just get out of here.
[Adora] For the honor of Grayskull.
[grunts]
There they are.
[grunting]
[Glimmer laughing]
Glimmer.
Wait, where's Entrapta?
Entrapta didn't make it.
What do you mean?
She's gone.
-Then, we have to go back for her.
-No, she's--
She's really gone.
[sobs]