[bird caws]
How could I let this happen?
-Adora, it's not your fault.
-It is my fault.
Entrapta's gone because of my plan.
This only happened
because we were all together.
Mermista's right, being together
makes us vulnerable.
Maybe there's a reason
the Princess Alliance fell apart before.
Maybe this whole thing was a bad idea.
Mermista, no, you can't say that.
Whatever.
I don't want to be a part of it anymore.
Sea Hawk, take me home.
[Glimmer gasps]
[sobbing]
Oh, Glimmer!
Are you hurt?
[Angella grunting]
Mom, you're crushing me.
-[Bow laughs]
-[Glimmer grumbles]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Mom! I'm fine, cut it out!
I will not cut it out.
I've been beside myself with worry.
You usually teleport out of my embraces.
-What's going on?
-Nothing. I just need to recharge.
That's all.
Of course. Guards, carry my daughter
to the moonstone chamber at once.
I don't need to be carried, I can walk.
You're embarrassing me.
Fine. Then you have time
to tell me what happened.
I received word of Entrapta's loss.
Well, Glimmer? Bow? Adora?
Someone tell me what happened.
-Commander, it's my fault.
-The thing is...
Leave my friends alone.
-Give us a minute.
-A minute?
You were being held by the Horde.
I have been going mad
telling myself awful stories
about what could've happened to you.
Jeez, Mom, relax.
I'm fine. We'll talk later.
This conversation isn't over.
I'm-- I'm sorry.
[groaning]
-It's happening more often.
-Does it hurt?
No, not much.
We need to tell your mom.
-She'll know what to do.
-No.
Glimmer, Shadow Weaver did something
to your powers. You can't teleport and,
whatever this is, keeps happening.
I don't want my mom freaking out
any more than she already is. Okay?
Besides, I always feel better
after I recharge, so...
Then it's agreed.
I'll recharge, stop glitching.
Then my mom never has to know.
[Hordak] Not only did you lose
the princess known as Glimmer,
but I learned that you've known
Adora was She-Ra all along.
[Shadow Weaver] Now you see why I felt
it was so important to bring her back.
[Hordak] All you did
was invite attack from an enemy combatant
with detailed knowledge of our operations.
If I had known,
I never would have agreed
to your foolish plan.
[chuckles] Yeah, bad plan.
Wasn't it your--? Oh.
-I can feel you watching me.
-I am not.
[Adora grunting]
Ah.
See, I told you. Just needed to re--
-[shouting]
-[Bow gasps]
-It didn't work.
-Work? It made it worse.
Glimmer? Are you up there?
[shouts]
Uh, guys? We have a problem.
We cannot let my mom see me like this!
There you are, Glimmer.
Are you feeling better?
[chuckles] Whoa, Mom,
can't a girl recharge in private?
-Anyway, we were just leaving. Bye!
-Is everything all right? Glimmer?
Glimmer, do not walk away from me.
I just wanted to talk.
Boy, Hordak really let
Shadow Weaver have it.
Did you see the look on her face?
Yes. Well, I mean, I think.
It's hard to tell with the mask and all.
[robot beeping]
[Catra] Serves her right.
If she wants to take credit for my plans,
she can take the blame, too.
-Oh! What is it?
-Shh.
[whispering] Oh, sorry. What is it?
[sniffing]
[in normal voice]
Yeah. Yeah, that's-- That's concrete.
[shouts]
Hi.
[sighs]
Maybe it's like a cold.
I've never been sick before.
Having an immortal mother
has some advantages.
-What do you do when you have a cold?
-Remain out of sight.
What? Displays of physical weakness
are strongly discouraged in the Horde.
And they're right.
I haven't been training enough,
and look what happened! [grunting]
Stop it, Adora. They're not right.
Okay, cold. Um...
Lots of liquids and, uh, rest.
[gasps] I'll make soup!
Great, and I'll nap. I bet when I wake up
I'll be good as new.
Yeah, just gotta let it run its course.
[groans] Why did I make my bed so high?
Give me a boost?
[both grunting]
[both shouting]
[crashing]
[gasps] We're not letting anything
just run its course. You're getting worse.
No, I'm not.
[shouting]
Okay, maybe a little.
Look, you got sick
because of whatever dark magic
Shadow Weaver made with the black garnet.
Maybe the sword can heal you.
She-Ra healed the trees in Plumeria.
Uh... Sort of, not really.
Well, She-Ra definitely fixed
the Sea Gate.
Glimmer's not machinery.
You don't know how to fully control
She-Ra's powers yet.
No offense.
This is a great idea.
She-Ra will fix me, and then everything
will be back to normal.
Mm-hmm. How hard can it be?
-Did no one hear what I just...? [groans]
-[Adora] For the honor of Grayskull!
[Entrapta grunting]
[door beeping]
-Prisoner.
-That's Entrapta.
I know her name, I was just...
Ugh, never mind. Lord Hordak himself
tasked me with your interrogation.
So, there's no use resisting.
I don't care what it takes.
I'm going to drag
the Rebellion's plans out of you.
-Ooh! What's that?
-[Catra] What? Hey!
[Scorpia] Catra! Oh! Oh, oh, there you go.
Fascinating.
Give it back.
-Oh, I like that thing. Can I have it?
-No. And stop. I'm interrogating you.
Okay, then. What do you want to know?
Why were you hiding out
in the Fright Zone?
I was waiting for my friends to get back.
They had trouble finding me before.
So, I figured I'd make it easier for them
and just stay put right here.
They left you.
No, no, they're my friends,
they'll be back.
Say, your tail secretes some kind
of paralyzing agent, right?
Do you think
I could have a sample, to study?
Hey, you can't touch
another woman's tail without asking!
Some friends. They left you,
and they're not coming back.
Isn't that just like Adora?
She left me behind, too.
Like I was nothing.
And me. I mean, I didn't want to go,
but she could've at least asked.
Adora got her precious Bow
and Glimmer back.
All these princesses care about
is people who are just like them.
But you're not like them, are you?
[Entrapta] Fright Zone log, hour 45.
Is that right?
I don't know if that's right,
it was hard to tell in the walls.
Hour 45, that's--
That's too many hours.
This angry feline person
seems to be correct.
They're not coming back for me.
You wouldn't have to be pretend
to be something you're not with the Horde.
Think of what you could accomplish here.
What we could accomplish, together.
I've made more progress
on my work in secret here
than I did in a whole non-secret life
out there.
They should see. Horde technology
gives me so much to work with.
Emily's the most advanced bot
I've ever built.
Wait, who's Emily?
Oh! How rude, allow me to introduce you.
[Scorpia grunts]
I gotcha, I gotcha, I gotcha.
Those princesses have no idea
who they've left behind.
Ooh!
The... Eternia... heal!
Heal...
Glimmer.
Who's ready to stop messing around
with sharp objects? Hey, look, I am!
-Maybe if you point it at me?
-Or, unpopular opinion,
don't point a sword
directly at our friend.
It's fine, I got this.
Maybe it's like a motion.
Like a jabbing motion? Or a strike.
Do you want to get hit with a sword?
Can everyone please be quiet? I have it!
[grunts]
Am I the only one who cares
about sword safety around here?
[gasps] I think it's working.
Yup, definitely working.
I'm pretty sure I feel something.
[shouting]
[grunts]
[Bow] Sword safety!
Honestly, I don't think
anybody's gonna notice. Oh.
Sorry again. About the wall.
-Don't worry about it.
-You're not mad? People usually get mad.
Are you kidding? I'm impressed.
You rebuilt that robot, I mean Emily,
all on your own?
While living in the vents?
Sure did. Not only that,
but she's better than ever.
Stronger, increased weapons capabilities,
and affectionate, too.
Who knows how much more powerful
she could be if I just had access
to a little First Ones tech.
You don't have any here, do you?
-First what?
-First Ones tech.
You know, advanced technology
left behind by a lost civilization?
Makes our modern innovations
look like children's toys?
I've been attempting to integrate
First Ones tech
into my experiments for years,
but my understanding
of their code is still rudimentary.
If I could just find the key
to their language,
there's no telling what I could build.
Such a find could yield
almost unlimited power. [laughing]
And where would one find this tech?
It's buried all over the planet.
It gives off a signal that can be traced.
Lately, I've been tracking
the strongest signal I've ever seen.
It must be a massive stash.
-Where?
-[Scorpia] Ugh.
Huh. [chuckles]
I mean, uh, where?
I've triangulated the signal
to somewhere in the Whispering Woods.
The whole shifting landscape thing
makes for a complicated variable,
but I've created a map
that's accurate within two quadrants.
How do I get my hands on this map?
Like any good scientist,
I carry everything I need on my person.
[Catra grunting]
I'm not sure if we can trust her yet.
But if she's telling the truth,
this could give us a huge advantage
over the Rebellion.
Hordak will finally see
how much more valuable I am
than Shadow Weaver.
I bet he'll promote you to...
What comes after Force Captain?
Keep an eye on Entrapta
while I go see if this pans out.
I hope it does,
I wanna build something big.
Oh, sorry, my bad.
Which hair part was in which thingy?
What good am I
if I can't even heal one princess?
[grunts] Why even carry a sword?
-[knocking on door]
-[gasps]
Everybody, just act normal.
Mom, we're busy.
I won't be long. You are requested
for dinner with me tonight. Alone.
But Mom!
I'm really tired.
Can't I just stay in my room and rest?
I'm sorry,
I don't know why I said request.
It's not a request.
You are required to have dinner with me
because I'm your mother and...
I'm also the queen, so I can make you.
Yikes. She's playing the queen card.
No need to answer.
I'll see you in an hour.
[shouting]
That's it. I can't stay here
and be useless. Bow is right.
-I don't know how to use my powers.
-I didn't say that. Or not that exactly.
The Horde has a lot of things wrong.
Okay, pretty much everything.
But one thing they are right about
is training.
And how can I train
if I don't know anything about She-Ra?
I'm going to go somewhere I can learn.
And then I'm gonna fix you, Glimmer.
[gasps] How? Can you do it in an hour?
Probably not,
since I'm not sure where I'm going.
I need to find the place
Madame Razz took me.
It's some sort of beacon.
I can't explain it,
but I know I can get answers there.
Running away. Great idea.
I won't have to go to dinner with my mom.
-I'll get my things.
-No, I have to do this on my own.
[shouts]
-[Adora crashes] Ow.
-She's okay.
I hope she stays that way.
-Going somewhere?
-Like I'd tell you.
I've got a lead on something big,
and I'm not about to let you
take all the credit again.
Not that it worked out
so great for you last time.
[breathing heavily]
Don't worry about that thing with Hordak.
I've got loads of experience
being yelled at.
Mostly by you, actually.
You get used to it.
I will not get used
to mediocrity like you.
And I certainly don't need your pity.
I was hard on you, I won't deny it.
And I won't apologize.
I just wanted to prepare you
for the world.
I wanted you to be strong.
Yeah, well, congratulations,
I'm plenty strong now.
And I don't need you.
[Bow] Listen, Glimmer,
I appreciate you trying,
but you can't protect me anymore.
We have to tell your mom.
We're not telling anybody's mom!
And what do you mean, protect you?
Isn't it obvious? This is all my fault!
If I hadn't gone to prom with Perfuma,
we wouldn't have been separated.
I wouldn't have gotten kidnapped,
and you wouldn't be sick.
See? All my fault!
That's crazy! It's obviously my fault!
I let myself get distracted.
I shouldn't have been so weird
about you hanging out with someone else.
I'm sorry, Bow.
You can't be sorry
when I'm trying to be sorry.
But your sorry is wrong
and mine is right.
You know what? Let's just hug.
[grunting]
-I'm glitching, aren't I?
-It hurts so much.
How am I gonna get through dinner
without my mom noticing?
Ah. Ooh. We start a fire,
then she'll have to cancel.
Just a small one?
It was definitely this way.
I think.
[grunting]
Oh!
That rock looks familiar.
[sighs] Because I passed it an hour ago.
I gave the staff the night off
so it could be just us.
And I made your favorite.
Well, I didn't make it,
but I had the kitchen make it
before I gave them the night off.
Thanks.
We've hardly had a chance to talk
since you returned.
Well, you know, not much to talk about.
Not much to talk about?
You were kidnapped!
And you lost a friend
during the escape and--
I get it, Mom. I failed.
-That's not what I--
-[shouting]
Stop! Make it stop!
Glimmer, what's happening to you?
What aren't you telling me?
Don't yell at me!
I know I messed everything up, okay?
-I know I'm a big disappointment.
-What are you talking about?
Entrapta died trying to rescue me,
the Princess Alliance is over,
and Shadow Weaver did something
to my powers!
I'm sorry I couldn't be perfect like you.
You have no idea
what it feels like to be such a screwup!
I don't know how you feel?
I got your father killed!
I ordered the battle
your father perished in.
-I've never forgiven myself.
-I-- I didn't know that.
Yes, well, you never talk to me.
-Why didn't you tell me you were sick?
-Because I was ashamed.
I acted without thinking,
the exact thing
you're always telling me not to do.
I teleported right into their trap.
The Alliance is over, and I'm to blame.
Oh, Glimmer, I'm the one who failed.
If I hadn't let the first Alliance
fall apart after your father died,
none of this would be happening.
You feel like a failure?
Don't make the same mistake I did.
I should have kept fighting.
And you should, too.
But the other princesses, they all quit.
-You don't think the Rebellion is done?
-With my daughter leading it?
Not a chance.
Even if my powers are gone?
We'll figure it out. Together.
[voices whispering]
[grumbles]
[grunts] This thing is useless.
No. But I've been walking
in a straight line!
[grunts]
I'm trying to help!
Why are you stopping me?
[grunting]
[gasps]
[grumbles, then yells]
I should've known better
than to trust a princess.
[voices whispering]
Hmm?
[shudders]
[whining]
Just let me fix this. Please, I--
I can't let anyone else get hurt.
Fine. You win.
You want me to be weak?
Well, I am. And I'm afraid.
Because I'm no good at any of this.
[gasps]
[grunting and shouting]
I'll never find this magical tech.
If it even existed in the first place.
On second thought.
[Catra chuckles]
Hey, Adora.