[grunts]
Hello? [echoing]
I carry the sword of She-Ra,
and I've come here for help.
Is anyone there?
Greetings, administrator.
What is your query?
Oh. I need your help to heal my friend.
She's been cursed.
I don't know how to save her.
The legends say that She-Ra
could heal people using this sword.
How do I do that?
What is your query?
Not this again. [scoffs]
For the honor of Grayskull!
-How about now?
-Administrator detected.
Welcome, She-Ra.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
One more time.
What can you tell me about this sword?
Subject: the Sword of Protection.
Classification: portable Runestone
keyed exclusively to administrator She-Ra,
Princess of Power.
How can I use this sword
to heal my friend?
Query not recognized.
[groans]
[sighs] Legends say the sword has
healing powers. Is that true?
One of the Sword of Protection's
many intended functions
is to heal and restore balance.
How do I do that?
Query not recognized.
How can I use the sword to heal people?
One of the Sword of Protection's
many intended functions
is to heal and restore balance.
Okay, is there someone else
I can talk to?
Query not recognized.
[grunts] Okay.
-Let me talk to Light Hope.
-Light Hope.
Light Hope. That's her name, isn't it?
The woman I saw when I touched the sword
for the first time. Where is she?
Yes, Light Hope is here.
She has been waiting for you.
Can I talk to her?
You will meet her soon enough.
First, you must let go.
What's that supposed to mean?
You are not ready yet. You must let go.
Let go of what?
[both shouting]
Hey! Watch it.
Catra? What are you doing here?
Unauthorized presence detected.
Security protocol activated.
Not again.
What just happened?
This isn't good.
You're not supposed to be in here.
[screeching]
[both gasp]
-What are those?
-Also not good.
[grunting]
Come on! We need to run.
[screeching and roaring]
What's going on?
Why are those things trying to kill us?
They're trying to kill you.
This place sees you as an invader.
Well, can't you tell them to stop?
No, I can't tell them to stop. Clearly,
nothing in here is listening to me!
-Adora?
-Stand back.
[grunting and shouting]
What are you doing?
[both coughing]
You shouldn't be here, Catra.
Those things aren't gonna stop
until they get you,
and since I'm protecting you,
they see me as a threat, too.
Uh, good thing I didn't ask you
to protect me.
Wait, you know, what--
Okay. Why are you here anyway?
How did you find this place?
It sent up a beam of light a mile high.
It wasn't hard.
Does Shadow Weaver know you're here?
I'd say Shadow Weaver's
got bigger problems right now.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Wait. No. I know what this is about.
Ugh, I knew you'd be weird
about me letting you escape.
I told you, it's not because I like you.
I mean, I didn't-- I didn't say anything.
Anyway, what are you doing out here?
Where are your new best friends?
I thought you did everything together.
Oh, my friends?
The ones you kidnapped
and held for ransom?
The ones you let Shadow Weaver
imprison and curse?
Yeah, obviously. What other friends
would I be talking about?
Come on. Those things will be back
any minute, we need to get out.
Well, we don't need to go together.
You do your weird
little magic quest thing,
I'll find my own way.
[sighs]
[Catra groans]
-Another dead end.
-No, it's not.
Eternia.
Eh, long story.
Cool, you found
the Infinite Darkness Room.
Have fun, I'm gonna find
another way around.
Uh... Where did the door go?
Wait, I think I see something.
Hello? Light Hope?
-What's--?
-[both shout]
Huh?
-What game are you playing?
-Whoa, whoa.
I have no idea what's going on.
There's no way we can be
in the Fright Zone.
So what is this?
Another Shadow Weaver mind trick?
I doubt it. Now let go of me.
Hey, you! Guard!
Uh, hello?
[laughing]
Hey, Adora! This isn't real!
-Adora? Adora?
-Catra?
Adora!
-Hey, Adora, there's a--
-Shh.
-[grunts] Does it look broken to you?
-It's not broken. You're fine.
-[shrieks] I'm bleeding!
-You're not bleeding!
Why would you try and pick a fight
with Octavia anyway?
I didn't do anything.
All I did was exist near her.
And scratch her on the eyeball.
And call her a dumb-face.
-Catra--
-What? She has a dumb face.
Where is she?
-Hey, Octavia! You're a dumb face!
-Huh?
[roaring]
-She's coming! [laughing]
-[young Adora] Run!
[both laughing]
What was that?
It must have been some kind of simulation.
It's tapping into our memories.
Why, I have no idea.
Ugh. This place is so weird.
How can you deal
with all of this magic stuff?
I'm only dealing with it because I need
to figure out how to heal Glimmer
after someone got her cursed.
What do you want? An apology?
You're not getting one.
-Can I ask you something?
-[groans] Can I stop you?
[both gasp]
Why did you help me escape
after Shadow Weaver captured us?
Not this again.
It's the one thing I can't figure it out.
You didn't have to do that.
You could've gotten caught.
Why risk it? Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Did you really think
I'd just let Shadow Weaver
erase your memory?
I don't know. Probably.
Yeah, well...
You never did have too much faith in me.
[sighs] Can you blame me?
[chuckles] Not really.
It wasn't all bad growing up
in the Fright Zone, was it?
I mean, you still have
some good memories, right?
Of course I do.
But it doesn't change the fact
that the Horde is evil.
I had no choice. I couldn't go back.
Hey, I miss you, too.
Wha--? [scoffs] I don't miss you.
Get over yourself.
Not until you admit you like me.
-I don't like you.
-[laughs]
[shouting]
Oh, come on.
[shouting and grunting]
[laughing]
-[thump]
-Ow!
You okay?
[shouting and grunting]
[alarm buzzes]
[man] And there's our winner.
[grumbles]
Good work, cadet. I like your focus.
This win will definitely be reported back
to Lord Hordak.
What was that? Way to gang up on me.
You were fighting dirty.
-I was just leveling the field.
-Hey, you were awesome.
-Did I hurt you?
-No, I'm fine.
You're just lucky I let you win.
-Right.
-I'm serious.
If I came in first, people might
expect me to actually start doing stuff.
Trust me, second place suits me just fine.
Yeah, okay.
-Come on, let's cool down.
-In a minute, I'll meet you there.
Hey, guys, wait up!
-[all laughing]
-So cool. Yeah.
[sobbing]
[shrieks]
[computer] Unauthorized presence detected.
Security protocol activated.
[Catra screaming nearby]
Catra? Catra!
[both grunting]
Catra!
[muffled] Adora!
[screaming]
[grunting]
[chuckles]
[shouts]
Are you okay?
-I had it.
-Sure you did.
-We need to make sure we stay together.
-Will you stop telling me what to do?
I'm sick of this stupid place.
Let's just get out of here.
What is your problem?
I was trying to save you.
For the last time,
I don't need you to save me.
I've been doing just fine on my own.
No thanks to you.
Catra, wait.
I'm sorry for leaving.
I couldn't go back to the Fright Zone.
Not after I saw what the Horde
was really doing.
I never wanted to leave you.
You could come with me,
you could join the rebellion.
I know you're not a bad person, Catra.
You don't belong with the Horde.
[door opens]
Let's just get this over with.
[grunting]
Catra, wait up!
What's it like
being the world's slowest person?
[crashing]
[both laughing]
Whoa.
-[Catra gasps] It's open.
-We're definitely not allowed in there.
[both laughing]
You don't have to go in there.
[young Catra] Whoa.
Wow.
[shrieks]
-Maybe we should get out of here.
-[Shadow Weaver groaning]
[gasps]
-[Catra gasps]
-[Shadow Weaver] Get out!
Catra, you stay.
What do you think you're doing in here?
-We were just playing.
-[Shadow Weaver] Insolent child.
I've come to expect
such disgraceful behavior from you.
But I will not allow you
to drag Adora down as well.
Shadow Weaver, it wasn't her fault,
it was my idea, too.
[Shadow Weaver] You have never been
anything more than a nuisance to me.
I've kept you around this long
because Adora was fond of you.
But if you ever do anything to jeopardize
her future,
I will dispose of you myself.
Do you understand?
Please, stop.
[Shadow Weaver groans]
-She didn't mean to.
-Adora.
You must do a better job
of keeping her under control.
Do not let something like this
happen again.
[grunts] You always need
to play the hero, don't you?
I was only trying to protect you.
You never protected me.
Not in any way that would put you
on Shadow Weaver's bad side.
Admit it. You love being her favorite.
That's not true.
Oh, yeah? When you left,
who do you think took the fall for you?
Who was protecting me then?
You don't have to let Shadow Weaver
treat you like that anymore.
You can leave, just like I did.
Oh, because I need to follow you
everywhere ou go?
I didn't mean it that way.
I don't want to leave.
What don't you understand about that?
I'm not afraid of Shadow Weaver anymore,
and I'm a better Force Captain
than you would've ever been.
You said you didn't care
about things like that.
Well, I was lying obviously!
Catra, just wait!
Why do you think I gave the sword
back to you in the Fright Zone?
I didn't want you to come back, Adora!
[screeching]
For the honor of-- [grunts]
Huh?
-You were fighting dirty.
-[Shadow Weaver] Insolent child.
-[Adora] I'm sorry, Catra.
-Let me out of here!
[groaning]
[young Catra crying]
Catra?
-[hisses]
-Catra, it's okay. It's just me.
It doesn't matter what they do to us.
You know?
You look out for me, I look out for you.
Nothing really bad can happen
as long as we have each other.
-You promise?
I promise.
Come on. Let's go back out.
[grunting and shouting]
Stop it. I'm not your enemy. Light Hope...
Just let me talk to Light Hope!
[metal crashing nearby]
[Catra grunting]
Catra?
Hey, Adora.
Catra, help me. Please.
This thing wouldn't work for me
if I tried, would it?
It only works for you.
Then again, you're special.
That's what Shadow Weaver always said.
Catra, what are you doing?
Ah, you know, it all makes sense now.
You've always been the one
holding me back.
You wanted me to think I needed you.
You wanted me to feel weak.
Every hero needs a sidekick, right?
Catra, no, that's not how it was.
[Catra laughs]
The sad thing is, I've spent all this time
hoping you'd come back to the Horde,
when really you leaving was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I am so much stronger
than anyone ever thought.
I wonder what I could've been
if I'd gotten rid of you sooner.
[shrieks]
I am sorry. I never meant to make you feel
like you were second best.
Please don't do this.
[sword clanging]
Bye, Adora.
I really am going to miss you.
Catra. Catra, no!
Adora.
You must let go.
[sobbing]
Ah. And then there's the day
Catra and I were on a boat together.
-Did I ever tell you about that?
-I'm pretty sure you did.
[rewinding]
[Scorpia on recording] Oh, one time,
Catra and I were on a boat together.
-That was the best day ever.
-Yup, you did.
I think that's when we really made
our connection, you know?
Did you ever meet someone
and you just instantly click?
[Entrapta] Yes,
it was like that with Emily.
What happened to you? You're filthy.
Are you okay? Do you need first aid?
Do you need to be nursed
tenderly back to health?
Scorpia, remember that little talk
we had about personal space?
Oh, right. Ten-foot radius.
-How'd it go? Did you find it?
-Uh, why is the princess loose?
Oh, right.
[grunts]
Seriously, though, did you find it?
An intact data crystal?
I have never seen one
so perfectly preserved.
This could be a game-changer.
Who knows what secrets it could contain?
[laughs]
Man, I knew Catra could do it.
It's like I was telling you.
She is the best friend ever.
[Catra] Just keep it down.
I'm going to bed.