[yelling]
-[Light Hope] Hello, Adora.
-[Hordak] Adora.
[all laughing]
[Catra] Every hero needs a sidekick.
-[Adora] For the honor of Grayskull!
-[Entrapta] I need a little more time.
[screams]
-Hello, Adora, you've come at last.
-[shrieks]
Light Hope,
I can't believe I'm really seeing you.
I mean, I've seen you... [chuckles]
In my brain, I think.
But this is real! [chuckles]
Is this real? Wait, am I dead?
I fell... I'm sorry. I'm freaking out.
-[clears throat] I'm Adora.
-Yes, I know.
I have been waiting for you
since you were an infant,
but I could not reach you.
And I could not protect you
from the Horde.
I watched you grow up from afar.
Wow, that's--
That's kinda creepy, honestly.
Creepy? Yes.
I have been called this before.
I chose this form so as not to alarm you.
But if it doesn't suit you,
I will choose another.
-Is this better?
-[shrieks]
Oh, no. That's, um--
That's actually way worse.
Forgive me. My human protocol
is many years out of date.
Allow me to select a new form
that you will find appealing.
Oh, no. Thank you. That's enough.
No, that's totally okay.
Please stop. [groans]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
But shouldn't she be... [grunting]
back by now?
She said she was... [groans]
going to get training to... [groans]
fix me!
How long is that going to take? Ow!
And what kind of monster
puts a chair here?
Okay. I'm worried, too, Glimmer,
but taking it out on the furniture
isn't going to help.
We can't sit here
and hope that she comes back eventually.
-We have to do something.
-Like what?
[knocking on door]
Princess, there's, uh,
something here to see you.
-Don't you mean someone?
-No, I mean something.
[whinnies]
Our horse!
I am my own horse.
Call me Swift Wind.
[both scream]
Our horse can talk!
I can speak my mind now, pretty crazy.
So, I'm thinking...
-He's a talking horse!
-As we've established now.
He has wings!
Okay, I'll give you a moment to freak out,
and then we need to talk.
[both gasping]
[blusters] Great.
I think Adora needs our help.
Since Adora transformed me,
I've been able to feel where she is
at all times. It's like instinct.
But now I feel a pull,
as if I'm being summoned to her side.
As part of Adora's herd, I need your help.
Will you come?
-Of course. Lead the way.
-But Glimmer, your glitching.
Is what got us into this.
Adora left to save me.
Now it's time for us to save her. You in?
Always. But I don't think
your mom is going to like us
leaving so soon after our mission.
She doesn't need to know.
We'll sneak out and be back
before my mom even realizes we're gone.
[shouts] Mom!
-[clearing throat]
-What are you doing here?
Coming to see why my guard
was escorting a horse into your room.
I like to think of myself
more as a role model for all horse kind.
I mean, uh, what talking horse?
What's happening?
You should get going
if you want to track down Adora.
You are not gonna stop us?
Glimmer, I told you I regretted giving up
after your father died.
I will not consign you
to the same regrets.
Commander Glimmer, I order you
to continue your mission to find Adora
and bring her back home.
Right away, Your Majesty.
Come on.
Uh, when we're back,
I'd like to talk about freeing
all the horses in your stables.
-I think that's--
-[grunting] Later.
Hey, I'm still talking
to the Queen! [neighs]
Please be careful.
Okay, I-- What is going on here?
Catra, you got my note.
The one you dropped on my head
from the air vent that says,
"Come to my lab"?
Yes, that's the one.
I've made great strides
in analyzing the data
from the First Ones data crystal
you brought me. Look.
-Where did this come from?
-Oh, you know, here and there, rooms.
Were there people in these rooms?
Well, not when I went back
to take the stuff.
[chuckles] You belong here with us.
So, the data... [squeals]
[whirring and chiming]
Ha! [laughing] Wow. Whoa.
[Entrapta]
Look at these readings. Incredible.
This seems to confirm my theories
about the techno-organic nature
of First Ones machinery,
resulting in thaumaturlogical
compatibility between magic and science!
[laughing]
I'm going to need you to try again.
But this time, talk like a normal person.
Scorpia seems like she understands.
Scorpia is drawing stick figures
holding hands.
I call it Super Pal Trio.
This is me, this is Catra,
and I think it's clear.
Come on. I'm a bit of an artist.
I looked at the rock,
which is a crystal, and used math.
-Wait, do I have to explain math to you?
-[groans]
Yes or no, did that crystal give you
enough data to upgrade our weapons?
Weapons? Ha!
This is so much bigger than weapons.
This could change everything.
Etheria's not just a planet.
Whatever the First Ones did to it,
it went deep.
And what does that mean?
You're asking me about my theories?
I've waited years for someone to ask me
about my theories.
-Hang on. I made a model.
-[Catra grunts]
I don't wanna be rude, but, um,
who are you?
I am Light Hope, Etheria's facilitator.
I was created by the First Ones,
as you call them.
Okay, quick follow-up,
who are the First Ones?
The First Ones were explorers
who journeyed from beyond the stars
to settle Etheria.
They built this place for you,
the Crystal Castle.
-[shouts]
-Adora, I have waited so long for you.
Now the time has come
to show you your destiny.
-Great. I actually had a quest--
-You are She-Ra, Etheria's champion,
appointed by the First Ones
to protect and unite our planet.
There have been many before you.
But the line was broken.
You are the first She-Ra
in a thousand years.
Behold, Etheria.
The First Ones didn't just settle
on the surface of Etheria.
Their technology runs
throughout the planets core.
This whole planet,
it's all First Ones tech.
Everything on Etheria is connected.
The princesses are granted power
over the elements
through their Runestones.
As She-Ra, it is your duty
to bring the princesses together.
Only then can balance
be restored to Etheria.
-That sounds great, but the thing is--
-You're correct. It is great.
-And what are these supposed to be?
-Runestones.
From the data I've managed to extract,
they regulate the planet
through the princesses.
They're directly connected to each other
and to the planet's power grid
-in a delicate balance.
-Which means?
Which means, they're our best
access point to hack the planet.
[Light Hope] When the princesses
and their elements are in balance,
Etheria functions as it should.
But the Horde is destroying us
in their quest for power.
There is no predicting
what they will do next.
-Hack the planet?
-Hypothetically. But it's not so simple.
There's only a handful of Runestones
in the whole world.
Runestone?
You mean, like the Black Garnet?
'Cause... [chuckles]
we have the Black Garnet.
The Black Garnet? You have a Runestone?
The Fright Zone has a Runestone?
Uh, duh. It was my family's.
But when the Horde landed,
we gave it to Hordak,
who then gave it to Shadow Weaver, who--
You tell a friend, he tells a friend,
it's one of those things.
Where is it? Can I see it, touch it?
Okay, calm down.
What exactly are you planning
on doing to the Black Garnet?
If we hack the Runestone grid,
we could boost the Garnet's power
and use it for... Well, anything.
-As power source, as--
-A weapon?
Potentially.
But if it's like my other experiments,
the results will be explosive.
I don't think Shadow Weaver
will like that.
Scorpia's right.
Shadow Weaver won't like it.
So, I will absolutely get you
the Black Garnet.
Leave it all to me.
What do you have for me, little spy?
[Entrapta on recording] Catra, I've made
great strides in analyzing the data
from the First Ones data crystal. Look.
This is all super good information, um,
and I can't wait to hear more. [chuckles]
-Just one thing, though--
-Is there something you do not understand?
I can start again
from the beginning if you would like.
[groans]
-I am Light Hope, Etheria's facilitator.
-Ugh.
[shouts] No, no. I got it.
Have I mentioned that you are chosen?
Can we skip to the part about my powers?
I need to learn how to heal my friend.
Your friend?
Yes. Shadow Weaver did something
to Glimmer and took her powers away.
I need to figure out how to heal her.
Her connection with her Runestone
was disrupted.
Can I fix it?
You will be able to do
many incredible things with training.
Great. So, uh, how long will this take?
Like a day or--?
Years.
Years? Glimmer doesn't have years.
She's hurt because of me. I messed up.
I got Glimmer and Bow captured,
and Entrapta-- It's my fault.
I have to fix it.
Yes. Your mission is to fix the planet.
My mission is to help my friends.
That's why I came here.
You are She-Ra.
Your purpose is to protect all of Etheria.
-You cannot help only your friends.
-Why can't I do both?
Adora, you do not yet realize
the power you have.
You are distracted by your attachments.
There was one before you
who could not let go. Her name was Mara.
Mara? Madame Razz's Mara?
What happened to her?
[Light Hope] Mara was
the last She-Ra before you.
She struggled with a power
that she could not control
until it became too much for her mind.
-She snapped?
-She was compromised.
She gave in to fear and faulty reasoning.
Her desperate actions led to devastation.
Mara stranded us in the empty dimension
of Despandos.
She broke the She-Ra line.
She nearly destroyed us.
Adora, I have waited here
for a thousand years alone.
I did not know if I would ever see
another She-Ra.
You must stay here and train,
learn to be the She-Ra
that Mara could not be.
I will. I will do whatever you want.
I'll come back and train,
and learn about everything.
But I have to heal Glimmer first.
I can save the planet and save her.
[gasps]
[shouting]
[Catra] Adora?
I just need a little more time.
[Light Hope]
You feel guilt at these memories.
As you said, your friends are endangered
by your presence.
It is better to let go now.
But I can't just leave my friends.
Alright, hurry it up. Those machines
aren't going to hook up themselves.
[Shadow Weaver]
They won't be hooked up at all.
Shadow Weaver. We just-- Uh--
Silence!
Did you really think you could invade
my inner sanctum without me noticing?
I never thought you were so bold
as to openly rebel,
but it'll be my pleasure
to put you back in your place.
[both groaning]
[robot chimes]
Oh, Shadow Weaver,
I can do whatever I want
with this hunk of rock.
[chuckles] Absurd.
-By whose authority?
-[Hordak] By mine.
Lord Hordak, I don't understand.
Catra and Entrapta have been working
on a way to meld
this strange First Ones tech
with our machines, to weaponize it.
I found out and was intrigued.
I gave Force Captain Catra
and her team my blessing to go ahead.
So, understand, Shadow Weaver.
I'm displeased with your interruption.
My Lord, you're really going to let this--
this princess tinker with my Runestone?
Her tinkering has boosted the firepower
of every weapon she's touched.
So yes, she gets to tinker
with whatever she wants.
Including the Black Garnet,
which is mine to give or take
as I see fit.
You can't. You can't do this!
I alone have learned
how to draw power from it,
a feat no sorceress has done before.
I have unlocked its potential!
And you wasted it on parlor tricks.
Force Captain Catra, proceed.
The Garnet is yours.
-Yes, Lord Hordak.
-No!
-Stop her! Don't let her--
-You won't take what is mine!
[grunts]
[yelling]
That's right, run away.
It's the only thing
you've ever been good at.
You've always been a disappointment.
You've learned nothing from me.
Oh, no. I've learned everything from you.
How to predict when you'll strike,
how to dodge, how to resist.
You thought you were punishing me
all these years? Wrong.
You were training me for this day!
[Shadow Weaver] No!
[groans]
Come back.
Come back to me. Come back to me.
Scorpia, restrain the sorceress.
We won't have to worry
about her any longer.
Entrapta, if you would.
[robot whirring]
All right, everyone, let's get weird.
[gasps] Look.
And then I realized I'm free,
but the other horses aren't.
So I named myself Swift Wind
after the swift winds of revolution
and left to go kick down stable doors.
-Freedom, equality and hay for all.
-[rustling]
Do you hear that?
[grunting]
[shrieks]
Get behind me.
What was that about?
I feel something.
We should run.
No. We have to get Adora.
Adora, then run.
Swift Wind, what is it?
A bad thing. Hurry. [whimpers]
Amazing. The garnet is siphoning energy
at a near exponential rate.
Yet the output is still building.
What does that mean?
It means things are getting interesting.
Is it just me or is it really cold?
[wind blowing]
-It's snowing?
-That's impossible.
It never snows in the Whispering Woods.
[explosion]
[grunting]
-What's happening?
-The bad thing.
We can't stay here.
Swift Wind, do you sense Adora?
[grunts]
There! She's over there.
[grunting]
This would be a great time
for my powers to come back.
Wait, wait. I know this.
Hang on. I think I can...
[neighing]
What is that?
Uh... This way.
-Adora!
-Adora, we're here.
Wake up.
I think I can reach her. Hold on.
Swift Wind?
Uh... Glimmer?
[both scream]
[gasps]
[distorted] The Horde is hurting us.
Balance Etheria.
Light Hope? Light Hope, come back.
-I don't know what to do.
-[Swift Wind] Adora?
Adora?
Our horse?
Once again, I'm no one's horse.
I'm Swift Wind.
-You can talk?
-Yes, I can talk.
You can talk?
I can see why you're friends
with Bow and Glimmer.
They need your help,
which is why I'm here.
-So, which way's the exit?
-I don't know.
Light Hope disappeared and I--
I don't know if I should go.
What do you mean?
Light Hope said if I leave here,
I'll make things worse.
She's right. Everyone will be better off
if I just stay far away from them.
It's for the greater good.
Well, that's stupid.
What? No, it's not.
Adora, I've had the ability to form
complex thought for like a week,
and even I know you can't help by hiding.
Where would all the horses I freed be
if I just sat in a pasture and moped?
[scoffs] I'm not moping.
[blusters]
I'm not. I hurt people,
I ruined my friends' lives.
If that's true, then why are Bow
and Glimmer here trying to rescue you?
Bow and Glimmer are risking their lives.
Not because you're She-Ra,
but because you're their friend.
What good is all your power
if you don't use it
to help the people that you love?
I'm not Mara.
I'm not the She-Ras of the past.
I didn't do this to fulfill some destiny.
I became She-Ra to help others.
My attachments,
my friends are a part of who I am.
So, are you staying or going?
Let's go.
Adora, you're back.
Adora, spiders!
For the honor of Grayskull!
[echoing]
[shouting and grunting]
[both laughing]
[neighs]
-Now, Swifty.
-Hold on.
[all shouting]
Guys, look.
-It's not just the woods, it's...
-It's the entire world.
Bright Moon. Swift Wind, hurry.
Wow. [gasps]
-What do you think it's doing?
-I don't know.
But I can work with this.