It's coming from the Fright Zone.
Whatever's happening,
the Horde is causing it.
The Whispering Woods
are freezing over. What do we do?
[grunts] We have to get home.
We have to make sure
everyone at Bright Moon is okay.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
-♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[Scorpia] Catra, you gotta see this.
Tidal waves, firestorms, earthquakes.
Man, Etheria's really taking this hard.
I mean, yay for us. But also, whoa.
The experiment has been more effective
than I could ever have dreamed.
This proves my hypothesis correct!
With the Black Garnet
at 200 percent power,
the precarious equilibrium that governs
all of Etheria's nature functions
has been thrown into complete chaos,
no doubt, as a result
of the other elemental Runestones--
-Ah! Hey.
-Translate.
By making the Black Garnet more powerful,
we've sapped power
from the other Princesses' Runestones,
upsetting the balance
and making the weather go screw-y.
It's in my notes, if you'd like--
Whoa, whoa.
What was that you just said
about making the other princesses
less powerful?
Well, the other Elemental Princesses,
that is.
Don't worry about me and Scorpia.
I don't have a Runestone,
and Scorpia doesn't have any connection
to the Black Garnet anymore--
-If she ever did.
-Huh? Somebody say my name?
And how would we make
an effect like that permanent?
Well, I'd have to run more tests
to know for sure, but...
Oh.
-Yeah, that should work too.
-Get a strike team together.
-We're going to Bright Moon.
-Bright Moon? Why?
Because we're going to take out
Bright Moon's Runestone.
And with the Whispering Woods frozen over,
there's nothing stopping us.
Hmm.
[grunts]
[all shouting]
-Look.
-[Glimmer gasps]
[Glimmer] That's Bright Moon.
-It's the distress beacon.
-Hang on.
-Mom. What's going on?
-The elements are out of harmony.
The Moonstone is using all its power
to counteract the cloud of darkness.
But it's not enough.
It's taking nearly all my strength
just to keep my connection with it.
That cloud is coming from the Fright Zone.
So what's our plan?
We do have a plan, right?
Guys?
The woods are frozen over.
There's nothing left
to shield Bright Moon from the Horde.
We have to prepare for an attack.
[Bow] Our scouts reported sighting
the entire Horde army in the woods,
moving towards us at top speed.
We must protect Bright Moon at all costs.
If the Moonstone is destroyed,
there will be nothing left
to stop the darkness.
Someone must have seen the beacon.
Why hasn't anyone come?
The Alliance is broken,
and other princesses
have their own kingdoms to protect.
-No one's coming, Bow.
-Someone's come!
Is it the princesses?
Oh.
Spinnerella and Netossa. [chuckles]
Thanks for coming, guys.
You still don't know what we do, do you?
Uh... No.
Seriously?
It's in the name. Net-tossa.
Nets. I toss nets, okay?
Yes, darling, you have beautiful nets.
At least you have powers,
which is more than I've got.
But it doesn't matter.
I don't need magic to fight.
Glimmer, not only are you
without your powers,
but you're still glitching.
It's dangerous.
-But mom...
-[Adora] Your mom is right.
I don't want you risking yourselves.
She-Ra can do this alone.
This is what she's for.
Adora, not even She-Ra can take out
an army of Horde soldiers on her own.
Then what good is she?
Adora, are you okay?
Catra will be leading the Horde
when they attack. I have to face her.
I can't let her hurt anyone else.
What happened to you
in that First Ones temple?
I saw Catra in there.
I thought I could get through to her,
but all I did was push her farther
to the side of evil.
Light Hope said
that I'd endanger my friends
by coming back, and she was right.
Everything that's happening now
is my fault.
You got this.
And we got your back.
Now, come on. The Horde will be here soon.
We have to be ready.
Welcome to the Bright Moon armory!
Well, not really, but I've been
stashing weapons in here for months.
[gasps] Dibs on arrows. [laughing]
[groans]
[neighs]
[grunts]
Hmm?
-Uh, no.
-[groans]
[Angella] Glimmer?
Mom! How did you know
we'd be in here?
Did you really think I wouldn't notice
you hoarding weapons?
I'm sorry, Mom.
I can't just stand by while my friends
and my home are in danger.
I have to do this.
-I know.
-Mom, I... Wait, what?
I've been trying all these years
to mold you
into someone more like me.
But you're too stubborn and hotheaded,
and brave, like your father.
This was your father's staff.
I think it's time it's time you had it.
[loud crash, all grunting]
They're here.
For the honor of Grayskull!
We got this, right?
Yeah. Definitely.
They're gonna be sorry they ever tried
to mess with Bright Moon.
Defend the castle. [grunts]
[shouting]
[shouting and grunting]
-[bomb beeping]
-Huh?
[gasps]
[grunting]
Adora.
[grunts]
-She-Ra needs our help.
-Go to her.
I'll keep the Moonstone lit
and the darkness away as long as I can.
You heard the queen.
For the Rebellion!
[grunting]
[shouting]
-Huh?
-Whoo!
-[Glimmer laughing]
-Yeah!
[chuckles]
[shouting and grunting]
[gasps]
[grunting and shouting]
[panting]
Hey, Adora.
Catra. Surprised to see me?
Not really. It wouldn't be that easy
to get rid of you.
[yells]
You know, I'm actually glad
you did made it out of there alive.
Because now, I can take you out myself.
[shouting]
[shouts]
[grunting]
Isn't that nice?
You've accessorized.
Not that it's going to help you.
[Scorpia yells]
Boom. Nets.
[shouting and grunting]
[Catra laughing]
Tired already?
Punching was supposed to be
the one thing you're good at.
[groans]
And I thought you
were supposed to be quicker.
[grunting and shouting]
Give it up, Catra.
There's no way you win this.
I already made it a lot farther
than anyone thought.
You, on the other hand,
you're not looking so good.
[Catra laughing]
-This isn't over.
-Of course it's not over.
[shouts]
It won't be over until Bright Moon
is destroyed and the Rebellion falls.
It won't be over
until darkness covers Etheria forever.
And it won't be over until I see
the looks on your friends' faces
when they find out that you failed,
that you were too weak to save them.
[yelling]
Enough! You've lost, Catra.
You sure about that?
[gasps]
[shouting]
What? Did you really think
this was about you?
That Runestone is your last defense,
isn't it?
[laughing]
Have fun.
[grunting]
[panting]
No!
[yelling]
[grunting]
So, where were we? Oh, yeah.
I was about to punch you.
Where's my shield?
[screaming]
[panting]
Uh-oh.
[She-Ra groaning]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[shouting]
Ah. Pretty.
[grunting]
Now, it's over.
Come on.
Hyah!
[gasps]
[yelling]
-Mom.
-Princess.
Huh? [shouts]
Adora? Adora.
Come on, don't give up yet, please.
We can still fix this, right?
Please, tell me we can fix this.
I...
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
[shouts]
Adventure!
-[Mermista] Don't do that.
-Sorry.
Ta-da!
-Mermista, Sea Hawk, you came.
-Yeah, sorry it took so long.
The sea kind of sucked today.
[coughing]
Come on, get up!
[grunting]
I saw the distress beacon.
Are you all okay?
Hmm.
Ha!
[gasps]
No!
Hmm?
I hope I'm not too late.
No. You're right on time.
[grumbles]
For Etheria!
[Angella] Glimmer?
-Mom.
-[Angella chuckles]
[gasps]
[shouts]
[laughing]
Go on, go get them.
-[shouts]
-[chuckles]
[neighing]
Yes!
-Glimmer, you're sparkling again!
-Yeah. What did I miss?
The princesses are united.
This is how it's supposed to be.
-What do you say? Ready to finish this?
-[chuckles] Thought you'd never ask.
-We're in.
-Let's do this already.
[Sea Hawk] Battle cry!
[yells]
[grunting and shouting]
[both laughing]
[shouts]
[grumbles]
[grunting]
[all cheering]
Adventure!
I've never seen nets like that.
Adora, it's over.
-Bright Moon is saved.
-And the princesses are finally united!
We did it.
That is how it's done in the sea.
-Really good job.
-Good job, girls. Onto the next.
-Yeah! We did things together.
-Isn't this wonderful?
[gasps]
[both laughing]
-[Adora shouts]
-[Bow chuckles]
Thank you.
[Hordak] Force Captain,
it seems your experiment has failed.
On the contrary,
the experiment was a huge success.
I know more about First Ones tech
than ever. This is just the beginning.
I got us closer to conquering Bright Moon
than anyone ever has.
Not to mention the Whispering Woods
is still in ruins.
Etheria is ours for the taking.
Very well, Force Captain Catra.
You will have other chances
to prove your worth to me
as my second-in-command.