[Bow grunting]
[gasps]
Ooh. Okay.
We need to reclaim the Horde-occupied
fortress for the Rebellion.
-How are we gonna do this?
-I'll teleport ahead to scout a path.
And I'll quietly shoot the turrets
with my trick arrows.
You'll have the advantage
in a sneak attack. Go!
[chirping]
[yawning]
[grunting and shouting]
Yes! And now-- [grunts]
[both gasping]
[crying]
He's dead.
[Bow] Oh, what?
Tiny Bow, you will be avenged!
[crying, then grunts]
[groans]
That clearly isn't gonna work.
Let's try this again.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you, ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
I shouldn't be dead.
-That turret came out of nowhere.
-You failed to make an observation check.
If we're gonna retake the pass,
we have to be prepared for anything.
The pass is the only way
in or out of this region.
The Horde seized it
while we were defending Bright Moon.
-So it's crucial we get it back.
-Why does that mean I have to die?
And after I made these for you!
Look. Our plans always fall apart. Always!
-It'd be impressive if not terrifying.
-We've gotten good at improvising, though.
[sighs]
If we're gonna pull this off,
we need a plan that won't fall apart,
that takes into account everything
the Horde could throw at us,
-including surprise attacks.
-But you're breaking Tiny Bow's heart.
-I mean, look at his face.
-He's smiling.
Through his pain, Glimmer.
Through his pain.
Guys, this pass is important. The Horde
won't give it up without a fight.
It's obviously gonna be guarded
by their very best and brightest.
Move those big weapon-y things!
Flap those banners! Uh...
Keep doing whatever it is you're doing,
guy I'm pointing at.
Now do a different thing!
And look sharp, Force Captain's orders!
Catra left me in charge.
Me. Can you believe it?
-Uh, no. I really can't.
-Ah, me neither.
She must trust me. I can't let her down.
-Kyle, man the parapets!
-I don't know what those are.
[Scorpia] Then find out.
[panting]
[groans] "Scorpia, you're in charge
of the fortress," she said.
"Even you can't mess this up," she said.
Even me. She's thinking about me.
Ah. Should I get her a thank-you gift?
What's her favorite color?
-Kyle, what are you doing?
-Uh, you said-- I--
Go find out Catra's favorite color!
[panting]
You guys know Catra. What would she like?
I need it to be something that says,
"Thank you," but also, "We are soulmates
tied together by the threads of fate."
We should spend less time
talking about Catra,
and more time checking the defenses.
-The reason we're here!
-[laughs]
Okay. You don't need to remind me.
My wildcat is counting on me,
and I won't let her down.
For Catra, I will defend this pass
with my very life!
[coughs] Wrong pass.
Yes, this is the pass
I'll defend with my very life.
No reason to worry at all!
Clearly that plan won't work.
So maybe if we try sneaking
past the turrets from a different side--
[Glimmer] You're going about this wrong.
We're not going to win by sneaking.
We gotta take the action to them!
[chuckles] Just let Glimmer handle this.
Using my awesome powers of teleportation,
I take out their first line of defense.
[imitating explosion]
Then I teleport onto the wall
and take out a line of soldiers
with one critical strike!
[Glimmer imitating explosion]
I backflip, front flip,
backflip into a teleport, poof!
Then I take out a Super Bot,
and it explodes!
Yeah, and I'm past the wall!
I'm unstoppable! I'm--
You ran out of teleports,
like, 12 teleports ago.
Then I land on you!
[both shouting]
Tiny Bow!
No!
Glimmer, we need to come up
with a plan based on reality.
Yes. And in that moment,
I really would land on Bow.
Hmm.
Using a limited number of teleports
isn't a bad idea.
So, Glimmer will take Bow
and, using her powers, teleport him
into the turrets' blind spot.
Bow shall act as backup, while you
and I breach the less-patrolled area.
[rumbling, then both shout]
-Uh... Why are you playing with dolls?
-We're not playing with dolls!
Yeah. They're war-table, battle figures.
And I don't know if I have one for you.
Hold on.
-Wait, aren't you supposed to be on watch?
-Oh, look, the fortress is still there,
like it was an hour ago. Watch complete.
[groans]
-Relax, I switched with Perfuma.
-We're still coming up with a plan.
-Am I in the plan?
-We're getting to--
I don't have you, but I do have a seashell
and a happy otter.
Uh... Googly eyes? Pass.
-What?
-Can we get back--?
[Mermista] I'll be She-Ra.
-You can't be She-Ra. I'm She-Ra.
-Not anymore. You snooze, you--
[both grunt]
Uh, wow, rude much?
[tablet beeping]
Alert Force Captain Scorpia.
We've got a princess problem.
I admit I got carried away.
But the rest of my plan could work.
Except you're not taking the biggest
variable into account: Catra.
She's been behind every Horde plan,
led the attack on Bright Moon.
She's devious--
And I've already thought of that.
I knew destroying the bots
would lure her out.
[chuckles] And so it has, Glimmer.
[purring]
[snorts] This is how you see Catra?
-[laughs] Yeah, this seems a little off.
-[laughs] A little?
You fell into my trap.
I've armed the tower with a bomb
capable of taking out
my greatest enemy, you.
Do you expect us to just sit here?
-No, princess, I expect you to--
-I cast Giant Flytrap on Catra!
[all shouting]
-Oops. Sorry, Bow.
-Ugh! What are you doing here?
Mermista said you were playing.
We wanna join.
Ugh. We're in the middle
of a very serious planning session.
-We have lots of ideas for plans.
-Aren't you on watch right now?
-[groans] But only if you're serious--
-[Frosta] I'm sitting next to Glimmer!
-What does that eat?
-[Frosta] I have ideas,
starting with we punch them!
Spy Bot, the mission is simple.
Spy on the princesses so I can stop them,
and impress Catra so much,
she'll finally admit we're best friends,
or at the very least have a bond
that can never be broken. Got that?
Uh, it's not turned on,
and, um, that's not how it works.
Good, yeah. I was just testing you
on whether you knew how to do that.
And you passed. So, kudos.
Now, let's go spy!
[clearing throat]
[Spy Bot powering up]
Oh, aren't you the cutest little fella.
Look at you with your little legs
and your antenna.
-You're just the cutest thing I've ever--
-Ahem.
Spying, yes.
That is the thing that we are doing.
[grunting]
[sighs] Second test.
-Do you want me to drive the Spy Bot?
-Yes, please.
Okay, everyone has a figure,
except Perfuma who's using her plant,
and Mermista who has that for some reason.
-Says the guy with a bag of dolls.
-They're war-table, battle figures!
-Okay, so I'm thinking--
-Hold on.
So far I have been shot,
eaten and squashed.
We're doing my plan.
And there will be no death, no dying,
just heroic good times.
I am Bow.
She-Ra's best friend
and defender of Etheria.
When the evil Horde strikes,
I strike back.
Ooh!
-We all get hats.
-[groans]
After I destroy the turrets
with my trick arrows,
Glimmer teleports us to the tower.
-There, someone waits in the shadows.
-[Catra meows, then laughs]
Catra.
[meows] Fools. I won't let you destroy
my purrfect plan!
What?
[laughing] This is kind of amazing.
It looks like I've got you meow,
evil doer!
I'd paws to reflect on your upcoming death
if I were mew.
-I don't know. I'm feline pretty good now.
-Oh, stop. You gotta stop.
-Now we're all hoping this plan kills us.
-Then purr-pare to meet your end!
[caterwauling]
Wait, she can do that?
No. But I ran out of figures
and only have this left, so she can now.
Also, the Horde has dragons,
as I did not make enough robots.
Not to worry.
I'll shoot her with my net arrow.
-Oh, come on!
-She would obviously duck.
You can't underestimate Catra
or the Horde.
-We can exploit a weakness in the wall.
-Is it my turn?
This isn't a game.
I use my magic to grow a Plant Golem
to take down the tower.
[thud]
[shouting]
[both screaming]
If it's made out of plants,
how does it roar?
[chuckles] It's plant magic.
[sighs]
Perfuma, we're not just making up
whatever we want.
-Plus, your idea is dumb.
-[scoffs] And what would you do?
Uh... I step forward, and I say...
[both gasping]
I am Mermista.
Fabulous secrets were revealed to me
the day I held aloft my trident and said,
"For the honor of Gray Whales!"
[squeaking]
Then it's like, sparkle, sparkle,
dolphin, sparkle.
-Mermista...
-I get shoes that are slightly better
than my normal shoes.
There's probably another dolphin.
-Mermista!
-Then I twirl, and my hair does this thing
where it looks all messy,
but it's actually, like, super-beautiful.
You can't transform into She-Ra!
Uh, duh, I'm Sea-Ra,
Princess of the Oceans, obviously.
No. If she gets to be Sea-Ra,
I get to have a Plant Golem.
The Winter's Bane needs no help
from a plant.
The what?
[Frosta] My enemies know me
as Frostbite Winter's Bane.
My friends call me Bane.
That is, if I had any.
But no one comes close
to the Winter's Bane!
She's got a broadsword
that enhances strength plus three.
-Her finishing move is the Snowstrike.
-[Mermista] What's that pink blob?
-Her sidekick. Glimmer.
-What?
We're getting so far from the real plan.
Can we please focus?
Yeah. Focus on how I'm not a sidekick!
[chattering]
We've got visual. Turning on the audio.
My army of Plant Golems
will take down the tower instantly.
Frostbite uses Snowstrike to encase
the tower in ice, then crack it, kapow!
You mean Sea-Ra will use
the Trident of Power to blow it up.
[Glimmer] You don't have
a Trident of Power.
[Mermista] Bow, make me
[Bow] I don't wanna die again.
-I can't believe it.
-Me either.
[laughs] They're gonna give us frostbite,
then attack us with a plant golem
and a woman named Sea-Ra,
and Bow's got a Trident of Power?
Who knows what that does?
Oh, we're doomed!
Ugh, they're obviously just coming up
with ideas. Terrible ideas.
We cannot risk it.
-Get in closer.
-Hey! Get off of me!
[Mermista] We should throw Bow
over the wall.
[Bow] Or everyone else over the wall!
[Adora] There goes taking this seriously.
No! Kyle, go grab one
of the other Spy Bots you packed.
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
Was that my job?
Really, Kyle?
I don't know how you haven't been fired.
-[Glimmer] I teleport in...
-And run out of teleports.
-My Plant Golem tears down the wall.
-The Horde will set it on fire.
Frostbite smashes the wall.
The ice armor cracks as you hit stone.
-Sea-Ra destroys the Horde Bots.
-There is no Sea-Ra,
-and you aren't taking Catra into account!
-Oh, sure we are. See?
I have a lot of negative things to say.
And I hate flowers.
No, no, no, she's more like,
I love ruining parties.
[laughing mockingly]
I'm a monster!
-[meows] What a...
-Purrfectly evil group.
[Catra laughing]
No. None of this is right!
[all groaning]
We've been here for hours.
It's time we attack.
The Horde will counter
whatever we throw at them. We'll go again.
We won't leave
until we have a perfect plan.
Adora, isn't this all going
a little overboard?
We've faced the Horde before.
What's the worst that could happen?
You wanna know the worst
that can happen? Fine.
I'm the heaviest hitter,
so Catra will separate me,
trap me, take my sword, so something
so I'm helpless when she turns on you.
She knows everything about me,
what I'll do, how to take me out.
They'll overwhelm Frosta and Mermista
with bots, fire on Perfuma.
Use her to draw Bow out, pinning him
between the bots and Horde soldiers.
Glimmer will teleport in, she won't have
enough magic to get out, trapping them.
Catra will make me watch
before she finishes me off.
Everyone is gone, the Horde wins,
Etheria crumbles. It's my fault!
The Horde nearly destroyed Etheria.
We were barely able to stop it.
If this plan isn't perfect,
if I'm not perfect, everyone will--
[Adora sighs]
Adora, I was captured by Shadow Weaver,
taken to the Fright Zone
and lost my powers.
Glimmer, not helping.
But you know what? We escaped.
I fought without my powers, and we won!
Bad things are going to happen.
That's life.
You can let it paralyze you
or you can roll with it.
Figure out the things you can,
and trust that your friends
have your back for the rest.
-You've got this, Adora.
-I cast friendship and support on my turn.
Here. This is my Trident of Power.
I want you to have it, since Bow
is making me a new one.
-I didn't agree to that.
-You will.
The Winter's Bane stands with you.
Also, me, Frosta stands with you.
-I can't tell if we're still in character.
-Thank you.
So, what do we do now?
We do what we do best. We improvise.
For the honor of Grayskull!
Let's go.
[Lonnie] We've added more bots
to the tower's weak points.
Kyle is hiding somewhere.
Rogelio is commanding the extra turrets.
And if there are plant monsters
or warriors in ice armor or Sea-Ra?
[groans] For the last time,
none of that stuff was real.
We've reinforced our defenses.
We got this.
Okay. Good.
And thanks, Lonnie.
-Who's Rogelio?
-Rogelio, the lizard guy.
-Oh, right. I wondered what his deal was.
-[groans]
[both gasping]
-[Plant Golem roaring]
-No.
-No, it can't be!
-[Kyle shouting]
[both shouting]
For the She-Ra!
[stammering] Fire!
[grunting]
-Yay, Frosta!
-This is colder than I thought,
but not a problem.
Snowstrike!
[grunts]
Huh?
-Thanks, Mermista.
-You mean Sea-Ra, Princess of the Oceans.
-Charge!
-I am Sea-Ra!
-Plant magic!
-The Winter's Bane!
-[all shouting]
-[gasps]
[shouts]
-It's over, Catra. You've lost.
-[Scorpia] Catra's not here.
But I'm happy to take you down for her.
[grunting and shouting]
[laughs] Whoo!
Yeah! Got you!
Bow!
[squealing]
[groans, then panting]
[grunting and shouting]
Catra's really not here
and she left you in charge?
Yes. Why do people
keep acting surprised about that?
[groaning]
-[gasps]
-[Scorpia] Bup, bup, bup!
Stay where you are,
or we'll find out if Sparkles
has enough magic to land on her feet.
Like I was saying, Catra trusts--
[grunts] Ow!
Hey, you don't hit the person
dangling you over the edge. Stop!
[grunting]
-Glimmer, are you okay?
-How was that for improvising?
-Also, it's your turn. I'm out of magic.
-Catra trusts--
Catra-- [shouts]
Catra trusts-- Huh?
Okay, seriously,
how many of you are there?
Oh, too many.
Whoa. [shouting]
[all cheering]
-That was awesome!
-Good planning session.
Thanks, guys.
-All in favor of blaming this on Kyle?
-Oh, yeah.
-[Scorpia] Yep. Yeah, that's unanimous.
-Oh, man.
[closing theme playing]