Hi, Catra. Did you have a nice nap?
[groans] Why is this taking so long? You
said there was a First Ones weapon here.
Where is it?
I never said "weapon."
I said there's a piece of First Ones tech
buried deep under the ice,
and a really powerful one at that.
The energy levels, it must be part of
the First Ones' supercomputer.
Just keep digging.
Hordak is not going to be happy
if we waste his time
and come back empty-handed.
A scientist never returns empty-handed.
There's always data.
I'm not here freezing my tail off
for data.
Find me something useful
or we're packing up and heading home.
This place gives me the creeps.
[roars]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end! ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
The Dragon's Daughter Five. She cuts
a fine line on the sea, does she not?
Wait. What happened
to the Dragon's Daughter Four?
Oh, oh, oh, was it adventure?
No. Termites.
I couldn't save the old girl.
Anyway, I'm honored to be a part of
another daring mission for the Rebellion.
Well, you know, we needed a boat
to get up here, and you have a boat.
Yes, I do. Heh. Truth be told,
I was glad to have something to do.
Mermista canceled our plans this week,
and she's hanging out with her friends
and didn't invite me to join. I...
Well, let this mission
distract you from all that.
We've received reports of Horde activity
in the Northern Reach. They've set up some
kind of outpost, but we have no idea why.
The Northern Reach is nothing but snow and
ice. What could they possibly be doing?
I don't know, but it can't be good.
[Catra grunting]
Okay, Scorpia, get your head in the game.
You've got this.
You and Catra have a special bond,
and deep down in her heart,
she knows that.
[sighs]
-Scorpia, good. You're here.
-Yes, I am.
Entrapta brought all this junk
from her lab.
Help me find a space heater or something
since apparently we live here now.
So, I've been thinking,
and I know you've been really busy
and focused on your career lately,
but would you ever want to...
you know, like, hang out sometime with me?
What are you talking about?
We are hanging out. Right now.
Yes, totally, totes.
But, uh, what I meant was, like, outside
of office hours. You know, we could, pfft,
I don't know, um, play a board game or do
some other type of bonding activity.
[laughs, then shouts]
[shouts] Careful with that.
It's a rare First Ones artifact.
I've been meaning to study it
but haven't gotten a chance.
The last time I deployed it,
it ended up infecting all of my robots
with some kind of murder-virus.
You brought along a murder-virus
and not a blanket?
It does other things, too.
For example, when it infected She-Ra, she
lost her powers.
Also, she got very floppy.
A She-Ra off-switch, huh? Why didn't
you say something sooner?
So, anyway,
in non-She-Ra business, [chuckles]
when I said we could do something--
-[alarm wailing]
-[gasps]
-[Entrapta] Uh-oh.
-What?
[chuckles] It's just a small bump.
I'm sure its fine.
But our drilling bots have gone offline.
All of them. At once.
-Come on. We should go check this out.
-[groans] I hate this place.
[Sea Hawk] Come to think of it,
Mermista never invites me
to hang out with her other friends.
I mean, heh, am I not cool enough
for them?
I'm so cool. I'm Sea Hawk.
[grunts]
What's wrong? Did you see something?
No. I think there's something else
out here.
You know, they say all sorts of strange
things happen in the Northern Reach.
Voices on the wind. Monsters in the snow.
Machines break down.
Sailors disappear without a trace.
We could be next!
I am cool, right? I am. Right?
[sighs] My tracker pad's been on the fritz
ever since that rogue communications hub
messed with it.
I'm having trouble pinpointing
the Horde's location.
Worry not. We'll follow our instincts!
This way!
Or there's this new signal. It's big.
It looks like a First Ones tech signature.
That's where the Horde will be.
Hmm. Hmm, hmm.
[echoing] Ah. Here we go.
Well, the drilling bots are gone.
What? They just disappeared into thin air?
Maybe there's scientific truth
to the rumors
about strange happenings in this region.
We weren't sent here to chase rumors.
Hordak wants tech.
If your bots can't dig it out,
-then maybe I'll send you down there to--
-[She-Ra] Catra.
It's been a while.
-Hey, Adora.
-You're pretty far from the front line.
I guess Shadow Weaver's keeping you
away from the action since you lost
the battle of Bright Moon.
Shadow Weaver? Wow.
I always forget how clueless you are.
We're here to take back this land. Time
for you to go back to the Fright Zone.
-You want us to go? Try and make us.
-My pleasure.
[grunting]
-Adventure!
-This is not how this was supposed to go.
[grunting and shouting]
Hey, while we're here, would you describe
me as "cool"? Be honest now.
Potentially.
Entrapta, whatever you're doing here
has to stop!
You don't understand
the forces you're messing with!
I know! That's the fun of it!
-Don't move.
-Oh, please. You'd never have the guts.
You know, as much as I love our fights,
it's way too cold for this.
Why don't we try something new?
[screaming]
Catra, what did you do?
-You said she'd be powerless.
-She will be.
-Eventually. I think.
-Actually, this is pretty cool.
I know you're still in there, Adora.
You've got to snap out of it.
Let go of the sword.
You're gonna be okay, promise.
[grunting]
Glimmer!
What is happening?
[all shouting]
This is the greatest thing
that's ever happened.
[grunting and shouting]
[laughing]
Adora, wait.
[Scorpia] Stay away from her.
Oh, I get it now. The sword got infected,
not Adora herself.
Huh. I guess she really is organic matter.
Catra, are you okay?
[laughing]
That went so much better
than I could've ever hoped.
Looks like you're mine now, Adora.
Come on, get her inside.
Is everyone okay?
[Sea Hawk shouts]
Well, I for one am shocked and terrified.
What happened up there?
It's Entrapta's disc.
It infected She-Ra once before.
We've got to get to Catra and destroy it
for good.
Okay, let's go, Glimmer.
Teleport us up there. Adventure!
[groans] I can't.
I exhausted my magic in the fight.
Until I can recharge, we're climbing.
That's terribly inconvenient.
Shouldn't you keep better count
or something?
[Glimmer groans]
[Glimmer] I hope Catra survives She-Ra so
I can wipe that smirk off her face myself.
Always so perfect. Look at you now.
You're coming back to the Horde
under my command.
So we're, uh, keeping her?
You saw her out there.
As long as we have this sword,
we have the power to make her go berserk.
We can turn the Rebellion's own hero
against them. That's good.
I wonder which of your friends
I'll have you annihilate first.
[chuckling]
[laughing]
It looks like the bots pinpointed
the location of the First Ones' tech
before they disappeared.
If you just give me a little more time.
Ugh. Hey. This dumb mission is over.
We have what we need right here,
the ultimate weapon.
Pack up.
We're taking her back to the Fright Zone.
-But Hordak wanted us to--
-Oh, wanted us to dig a useless hole?
Forget it. I'm bringing She-Ra back.
[alarm wailing]
I'll go. It's probably
just more Rebel idiots.
-Scorpia, keep an eye on Adora.
-Oh, yeah. Yeah.
I will absolutely look after
this sleeping, non-moving person.
Uh...
[Entrapta] She went that way.
[Sea Hawk] I'm a pirate!
Pirates are the definition of cool.
Although, you would think
I'd get invited to more parties.
I mean, you think I'm cool, right?
[shouting]
♪ [singing] I'm Sea Hawk, I am, I am ♪
♪ Want to take a guy for granted?
Then I am your man ♪
♪ Unappreciated in all I do
Why can't they see I'm very cool? ♪
♪ Guys, back me up, I'm very cool ♪
Just wanted a moment with Catra, but, no,
I'm stuck babysitting her ex-best friend.
[crash]
[shouting, then laughing]
Uh... You okay, Adora?
-Wow. You are a big bug.
-Whew. Yep, that is the truth.
Glad you're seeing clearly.
Now, come on, I'm taking you to the lab.
[groans] What was the code again?
Um, maybe--
Boop, boop, boop.
Stop that.
-Okay, wait. I'm pretty sure it was...
-Boop, boop, boop.
Don't. Don't. Stop.
Why are you making this
so much harder for me?
Please. Please. I'm a woman on the edge.
I've had a real challenge of a day.
Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop!
How did you do that?
I put in Catra's favorite number.
[chuckles]
[groans] I get it. You know
Catra's favorite number, and I don't.
Rub it in my face, why don't you?
Uh... That's not good.
[laughing]
[gasps]
Change of plans. How about we stay inside?
Yay, it's girls' night in!
[snoring]
Any sign of She-Ra? Preferably the
version that won't throw us off a cliff?
No. No She-Ra.
Just a terrifying snow monster!
[all gasping]
[roaring]
[all shouting]
[groans] Can't believe I'm stuck
in a closet here with you.
I should be by Catra's side,
protecting her.
Why can't you just stay out of our way?
[gasps] Catra?
[panting]
Inspector Pirate?
Adora. Ahem. I'm here to rescue you.
Uh... More like, I'm here to rescue you.
[laughing]
That doesn't make any sense.
-Is she all right?
-I don't know.
She is getting on my last nerve.
And she's not going anywhere.
We'll see about that. En garde.
[both grunting]
You guys are my best friends.
[alarm wailing]
[alarm powering down]
[metal rattling]
[monster roars]
[grunts] I really hate this place.
What's happening?
Why is the power going out?
By drilling into the ice,
we've unleashed these creatures.
Now they're obsessively trying to
destroy us. What an unexpected twist!
Where did these things come from?
I'm guessing it's something to do
with that giant pit Entrapta dug.
Bow, their eyes,
they're red like She-Ra's.
Do you think maybe the monsters have been
infected, too? Ugh! Catra is the worst!
[roars]
-Think you have one more teleport left?
-Hope so.
Hi!
[shouts]
Ow.
Fascinating.
Hand her over.
Let go! Catra entrusted me
with watching her. I can't let her down.
Catra. [chuckles] She's mean.
She's misunderstood!
You of all people should know that.
I mean, you grew up together.
I can't compete with that.
No matter what I do,
I can't seem to break down her walls.
But you two, even when you're trying
to kill each other,
you can tell there's a real bond.
I just...
I wish she would see me
as worth her time, too.
I-- I know how you feel.
Always great to see you, Sparkles,
but we're a little busy here.
Where's the disc, Catra?
What? You didn't like my new,
improved version of She-Ra?
Entrapta, please,
look who you're working with.
Whatever the Horde is giving you,
it's not worth the damage you're doing.
Those monsters outside are infected
by the same virus that's infecting She-Ra.
-[thud]
-[grunts]
Infected? That can't be right. The disc
only infects First Ones tech. Unless...
[gasps] the bugs are First Ones tech.
[yawns]
I mean, just once I'd like to hang out
with Mermista and her friends.
I'm good at groups.
I have excellent stories of derring-do.
-Why don't they want me around?
-[Scorpia] I hear you.
Catra's been so busy
since she got promoted.
But she still always expects me
to make time for her.
Does she even understand
how much I do for her?
Exactly. It seems like the only time
anyone wants to hang
is when they need me give them a ride
or do something for them.
Ugh. Tell me about it.
Catra once used my rock hard exoskeleton
as a nail file. I even had to buff.
[laughing]
[both laughing]
Is there something wrong with us?
You know, you guys, you're really great.
You're just, like, the best.
You're good friends and good people.
And I like you.
You are so pointy.
You know what?
She's right. We are really great.
I'm clever, roguishly good-looking,
and a top-notch sailor.
I don't care if anyone thinks I'm cool.
I don't need their opinions
to validate me. I'm Sea Hawk.
And me, I am brave, strong,
give great hugs, and I'm loyal.
You may have left Catra,
but someday she's gonna see that I won't.
I'll always be there for her,
because that's who I am.
Yay!
I'm also someone who's about
to kick some bug butt.
Let's show them what we're made of.
[rumbling]
We have to destroy the disc,
or none of us are getting out.
-Huh. Guess I must've lost it.
-Catra, it's in your pocket, remember?
[groans]
[all shouting]
[roaring]
For the Horde!
I don't agree with that sentiment,
but I'm also here.
Pew-pew!
Hey, I know you.
Adora, I'm so glad you're okay.
-Catra, are you all right?
-Just find the sword. I've got Adora.
[grunting and shouting]
-No, you don't.
-Hi.
En garde.
Just give us the disc!
Are you kidding? I've got control
of Adora. I am not giving that up.
[roaring]
[both grunting]
[all groaning]
Catra, you have to destroy the disc.
It's the only way to stop them.
Catra!
Scorpia, you can end this.
You've got to break the disc now.
Don't you dare.
Uh...
It seems to me that caring about someone
is the greatest adventure of them all.
Sorry, wildcat. This is for your own good.
No!
-Oh. What happened?
-[Catra groaning]
Hey, put me down.
[Catra sneezes]
What're you so happy about? She-Ra won.
And we didn't get what we came for.
The mission was a failure. How are we
going to explain this one to Hordak?
Failure? This mission
was a resounding success.
Ta-da!
I got the First Ones tech.
What? When did you even--
How long have you had that?
A while. But we were having so much fun,
I didn't wanna say anything.
Isn't it amazing?
This puppy'll power Hordak's portal
technology and then some.
[laughing]
Hordak is gonna be so thrilled.
Hey. Thanks for getting us out.
Anytime.
[chattering]
[groans] All right, come on.
Really? Yes. Oh!
Thank you.
Oh, gosh. Look at us.
Just two peas in a pod.
So when I brought it up before, I said
board games, but it doesn't have to be.
We could do anything. I'm open.
I like bowling. It's difficult for me
with my claws, but...
[closing theme playing]