-[sighs] Thanks for coming with me, guys.
-Of course.
And the queen is okay with us taking off?
I would've thought a mission
to the Crimson Waste
would've been too risky for her.
Oh, she hates this idea,
which is why I didn't tell her.
It's not like anyone else has a plan
to stop Hordak from opening a portal.
You're right. Tracking Mara's message
to the source is the best lead we have.
Plus, for an inhospitable desert,
this place is kind of beautiful.
Oh, there's even a cute little bird.
-[tweeting]
-[all shouting]
Never mind, this place is terrifying.
Okay, I know it's scary and dangerous,
but if there is something to do
with portals here,
we have to find it for the Rebellion.
And... for me.
Which way now, Bow?
Uh... [laughs]
So, uh, slight problem.
Uh, my tracker pad, it's dead.
So, we're without a map,
and the plants are evil. Heh.
But it's okay.
We're coming from the north.
If we keep going south,
we'll cross the center.
And, uh,
I'm something of an expert tracker,
thanks to the Horde's
survival skills training.
We just have to keep going... that way.
Problem solved.
I've got this under control. [laughs]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you
Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[Entrapta] Day 135,
this could finally be it.
Initiating first test. Here we go. Aha.
[gasps]
-Something's wrong. I'm turning it off.
-No, you fool. It'll blow.
[grunting]
This doesn't make any sense.
It should work.
The machine didn't have enough power,
so we added First Ones Tech.
Then it was blowing out the power grid,
so we rerouted it.
Now it's powered, it's functioning,
but it won't activate a portal.
It's like there's a key.
Maybe when Catra brings that tech back
from the Crimson Waste--
[laughs] Catra is never coming back
from that fool's errand.
The machine is a failure.
We're done here. Get out.
-That was just our first test. If we try--
-I said, we're done.
[all shouting]
Okay, to review, the plants are evil,
tech doesn't work,
and sometimes, a sand dune is
a pile of very angry, sand-colored snakes.
So, I think we're getting
the hang of this.
[groans] Why can't I just teleport us
to the center of the Waste?
You don't know where it is and would
run out of power before we made it.
Oh, thank you for reminding me
that my powers are limited.
-You think I don't know--?
-Glimmer.
I'm fine. [chuckles]
Where's Adora?
[groans]
[rumbling]
And quicksand. That is now on our list
of things to avoid.
Wow, I'm learning so much today.
Adora, you know we support you
all the way,
-but maybe we're not prepared for this.
-We just need a little rest.
-I'll figure out how to build a shelter--
-Or we could go there?
Okay. Problem solved.
We'll get out of the heat,
and maybe there's a map or water inside.
Adora, I doubt
there's anything useful here.
The Crimson Waste's been abandoned
for hundreds of-- [shouts]
Just act tough. Try to blend in.
[Glimmer] Ha!
[sighs]
Good afternoon, fellow patrons.
Except, I don't even care
if you do have a good afternoon,
-because I'm bad.
-Bow.
Hi. Is this the center of the Crimson--?
Excuse me? Hello? We--
Okay, that didn't work.
[chuckles] Adora, I'm not so sure
these are the kind of people
we should be asking for help.
Hello. Sorry to interrupt, uh,
but we're not from around here,
and we're hoping
someone would give us directions?
You're outsiders.
Uh, yeah, I guess we are.
We don't like outsiders here.
And since the Crimson Waste
didn't take care of you...
we will.
[glass breaks]
We didn't mean to disturb you.
[grunts]
[Huntara] There's only two rules
in the Crimson Waste.
One, the strong make the rules.
And two, don't annoy me when I eat.
I made rule one. They broke rule two.
-[all gasp]
-Are you all staring at something?
[whimpering]
Kids, what are you doing,
asking these lowlifes for help?
Don't you know you can't trust anyone
in the Crimson Waste?
[chuckles] Up until two minutes ago,
we didn't know there was anyone
in the Crimson Waste.
Scoundrels, criminals, outlaws,
all of them. Be careful, kids.
Next time,
I might not be around to save you.
Oh, wow.
-We need her.
-What?
Excuse me? Hi, can we join you? Great.
-[giggles]
-[scoffs]
I'm Adora. This is Bow and Glimmer.
And we came to--
Blondie, Boy, Glitter, got it. Huntara.
Now what do you want?
-It's Glimmer. Actually, Princess Glimmer.
-Oh, a Princess. Me, too.
I'm the Princess of Crimson Waste.
Can you tell?
Or am I not sparkly enough for you?
We're looking for something
in the center of the Crimson Waste.
It's important we find it.
You seem like you know this place well.
Can you take us?
Did you not hear what I just said
about trusting people?
Well, yeah,
but you said that while saving us.
So, you can't be all bad. What do you say?
[laughing]
Excuse us for one moment.
You sure about this, Adora?
All the scary people
are scared of Huntara,
which is not usually a great sign.
We can just ask for a map or--
A map won't get us past the scary plants
or quicksand
or whatever else is out there.
We need a guide.
If I say no, you'll go out there
by yourselves and get killed, is that it?
I mean, not ideally, but yeah.
[all groaning]
Looks like you've got yourselves a guide.
Great. See, guys, problem solved.
I know Hordak told me to go away,
but I have some ideas
for the portal machine.
Emily, will you cut that--? [shouting]
Curious.
[Hordak grunting]
Okay, Emily, you might have a point.
[beeping]
Quietly, quietly.
[metal clanging]
[shouts]
Hi.
Get out.
Get out right--
[groaning]
So, heh, for a place that's
supposed to be uninhabitable,
the Crimson Waste sure is habited.
Crimson Waste takes in all sorts.
They come running from the law,
from their enemies,
from different kingdoms.
-From the Horde?
-[growls]
The war will destroy all those idiots
caught up in it.
What are you running from?
[shouting]
Huntara doesn't run from anything.
You got that?
I want to be here.
Wait.
Huh. Not bad, Blondie.
What can I say? I'm a fast learner.
Cocky. Heh. I like that.
Give it some time, you'll do well here.
No, thanks.
This has been a really terrible,
snake-filled day.
Honestly, I don't know
what we would've done without you.
[groans]
-[whispering] We should say something.
-No, we are supporting her. Now, shh.
-You shush. Shh.
-Shh.
[both shushing]
-No, you. Quiet.
-What? You.
Your travel companions are loud.
Ha. Well, it's been a long trip
from Bright Moon.
Bright Moon? [grunts]
Listen, I know my tracker pad
isn't working,
but I'm sure we're going the wrong way,
a different way than we'd been going.
We wouldn't be going anywhere
without Huntara.
-This is probably just a shortcut.
-[Huntara] We're here.
[gasps]
[Glimmer] Uh...
We're where?
This can't be the center
of the Crimson Waste.
There's nothing here.
There has to be something here.
I was so sure. The message said-- [grunts]
What?
[groaning]
-[both shouting]
-Adora.
[grunts]
[grunting]
For the honor of...
Paralyzing darts.
But you probably figured that out,
being a fast learner and all.
[all grunting]
Outsiders are a risk to all of us.
I did tell you
not to trust anyone, Blondie.
[gasps]
Ta-da! I made you soup.
Soup always makes me feel better.
[grunting]
Okay, I know one big soup
is probably better,
-but they're so cute.
-[sniffs then shouts]
I am not discussing this.
[grunting]
[Entrapta] Your armor,
-it's holding you together.
-It is none of your concern.
You're from another planet.
That thing in the vitrine looks like you.
You've got tech
compensating for your body.
As a scientist, I'm not going to stop
until I figure out what's going on.
Now, tell me everything.
[groans]
You wanna know what I am?
I am a clone.
A clone of the Emperor
of the Known Universe.
Horde Prime.
Horde Prime cloned himself,
building an army to conquer all he saw.
Planets, worlds, galaxies fell before us.
I was his top general.
But there was a defect in my cloning,
and defects are worthless to Prime.
I was sent to die on the front lines.
But during battle, a portal opened
and sent me crashing to Etheria.
Stranding me here.
With nothing but a broken ship,
I built an empire.
When my portal opens,
I shall bring forth my brothers' armies
to crush the Rebellion.
And Horde Prime will see
that he was wrong.
I am not a defect.
I am worth something.
[groans]
But my portal machine does not work.
I haven't conquered the planet.
I could not even clone
a new body for myself.
Perhaps--
Perhaps Prime was right.
-I am a failure.
-[Entrapta shouts]
Oh, no, no, no. I'm listening.
I heard you.
I've got an idea, but I need my tools.
Be right back.
[Glimmer pants]
Okay, ninth time's the charm.
Everyone, hold on. One, two...
[all grunting, then thud]
[Adora] Bow, are you okay?
[Bow] Luckily, everyone landing on my ribs
distracts from the other bruises.
[Glimmer] I'll get it this time. Hold on.
[all grunting]
I'm sick of this.
We've been tricked, robbed,
temporarily paralyzed.
-Now we're stuck here in the middle of--
-[Bow] Glimmer.
I mean, I'm so glad
we finally got out of there.
Adora?
Having this mission
made me feel in control.
After the last few days,
I really needed it. I needed answers.
I thought if I found out more about Mara,
I'd find out more about myself,
where I came from and why.
And we'll still get those answers.
We're not beat yet.
Sure, this road trip
has been kind of a disaster.
[Glimmer] Pretty standard for us.
But we know you're going through a lot,
and we've got your back,
whatever you need to do.
Besides, it's not like you stole
our weapons and left us stranded.
-[Adora] It's Huntara.
-Exactly. It's Huntara's fault.
No. It's Huntara.
Ooh, this is gonna be so much fun.
I do not need your help in this.
[Entrapta] Everybody needs help sometimes.
And you shouldn't be upset
that you're not perfect. Take Emily.
Her programming is glitchy,
the left leg sticks, and she's loud.
Emily's got quirks,
but that's why I like her.
Imperfection is what makes
scientific experimentation possible.
Imperfection is beautiful.
At least to me.
Stand here.
And you're really way too obsessed
with this whole failure thing.
-I mean, I'm a failure. Shh.
-You are not a--
I don't fit in.
I became friends with Adora,
but she abandoned me.
Then I became friends with Catra,
but she doesn't talk to me anymore.
[alarm buzzes]
But that doesn't mean I give up.
I scrounged up more pieces
of First Ones Tech,
and I can't think of
a better use for it than this.
[grunting]
Ta-da!
Your armor is more of an exoskeleton now.
The tech compensating
for your organic body.
What does it feel like?
Powerful.
[chuckles]
I--
I acknowledge the work you put into this.
It is very
technologically sound.
[screeches]
Uh... No matter what you say,
you are not a failure.
-Any who discount you are utter fools.
-Thanks.
I like being friends with you, too.
What do you think this one does?
[shouts]
Stop messing around.
Come on, we're just having fun.
Didn't you see the shock
on those outsiders' faces?
Oh, look at this.
I think Huntara liked them.
Are you feeling guilty?
[grunts]
I did what I had to to keep us all safe.
[laughing]
You mean, keep yourself safe.
You act so tough,
but you're running scared from something,
just like the rest of us.
[growls]
I don't run away from anything.
I am Huntara of the Crimson Waste.
Nice. I'm Princess Glimmer of Bright Moon,
and I sparkle.
[grunting]
[groaning]
[shouting and grunting]
[Adora] That's mine.
Then come and take it.
That's mine.
[growls]
[grunts]
Ha!
[Adora grunting]
Quick, time for She-Ra.
Wait. You know about She-Ra?
Know about She-Ra?
[laughing]
I am She-Ra.
For the honor of Grayskull.
She-Ra is a person?
Where did you hear about She-Ra?
After all, it's not like it's something
they teach you in the Horde.
I was a Horde soldier.
They told us we were heroes
freeing Etheria from the evil Princesses.
But when I saw what we were doing,
how Hordak just threw soldiers away.
Well, you know what we saw.
You were one of us.
That's where you learned to fight,
isn't it?
-I'd recognize that training anywhere.
-You deserted. I did, too.
-And I joined the Rebellion.
-Then you're a fool.
One girl can't make a difference
against the Horde,
even a tall shiny girl like you.
-It's useless to try.
-Maybe, but I'm not alone.
I won't stand by
and watch people get hurt.
And I won't run away.
Huntara, I need your help.
I need you to help us find
what we came for.
Together, we can all bring this war
to an end.
You need to drop your weapons.
[groaning]
Come on, Huntara,
let's grab our loot and go.
[grunting]
You're right. What I saw in the Horde
scared me, and I ran.
But I'm not gonna run anymore.
I face my problems head-on.
And if you're trying to stop the war,
then I will do what I can to help you.
Come on. We've got lots of ground to cover
before we reach the ship.
What ship?
Adora...
what is that?
It's--
It's Mara's ship.
[closing theme playing]