-[shouts]
-Oh.
-You're already here. Perfect.
-Yeah. Where have you been?
Is this some new She-Ra form?
No. This is Huntara. She's the leader
of the Crimson Waste. Or was.
Uh, we don't have time to get into it.
We need to get to the Fright Zone.
The world doesn't stop
just because you aren't here.
We have been planning our attack
on the Horde.
That's a relief,
because Catra kidnapped Adora.
[all gasping]
The Horde has Adora?
Which also means they can open a portal
because they have her Sword.
-What? I don't understand.
-There's no time.
-Glimmer, slow down.
-We need to go to the Fright Zone now.
We? You are not going anywhere
until you explain.
Glimmer, outside. Now.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[grunting]
This suit may be my best work yet.
[shouting]
No reason to get in a tizzy.
I have never been in a tizzy.
You can't expect everything
to work perfectly overnight.
Like our machine.
We still haven't figured out
the missing piece
that'll let us cut through
the planetary interference.
If we try now, the portal might not be
stable long enough to get anyone through.
[sighs]
We only need to open a portal
for a short time.
Long enough to send a signal
through to Horde Prime.
Once he receives it, he should have
no trouble opening a portal from his side.
And then you'll have to go with them.
But there's still so much data
we could collect. What's the rush?
We'll just keep working on it
until it's perfect.
[grunting]
[gasps]
[Catra] What?
Heh. Didn't expect to see me again?
[Entrapta] Oh, you have a whip now?
Focus. I got what you needed.
This sword is the key to the whole planet.
I suppose it makes sense.
She-Ra's sword is First Ones tech,
maybe the most powerful I've ever seen.
All this time,
this was the key that we needed.
I guess I should figure out how it works.
[snapping]
I brought you everything you need
to open a portal
and finish the Princesses off for good.
What are we waiting for?
Hmm.
[continues grunting]
We're wasting too much time.
We need to act.
The Horde has Adora and the Sword.
And then what?
How are you going to get in?
You have no plan. We are not rushing in.
I won't lose anyone else.
Before I started "rushing in,"
the Rebellion hadn't made a move in years.
You need me.
I need you to be a leader, and that means
not running off whenever you like.
What's the point? You'll always be around,
telling me what I can't do.
You never listen.
I try and try to reach you, to trust you.
[laughing]
You wanna talk about trust?
How come you never told me
that Shadow Weaver was Dad's old teacher?
I...
It was a long time ago.
You know what? We should be talking
to her. She knows the Horde.
She can't be trusted.
We have to do something.
You would see that
if you weren't totally paralyzed by fear.
I am your queen,
and I say
we cannot afford to lose anyone else.
Either come up with a reasonable plan,
Commander Glimmer,
or stay out of the way.
[sighs]
[whistling]
Uh...
With the sword connected
to the portal machine,
we should finally be able to bypass
the planetary interference.
I just have no idea how it works. Heh.
[Adora grunting]
Must she be here?
Good question.
I'm not sure if we just need the sword
or if we need She-Ra, too.
You wouldn't happen to know, would you?
No. Even if I did,
I wouldn't tell the Horde.
[Entrapta] That's okay.
I like figuring stuff out.
Please, Entrapta, you don't wanna do this.
Silence. Entrapta, begin.
You...
You took me away from my family
when I was a baby.
You lied to me my whole life,
about the Princesses,
about Etheria, about who I am.
I could not have lied to you
about who you are.
I have never known nor cared
about someone as inconsequential as you.
[Adora shouting]
You should care, because I'm the one
who's gonna make sure you fail.
I will not fail.
You have no power to stop me.
I am opening that portal.
And I am going to use your own sword
to wipe out the rest of your pathetic
Rebellion once and for-- [grunting]
[growls] Get it to work.
[gasps]
Wow.
[grunting]
[Bow] This is a bad idea.
It's a great idea.
Okay, it's terrible.
But what choice do we have?
I wanna help as much as you do,
but Shadow Weaver?
Adora needs us now.
And Shadow Weaver would know
all about the Fright Zone's weak points.
Let's at least talk to her.
[shouts]
[Shadow Weaver] Princess.
It's about time.
You knew we were coming?
Him, I had no idea about. But you...
You are smart, you want to stop the Horde,
and you know I'm the only one
who can help you.
I must admit, I thought it would
take you longer to speak with me.
Catra kidnapped Adora
in the Crimson Waste.
We need to get her back, before the Horde
uses her and her sword to open a portal.
[Shadow Weaver] His machine is complete?
And they have Adora? We must hurry.
If Hordak has the opportunity
to open a portal,
he will do so immediately.
The Alliance will never get there
in time--
But perhaps...
What? What is it?
Let me out and I can help you teleport
right into the heart of the Fright Zone.
[chuckles] Me?
I couldn't even get to the edge of the
Fright Zone without running out of power.
-I'm nowhere near strong enough.
-But I can make you stronger.
I'm still the only sorceress who has ever
been able to tap into a Runestone.
If you allow me to access your connection
to the Moonstone,
I can enhance your powers.
You could teleport us all the way there.
Uh, us?
I suppose you could come.
We'll teleport into Hordak's sanctum,
disable the portal machine,
and find Adora.
You can really make me that powerful?
You think of yourself only as a Princess,
but you're the child of a great sorcerer.
You have a more powerful connection
to magic than you've ever realized.
Let me show you.
You just wanna use Glimmer's power
to escape.
I want to destroy Hordak.
We must strike now.
Hordak can't be allowed to open a portal.
We'll never have another opportunity.
You know that.
[gasps]
[Bow groaning]
-Hey, would you look at this?
-You can't take that.
-[laughs] Let's make this thing official.
-It doesn't even fit.
[groaning]
Not bad. You look good in a uniform.
Catra. Catra, there you are.
-I have been looking everywhere for you.
-I've had my hands full.
Any minute now,
Hordak's going to open a portal
and I'll be the reason
the Horde defeats the Princesses.
But hey, I couldn't have done any of it
without you. Thanks.
[laughing]
[shouts]
You're right. Just look away.
-I can't. What's taking Hordak so long?
-Entrapta...
we never meant to leave you behind.
We thought you were dead.
But Catra said you abandoned me.
Catra would say anything
that helps her get what she wants.
Catra is my friend. I think.
Yes, the data says she is.
Look, I understand.
Catra was my friend, too.
But she makes bad decisions.
This is one of them.
The Horde's armies will come through,
and then it's all over for Etheria.
You can't open a portal.
Oh, but I can.
Did you miss the whole sword
makes the portal machine work thing?
-I really don't have time to explain it.
-It's too dangerous.
All exploration has an element of danger.
But think of what we could find.
Whole worlds, galaxies,
things we can't even imagine.
Entrapta, please listen.
It isn't going to work.
The last She-Ra made it
so we could never open another portal.
Trying could destroy everything.
I have noticed some anomalies
in my portal trials.
They could potentially pose a problem.
Maybe I should run more tests.
You won't try to escape if I just pop out
for a quick sec, will you?
Uh...
No?
Okay, great, really appreciate it.
Come on, Emily.
[grunting]
[all gasping]
What do you think you're doing?
Don't try to stop us.
This is the only way to save Adora.
We're not trying to stop you.
We wanna come with you.
We could do the whole "You can't
come with us, it's too risky" thing.
Or you could just accept
that we're coming. Because we are.
A larger group
will be a disadvantage. I won't--
[Mermista] We're calling the shots.
You're gonna have to make that thing
bigger, weird scary lady.
Glimmer?
Quickly now.
[gasps]
[grunting]
No.
[shouts]
[gasps]
We did it. I did it. Oh, that was amazing.
Hmm. Kind of figured Hordak's sanctum
would be way scarier and not so empty.
Yeah, no,
decorating is not their strongest suit.
We aimed for
Hordak's sanctum, but obviously we missed.
We're not far. Stay behind me.
And try to be quiet.
[door opens]
We have to go.
I'll hold her off.
[squealing]
[grunting and shouting]
[alarm blaring]
My turn.
I didn't almost drown
in these sewers for nothing.
I want in.
[thud]
We'll keep them busy. Go.
Lonnie, why did you pull--? Shadow Weaver?
[grunting]
Heh. I heard you were with the enemy,
but are you actually holding hands
with a princess right now?
There's no sense in trying
to fight us. You don't stand a chance.
Join us, or stand aside.
[shouts]
[grunting]
[Bow shouting]
-Bow.
-Don't lose your focus.
Concentrate.
[groaning]
[shouts]
Catra, there's no need for us
to be enemies.
I can help you.
I can offer you a way out.
So, what? You're on the side of good now?
You made me this way,
and you get to be the good guy?
[shouting]
Do you know what happened to me
after you escaped?
Do you even care?
You couldn't wait to get away from here,
from me.
But you came back for Adora.
I came back to stop Hordak.
I will make sure he's destroyed.
Don't make me destroy you, too.
Oh, I'm going to make sure we win.
We're going to open that portal,
and then there will be nothing left of you
or the Princesses.
[groaning]
[grunting]
Stop it. You're taking too much.
No. You can't fight them,
they're too strong.
Ah, boy, I really appreciate you
letting me assist you. I miss hanging out.
Yeah, you've been so busy
with Hordak lately and Catra--
I mean, she's got her new friends.
Oh, this is not good.
Oh, you want me to go, too?
I understand. I'm probably in your way.
I'll just--
No, not that.
I've been running diagnostics
on the portal. Watch.
[explosions playing on screen]
You are right. That is not good.
Is that gonna happen?
I mean, to the actual planet?
This is just an illustration.
What will actually happen
will be much worse.
If my numbers are right, and they are,
if we open a portal,
the anomalies will be catastrophic.
It'll unhinge time and space,
creating a warped reality
that will collapse in on itself,
erasing us from existence.
I never thought I'd say this,
but we can't go through with it.
[door opens]
[Scorpia] Catra.
[grunts]
Why aren't you in Hordak's lab?
Uh, mm...
There's no time.
-We need to fire up the portal machine.
-[Entrapta] We can't.
Opening a portal right now
will be disastrous.
It's going to collapse
and take us all with it. Adora was right.
[Catra] Adora is right.
[chuckling]
Adora gets everything she wants.
[sighs]
But not this time.
This time, I am going to win.
I don't care what it takes.
We are opening that portal now.
No. I won't. I need to tell Hordak.
He'll understand--
[shouting]
[panting]
-Get her out of here.
-What do you want me to do with her?
I don't care. Just get rid of her.
-Put her on the transport to Beast Island.
-Beast Island? You can't.
You wanna be next?
[shouting]
-Glimmer, no.
-There's no choice. Do it.
[Hordak] Oh...
She did it.
The Princesses are here.
There's no time,
we need to open the portal.
Where's Entrapta? I need her.
Who do you think let the Princesses in?
[gasps]
[groans]
[shouting]
But she--
She wouldn't.
[laughing]
-Did you really think she was on our side?
-[shouts]
Oh, you can't trust anyone,
especially a Princess.
They'll just use you
to get what they want.
Open the portal and let's end this.
[grunting]
[Bow] This way.
Bow.
Forget about them. Pull the switch.
[grunts]
Catra, please, don't.
No!
[ominous theme playing]