[Adora] So, where's Glimmer again?
Didn't she call us here?
Uh, I'm sure she'll be here soon.
[both shouting]
-You're all here. Good. Just one second.
-Glimmer... [groans]
Oh, I see. She's really taking
this queen stuff seriously.
As part of my new anti-Horde strategy,
I'm sending you, Adora, Bow and Huntara
to retrieve Mara's ship
from the Crimson Waste.
Then, Bow will repair it
and then we'll have a spaceship.
Take that, Horde.
-Uh, Glimmer?
-What?
The Crimson Waste is a desert.
Doesn't Mermista need, like, water
to use her powers?
[Mermista slurping straw]
Oh, good point.
Be right back.
She gonna do that all the time now?
-Oh, definitely.
-Did I hear the queen?
She's needed
in the defense meeting immediately.
Oh! Hello, everyone.
What a wonderful...
[sneezes]
interruption to my morning meditation
and to see so much of our beautiful planet
before I've had my daily tea ceremony.
Sorry, I may have gotten
a little lost on the way.
But like I was saying,
the Waste has tons of plants
-which you can use to bring the ship back.
-The Crimson Waste?
That's the one.
As my first act as queen,
I'm sending you all on the mission
while I stay back
and do important queen duties.
Hey, leave it all to us.
It'll probably be a boring mission anyway.
[chuckles]
Queen Glimmer, you are extremely late
for your next meeting.
[sighs]
-We'll go the fun way.
-[shouts]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong
And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
So, this is, like, your kingdom?
I'm not a princess.
Still, it must be nice to be home.
Do you miss it?
I left. Now I'm back.
-No need to make a big thing out of it.
-Mm-hm.
You, um, make flowers?
I control all plants.
Watch.
[humming]
[grunting]
Uh-huh.
[groaning]
It's just something
I'm blessed to be able to--
[shouting]
Uh-huh.
Blessed.
If we run into trouble, is flower girl
gonna be able to handle herself?
Oh, Perfuma?
Oh, yeah, she's a demon in battle.
[groaning]
Plus, I got this.
[laughs]
-A bracelet?
-No.
This is how I'll carry my sword
from now on.
It's pretty great, right?
I know you trained with the Horde, too,
but I think all this time
with the princesses has made you soft.
[gasps]
[groans]
[chuckling] Soft?
Are you serious? I'm as tough as ever.
I bet I can beat you to the ship.
[snorts] Never gonna happen.
Ah.
Here, let me help.
What are you...?
[shouting]
I'm trying to expand my arsenal
with new tech. What do you think?
Why would you have an arrow for this?
It just seems like there are easier ways.
Your intention was kind. Thank you.
Wanna talk about it?
I'm trying to be zen about this,
but if I'm being honest,
and I always try to speak my truth,
I just don't get cacti.
They're so rough and unfriendly.
Well, maybe if you give cacti a chance,
you'll find that under that rough surface
she's a really great friend.
Huh?
Uh... This cacti thing
is about Huntara, right?
What? No, I really mean cacti.
They're the one plant I can't control
or keep alive.
Everyone says they're so easy,
but you still have to water them,
and I always under water
and then over water. And I...
[humming]
[sighs]
That's better. I'm-- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I greet each dawn
with a centering morning ritual
to make sure I am my best self,
but today my ritual was interrupted.
And now I am here, surrounded by cacti.
Cacti that hate me. [sobbing]
How am I ever gonna use them
to move the ship?
Uh...
That may not matter.
[panting]
I can't--
I can't believe the Horde took the ship.
Also, I could've run more.
Or it could've been any number
of Crimson Waste scavengers,
and I could have run more.
Gosh, well, I guess
we'll just have to come back another time.
[device beeping]
Yeah, I'm ready.
Sorry, it's my pad.
I souped it up so Glimmer can check in.
How's the mission? Got the ship yet?
[chuckles]
-[Adora] No. Hang up. Bow. Turn it off.
-Well, there's a small problem--
No, Bow. Stop it.
What's Adora doing?
Dancing.
Because, uh, the mission
is going just so great.
But we, um, have to go
do more mission stuff now.
-Talk later, bye.
-Wait, don't...
There's no reason to worry her.
We'll find the ship.
This is my home turf.
Huntara can track anything in the Waste.
I'm an expert tracker, too.
Then you know, it's all in the sand.
Mm-hm. Rubber, mechanical.
You may be right, it was the Horde.
Uh-huh. Definitely,
definitely getting rubber.
And, uh, sand.
We could also,
you know, just follow these.
Oh, of course.
I should have known.
Uh...
Should you, though?
Because I don't see anything.
-Oh, well, we tried!
-Don't give up yet, flower girl.
[gasps]
The Valley of the Lost.
It's a smuggler's haven, and my home.
[roaring]
[chattering]
How are we supposed to find
anything in there?
This has been
my gang's base since I arrived here.
Nothing can hide from me in this valley.
[laughs]
[woman] Come back here.
[gasps]
[growls]
[grunts]
[gasps]
No.
-Shh. Catra's goons are here.
-They're not her goons.
They're my goons.
I just never got a chance to fire them.
I'll fix that now.
Maybe it's best to avoid confrontation?
You're afraid to fight, flower girl?
No, Perfuma's right.
There's sure to be others.
We'll be outnumbered.
I don't like not fighting.
Understood.
But finding the ship is our mission.
[woman] They went this way. Over here.
[Horde soldiers grunting]
The Valley is crawling
with Horde soldiers.
And we still don't know where the ship is.
This is still my home.
And I know who can help.
Careful. We need this junk intact
so Hordak can make new weapons.
[Scorpia] Oh, I am so sorry about that.
This isn't what I want
to be happening right now.
Okay. Sorry, sorry.
-That was fast.
-What, did you miss me already?
-Just don't drop anything else.
-No.
These guys look like
they've got it covered.
[clicks] I'd rather hang out
in here with you.
[groans]
What is going on?
Again, I am just so sorry about-- [shouts]
[Scorpia gasps]
Okay. This is...
This is a thing that I'm seeing.
Are you also seeing two of me?
[gasps] Oh, I have a twin.
I felt this emptiness and like there was
someone who would just understand.
Oh, this is making so much sense to me.
Ugh. Who am I kidding?
Hordak probably cloned me.
I signed a lot of paperwork at some point.
Yeah, being quiet now.
Who are you
and what exactly are you trying to pull?
[screams]
[gasps]
Are you sure we can trust her contact?
You scared?
Of course not.
Good, because we're here.
Ugh. Who would pay for this junk?
Fools, just like you.
You shouldn't be here.
It's not safe.
Hurry.
Grox, what's going on? Where's the gang?
Hiding.
The Waste has been infested
with Horde scum since you left.
Can't turn without running into them,
interfering with business.
-[grunts]
-Things here haven't been easy.
You're a real sight for sore eyes.
You, too.
Grox, I need your help.
We're looking for a ship.
And I got just the thing to help.
Aha.
Found it.
Now, before I do this, Huntara,
I need you to remember one thing.
One very important thing you forgot.
This is the Crimson Waste.
Trust no one.
[blowing horn]
I've got the Rebel intruders.
You sold us out?
[laughing]
Look at you.
The Huntara I knew
would've seen this coming.
You've gone soft.
-[woman] They're in there. Come on.
-Leave her. We have to go.
I'll be back for you.
Run along now.
That's what you're good at.
They went out the back.
Looks like there's no
avoiding a fight now, Princess.
For the honor of Grayskull.
Perfuma, cactus, block off this alley
so they can't surround us.
You can do this.
[shouting]
I can't do this.
[Huntara] Run.
[grunting]
[device beeping]
Bow, turn it off.
Ugh. I'm in the middle
of the most boring meeting.
[whispering] Can't talk.
We're being chased
through a smuggler's den.
[gasps] You are? That sounds so fun.
Quiet that thing.
-I'm gonna have to call you back.
-Don't hang...
Pleasure to meet you.
The name's Double Trouble.
And I'm about to become
your new best friend.
-Oh, yeah? I'm done with best friends.
-Mm?
[scoffs]
Enough games.
What do you want from me?
It's not what I want from you,
but what you want from me.
All I want from you
is for you to stop being me.
Oh, sorry.
I plain forgot.
Sometimes I just get so lost
in my character.
Ta-da!
Thank you, thank you.
[gasps]
I gotta sit down.
-This is what you really look like?
-More or less.
Of course, we all wear costumes.
I just happen to be able to wear
other people as costumes.
For a price.
Huh. So it's money you're after.
[laughing]
Aren't we all, darling?
But if you don't require
someone with my gifts,
I'll just take my business
to the other side.
How exactly
are you planning on doing that?
I have a knack
for getting out of tight spots.
-What?
-And you can change into anyone? Anytime?
Ugh. "Change"?
What I do is so much more than changing.
I prefer "transform."
My real gift is committing to my roles.
Sure, I can physically replicate anyone,
but that doesn't mean a thing
if you can't be them emotionally.
It's an art.
[woman] Rebels. In the valley.
Perfuma, what happened back there?
[grunting] I hate cacti.
There, I said it.
I love and honor all things, except cacti.
And I don't like spitting
or Crimson Waste.
It is full of negative energy.
Well, it wasn't always like this.
It used to be a great place,
where an honest criminal
could carve out a life.
Well, it's terrible now.
I know.
Ouch.
[device beeping]
Did you seriously hang up on me?
Yeah, but just because
we were running from the Horde.
And now we're hiding from the Horde.
Also, the Horde has Mara's ship.
-[grunts]
-Sorry.
-We totally have it under--
-Really? This is so cool.
A dire situation.
Odds against us.
I can't believe I'm missing this
for a dumb meeting.
Okay, hang tight. I'm on my way.
Wait, Glimmer, don't--
We can't wait for Glimmer.
The Horde's probably going to take
the ship, whatever they can get,
back to the Fright Zone.
I think I know how to find it.
We'll use this.
Horde badges
have tracking devices built in.
That's how they found Catra
when we kidnapped her.
I can hack into their system
and see where all of the Horde soldiers
are in the valley.
They're sure to be with the ship.
And there's our ship.
I have a plan,
but it's gonna depend on you, Perfuma.
We should come up
with a different plan then.
Come on, Perfuma,
you're one of the strongest people I know.
If you hadn't rescued me
in the Battle of Bright Moon,
I wouldn't be here now.
Or me.
You rescued me from the Fright Zone.
We're not in the Fright Zone.
We're here,
and I'm just a useless flower girl.
[Huntara] No, you're not.
I've been wrong about a lot.
I was wrong to leave my home.
I was wrong about Grox.
And I hope I'm wrong about you
because we need your help.
You want my help?
[chuckles]
For the honor of Grayskull.
Hello.
[grunting and shouting]
[Catra] Hey.
Careful with the goods.
[groaning]
Focus. Um, uh...
[humming] Right? Do it with me.
[both humming]
You got it. All right.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm not strong enough
to lift this by myself.
[gasps] I don't have to be.
We're underground.
You're just noticing that now?
You know what else is underground?
Roots.
[grunting]
[gasps]
These cacti have the most powerful
root system I've ever seen.
I was so wrong about them.
[Huntara] And I was definitely wrong
about you, flower girl.
[grunting and shouting]
[gasps]
We have a problem.
I got something more important to do.
It was fun distracting you, though.
[shouting]
-Oh.
-[laughing]
How did she get out of that?
-Yeah.
-Yes. We did it.
-I'm sorry I doubted you.
-It's all right.
We're all on a journey
of personal growth today.
I was so wrong to insult your home.
It turns out cacti have flowers too.
[shouts]
Hey, you didn't save any bad guys for me.
I made it here as soon as I could.
I only got a little lost, in the ocean.
Aw.
-You should've waited for me.
-Sorry, but we did get the ship.
Your first mission as queen is a success.
Hmm.
Queen Glimmer, I need to stay,
and take the Waste back for the Rebellion,
and for my people.
I won't abandon my home again.
Aw, say no, Glimmer.
I've gotten fond of this desert rose.
Let anyone hear you calling me that
and I'll throw you
into another exploding cactus.
[both laughing]
[all laughing]
I don't get it.
You had to be there.
Wow. [chuckles]
Bravo. Yes.
Oh, stop.
Did you really like my audition?
Like doesn't cover it.
Well, I could've used more time
to prepare.
Really get into your skin.
-I grew up with Adora and you fooled her.
-[gasps]
If you can do that, we can do anything.
This is gonna be fun.
[closing theme playing]