[cawing]
[grunts]
Now.
[soldier shouting]
Boom, nets.
Everyone, be ready.
Our scouts reported the Horde
is transporting a new prototype weapon.
They wouldn't brave the Whispering Woods
unless it was something powerful.
If I know Entrapta, this thing
is gonna be big, unpredictable and...
invisible.
Genius.
Or it's just empty.
But our scouts said Catra
would be moving the weapon today.
It's supposed to be here.
[robots approaching]
It's an ambush.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
-♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
-♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
I don't understand how this happened.
The Horde must have figured out
we were going after the transport
and laid a trap.
Ooh.
Uh--
Are you all okay?
Never been better.
[both shout]
Okay, we've been slightly better.
How do they keep doing this?
No matter where I send you,
the Horde always shows up
to ruin the mission.
And I'm just sitting here, I--
It's okay, Glimmer. Everyone knows
you're needed in Bright Moon.
So, what's the plan now?
Did someone say Swift Wind?
Swift-- Hang on.
-Did someone say--?
-No one said Swift Wind.
But you just did. Anyway, I backtracked
down the path the transport was on.
It came from the mountains,
on the far side of Bright Moon.
That could be where they're keeping
the weapon. We have to investigate.
A smaller team will avoid detection.
Get in and out
before the Horde even knows you're there.
I hate sending you guys back out.
Whatever this is, we need to destroy it
before it's used on innocent people.
-Right, guys?
-Count us in.
Darling, your arm.
Uh-huh? Nice try.
Spinnerella refuses to accept
that I busted two more bots than she did,
so I'm winning.
-There is nothing to win--
-[clearing throat]
So, uh, hey, how about we take
this conversation to the War Room?
-We've got a mission to plan.
-Great. Let's go.
[groans]
Oh, sorry, Your Majesty.
Sorry, Flutterina, I didn't see you.
Oh, it's okay.
Are you guys going on a mission?
Can I come?
Not this time.
And not all of us are going.
Next time, then.
Rebellion Soldier Flutterina is ready.
Have fun.
I can't get over
how ridiculous you look, "Flutterina."
Right? I said to myself, "Double Trouble,
what sort of character
would the Princesses trust?"
Someone tooth-achingly cute and pink.
Then it came to me, Flutterina.
A role for the--
Yeah, great, whatever. Is there any news?
Your team did quite a number
on the Rebels.
They came limping back in,
so despondent, such emotion.
Oh! It was breathtaking.
Your intel was good,
but they still got away.
Espionage is a long game, kitten.
The Rebels are tired, demoralized.
[laughing]
And you should've seen Glimmer's face
when she realized
she'd been outsmarted again.
How is the Horde always two steps ahead?
Angry sparkle, growl.
And any intel on She-Ra?
Or are we done here?
So serious.
Remember, this is supposed to be fun.
This is supposed to be war.
No reason it can't be both.
[grunts]
All business, no fun.
She-Ra's putting together a team
to track down Hordak's new weapon.
She-Ra's not going to find anything.
But they'll all see the weapon
when the time comes.
Ooh.
Foreshadowing.
Love this.
[sighs]
[laughing]
[grunting and shouting]
-[Shadow Weaver] Impressive.
-Huh?
What are you doing here?
I've come to tend my garden.
You've got to be kidding me.
You're gardening?
You?
One must keep oneself occupied.
Your power is truly a sight to behold.
It's no wonder,
you being Micah's daughter.
I'd never seen a sorcerer like him.
I get it.
I'm the daughter of an angelic being
and a powerful sorcerer,
and I'll never be as good
as either of them.
That's true.
You'll be better.
[Shadow Weaver chuckling]
Don't you remember your raw magical energy
when we invaded the Fright Zone together?
I remember you draining me.
[Shadow Weaver] Yes.
But I did help you become more powerful.
Well, luckily, I don't need your help
for that anymore.
No, I suppose not.
Of course, it's all wasted
if you don't use it.
I've been watching you.
You're trying to be like your mother,
overseeing things from afar.
But you are not her.
You must decide for yourself
what kind of queen you will be.
And I've decided.
I'm a queen who doesn't take advice
from prisoners.
[Swift Wind neighing]
Stay close, and stay quiet.
Just for the record,
I'm being way quieter than you--
Guys, do you hear something?
[gasps]
It's an ambush. Again.
This one's mine.
Ha! Two for one.
Still winning.
[laughs then gasps]
Is...
Is that the new weapon?
It's not very big.
Or move-y.
It could be a surveillance bot.
[gasps, then shouting]
[all shouting]
[panting]
[She-Ra] Bow?
Bow!
[sighs]
[groaning]
-[Bow] Did we win?
-Bow.
Thank goodness. I was so scared.
I feel like we didn't win.
Bow, are you okay?
Don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
I'm just, you know,
gonna lie here for a bit.
[grunts]
Why is he not okay?
Even with healing,
he's still going to need some time
to recover.
I can't keep sending my friends
into ambushes.
How does the Horde know our every move?
I'm sorry, Your Majesty.
I hate to suggest it,
but could they be tracking She-Ra?
That could explain
how they always know where you are.
Bow...
I'm sorry. It's my fault you got hurt.
[Glimmer] No.
This is Catra's fault.
Her, and her bots, and--
And me.
I sent you out, knowing it was dangerous,
while I stayed here, safe and sound.
Don't worry about me.
I'm the one who worries about you.
Can we go back to that? Please?
I'm going back
to find that bot and destroy it.
No. If the Horde is tracking you,
they're gonna be ready. What if--?
Glimmer, you said it yourself.
We can't risk more people getting hurt.
General?
[groaning]
Don't worry, Bow.
I'm gonna take care of this.
Catra. I knew you were behind this.
-Ugh.
-Oh, no, the new weapon! It's firing.
[shouting]
It got me in the abs.
The most vulnerable part of the body
that I refuse to cover,
because I don't own real shirts.
[groaning]
[crying]
If only I was there to sparkle at it.
Oh, Bow!
Glimmer!
She-Ra! [blows raspberry]
[laughing]
Show me She-Ra again.
[She-Ra] I'm She-Ra. [blows raspberry]
[laughing]
Ah.
There it is.
There what is?
The thrill
of seeding destruction and chaos.
Ahem. I'll be thrilled if the Pulsebot
really blew that dummy up.
Sadly, Bow's been healed
by some glowy magic.
-Very dramatic stuff.
-[growls]
Oh, cheer up.
I'm sending coordinates
for She-Ra's position.
She's going back out to destroy the bot
that hurt her friend.
Ugh. Typical heroic Adora plan.
Too bad we'll be gone
by the time she gets there.
But if it's to take down She-Ra,
I think we could stand a delay.
I knew there was a reason I liked you.
Having fun yet?
You know, I think I am.
[Shadow Weaver humming]
Give us a minute.
That's an order.
I need--
The Queen demands your help.
[Shadow Weaver] I see.
And what is it I can do?
You know Catra best.
She's been two steps ahead
this entire time.
Show me how to think like she does,
so I can figure out her next move
before anyone else gets hurt.
[Shadow Weaver]
You don't need to think like Catra.
I told you you're more powerful
than you know.
Are you willing to use your power?
And how, hypothetically, would I do that?
Magic, of course.
A location spell is a simple
but powerful tool for any young sorcerer.
All it takes is a few ingredients...
and the will to see it through.
You've been growing magic plants
this whole time?
What do these do?
[Shadow Weaver]
Those are daisies. I find them cheerful.
Now, the final ingredient,
added by the spellcaster.
Did I do that?
[gasps]
Think about what you're searching for.
Keep it in your mind.
[Glimmer] A secret outpost.
The Horde has been operating
out of the Whispering Woods
this whole time.
Well done.
Oh, no.
Adora's looking in the wrong place.
If we can warn her in time,
we can send her to the outpost
and stop Catra once and for all.
But if Catra's tracking She-Ra,
she'll know we're coming
and clear out before we get there.
Catra won't be expecting an attack.
Her attention will be focused on Adora.
It would be the perfect time to strike.
Are you suggesting I use Adora as bait?
[Shadow Weaver] As a distraction.
But the decision is yours alone to make.
What will you do, Your Majesty?
I don't see any sign of the Horde.
I can take it from here.
I'm not leaving until I destroy this bot.
No. Princesses stick together.
We'll find it.
Ha. You wanna fight some bots. See, Adora?
She is just as competitive as I am.
See, this is why no one comes
to game night anymore.
Adora, tell her.
-Oh, I don't--
-Maybe people don't come to game night
because you insist
on serving vegetable platters.
No one likes vegetable platters.
Right, Adora?
[robot powering up]
Fall back!
[panting]
[robots powering up]
[soldiers shouting]
-What are you doing back--?
-[shouts]
It's you.
Who else would it be?
Didn't anyone ever teach you
to put away your toys?
Otherwise, someone might come
and break them.
You think I don't have more?
I think most of your bots are busy
with She-Ra, leaving you defenseless.
Using your own friend as a decoy?
Wow, didn't know you had it in you.
Guess you don't know everything.
[grunting and shouting]
You even taste like glitter.
Where you going, Catra?
Not scared of some sparkles, are you?
The Pulsebots
are out vaporizing your friends,
but I bet you'd like to see our upgrade.
We were saving it
for a special occasion, but this'll do.
[gasps]
You're gonna bring the whole place down.
Don't worry.
I'm not planning to stick around.
It's revving up to send out a pulse
strong enough to level half the woods.
So you'd better choose. Me, or the bot?
[shouts]
Looks like I don't have to.
[powering up]
[grunting]
Word around Bright Moon was that the Queen
had disappeared on a mission.
I thought I'd come check on you.
Double Trouble. About time.
[grunting]
I don't know how long I can do this.
Glimmer?
Thought you could use some help.
Whoa.
-[gasps]
-[robot powering up]
[shouting]
Spinnerella!
Spinnerella, please, talk to me.
Fourteen.
What?
That was 14 bots for me.
I win.
[chuckles]
That's my girl. You win.
Should I start counting too? Because...
I got the rest.
You should've seen me out there, Bow.
I was like...
[shouting]
Sounds really cool.
But also, really awful?
Ugh. Come on, guys.
Can't we just enjoy this victory?
This isn't over. We need to figure out
how the Horde is tracking me.
But until we do,
at least we can use it to our advantage.
By using me as a decoy?
I know it was dangerous.
But it was the only chance I had
to take out the rest of the bots
before Catra could unleash them.
And it worked.
I'm not gonna stay behind anymore.
That's not the kind of queen I am.
I wanna be out there,
fighting to protect my kingdom.
Side by side with my best friends.
And now that Shadow Weaver's
teaching me magic,
I'll be twice as effective.
What? Shadow Weaver's teaching you?
Guys. We won today,
and no one else got hurt.
-That's what counts.
-Glimmer, I don't know--
Now, I'm gonna go raid the kitchen
in celebration.
-Glimmer.
-I'll bring back some cake.
[Double Trouble] Here's your stop, kitten.
What are you going to tell your boss
about all his shiny new bots
getting blown up?
I'm going to say,
"You're welcome for testing them
before we moved ahead with our big plan.
Obviously they were garbage."
Hey, thank you, by the way for saving me.
I don't know what I would've done
if you hadn't shown up.
Well, I live to serve.
For a price, of course.
Marvelous. And don't worry, darling,
I'll keep a better eye on Glimmer.
Who knew she was so powerful?
Heh. Whatever.
If she hadn't used Adora as bait.
Oh, yes. How devious.
I'd assumed she was all glitter, no grit.
Yeah, that was unexpected.
And then she showed up alone.
Huh. Looks like the friendship
might have a few cracks, huh?
Would be a shame if someone were there
to take advantage of them.
[closing theme playing]