[Kyle] Ow!
[Kyle shouting]
Will you stop messing around
back there, Kyle?
We're almost out of these creepy woods.
[She-Ra shouts]
[shouting and grunting]
[yawns]
[chuckles]
This is kind of fun.
You are not taking
your training seriously.
What? Me?
That doesn't sound like me.
Adora.
Ugh. Come on, Light Hope. It's not
like I'm learning anything new here.
Then I must offer
more hands-on instruction.
There is a bot behind--
Am I done now?
I sense resistance.
Because this is useless.
I don't need more training.
I need answers.
We're fighting a war, and the Horde
has been one step ahead at every turn.
Glimmer thinks
that they're tracking She-Ra somehow.
Is it because my sword is First Ones tech?
Or because I'm a First One?
And what does that even mean?
Who were they? When we found
Mara's ship, she left a recording behind--
Adora.
Mara was compromised.
She became unhinged.
She didn't seem unhinged.
She seemed scared.
And she was talking about a weapon.
If there's something that can protect us
from the Horde, I need to know about it.
Once you balance the planet,
all will be clear.
It is your purpose as She--
She-- She-- She-- She--
-She-- She-- She-- She--
-Oh, wow.
Really? Way to avoid the subject.
Catra better appreciate us
going behind enemy lines
to get this armor plating stuff for her.
[shuttle powering down]
[grunts]
[alarm buzzes]
Guys? Are we home?
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Stupid glitchy door. [grunts]
That is not the Sword of Protection's
intended purpose.
[sighs] Yeah, well, if you're not gonna
tell me anything, I'm leaving. [grunting]
You cannot leave.
My sensors have detected
a fluke spore cloud
blooming in the Whispering Woods.
It is not safe outside.
Well, that's convenient.
You want me to stay here, so you can
not answer more of my questions?
-Adora.
-[gasps]
Light Hope!
Light Hope?
Hello, my name is Light Hope.
How may I assist you?
What's going on?
My system is rebooting.
I would like to answer your query,
but the information as to what is going on
has not yet loaded.
Who are you?
[gasps]
We shouldn't have come
through the Whispering Woods.
It's not safe.
Well, obviously Catra felt it was worth
risking us to get this cargo back sooner.
[shouts]
It's attacking!
Stand back. I'll handle it.
[Lonnie] What is this stuff?
[croaking]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Oh. Oh, it's actually kind of pretty.
Like snow.
[sizzling]
[shouting]
It's hurting! I made a mistake!
Will you quit it, Kyle? [grunts]
[roars]
Why didn't you say it hurts?
[roaring]
I know, Rogelio.
One of us has gotta go back outside
and fix the transport.
Uh, uh...
But outside hurts.
Then we'll just have to stay in here
and wait out whatever is happening.
What? We'll be trapped here?
Maybe for hours or days?
With only each other for company?
And we won't be able to get back
to the Fright Zone?
This is great.
[both groan]
Seriously. The Fright Zone's been
so stressful lately.
Out here we don't have to worry
about Catra showing up and yelling at--
Where are you?
You were supposed to be back an hour ago.
Uh... Uh...
Well, the woods are attacking us
with very painful snow.
Why is he talking?
There's some weird acid storm out there.
-But we're assessing the situation.
-Assess faster.
Hordak needs that armor plating
from the rebel mine, now.
The plan can't fall behind schedule.
Maybe if you told us
what this big plan is, we could help you--
I doubt that, seeing how you failed
to do the one thing I asked.
Hey. It's not our fault.
The transport broke down,
and it's too dangerous to go out there.
I don't care! I gave you an order.
Pick someone,
send them outside, and fix it.
Now.
[sighs]
Understand?
Well?
Yes, Force Captain Catra.
[groans]
Not it.
[chuckles]
[Adora] What do you mean, who am I?
Light Hope?
The Light Hope operating system
is attempting to reload.
Please stand by.
I am pleased to report
that my system is now at 22 percent.
Oh! I have just learned
how to move about the castle.
[shouts]
[chuckles] Okay there.
You seem like you're having fun.
Uh...
Light Hope?
My personality profile
has not fully loaded.
Am I not usually fun?
Oh, no. No, no.
I've never seen you like this.
I have also never seen you like this.
Because your identity has not yet loaded.
Who are you?
Adora.
But I'm, you know...
[whooshing]
She-Ra.
My primary purpose is to train She-Ra.
How may I assist you?
Well, just before rebooting,
you were gonna tell me
all about this weapon Mara mentioned,
and about where I come from,
and about everything
I've ever wanted to know.
Of course.
I will answer all of your questions.
But that information has not yet loaded.
I did, however, just learn
how to control gravity
in the Crystal Castle.
[shouting]
That is not right.
Do not worry, I will fix it.
No, no, no.
[shouting]
[Lonnie] Okay, here's the situation.
One of us has to brave the acid snow,
go out there, and fix the transport.
So we're gonna choose
who goes outside fair and square...
with a game of bot-shield-laser.
Wait, how come you get to decide
what game we play?
Because I'm clearly the leader.
[roaring]
See? Rogelio agrees.
Oh, pipe down. We go on three.
One, two, three.
[groans] Let's try that again.
[shouting]
Apologies.
You appear to be in pain.
Should I adjust the gravity again?
No. Has your system loaded anything
about Mara's weapon yet?
Or, you know, anything useful?
Are spiders useful? Because I have
just learned how to make spiders.
No, they're not. Get rid of them, please.
[grunting]
I am so sorry,
but that information has not yet loaded.
[groans]
For the honor of Grayskull!
[shouts]
[Kyle] Yes!
[chuckles] Shield beats bot. Uh, but,
Lonnie, your laser beats shield, so...
-So you win?
-[laughs]
Except Rogelio's bot beat laser...
Okay, so I beat Rogelio,
but you beat me, and Rogelio beat you.
That means...
we're all winners.
That means this isn't working.
[groans] We need a new game.
[croaking]
Ooh. I have an idea.
[roars]
It would be really good
if your system could finish loading now.
[Light Hope] I agree.
However, my reboot
appears to have malfunctioned.
Loading is frozen at 36 percent.
We must manually override the system
to bring my programming fully online.
How do we do that?
And how can we do it fast?
We must connect this data crystal
to the core processing unit.
I made a crystal.
So where is the core processing unit?
And please don't say--
It is on the other side of these spiders.
[She-Ra groans]
Do not worry.
I will assist you.
Apologies. I made more spiders.
Oh! I know what will help.
No, don't--
[coughing]
I simulated the ocean.
Spiders cannot swim.
What the--?
[grunts]
[laughs]
Perfect score.
Ah? Ah?
Try to beat that.
Okay, wait a minute.
When Rogelio bounced it off of that thing,
you said it was minus five points.
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
Yes. He forgot the magic password,
and he's standing in the loser zone.
You're not wearing the hat,
so another five-point deduction for you.
What? These rules
don't even make any sense.
You're just a sore loser.
Now, watch the master.
[chuckles, then grunts]
Hey! Watch out!
[shouts]
Kyle, did you just lose the game
that you made up?
Uh... [chuckles]
No. No, that's a different move,
and I get all the points and I win.
Oh, uh-uh. No way. Not happening.
[shouts]
Apologies, She-Ra.
I did not know that humans cannot swim.
However, you will note
that I did get rid of the spiders.
I can swim.
I just can't breathe under water.
Interesting. I shall make a note of this.
[Adora grunts]
It's not the ocean. I'll give you that.
[grunting]
What's happening?
It seems that the spore storm outside
has worsened.
It is compromising the Crystal Castle.
Don't tell me the information
for how to stop that hasn't loaded yet.
[shouts]
We need to get
to the processing unit, now.
Place it in the left slot.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Of course my system is only at 36 percent,
so I suppose I am 36 percent sure.
-Perfect.
-It is in fact far from perfect.
I was being sarcastic.
What is "sarcastic"?
Trust me, that information
is never gonna load for you.
Oh.
What?
So, is everything reset now?
Can you finish telling me
about the weapon and Mara?
Hello, my name is Light Hope.
How may I assist you?
[groans]
Guys? Do you think anybody's
gonna come and save us?
Nobody is coming. We gotta save ourselves.
And we better pick someone
to fix the transport soon
or Catra is gonna kill us.
[grunts] I don't even know why we bother.
She doesn't trust us.
She's obsessed with this big plan.
It's the only thing that matters to her.
[Kyle] Don't say that.
Look, she may be mean,
but we've always had each other's backs
ever since we were kids.
She probably sent us on this mission
for, like, team-building.
[croaks]
You guys are the only family
I've ever had.
Even Catra.
Remember when she used my ration bars
to make that cake for Adora?
Uh, that never happened.
That was the weird fake portal reality.
Wait, what?
But we're a unit.
[laughs]
You wanna know what we really are?
We're expendable.
Catra doesn't care about us.
Adora left us.
Everything they taught us in the Horde
about loyalty is meaningless.
It's everyone for themselves.
Fine. Nothing matters, I guess.
Then I'll do it. I'll fix the transport,
so I don't have to be stuck in here
with my non-friends anymore.
[roaring]
Oh, knock it off, Kyle.
You knock it off, Kyle.
What? That doesn't even make any sense.
Nothing makes sense anymore.
Kyle, quit fooling around.
Will you help me out here?
[croaking]
Me? This isn't my fault.
Rogelio.
Please tell me that this time
all your information has loaded.
I am back to full functionality.
Disregard. That was incorrect.
My system reboot
is still at only 36 percent.
Look. I made a bird.
Of course, it was the wrong slot.
I don't know what I expected.
Even when you do know everything,
you don't tell me anything.
You are useless!
[gasps]
Oh, Light Hope, I'm...
I am a hologram.
My primary purpose is to train She-Ra.
If I am not doing that,
then I have failed.
I am sorry, Adora.
Wait, Light Hope.
Light Hope?
[Mara] Light Hope.
Light Hope. Look what I brought you.
[gasps]
Flowers. They're blooming
all over the planet right now.
-Here, smell.
-I have no olfactory sensors.
I cannot smell.
[Mara] They're pretty, though, right?
Pretty. Yes.
They are aesthetically pleasing.
Thank you for bringing them.
I thought they might liven the place up.
I mean, it must be hard
being stuck in here all the time.
I do not mind.
Not when you come to visit me.
[gasps]
[laughing]
I looked at my loaded data banks to see
if I could find the answers you seek.
All I have on Mara
is this memory and a sensation.
Warmth. Her memory brings me warmth.
You and Mara were close?
Yes. We were.
Are we not close?
It's just that you keep things from me.
I know it's in an everything-
will-make-sense-in-time kind of way,
but it's also pretty annoying.
"Annoying." This word has not yet loaded.
Is it good?
No.
I did not think so.
It is my role to watch over She-Ra.
I want to serve She-Ra,
to protect her
to the best of my abilities.
But sometimes,
those abilities are not enough.
Sometimes I feel that way too.
I'm sorry about Mara, and I'm...
I'm sorry I'm not her.
But we could be friends too, if you want.
Friends.
Yes. I would like that.
Come on, let's get you fixed.
[grunting]
Okay, you made your point, Kyle.
-Now turn around. That's an or--
-[helmet beeps]
[grunting]
[shouting]
We shouldn't have let him go out alone.
The armor plating?
Oh, Catra will kill us if it's damaged.
[grunting]
[shouting]
[Lonnie grunting]
[groaning]
You promise this other slot
is the right one?
I am 36 percent sure.
It'll have to do.
Feeling better?
Reboot complete.
Hello, Adora.
The spore cloud has dissipated.
It is safe for you to leave.
You don't wanna hang out with me anymore?
What would we hang from?
Come on, we just saved the Crystal Castle.
There is still the matter
of balancing the planet.
I know that you're just trying
to protect me,
but now that we're friends,
you know you can trust me
with the truth about everything, right?
Once you balance the planet,
all will become clear.
[sighs]
We'll get there.
[groaning]
You came for me. You do care.
We just knew you were gonna mess it up
like you always do. Okay?
[growling]
[chuckles] Hey, you too, buddy.
Probably?
All right, we've gotta get back
to the Fright Zone.
Just keep your leg elevated till then.
[Mara] They're pretty, though, right?
[Light Hope] Pretty. Yes.
They are aesthetically pleasing.
Thank you for bringing them.
I thought they might liven the place up.
It must be hard
being stuck in here all the time.
I do not mind.
Not when you come to visit me.
[laughing]
This memory should have been purged
per directive
of the Heart of Etheria Project.
Permanently delete.
[closing theme playing]