I called you here
to discuss what happened today.
The mission to retake Dryl
was a complete disaster.
We barely made it out.
I wanna know why.
The Horde knew we were coming.
They were ready.
How do they keep doing this?
We thought they were tracking Adora,
but she wasn't even there today.
Isn't it obvious? There's a Horde spy
somewhere in Bright Moon.
And no one is going anywhere
until we figure out who it is.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ♪
♪ Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Mermista, it's very unlikely
that there's a spy--
We need to investigate.
I'll be the lead detective
since I've read
every single Mer-Mystery book.
Mer-what?
Mer-Mystery. It's only the best
undersea mystery novel series ever.
There's 18 of them. It taught me
everything about solving mysteries.
Murder mysteries.
[Sea Hawk grunts]
Um... But no one's been murdered.
-Yet.
-[shouts]
First, we need to question the suspects.
Who are the suspects?
Everyone is a suspect.
Everyone? Is anyone else sweating?
I'm sweating.
This is a waste of time.
We know that the Horde is pulling
their troops back for something big.
-That's what we should be investigating.
-[Adora] No, Mermista's right.
And it can't be me the Horde's tracking
since, once again, you used me
as a distraction today.
A spy is really the only thing
that makes sense.
Maybe they didn't fall for the distraction
because you're a bad actress.
And who would the spy even be, anyway?
Heh. How about the Horde officer
who's living at--
I'm sorry, being held prisoner
at Bright Moon?
Shadow Weaver has actual shadow spies.
We met them.
[Mermista] Shadow Weaver does seem
like the obvious suspect.
Which means it definitely isn't her.
It's never the obvious one.
Like in Mer-Mystery:
The Pearl Who Knew Too Much.
You think it's the pearl, but it's not.
Spoilers.
It's time to interrogate the castle.
How are you doing that?
I practice at home.
[sighs]
[humming]
Move. Now. We don't have all night, Kyle.
Meow. You all right there, kitten?
About time you checked in.
Are the Princesses
still moping around about Dryl?
[scoffs] No.
Watching them mope was my favorite.
Now they're playing detective,
searching for the elusive Horde spy
who foiled their plans.
Wait. Spy? Is your cover blown?
Please. Who would suspect
a goody-two-shoes like Flutterina?
Besides, if they get suspicious,
I'll do a quick wardrobe change
and throw the blame onto someone else.
They better not. Keep them in Bright Moon.
If they catch on
before the plan is complete,
before our big mission is done, I--
Darling, darling, don't worry.
I'll just tire them out a bit.
Where were you when the murders happened?
-The what?
-[Perfuma grunts]
[grunting]
Don't think you can get away with it.
Although there still
aren't any murders, Mermista.
-Yet.
-[grunts]
I sincerely do not have time for this.
According to a bunch of other people...
Witnesses.
you weren't where you were supposed to be
at the battle for Dryl.
I followed the plan exactly.
[grunts] A likely--
Sorry, a likely story.
Admit it. You were slipping away
to warn the Horde of our plan.
Just like in Mer-Mystery:
Secret of the Abalone.
That one's really good.
You should read it.
Look, this is what happened.
On approach to Dryl, Glimmer filled me in.
She-Ra would lure away the Horde.
Team A, Frosta, Bow, and Flutterina,
would scout ahead.
Team B, Sea Hawk and Mermista,
would guard the exits.
Team A indicated the coast was clear,
and we converged on their signal.
-That's when Frosta ran into us and said:
-We haven't finished scouting.
[Bow shouting]
Oh, my.
Team A sent the all-clear.
If you wanna know
what went wrong, ask Bow.
Okay, I confess, it was me.
We're not even interrogating you.
I mean, if I am the spy, it's an accident.
I think. Can you be an accidental spy?
Do I have an evil alter-ego?
Or was I brainwashed
and I'm just realizing it now?
So, like, are you guys
still questioning me or...?
It all goes back to what happened in Dryl.
Everyone was in position,
and I was using my new tech
to look for remaining Horde soldiers.
But then, my goggles glitched,
and I don't know what happened.
I started to see double.
That's when the other team
came in way too early.
I tried to signal everyone to fall back,
but my tracker pad was missing.
Whoa.
Don't you see what this means?
Either I lost my tracker pad at Dryl,
and that gave the Horde vital information,
or I did it on purpose
because I am the spy,
and I gave the signal
and I didn't even know.
You're blowing my mind.
Bow! You aren't the spy.
You don't know that.
It all makes sense.
Who else could it be?
So you're telling us
you really didn't know
about the plan to retake Dryl?
-Really?
-Not a bit.
I've been busy with my garden.
She's always been paranoid
like this, you know.
[chuckles]
I am not being paranoid.
You were spotted around the castle
without your guards this morning,
and I wanna know why.
Actually, Adora, that's--
I was engaging in a ritual.
Essence of echinacea.
A dash of ginger root.
Ah. My daily morning ritual.
[laughing]
Okay, you expect us to believe
you were just having tea?
She's the spy. You're the spy.
Who else could it be?
[Shadow Weaver]
I am not the villain of this story.
As to your question,
Glimmer saw fit to grant me
free rein of the castle.
My guards have been dismissed.
No guards, seriously?
Yes, seriously.
-What has she done other than help us?
-Do you really want me to answer that?
Girls, every moment you waste here,
the Horde gets that much further ahead.
In order to catch a rat,
you need to spring a trap.
Well, in order to catch the spy,
we need you to admit that you're the spy.
Let it go, Adora.
There's lots of other people it could be.
Like who?
[Sea Hawk] Ah.
I love recounting
the epic tales of my exploits.
My heroic exploits.
[groaning]
It definitely isn't Sea Hawk.
Why did you even bring him in?
You said everyone was a suspect.
[Sea Hawk] Exploits for the ages.
Narration.
I was supposed to be guarding the door.
But Perfuma relieved me of duty,
so I could join the fight.
I advanced through the courtyard,
avoiding the booby traps,
risking my very life, just like
in Mer-Mystery: Serpent of the Sea.
Wait, is that where my book went?
Sea Hawk, I've been looking for it.
That's when the clouds parted,
and the moonlight illuminated
my dearest Mermista in the distance.
[giggles]
[Mermista] Moonlight? The battle happened
this morning.
[Sea Hawk] I made my way
over to her, when...
[gasps]
we were ambushed.
My sole aim was to protect Mermista
from the Horde.
Thinking quick, I took on
the 40 to 50 Horde soldiers surrounding us
and saved Dryl.
We lost Dryl, and you punched,
like, one guy before Glimmer got us out.
Exactly, 100 guys.
Wait, wait, I was with the General
the whole time.
And why weren't you
with Sea Hawk, Mermista?
Because Frosta waved me over,
but disappeared before I could reach her.
But that doesn't make any sense.
She was with Bow, and then Glimmer,
and then the others were--
Who wants to watch me do some squats?
I bet Adora and Glimmer
don't shove suspects out the door.
[groans]
Okay, Flutterina, where were you
at the start of the battle?
With Bow and Frosta, of course.
Like we planned.
Is everything okay?
Everything is fine. Now--
It's just that, everyone's so on edge
after what happened in Dryl.
Have you tried interviewing
Shadow Weaver about it?
She seems kind of untrustworthy.
Oh, no, according to Glimmer,
she's totally trustworthy,
and it's fine to just let her walk
around the castle whenever she wants.
Can you please not start this up again?
I'm just saying,
it would've been nice if you told me.
I don't have to tell you
about every decision I make.
[panting]
But you tell Shadow Weaver?
Maybe it's because Shadow Weaver
actually listened
when you and Bow kept leaving without me!
You two seem like you have
a lot to talk about.
Maybe I'll just come back later.
I don't know
why I'm going along with this.
The Horde is obviously planning something.
We should be out there, looking for them,
not stuck here, playing around.
No one's playing around, Glimmer.
There is a reason we've been losing.
And we're going to keep losing
if we don't act soon.
-[shouts]
-There you are.
Why are you just standing around?
This isn't Mer-Mystery: The Case Of People
Who Just Stood Around,
the sequel I wrote right now
about all of you.
Who is even left to question?
I think I saw Mermista
with Bow's tracker pad.
Wait, you guys have been here
the entire time?
Tiny scone?
I can't believe you read those too.
Mer-Mystery: The Maltese Otter
is my favorite.
Ugh, that one's so predictable.
I saw that twist coming a mile away.
[neighing]
-Swift Wind, you weren't even there.
-I told you how I took out 100--
-No, 150 guys, right?
-[Mermista groans]
You have to arrest me
for everyone's safety.
Otherwise, my evil alter-ego
might do it again.
Bow, knock it off.
[neighing]
Still no. And put that back.
[Mermista] It's not them.
-[Perfuma] No.
-[Glimmer] No.
Okay, dude, I think,
like, maybe She-Ra did it.
[Frosta] Hey, we already questioned you.
Oh, yeah, I came back for the tiny scones.
I made a fresh batch.
Fizzy beverage?
[chattering]
If you just lent me the book,
then I'll show you who done it.
-We should interrogate him again.
-Happened in Pearl in the Window.
Glimmer? Where are you going?
This isn't working.
Nothing we do is working.
The Horde is always ahead,
and I can't just wait
for the next bad thing to happen.
So, what? You're gonna teleport
into the Fright Zone
and try to solve this by yourself?
Someone's gotta do something.
Glimmer, please.
You can't leave in the middle of the night
without backup.
The less people involved, the better.
We don't know who to trust.
And what about me?
Were you gonna tell me? Or Bow?
-Adora, I--
-Stay.
Please.
I know we can figure this out
if we work together.
No more secrets
and doing things without us.
We need you here.
I need you here.
Okay. I'm here.
[Bow] Adora! Glimmer!
Where have you guys been?
The communications panel
in the War Room has been severed.
When did this happen?
I don't know. We were passing
by the room when we saw it.
Wait, we saw you run out of here
two minutes ago.
Uh, what are you talking about?
I was with Perfuma.
Could the storm have done something
to cause this?
This wasn't an accident.
This was sabotage.
The General is working
on restoring communications.
In the meantime, there's a backup device
in the dining room, should we need it.
All of us here knew
we were trying to unmask the spy.
And we were the ones
who made the plan to take back Dryl.
We've ruled out all other suspects.
Which means the only person
the spy could be is one of us.
[gasps]
Perfuma let the Horde take the doors.
I wasn't there.
[gasps] Wait, your team was the one
who told us to come in,
and you led Mermista away.
I did not.
Trying to throw the blame
on someone else, huh, Frosta?
If Mermista knows so much about mysteries,
she'd probably know
how to plan the perfect crime.
And there was water by the tracker pad.
Water that could've been melted ice.
It's probably me.
It's not you, Bow!
Or maybe it is,
like in Mer-Mystery: Salt-er Ego.
It couldn't be me. I was busy fighting
at least 200 soldiers.
This is a waste of time, Glimmer.
Shouldn't we be--?
Stop.
Stop questioning my choices,
stop whining
about being a decoy, just stop.
-Okay?
-I'm not whining.
[Glimmer] All you do is question me,
question my authority.
It's exhausting.
[shouting]
Okay, I lied.
I didn't fight 300 soldiers.
Mermista, will you ever forgive me?
Sea Hawk, we all knew that.
I don't know who to believe anymore.
I can't trust my own eyes.
-Who am I?
-[Adora] Look at what she's doing.
Look at what she's doing to you.
Shadow Weaver wants power,
and you are listening to her.
Oh, what? Are you jealous because you
aren't Shadow Weaver's favorite anymore?
Or are you just mad that I'm queen
and in charge and you're not?
That's ridiculous.
You just run around
playing the perfect hero.
You have no idea
how hard it's been for me.
Because you stopped
including me in your decisions.
We used to be a team. And now?
I don't know what we are.
Come on, backup communicator,
where are you?
Hey, Flutterina.
Looking for something?
Glimmer? Heh. Adora.
Hi, hi. Uh, just looking for the bathroom.
[chuckles]
Okay. Okay. This looks bad,
but it isn't what it looks like.
So let's all just...
[shouts]
Oh. [laughing]
I see.
Give it up, Flutterina.
If that's really who you are.
Magic. How very clever.
Isn't it? Shadow Weaver helped.
You see--
The reveal of how they caught
the murderer is my favorite part.
[groans]
[Adora] In order to catch a rat,
you need to spring a trap.
So we set one up of our own.
[Mermista] Classic murder mystery move.
[Perfuma] There's no murder-- Never mind.
[Glimmer]
We knew a backup communication device
would be irresistible
to whoever destroyed the original.
[Adora] We wanted the spy to feel
safe enough to make a move,
so we created a diversion.
[Glimmer] Adora managed to be
a really good actress, for once.
[Adora] It was really hard.
Do not ask me to do that again.
So that brings us back to you.
Who are you really, Flutterina?
[shouting]
[gasps]
Please...
call me Double Trouble.
You're a shape-shifter?
[gasps]
It wasn't my goggles glitching.
It was you,
pretending to be Frosta at Dryl.
And Perfuma.
Don't shortchange my credits, darling.
[all gasping]
May I say, as one actor to another,
that was truly a masterful performance.
I really bought that you two
were furious at each other.
If you would indulge me,
were you inspired
from any real emotion or experience?
Enough. It's over, Double Trouble.
Now tell us what the Horde is planning.
[Double Trouble] Over?
Oh, love, it's just beginning.
The Horde has been planning
a massive attack for some time now.
I let Catra know
that you were going to Dryl.
After that, all I had to do
was plant seeds of doubt.
Sowing chaos where I could.
[groans]
[both laughing]
Bow, seriously, you aren't the spy.
Hey. Mermista?
[Double Trouble] It wasn't hard.
I just had to keep you isolated
and at each other's throats
until the plan was underway.
Salineas.
If the Horde controls the seas,
they control Etheria.
That will never happen. We won't let it.
Now that we know their plan,
we can stop it.
No. Stop it?
Oh, this was a ruse, darling.
A distraction.
The Battle of Salineas is over.
It happened earlier this very evening.
It's too late.
Salineas is gone.
-No.
No, it's not too late. It can't be.
[sobs]
We can fix this.
We have to be able to fix this, right?
[Glimmer] This won't happen again.
I won't let it.
We won't give up.
We will take back Salineas.
Take back all of Etheria.
No matter what it costs.
No matter
what the Horde throws at us next.
[closing theme playing]