[Razz humming]
Broom!
Where are you?
Ah. There you are.
What are you just sitting around for?
Today is an important day!
We have to get ready for our guest.
Perfect.
Oh, Adora.
You're just in time.
Heh. Razz, I told you before.
My name isn't Adora.
It's Mara.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong
And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[Razz] Yes, yes, of course you're Mara.
Who else would you be?
Now, come on, silly.
We don't have much time.
Today is a very important day.
Why is today important, Razz?
Uh, because--
Because it's important-- [gasps]
Because today we are making a pie.
Don't you remember?
You promised!
That sounds great, Razz.
But I can't stay long today.
[Razz] Ah, nonsense, dearie.
Now, will you help Madame Razz
find her rolling pin?
It must be around here somewhere.
-It's a rolling--
-[Adora] Madame Razz?
Mara?
Oh, Razz! It's you! I finally found you.
Mm. If you say so, Mara.
Now, come on, it's getting so late.
I'm not Mara. Ugh! It doesn't matter.
Razz, you have to help me.
Everything's falling apart.
The Rebellion is losing worse than ever,
and Glimmer--
I need to find another way to help
the Rebellion. We can still win this.
There was something Mara said
in her message.
She talked about some kind of weapon?
[gasps]
You do know something.
If there's some kind of First Ones weapon
out there, you need to tell me.
We could use it to defeat the Horde,
and free Etheria,
and then Glimmer would finally see
that she was wrong about--
What was that for?
Ah, you need to stop being so forgetful,
Mara.
We're making pie today with Swift Wind.
Once again, I am Adora,
and Swift Wind isn't even--
-[Swift Wind] Hello!
-[shouts]
Swift Wind? What are you doing here?
Oh, I visit Razz all the time.
You gotta check up on old ladies
alone in the woods.
Come on, Adora, have a heart.
Okay. Maybe you can help.
I need Razz to tell me
about Mara's weapon.
Mara's weapon? Like, the sword?
She-Ra's sword?
Ooh, did I solve it?
Did I solve the mystery?
No! The weapon Mara talked about
in her last message on the ship.
Bow's with the ship trying to clean it up,
but it's still too glitchy to make out.
This...
-Razz.
-Those.
You knew Mara.
Did she ever tell you--?
What are you looking for?
Sugar for the pie!
I must have some around here somewhere.
Never mind, I know where we can get more.
Come, dearie.
Not a moment to waste, let's go!
Apparently, we're making pie.
-Oh, yes.
-[Adora] Wait!
Why are we following a wacky old lady
through the woods?
Because she knows something
about the weapon.
Razz is leading us somewhere important.
Somewhere where I can get answers.
I'm sure of it.
Adora, as your noble steed,
I'd be remiss if I didn't point out
that Razz is kind of...
Ha! Have to get up earlier than that
to trick me, Loo-Kee!
[grunting]
Well, you know, she's, uh-- She's Razz.
Do you really think she knows anything?
Madame Razz always shows up
exactly when I need her most.
She helped save you,
and she helped stop the portal.
She knows more than she lets on.
There is a method to this,
I just have to figure it out.
Is losing her part of the method?
Razz?
Adora, come! There's not much time.
You need to keep up. Where are you?
[Mara] Who are you?
How did you find this place?
Ah, Mara, dearie, there you are.
Madame Razz wondered where you went.
H--? How do you know my name?
Oh, is this the first time?
[gasps] It's been so long
since it was the first time.
[chuckles]
Never mind,
Razz is only here to borrow some sugar.
What--? Hey!
This location is highly classified,
you can't just--
[Razz]
How can you find anything in here, Adora?
-This place is a mess!
-Give it--
[grunting]
Magic.
You know how to use magic.
[laughs]
Hey, stop that!
Wow.
No-- Don't--
-Mine! It's mine! I--
-[grunting]
-Intruder detected.
-[both shout]
Razzle Dazzle!
Mara, who is this person?
I don't know.
She just wandered in.
Do you see the ghost, too?
[laughing]
Her presence is unauthorized.
You must remove her from the premises
or I will be forced
to alert your superiors.
Your ghost is mean. Ah.
-What are you looking for?
-[Razz] Sugar!
How can Madame Razz make a pie
without sugar? Ah.
Don't ask such silly questions, Adora.
Adora?
[Razz] I need to get up.
-Why do I put it so high?
-Razz, is it?
All right, here you go. Sugar.
Ah! Thank you, dearie.
You cannot let her take things and leave.
She could've been exposed
to classified data
about the Heart of Etheria Project.
We need to detain and interrogate her.
You really think
she's somehow found information
about a project so classified
even I don't know all the details?
Come on, Hope, look at her,
she's clearly harmless.
Besides, we're here
to study this planet's magic, aren't we?
Who'd know more about Etheria's magic
than the Etherians?
You know I have to report this.
It is in my programming.
Can't you let it slide? Please, Hope?
For me?
Unauthorized presence, not detected.
Any reports to the contrary are incorrect.
Thanks, Hope.
Couldn't ask for a better friend!
Friend.
[Mara] Okay, Razz, promise you'll stay
away from the ship from now on.
Sure thing, Adora.
See you tomorrow.
No, you can't come back tomorrow.
And why do you keep calling me Adora?
Who's Adora?
Razz, wait!
There you are.
Oh, it's a First Ones' ruin.
I told you Razz was taking me somewhere.
These marks were made with a sword.
Mara's sword.
She was here.
She did this.
[Swift Wind] Wow. Mara did this?
She really was crazy.
[Razz] Aha!
You found it.
Found what? What does it mean?
Sugar!
Now we just need the berries.
[Razz humming]
Razz, this was left deliberately.
Did it belong to Mara?
Oh, yes, dearie. She left it for you.
-She wants to talk to you.
-What?
Come on, slowpoke.
Help an old lady pick some berries.
Razz, Mara's gone.
She's been gone for a thousand years.
Hmm? No, that doesn't sound right.
She's helping me make a pie today.
She promised, you know.
No, I'm helping you make a pie.
Yes, that's what I said.
[sighs]
Razz, why is today
the day we have to make pie?
Because today is important.
But why is it important?
Uh...
It's important because, uh-- Because--
Oh, because I have to duck! [shouts]
[roaring]
Watch out!
For the honor of Grayskull!
[grunting and shouting]
Razz, run!
Mara, no!
[shouts]
Stop!
It's all right.
No one here will hurt you.
[roars]
[stammering]
Go now.
Be at peace.
Razz?
I'm sorry,
I thought it was gonna hurt you. I--
That's all right, dearie. Come here.
Wha--? What are you do--?
[gasps]
How am I doing this?
How is it possible without the sword?
[laughs]
She-Ra is not a sword.
She-Ra is you.
Etheria chose you.
But my people chose me to be She-Ra.
I need the sword
to control She-Ra's magic.
That's what my superiors always told me.
[Razz laughs]
She-Ra was here
long before your people arrived.
You cannot control magic.
Magic simply is.
I love Etheria.
I love how old, and weird,
and beautiful it is.
I'm sworn to protect it as She-Ra
just as I'm sworn to serve my people.
But I know we're doing something
to the planet.
The Heart of Etheria Project,
I don't know all the details,
but I know it's big.
They say we're the heroes,
but I don't know if it's right.
She-Ra protects Etheria.
Your people made the sword,
but they did not make She-Ra.
[Adora] What people?
Are you talking about the First Ones?
The Sword...
Mara...
She said she would come back.
She promised.
We were going to make the pie.
I've been waiting for so long.
Mara? She was here, too, wasn't she?
Everything we're doing,
the berries, the sugar, making the pie,
it helps you remember.
[Razz] Oh, Mara.
You were never supposed to succeed.
They made a plan for you.
Razz could not do anything to help.
I am sorry.
Then help me.
Adora, not Mara.
Adora?
Yes. Mara wanted me to warn Adora.
There is a great evil
at the Heart of Etheria, Adora,
and it is waking up again.
You need to talk to Mara.
[gasps] It's getting late.
We have to hurry.
We have to put the pie in.
What?
Not much time, not much time...
Okay. Razz.
What was it that you were just saying
about the evil at the Heart of Etheria?
Huh?
-Doesn't ring a bell.
-What's at the Heart of Etheria?
Light Hope said Mara snapped,
but there's gotta be more to it than that.
There was a reason why she broke
everything, why she put us in Despondos.
She was afraid of something.
Was-- Was she afraid of the sword somehow?
Of being She-Ra?
No, no time, there's no time.
Please, Razz.
You have to remember something.
Remember, remember.
I try to remember,
but it gets all muddled up.
Adora, Mara...
It always ends the same.
The present, the future...
[Mara] Razz?
The past.
Mara, dearie, you're just in time,
the pie is almost...
I can't stay long, Razz.
Nonsense, we're making pie today.
Or have you forgotten?
Ah-ah-ah.
And they say my memory is bad.
[laughs]
Razz, listen.
I figured out what my people are doing
with the Heart of Etheria.
What they've done to the planet.
It's going to activate soon,
there's no time.
I have to get to my ship.
[grunts]
It's starting.
But the pie?
Tomorrow, Razz,
we'll make a pie tomorrow, I promise.
[Mara grunting]
I can't stop it.
But I can keep them
from hurting anyone else.
Mara!
[grunting]
[screaming]
[bell dings]
It's time.
[snoring]
Razz?
-Razz!
-What?
-Come on, Swifty.
-Where are we going?
The pie's done.
[Mara grunting]
[gasps]
You're not Mara!
[shouting] Ow.
Madame Razz?
Adora, help me find Mara,
you know where she is.
Adora, who's that lady?
It's okay, it's just Razz.
-Madame Razz?
-[Razz] Adora!
You need to talk to Mara.
You have everything you need.
I have everything I--
What are you doing?
[gasps]
Wait, I know this.
She-Ra!
[grunting]
[Light Hope] What are you doing, Mara?
You have de-- De--
Destroyed my intraplanetary systems.
You are behave-- Be--
Behaving erratically.
Where is the sword, Mara?
The sword is gone.
There's not going to be a She-Ra anymore.
It is your destiny to be She-Ra.
She-Ra's destiny
was to be a part of your machine.
But I won't ever let you use her again.
The Heart of Etheria has been activated.
Your mission will be fulfilled.
There will be peace throughout the galaxy.
You will be a hero.
How will destroying worlds bring peace?
You're trying to di-- Disable me.
It will not work.
The Heart of Etheria
will achieve its function, as will you.
You are She-Ra.
This is your destiny.
You're not Light Hope.
I am the same basic operating system.
You're not her.
And you don't get to tell me
what my destiny is.
[powering down]
Activating portal into the Dimension
of Despondos in three, two, one.
[Mara] Adora...
I know you're there.
Razz said you would be there.
Mara?
[Mara grunting]
I don't have much time.
I barely made it out.
If you are seeing this,
it means you are the new She-Ra.
It means I failed.
I don't know what they told you,
it wasn't all bad at first.
We were the first ones to settle Etheria,
to really study this planet's magic.
How could it go so wrong?
You can't trust Light Hope.
She's been reprogrammed
to set off the weapon at any cost.
-The weapon...
-The weapon. What is it?
Didn't know what they were doing
until too late.
I knew they were rerouting Etheria's magic
for their own purposes.
Siphoning it,
collecting it in the planet's core.
The Heart of Etheria.
The Heart of Etheria Project.
It was supposed to be an energy source,
capable of so much good.
But that's not what they made.
My people turned our planet,
all of Etheria, into a weapon.
And She-Ra is the key.
What?
I opened a portal to a completely empty
dimension and pulled Etheria in.
I hid us from the rest of the universe
to keep everyone safe.
This is the one place
they'll never find us.
The weapon can't hurt anyone else here.
I saw what they would do.
The deaths that would follow.
I couldn't stop them before,
but I can now.
Hiding is our only option.
Adora, this isn't over.
The Heart of Etheria
is still siphoning magic, storing it.
It's unstable. It will tear Etheria apart
if it goes off again.
So, it's up to you now.
I couldn't stop it.
In the end, I wasn't strong enough.
But you, Adora, you will be more powerful
than they ever planned.
[grunting]
Adora, I believe in you.
You can save the world we love.
The weapon...
The weapon is Etheria.
And Mara...
sacrificed herself to save everyone.
[laughs]
She was brave, my Mara.
For you, Mara, dearie.
[closing theme playing]