Are you sure we're going the right way?
Like, 100 percent sure?
[sighs] For the last time, I don't know.
We have to trust
that the navigation system
knows what it's doing.
Now stop asking.
[Bow] We've gotta be close.
Any minute now.
Beast Island is around here.
Somewhere.
We will find it.
We have to.
Do you think Glimmer will still be upset
when we get back?
We did sort of, kind of,
completely disobey direct orders.
She'll understand.
We all want what's best for Etheria.
And once we get Entrapta back,
Glimmer will know
we made the right decision.
Right, but-- I mean, what if she doesn't?
-What if she never talks to me again?
-[alarm beeping]
Uh, Bow, the thing that's blinking,
should it be blinking?
I don't know, a ship?
Uh, guys, I'm sensing something out there.
Something big, and it's not good.
And I think I hear--
[all shouting]
[alarm wailing]
-Don't panic. No one panic.
-[groaning]
[grunts]
Uh, nope. Never mind. Panic!
[all shouting]
Ehh.
Look.
It's Beast Island.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you
Ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
As kids, we were warned of the dangers
on Beast Island.
There were the chibbits
with razor-sharp teeth,
scruffers with razor-sharp horns,
-razorfins with--
-Razor-sharp fins?
Razor-sharp teeth, actually.
-I don't know why it had that name.
-[Swift Wind] Adora.
[sniffing]
[shouts] Okay. That's normal.
[gasps] Entrapta. She must've been on it.
-Where do you think she went?
-[droning noise]
What is that noise?
What noise?
[grunts]
It's gone. [grunts]
You didn't hear it?
Uh, any scary Horde bedtime stories
about noises only horses can hear?
Not that I can remember.
I heard the same sound earlier,
right before Mara's ship crashed.
[Bow] First Ones' tech.
This is all First Ones' tech.
But it's corrupted, melted down.
This must've been some kind
of First Ones' dumping ground.
[Bow groans]
[beeps]
[groans]
We should get moving
while we still have light.
Entrapta's here somewhere.
[creature roaring in distance]
♪ On this awful nightmare island ♪
[groans]
♪ Which we went to on purpose ♪
♪ So, everything's great ♪
♪ Hey, let's take a fun stroll
Through nightmare island ♪
♪ Just kidding ♪
-♪ It's definitely not weird and scary ♪
-[chittering]
♪ I wanna go home ♪
[chittering stops]
Maybe everything went quiet...
for a good reason?
[both panting]
[creature growling]
Nope. A bad reason.
Okay, no one move.
Maybe it won't see us.
[all shouting]
For the honor of Grayskull!
-[gasps]
-Uh... Adora? [shouts]
Run!
[Swift Wind grunting]
-What happened? Why can't you be She-Ra?
-[groaning]
[Adora] I don't know.
-There it is again, that sound.
-[droning noise]
Really? No one else hears that?
[gasps]
[grunts]
[all shouting]
No!
Come on, come on.
For the honor of Grayskull!
[shouting and grunting]
-Adora!
-[gasps]
[grunts]
[grunting and shouting]
Whoa.
Who is that guy?
Thank you. You saved us.
Who--?
[gasps]
[Bow] King Micah.
Light Hope?
[clearing throat] The queen of Bright Moon
demands to speak to Light Hope.
Now.
On behalf of the Great Rebellion,
I need you to answer my questions.
Eternia?
Okay, I know you can hear me.
So, that's how it is.
Fine. I'll just have to make you listen.
[grunts]
[Light Hope]
Unauthorized presence detected.
Security protocol activated.
[spiders screeching]
You're not getting rid of me that easily.
[grunts]
Your Majesty.
Huh?
You know who I am? [chuckles]
Please don't kneel. I'm no king here.
Of course we know.
Oh, uh, I'm Adora,
and this is Swift Wind and Bow.
King Micah, it's so great to--
[grunting]
Meet you.
Huh.
Apologies.
It's been quite some time
since I've talked to anyone else.
Anyone real, that is.
And you are real, right?
Very real. Heh. Yeah.
Hi. Uh...
Are you real?
I mean, we kind of thought you were dead.
If the Horde had their way, I would be.
They exiled me here, but I survived.
King Micah, we're from Bright Moon.
We know your daughter, Glimmer.
-My sweet Glimmer? Huh?
-[creatures roaring]
[shouts] There's no time for pleasantries.
We have to move. Quick, follow me!
[groaning]
[Bow] Wow.
We should be able to rest here
for a moment.
A safe, quiet mome--
[all shouting]
Gotcha!
Oh-- I'm so sorry. Where are my manners?
Bug?
-Uh, mm. No.
-[whines]
So, what brings you to Beast Island?
We came here looking for our friend,
Princess Entrapta?
Any chance you've seen her? She's got
purple hair and really likes robots.
Like, really, really likes robots.
Yeah, I know her.
She stole my rations.
Only the tiny ones for some reason.
That's great.
I mean, not the food part,
but the other part.
She's okay, or she was not long ago.
-Did you see which way she went?
-Why, yes.
Is that horse talking?
I can hear you.
I'm Swift Wind, and I ev--
It has wings!
Well, this is definitely Glimmer's dad.
[laughing]
[grunting]
Your Majesty, could you let me go?
Oh, right. [chuckles] Sorry.
Like I said, it's been a little while
since I've talked to people, or horses.
Because horses talk now,
and that's normal.
You were saying something about Entrapta.
Do you know where she is?
Yes. Your friend headed straight
for the center of the island
before I could stop her.
Sounds like Entrapta.
-Could you point us in the direction--?
-You can't go there.
You'd never come back.
It's where the signal is the strongest.
The signal.
That must be the noise I've been hearing.
-What is it?
-You've heard it?
Then we have to hurry.
This place is a mass of ancient tech,
mostly degraded,
but some of it still works.
And something at the center of that island
never stopped signaling.
The signal dulls your resolve,
exposes your vulnerabilities,
it pulls you in.
Everything that stays on Beast Island
becomes a part of it eventually.
Why can't Adora and I hear it?
Stay here long enough, and you will.
I've heard it every day,
for months, years.
I have no sense of time here.
But I fight it.
Nothing will stop me
from getting off this island
and reuniting with my family.
But enough about me. Tell me news
of the Rebellion and Bright Moon.
And my baby girl. You know her?
Glimmer? Sure.
She's...
-Well, she's--
-She's our best friend.
We're the Best Friend Squad.
Sounds like my baby girl. Heh.
Always in a hurry to grow up
and be friends with the older kids.
What about Angella? Have you seen her?
-Your Majesty, I--
-[creature screeching]
-What is that?
-We should keep moving.
I'll help you find your friend, and then,
can you help me escape this place?
Of course.
We'll all get out of here together.
Then why are we waiting? Follow me!
[gasps, then screams]
[panting]
[groans]
[chuckles]
So, you're telling me that horses
are now allowed in the War Room,
-and they all get chairs?
-Big important chairs, yep.
And also, unlimited sugar cubes.
Ehh. Sounds good to me.
[grunts]
I can't believe Glimmer's dad
has been alive this whole time.
And he's so cool.
[retching]
Little weird,
but I guess that's to be expected
after all this time alone.
Glimmer will be so happy
to see her dad again.
She'll have to forgive us
for going against her orders,
escaping Bright Moon
and taking Mara's ship.
Not that we technically did
anything wrong,
or need to be forgiven.
I mean, Glimmer kept us in the dark.
The truth is
she hasn't been a good friend.
But have we been?
Can you even have a fight
with a best friend
and still be best friends?
And don't get me started on Shadow Weaver.
Are you okay?
[sighs] Yeah. It's just--
Why can't I be She-Ra here?
What if something on this island
infected the sword,
or what if Glimmer is right
and all I do is ruin everything? I...
I just feel useless.
Hey, you aren't useless.
We'll figure this out.
You're still a hero,
I'm still a tech master,
-Swift Wind's still--
-[neighing] Woo-hoo!
[shouts] That's not food!
[grunting]
[chuckling]
He's still a horse.
But now we've got Cool Sorcerer Dad
helping us.
You're right.
[grunts]
Are you gonna send more spiders
for me to destroy,
or are you gonna talk to me?
The First Ones stole the magic of Etheria,
the magic of my people.
Please, talk to me!
That magic is how I stop this war.
It's how I save everyone.
That magic,
the magic at the Heart of Etheria...
I want to use it.
[Light Hope] Temporary
administrator access granted
to Queen Glimmer of Bright Moon.
Queen Glimmer, proceed.
[droning noise]
The signal, it's getting stronger.
We're getting closer.
Don't let it distract you.
Tell me, what is she like, my Glimmer?
Stubborn.
Real stubborn.
-[scoffs] Bow.
-What?
She's also brave.
She's one of the bravest people I know.
I just-- I wanna be the hero she deserves,
and I don't know if I have been.
Great, great.
Oh, and does she still have
her favorite stuffed animal?
-The one I made for her, Kowl?
-Oh, yeah.
She's even started to use
your sorcerer staff.
Isn't that kind of dangerous
for a little kid?
Pfft.
Try telling her that.
Not like she listens to anyone these days,
that is, except for Sha--
[chittering]
What is that?
It's the pookas.
[gasps]
Pookas?
That sounds adorable.
Let me guess,
more razor-sharp scary things?
Pookas travel in packs,
hunting their prey across the island,
luring them in and surrounding them
until it's too late.
And right now, they're hunting us.
[groans]
Run!
We never should've come here
without Glimmer!
She could've teleported us
out in a second.
Why couldn't she just trust us?
Why couldn't she trust me?
Glimmer's in the field?
She's fighting? She's too young.
Angella shouldn't have let her--
[grunts] Tell me the truth.
Glimmer's not a little girl anymore,
is she?
How long have I been gone?
[chittering stops]
No, no, no,
silence is always for a bad reason.
Where did they go?
It's kind of cute.
-[roaring]
-[shouting]
But mainly scary!
I told you!
Swift Wind!
[grunting]
Swift Wind! Wait!
-[droning noise amplifies]
-[grunting]
I--
Hang on.
[Swift Wind] The signal.
You hear it, too, now, don't you?
It's so loud.
I can't think straight.
No!
Swift Wind, we have to keep going.
They're right behind us.
We can't stay. The signal's too strong.
The pookas lured us right into a trap.
We have to move!
[groaning]
-Bow!
-Bow.
No, not you, too.
You have to fight it.
[Bow] It's too late, isn't it?
We couldn't fix it.
No. We can still get out of here.
Micah, help him.
[grunting]
King Micah!
Don't give in now,
not after all this time.
We'll get you back to Bright Moon.
Glimmer needs you to come home
and help her be queen and--
[Micah] Queen?
If she's queen, then that means...
[grunting]
[Adora] No. No!
King Micah.
Bow.
Swifty.
Please. I can't do this alone.
I can't-- I can't...
I can't do this.
Glimmer was right.
Take care of each other.
[inaudible dialogue]
Glimmer?
[gasps]
[shouting]
I won't give up!
Not on my friends, not on Etheria,
not on myself!
For the honor of Grayskull!
[shouting]
[grunting]
[groaning]
Huh?
You did it.
You're She-Ra again!
[Micah] She-Ra.
It wasn't the signal that was blocking me
from being She-Ra.
It was me.
I was afraid of what Glimmer said,
that all I've ever done
was make things worse.
But I promised I'd take care of her,
-[neighs]
-[gasps]
take care of everyone, and I will.
So, you're the legendary warrior She-Ra,
and my daughter is queen?
There's a lot we need to catch you up on,
Your Majesty.
But first, let's go save our friends.
[pookas chittering]
[growling]
[grunts]
Woo-hoo!
Yeah!
We did it!
Take that, you terrifying
yet adorably named creatures!
[whines]
Get behind me.
[all gasping]
Princesses! I saved you!
[Glimmer] Light Hope?
Is that you?
The Crystal Castle is intended only
for She-Ra and her steed.
You are trespassing.
[gasps]
Well, She-Ra's not here right now.
She took Bow and ran off
on a stupid mission
and left me.
Left us all behind.
She's too afraid
to use the magic at the Heart of Etheria,
but I'm not.
Perhaps entrusting She-Ra
with this mission was a mistake.
Adora is compromised.
She is not willing to do what is necessary
to protect Etheria,
but you are.
Yes.
Adora has made much progress,
but she still has not succeeded
in balancing Etheria.
If the planet is not balanced,
the Heart of Etheria cannot be accessed.
Balance the planet?
What does that mean? And how do I do that?
There is only one piece still missing.
The princesses are conduits
for the Heart's power.
They must all be connected
to their Runestones
for the Heart of Etheria to function.
And that will make us stronger?
It will give you power
like you've never known.
The final piece is a princess
who has not yet accepted her destiny.
A princess robbed of her power
by the Horde's meddling.