♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[crying]
[Adora] Catra!
[shouts] Catra, come out.
I know you didn't mean to hit Lonnie.
It's okay, I'll tell them.
They won't be mad.
But first, you gotta come out
and tell her you're sorry.
We were all just having fun.
You didn't have to do it.
Why'd you do it?
[Adora screams]
[hisses]
Are you guys following me?
I am here to attend to your needs,
little sister.
It is Prime's command.
Can't go two steps
without one of you breathing down my neck.
If I'm a prisoner,
he might as well make it official.
You are our honored guest.
We are here
to make your stay more comfortable.
Right.
[shouts]
This part of the ship
is off-limits to you, Catra.
You called me Catra.
None of the other clones do that.
You remember me, don't you?
Here's a clue, you don't like me.
Hordak.
It is wrong to have a name.
Prime's chosen servants
are but parts of the whole.
Look, it's okay. The name thing
can be our secret. It's just--
It's good to see a familiar face.
This part of the ship
is off-limits to you, little sister.
Yeah, yeah, got it.
[Adora grunting]
We're getting closer to the signal
Entrapta triangulated.
We should reach Glimmer in the next--
Nope!
[groaning]
What are you doing?
You can't take apart the ship
while we're inside the ship.
Did you forget about the, I don't know,
crushing void of space?
I love thinking
about the crushing void of space!
But there's always improvements
to be made.
-I could boost this baby's speed.
-[drill whirring]
No! We have to keep the ship intact
until we can reach Glimmer.
-[thud]
-[gasps]
Sorry.
[Bow] You, stand there.
You, stay there.
And until we reach Glimmer,
nobody is going to touch anything.
[rumbling]
[computer] Diagnostics have revealed
a prob-- Problem.
My user interface will now shut down
to conserve energy.
-Goodbye.
-No.
No, no, no!
I didn't do it.
[grunting]
[Catra] Hey there, princess.
How's the escape attempt going?
[scoffs] You again.
Why do you keep coming back here?
Just bored, I guess.
No, I mean,
Horde Prime told you not to talk to me.
He's gonna catch you eventually.
Why risk it?
You're lonely, aren't you?
What do you know?
You're the prisoner here.
I can go where I want.
So, stay here by yourself for all I care.
Okay, okay.
You're right.
It helps having someone to talk to.
Even if you're the last person
I'd ever wanna be stuck here with.
[chuckles] Trust me, Sparkles,
the feeling is mutual.
So, what would you be doing
if you were back on Etheria right now
and not, you know,
a prisoner on an alien ship?
I guess maybe...
Maybe I'd go teleporting
all around Etheria,
visiting the other princesses
in their kingdoms.
If it were a really perfect day,
Bow, Adora and I
would be having a sleepover. [chuckles]
We'd raid Bright Moon's kitchen for cake
and then we'd eat it
with our hands right off the platter.
We used to have those.
-What?
-Sleepovers.
Me and Adora,
when we were cadets in the Horde.
We'd play tricks on Kyle,
stay up all night whispering about...
You know, whatever.
Did Adora still thrash around all night
and, like, sleep-fight?
What was that about?
She always did that.
Adora can't even relax when she's asleep.
I miss them.
I was so awful to them
the last time we saw each other.
I'd do anything to go back
and make it right.
What about you?
What would you be doing
if you were back on Etheria?
I'd--
Uh, nothing.
There's nothing for me on Etheria.
It's okay! I'll fix Darla.
-Darla?
-I named the ship Darla.
It just felt right.
Uh... Okay, you can fix Darla.
-But we have to be careful.
-[Entrapta] Great!
-Entrapta!
-[laughing]
I promise not to move or touch
or break anything.
Okay, I'll be right back.
-Huh? Uh-oh.
-[steam hissing]
Bow?
There's a thing...
Oh!
Ha, ha!
I got this.
Now, where are you two going
in such a hurry?
Contacting Planet 1659 ground base.
Please prepare to receive our brother
into your flock.
[grunts]
[voices murmuring]
There you are, little sister.
I seek your company.
Sister, thank you for joining us.
I have been scouring,
searching for She-Ra,
but what I seek is not yet to be found.
My drones recorded a ship
leaving the planet.
A ship of such ancient design
that it is not detectable
by my instruments.
How can this be?
I don't know.
Hmm...
I don't.
Me and Adora, we're not friends.
I don't know anything about her plans.
And yet you seek to protect her.
You have been speaking to our guest,
Queen Glimmer,
against my command.
Have you not, sister?
You have pity for her.
You will speak to her,
and learn what you can.
She must have some knowledge
of this mysterious ship.
That won't work.
She doesn't trust me.
She's not gonna give me anything.
Believe me, if I could tell you
where Adora is I would.
She's my enemy.
I want her gone.
Oh, look at you, poor sister.
Your Adora causes you nothing
but suffering.
Don't you want to be free of it?
[gasps]
There is another way.
Let me show you.
Step forward.
You spoke with our little sister
this morning, did you not, brother?
What was it she said to you?
She gave me a name.
Forgive me, brother.
Please take this affliction from me.
Hmm.
Those who seek freedom will be granted it.
[clones] Cast out the shadows.
Cast out the shadows.
[shouting]
I am sorry that you must suffer.
All beings must suffer to become pure.
Behold the purest among you.
One to be honored.
[clones] Yes!
Yes!
Do what I ask of you.
[gasps] Yes.
-Give us some privacy?
-Of course, sister.
Prime sees all.
-What's with the babysitter?
-Here.
It's the dumb food you wanted.
You know,
from your perfect day or whatever.
I remember. I just--
Thanks.
Don't go thinking
I actually care about you.
I'm supposed to talk to you.
So, eat the stupid cake
and then answer my questions.
-What's going on?
-Don't say anything, just look at me.
An old First Ones ship
left Etheria's atmosphere a few days ago.
Prime cannot track it.
What do you know about it?
[gasps]
Adora's on that ship, isn't she?
You can't tell him. You know
what he'll do to her if he catches her.
Adora's on her way here.
She's coming for you.
I don't have to do anything.
I just have to let it happen.
And you think Prime will reward you?
As soon as you're no longer useful to him,
he'll get rid of you in a second.
I always find a way out.
So, you'll just run away?
To what?
If Prime captures Adora,
he can use the Heart of Etheria
to wipe out the whole universe.
Is that what you want?
Please, Catra.
Do one good thing in your life.
[shouts]
Don't talk to me like you know me.
You don't know anything about me! Hey!
Let me out!
[crying]
[door beeps]
Adora, have you seen Entrapta--? [shouts]
What are you doing?
I have everything under control.
That's not what I asked.
I told you not to touch anything.
It's bad enough
that Entrapta has disappeared somewhere.
Oh, yeah.
She was just in here.
She said she was looking for...
Uh...
a blowtorch
and a really long piece of rope.
Why didn't you stop her?
I kind of had my hands full here.
Adora, we are so far out of our depth
right now.
We're about to fly
into the heart of an evil alien empire,
and all we've got between us
and certain death
is this falling-apart old ship.
But now the ship's broken,
and we haven't got Glimmer,
and who knows where Entrapta... is.
Hi.
[shouts] What are you doing out there?
I made space suits for us
and then I fixed the ship from space!
Where I am!
[Adora]
Oh, so that's what the rope was for.
Is this a good laugh or a bad laugh?
Well, the longer it goes on
the more I think it's a bad laugh.
Entrapta, get inside.
Adora, put down the tape.
We're just going to get back on mission,
and nothing is going to derail us again!
[ship powering down]
I got it.
[shouts]
It is as our sister said.
We have done a sweep of all quadrants
in our vicinity,
and we have located the Etherian ship.
It is almost here.
You have done well, little sister.
Soon, She-Ra will be mine.
And with her, Etheria.
All because of you.
You made the right choice.
You will be exalted, raised up
above the other wretched creatures
of your home world.
Is that not what you wanted?
Yes, Lord Prime.
Go now in peace.
[Catra sobbing]
[Adora] Catra?
It's dinnertime, and you're missing it.
It's the gray kind tonight.
I know it's your favorite.
What are you doing?
Well, if you're missing dinner,
then I am, too.
Just go!
Eat with your new best friend, Lonnie!
Is that why you hit her?
I know you like her better than me.
You're supposed to be my friend.
I am your friend, Catra.
I'm always gonna be your friend.
You should say sorry to Lonnie.
And then we can all be friends.
[grunting]
No.
Come on, Catra.
[Catra]
I'll never say sorry to anybody, ever.
[kids giggling]
I'm always gonna be your friend.
[shouting]
It's nothing personal, Hordak.
I'm coming in.
What are you doing?
I wanna do that one good thing in my life.
Like you said.
So, come with me.
Where are we going?
What's the plan?
How do I know I can trust you?
You don't.
[gasps]
Little sister,
why is our guest out of her quarters?
She wanted to get some fresh air.
Didn't you, princess?
Hit the back of the neck.
That should take them down.
-[chuckles] Not bad, Sparkles.
-[alarm wailing]
Let's go.
-What are you doing?
-What does it look like?
Getting you out of here.
Good. That should hold them.
Wait, are you--? Are you saving me?
Not you. Adora.
Even if I sent her a message to stay away,
she'd still come for you.
That's just how she is.
[banging on door]
[clones grunting]
What about you?
Me? All I do is hurt people.
There's no one left in the entire universe
who cares about me.
Is it working now?
Are you there, Darla?
-[computer] Yes. Welcome back, Entrapta.
-[shouts] I missed you.
There is a transmission being received.
-Would you like to open communication?
-Patch it through.
[Catra] Adora?
Catra?
Don't sound so happy to hear me.
I'm sending Glimmer to you.
I don't know your location,
but I can get her to your quadrant.
-You have to be there to catch her.
-Wait, wait, wait, what?
What's going on? Glimmer is with you?
We don't have time.
You need to get to these coordinates now.
Don't come here, no matter what.
Horde Prime is ready for you.
Catra, I don't understand, what is--?
Just listen!
Adora...
I'm sorry.
For everything.
Catra!
-[radio static]
-No. No, no, no!
Catra! Come back!
[computer]
The communication channel is closed.
Entrapta, do whatever it takes
to get us to those coordinates.
[Entrapta] We are arriving
at the coordinates.
Copy that. We're ready.
There!
Glimmer!
[shouting]
-Glimmer.
Bow?
Adora?
-What happened back there?
-I think--
I think Catra saved me.
I think she saved us all.
The Etherian ship has changed course...
but your treachery will not save them.
There is no darkness
that my light cannot pierce,
no distance that my hand cannot reach.
[clones] Prime casts out all shadows.
Prime casts out all shadows.
They will not be able
to hide from me forever!
You were beloved in my sight
and this is how you repay me.
What did you expect?
After all,
us Etherians are so very emotional.
It doesn't matter what you do to me.
Glimmer is gone
and you will never
get your hands on Adora.
Oh, my child, you're wrong.
Everyone has a place in my empire.
You will be of use to me yet.
[closing theme playing]