[spaceship whooshes]
[rumbling]
[computer] Alert. We are being pulled in
by an outside force.
[hatch whooshes open]
[grunts]
You won't find anything. I came alone.
I hear Horde Prime's been looking for me.
Figured it was time we met.
Yes, you will be brought before Prime.
And there you will receive your judgment.
[grunts]
-Aah!
-Ooh!
Spacesuit testing officially a success.
All suits stood up to ship's velocity
with zero loss of life.
Wait, what?
-That was a possibility?
-We're in.
[Bow] They didn't find us.
Good. Be quick and don't get caught.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you, ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have and never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[breathing softly]
Okay, everyone, sound off.
I'm heading to Horde Prime's
holding cell to get Catra.
And Entrapta and I are gonna gonna hack
into the ship's server
and download any intel
about Prime's weak points.
Look for a room
with a lot of glowing tech in it.
I remember them taking me past it
when they took me to--
That has to be the server.
Then that's our access point.
Although, as long we're here,
you wouldn't mind if I just
took a few readings--?
Okay, to the server room.
Okay, uh-- Everyone just be careful.
[humming]
You will go alone.
[Bow] You've got this, Adora.
Keep him talking.
[Glimmer scoffs] Knowing him,
that is not going to be a problem.
[gasps]
Prime.
Welcome, Adora.
[♪♪♪]
[sighs anxiously]
-[Bow] Hey.
-[gasps]
You okay?
[sighs]
What, you worried about me?
Maybe. Just be careful, okay?
Yeah. You, too.
Still no sign of the server room.
This place is so big and empty.
Where are the vents?
How does anyone get around in this place?
Call you right back, gotta go.
[grunts]
-[gasps]
-Mm!
[muffled grunt]
That must be the server room.
Unh!
[gasps]
[whimpers]
[Entrapta whimpers loudly]
Uh... Hello. Would you believe
that we're the inspectors?
-[snarls]
-[both scream]
Forgive my unseemly state.
It is a tedious task, but a necessary one
to maintain this vessel.
This is how it's going to go.
We're gonna make a deal.
You're gonna give me Catra,
and then you're gonna let me leave again,
free and clear.
I have something you want,
a weapon that only She-Ra can activate.
The Heart of Etheria.
And if you don't do as I say,
then I'll use it
and destroy you and your empire for good.
[squirts]
[dripping]
[laughs]
-[laughs]
-[Adora clears throat]
Is something funny?
You are not going to use the weapon
or you would have already done so.
You would never risk the safety
of your Catra.
You don't know me.
And you don't know what I'm capable of.
Oh, but I do.
[steam hisses]
I am old, far older than you can imagine.
My brothers lend me their life force,
and when one vessel fails me,
I simply elect another.
Thus, Prime has reigned eternal
through the centuries.
There is something so familiar
about you, Adora.
[gasps]
[Prime] A face I have not seen
in a thousand years.
Not since I faced your ancestors
and crushed their once-mighty empire
beneath my heel.
You call them the First Ones.
And you are one of them,
are you not, Adora?
Whoa!
Aah!
[whimpers]
Oh, come on, baby, come on.
Hordak?
[yells]
Entrapta, no!
What are you doing?
[Entrapta] Hordak?
That's you, isn't it?
I brought it for you.
I thought you might need it.
Do you recognize it?
Do you recognize me?
-[grunts]
-[whimpers]
-[snarls]
-[screams]
You are trespassing.
Prime shall hear of this,
and his punishment shall be merciless,
for Prime sees all...
[crackling electricity]
-No, no.
-[whimpers]
Stay in there!
Whoa...!
Well, that's definitely not Hordak.
So, we can cross that one off our list.
I wasn't aware we had a list.
[gasps] Where am I?
I cannot connect to the hive-mind.
I am alone?
I am alone.
[sobbing]
[Entrapta] Uh-oh!
We broke him.
Horde Prime.
How will he see my thoughts?
How will he know that I am faithful?
[sobbing]
It's all right.
We'll, uh... We'll tell him.
Okay, buddy?
You will tell him?
Uh... Sure.
You know Horde Prime?
[grunts]
Aah!
Please, let me accompany you
and prove myself worthy to Horde Prime.
No, that's-- That's really okay.
Can you open this door?
[humming]
-[squeals]
-We're not keeping him.
But we broke him.
We're responsible for him now.
Plus, he can open doors.
Can you take us to the server room?
I would be honored to serve one
who is a beloved of Horde Prime.
[sighs]
All right, then, Wrong Hordak.
Lead the way.
[groans]
Or point and I'll just keep dragging you.
That's fine, too.
[gasps]
Guys, I found the cell,
but Catra's not here.
What do we do?
[static]
Bow? Entrapta?
Adora?
[Prime] I thought the First Ones were all
gone, but clearly some faction remains.
That race of tyrants abandoned you
on a forgotten planet
in a shadow dimension.
They made you their weapon, their She-Ra.
I don't fight for the First Ones.
I fight for my home,
for myself and for my friends.
Now, for the last time, where is Catra?
[Catra] Adora?
Catra? Where are you?
Of course, your Catra.
She hoped you would come for her,
poor thing.
So, all I had to do was wait.
As she would have said,
"You are so very predictable."
Come here, child.
[footsteps]
Hello, Adora.
Come on, Wrong Hordak.
Any clue where the server room is yet?
Forgive me, brother.
The ship is designed
so that it may only be navigated
by one who has access to the hive-mind.
And I have been cut off.
There's something in here,
a big energy signal.
This has to be it.
-[humming]
-[gasps]
Adora, we found it.
[static]
Adora?
What did you do to her?
I have made her anew.
I saw her mind,
so ensnared in rage, and grief, and pain,
and I brought her to the light.
Isn't that right, little sister?
Catra, you have to fight it.
My place is with Horde Prime, Adora.
I don't want to leave.
Tell her what I've done for you.
Prime has given me peace.
Something you could never do.
You broke my heart.
But he has made it whole again.
Don't you see? This is for the best.
I'm happy here.
You could be happy, too.
Let her go.
[gasps]
Shall we make a deal, Adora?
I will give her to you, if you want her.
But first, you must do something for me.
You will give me She-Ra.
Never.
Very well.
-[clicks fingers]
-[high pitched-hum]
[all cry out]
[gasps]
[Prime] You miscalculated.
I see all.
I know all.
You thought yourself worthy
to challenge me,
but you are nothing but a false hero,
the last of the First Ones
to fall at my hands.
-You have led your friends to destruction.
-[gasps]
[gasps]
Go on, fulfill your purpose.
Bring out She-Ra and strike me down.
Ah... But you two
must have a lot of catching up to do.
I will leave you to it.
Let me know
when you're ready to make a deal.
[panting]
[grunts]
Hey. Remember me?
Haa!
[grunts]
Catra, listen to me.
I know you're still in there.
I'm not leaving without you.
[laughs]
It's gonna be okay.
[bones cracking]
[groans then screams]
Everything is already okay.
We are with Prime now.
There is no need for you to suffer, Adora.
Come into the light with me.
[yells]
Unh!
[laughs]
Snap out of it, Catra.
I don't wanna hurt you.
[laughs]
But you have already hurt me.
Prime has set me free of that pain.
The pain that you caused.
He will set us all free, forever.
A world of peace without end.
[♪♪♪]
Catra!
[laughs]
[grunts]
-[groans]
-[Catra and Prime together] Oh, Adora.
How long will you drag this out?
You will destroy the ones you love
in the process.
[groans]
Horde Prime's server
is infinitely more complex
than anything I've ever encountered.
It's like a neural network,
branching off in every possible direction
in a three-dimensional configuration.
What does that mean?
It means it's gonna take a lot longer
to decipher than I thought.
We have to get out of here. Whoa!
Brothers, why do you attack?
We serve Horde Prime's will.
Enemies of Horde Prime
will know the terror of his--
Unh!
I always hated that guy in particular.
And also,
all the other guys I hit on the way in.
-Glimmer.
-[laughs]
[whimpers]
[snarls]
We have to get out of here!
But I haven't finished yet.
There's no time.
We might not be able to hack him,
but we can still make him hurt.
[yells]
[electricity crackling]
Let's go!
[explosion]
[Prime and Catra together] She was
afraid in the end. And she suffered.
Perhaps I will make her my new vessel,
though she would not last me long.
What do you think?
Adora?
[yells]
[glass shatters and electricity crackles]
[laughs]
[gasps]
Oh!
I am not giving up on you, Catra.
Then you're a fool.
You cannot stop Horde Prime.
He will reign triumphant
over all the universe.
It is destiny.
[screams]
No!
[glass shatters and explodes]
[glass explodes]
[electricity crackling]
Adora, you should have stayed away.
Why did you come back?
We both know I don't matter.
You matter to me.
[gasps]
[grunts]
[screams]
Come on, Catra.
You've never listened to anyone
in your life.
Are you really going to start now?
You're such an idiot.
Yeah. I know.
[laughs]
I'm going to take you home.
Promise?
I promise.
Adora...
[gasps and groans]
[Prime and Catra] Disappointing.
Some creatures are destined
only for destruction.
-[electricity crackling]
-[screams]
No!
[Adora groans]
[gasps]
Catra?
Catra? It's okay.
I'm here.
[breathes weakly]
[footsteps]
I am sorry for the needless waste, Adora.
It did not have to be like this.
Are you ready to cooperate?
[humming]
For the honor of Grayskull!
[♪♪♪]
You miscalculated.
[rumbling]
[panting]
What do we do?
I've got an idea, but you have to promise
you won't be mad that I maybe, possibly,
100 percent disregarded those times
you told me not to tinker with the ship.
Entrapta, if you get us out of here,
you can tinker with the ship
as much as you want.
[laughs] Great! Hey, Darla!
[whistles]
[rumbling]
[crash]
[whirring]
-Good girl.
-[whimpers]
We need to find Adora
and get out of here, now!
[humming]
[♪♪♪]
She-Ra.
She's back.
[snarls]
[yells]
[Darla] Shields at 30 percent.
Hull compromised.
Interspace travel not recommended.
[alarm sounding]
[humming]
[bleeps]
[Darla] Administrator detected.
-Hello, She-Ra.
-Hey, Darla.
Get us out of here.
Affirmative.
And, Darla, make it quick.
[crash]
Come on, Catra.
You're not done. Not yet.
We're going home.
[♪♪♪]
[Catra coughs]
Hey, Adora.
Entrapta?