Okay, She-Ra, I know you're in there.
-Oh, you almost had it.
-[gasps]
Will you stop distracting me?!
Sorry, but there was definitely
some glow-y action going on there.
Come on, Adora. You can't let
distractions keep you from transforming.
[Catra] What's going on?
Ooh! Are we messing with Adora? [grunts]
Catra, do you have to sit right there?
-What? I'm not doing anything.
-Adora, concentrate!
Yeah, Adora, concentrate.
You can do it.
[Catra purring]
[grunts]
-[Entrapta] This way!
-[Adora groans]
Oh, hi, Adora.
Don't mind us.
-Entrapta, do you have to do that in here?
-Yes.
This is where the signal is strongest.
We're less than a day out from Etheria.
We'll be in range to send a message
to the Rebellion soon.
I can't believe...
I'm a day away from meeting my dad.
It's been so long. I barely remember him.
Ready to be home?
Not really.
Okay, fine. Maybe.
[Entrapta cackles]
What do you think's going on right now
on Etheria?
Our friends have still not returned
from their perilous space mission.
So, it's up to us to save Etheria.
Onward, to a secret,
underwater party adventure.
[Mermista groans]
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you, ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong
And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have ♪
♪ And never let it go ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[chuckles] Okay, so, it's not
that I didn't understand the plan,
but I didn't understand the plan.
Why are we dressed like this?
Because it's a secret undercover mission
to find Prince Peekablue.
The reclusive Peekablue is a hermit.
But he was spotted at the top-secret
Enchanted Grotto's underwater soiree.
A gathering place
for all well-heeled criminals of Etheria.
Hmph! So, he'll show up to a criminal
enterprise, but won't so much as RSVP
to my drum circle
so I know how many drums to have?
All right, yeah, I got it.
And, uh, why do we need him?
Because Peekablue has
the power of Farsight.
He can magically see to the edges
of the universe.
If we recruit him, he can tell us
where Adora and the others are.
We have to warn them
that Prime is chipping people on Etheria
and get them back ASAP.
No one at the soiree can know we're there.
So, I've assigned everyone
undercover aliases.
-[gasps]
-Scorpia, you're Lynda D'Ream,
a farmer and mother
to five little scorpions.
[chuckles] "Lynda D'Ream"?
I don't know if you've noticed,
but I'm not exactly great at lying
or pretending or blending in.
I mean, I'm just the muscle.
-Not a spy.
-Nonsense, Lynda.
You were born for this role.
Perfuma, you're Tara, a blacksmith.
Ooh! I love it.
What if Tara has an unmatched skill
at cards and wears an eye patch
and has a dark, checkered past
and an evil twin?
Ooh! I can play the evil twin.
Keep it simple, Tara.
[Perfuma giggles]
[Mermista] Okay, the sooner we find
the prince, the sooner we figure out
where our friends are.
[Spinnerella] There you are.
Hey, you.
Any chance I could steal you away
for a moment?
[sighs] Not now, darling.
After what happened at Elberon,
we need to focus on the next move
for the Rebellion.
Please? It'd only take a second.
I don't have the time.
Oh, yeah, sure. I understand.
Is it me, or is she... mad at me?
I don't know.
It honestly doesn't seem like
she's feeling much of anything.
[gasps] It's our anniversary!
And I completely forgot.
Oh, I gotta fix this, Swifty.
[indistinct chatter]
The dolphins roll in the tide at dawn.
[roars]
Secret, underwater party adventure!
Why are we in a broom closet?
Yeah, where's the soiree?
Oh, this isn't the soiree.
-This is the soiree.
-[Perfuma giggles]
This place is swimming
with bounty hunters, pirates and sirens
who would sell us out in a beat
of their cold-blooded hearts.
We need to blend in,
and find the prince quickly and quietly.
Do not ruin this for me.
[chuckles]
You don't have to tell me twice.
These are my people.
I just have to work the room and--
[whimpers]
Ugh! What is it?
Oh, no, nothing, nothing, nothing.
I just didn't know, uh, he'd be here.
I thought these were your "people."
They are my people.
Which means that most of them
have sworn revenge against me
at some point.
[grumbles]
Quick! Let's, uh, go mingle.
[stammers] Over there.
Okay, it's game time.
Tara's gonna go chat up those fellas.
You go mingle with those ruffians there.
Good luck, Lynda D'Ream.
Oh, gosh.
What a lovely shindig, huh? [chuckles]
My word, that sword is very pointy.
-[blow lands]
-[grunts]
I really hope this doesn't get in the way
of rekindling...
I... [stammers] Wrong word.
Uh, relighting our friendship.
Nope, that's-- That's bad, too.
Look, I'm sorry I set your boat on fire.
-Do you forgive me?
-[muffled grunting]
Excellent, I'll take that as a "yes."
Sea Hawk, focus.
This cannot be like the time you ruined
the Cephalopods Literary Society.
Aw, don't worry.
Now that he can't blow my cover,
it's smooth sailing from here. [exclaims]
[roars]
[all laughing]
Yeah. Totally.
[sighs] So, underwater, huh?
Things? Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Peekablue? Anybody? No? Nobody?
Okay. Well, uh...
never mind. Well, good night.
And that's when I told him,
I don't even know how to swim.
[all laughing]
Please tell me that's the last
of your disgruntled former cohorts.
[chuckles nervously]
Uh, perhaps we should just stay back here?
[gasps]
[groans]
-[Mermista grunting]
-[crashing noises]
How did it go? Did you find out anything?
Yeah. I found out I'm really bad at this.
[sighs]
Don't say that.
That-- That's just the old you talking,
consumed with all that self-doubt
the Horde instilled in you.
I'm just--
I'm not really the leading-lady type.
That's nonsense.
You're amazing. You have the biggest heart
and you could do
whatever you put your mind to.
-Really?
-Okay. What do you, Scorpia, like to do?
Well, I always liked singing.
But I'm bad. Everyone said so.
Well, Catra said so, but it's fine.
Scorpia, you should do things
not because you're good at them
but because they make you happy.
Follow me, okay?
Repeat after me:
I can do this.
Perfuma can do this.
-Perfuma can--
-No, no, no. You can do this. Heh.
Say "I."
I-- I can do this?
I can do this.
I can find Prince Peekablue!
Yes! That's the spirit.
We'll find him, even if he's hidden
in the darkest, most secluded corner
of Etheria.
[Peekablue] Good evening,
misfits of the sea,
outlaws of the land
and everyone in between.
I'm your host,
-Prince Peekablue!
-[crowd cheering]
-Peekablue!
-Prince!
Wow, I guess I don't know
what a hermit is after all.
We've got a great evening
of entertainment for you.
Singers, dancers, and if you're lucky,
a little bit of Farsight for you.
This is our chance.
I'm gonna go get Mermista and Sea Hawk.
Don't take your eyes off Peekablue.
[Peekablue] Next up,
we got Swen on the piano.
Give it up for Swen.
[applause]
[playing jazzy music]
How could I forget?
Spinny probably has
a great surprise planned
and I'm going to have to plan something
even better to beat her.
[groans]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[gasps]
[groans] Okay, anyone else?
That's all of them.
[clears throat]
Now, at last,
we're ready for secret, undercover
and underwater party adventure!
[Mermista groans, then gasps]
-Mermista? What is it?
-Huh?
Uh, nothing. Uh, nothing at all.
Then why are you hiding behind the bar?
[groans] Fine.
There might be someone here
that I absolutely cannot deal with
right now.
What? Who?
Someone whose boat I maybe, sort of,
kind of set on fire.
-What?!
-Shh!
I just wanted to know what it felt like.
[muffled] You are everything
I've ever wanted.
Stop looking at me like that.
[jazzy music continues]
Psst! Hey, is that you, Peekablue?
[music stops]
[gasps]
[Scorpia] Oh...
Hi... Uh...
I'm Sco-- Lynda. D'Ream? Hello.
Oh, I can't watch.
[chuckles] Trying to get backstage--
Performer-- I'm a performer.
-[grunting]
-[feedback whines]
[Perfuma] Yay!
Go, Lynda!
I can do this.
-[clears throat]
-[feedback whines]
[playing jazzy music]
[singing softly] ♪ Sneak
Don't make a sound ♪
♪ Sneak
Just look around ♪
[normal voice] ♪ I've always been strong
But now my nerves are gone ♪
♪ 'Cause I know I can do it
Sing, dance, be a spy ♪
♪ Hiding before your very eyes ♪
♪ How could I sneak
With this fine physique? ♪
♪ Discover the truth
It doesn't take a sleuth ♪
♪ For now I'm a spy
Spying in disguise ♪
♪ Hiding before your very eyes ♪
[singing loudly] ♪ Until you discover
Stay undercover ♪
♪ Seeking a clue
That will lead me to you ♪
♪ Yes, I'm a spy
Spying in disguise ♪
♪ Hiding before your very eyes ♪
♪ Sneak
Don't make a sound ♪
Just look around ♪
♪ I'm a spy
I'm a spy ♪
♪ I'm a spy ♪
-[crowd cheering]
-[Sea Hawk] Oh, yes!
Those pipes.
Bravo!
Oh. [chuckles] Thank you.
Thank you.
[sighs] I did it.
Swen?
[Scorpia gasps]
It's you.
Oh, wow, Prince Peekablue,
I have been looking all over for you.
That was quite a number, honey.
But I really don't have time to chitchat.
Okay, yeah, but see, we need your powers
to fight Horde Prime
-and see where our friends are.
-Friends?
Do you mean Glimmer and Adora?
Wow, you're amazing.
Come on, do it again.
Can you see them right now?
I can see...
a bright, shiny woman among the stars
with her great big sword,
fighting against Horde Prime!
-She-Ra, in space!
-[gasps] Wait, fighting with her sword?
But Adora broke the sword.
[stammers] Farsight never lies, darling.
[clears throat]
Now I must insist you leave.
I need to get into character
for my next performance.
"Character"?
Hmm.
Strangest thing,
but I think we've met before.
Oh, Perfuma's flower crown workshop.
Yes! Perfuma. She's a doll, isn't she?
Never miss a shindig with her.
[whimpers]
The real Peekablue has never met Perfuma.
Who are you?
[blow lands]
[groaning]
Double Trouble?
[gasps]
[sighs] Bravo. You caught me. Again.
What are you doing here?
Where's the real Peekablue?
Wouldn't know.
After things ended with my cash-kitten,
I needed another gig.
I had heard all about
the elusive Peekablue.
A seer who no one has seen in years?
How could I resist?
So, this whole mission has been
a big waste of time.
I might not have the prince's gifts,
but I know where your friends are.
And I'll tell you.
For a price, of course.
Fine.
While I was wandering
through occupied territories,
I posed as a clone,
trying to get in good with Big Brother.
Turns out, it wasn't for me.
It makes for a very dull audience
when everyone's mind-controlled.
Half the crowd out there is chipped.
-What?
-That's not all.
Prime is angry.
She-Ra showed up
and stole his little kitten away.
Your friends are on their way home,
but Prime set up a blockade
around the planet, ready to strike down
anyone daring to pass.
They'll never make it.
Hey, you.
I'm so sorry about today.
I forgot all about it.
Don't worry.
All is forgiven.
You promise you're not mad?
I could never be mad at you, beloved.
"Beloved"?
You've never called me that before.
Show me your neck!
What a shame we can't be together.
In Horde Prime's light.
[whimpering]
What have you done?
Are we done here?
-[thudding]
-[gasps]
Mermista?
What are you doing?!
Step out of the darkness
and into the light of Prime.
Mermista. Mermista, no!
[yelling]
[gasps]
We are in a delicate underwater bubble.
So, can you please stop hitting
one another?
We need to get out of here.
[all gasp]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
There's no way out.
I know a way out.
Take me to the stage!
I mean it. Take me to the stage.
-[Scorpia grunting]
-[Sea Hawk whimpering]
[yells]
[tree branch snaps]
-[Swifty whinnies]
-[gasps]
[Perfuma yells]
The theater has...
Um, a little help?
I need to lift my hand to the heavens.
The theater has many secrets.
I'll hold them off.
Get on that platform and get out of here.
That's your cue, hot stuff. Let's go!
[gasps]
[both yelling]
Perfuma, go!
-Scorpia, come on!
-[Scorpia] There's too many of them.
And this place is coming down
unless someone stops it.
You have to get out
and protect the others.
Go. Now!
What? No!
You're coming, too!
[Scorpia] Nah. This is why I'm here.
I'm the muscle, remember?
I can do this.
[screaming]
[Netossa grunting]
I'm sorry!
Run, quick!
[Swifty whinnies]
Happy anniversary.
[chiming]
Ha! A signal.
We're in range. Patching us through
to the Rebellion's communication line.
-Adora?
-Perfuma.
What's going on?
I... I...
We're on our way back.
Just hang on a little longer.
-We're almost there.
-No! Don't come back.
Horde Prime knows you're coming.
There's a trap, a blockade.
You'll never make it through.
You need to stay away.
The Rebellion's been compromised.
Horde Prime has them.
We lost. I'm so sorry, we lost them.
[yelps]
[static crackling]