[Bow] So, wait, hold on.
Where have you two been
this whole time again?
[Shadow Weaver] While you were traipsing
around in space,
some of us have been working to stop
the Heart of Etheria
from falling into Prime's hands.
We discovered the same thing you did.
Rumors of a Failsafe
that will break the restraints
the First Ones built
and set the stolen magic free.
Are you kidding?
After everything that happened last time,
you're still going after
the Heart of Etheria?
And you're helping her?
We're trying to free the magic
for all of Etheria
so we can be strong enough to fight Prime.
I'm doing this for your father
and for you.
Shadow Weaver is the lesser of two evils.
-At least you admit she's evil.
-[growls]
[Shadow Weaver] You're one to talk,
aren't you?
[both growl]
Tell us what you know about the Failsafe.
What makes you think it's in Mystacor?
As any good sorcerer knows,
Mystacor was built on the ruins
of an ancient First Ones citadel.
And beneath Mystacor--
Ooh, ooh. Can I tell this part?
Go ahead.
Beneath Mystacor,
there are many secret tunnels and rooms,
forgotten and sealed off.
No one has been able
to access them in centuries,
but there are whispers
of what they contain.
An artifact known as the Crystal of Arxia,
hidden there by a group
of traitorous First Ones.
You said I could do it!
You were taking too long.
Arxia. That must be the outpost
that Mara's rebels were talking about!
The Failsafe might be underneath Mystacor!
[Shadow Weaver] Reaching it won't be easy.
But I have spent my whole life
studying the secrets of Mystacor.
I can get us in.
If you figured it out on your own,
why come back here?
Why do you need us at all?
[Shadow Weaver] Because Mystacor
is controlled by Micah,
who, you may recall,
is controlled by Horde Prime.
You have allowed Prime
to take too much ground.
If he seizes the Heart,
it will all be over.
There is no more time
for half measures, Adora.
You must act now.
It's the only lead we have.
We have to try.
It'll have to be a stealth mission.
Catra, do you think you and Melog can--?
Oh, leave her to sulk.
We can't let her slow us down.
You guys get ready. I'll find her.
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you, ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
♪ And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have ♪
-♪ And never let it go ♪
-♪ Oh ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
Catra. Are you coming with us to Mystacor?
Why would I do that?
Seems like you and Shadow Weaver
have it handled.
[sighs] After everything she's done to us,
you're really going to follow her?
I don't like it either,
but this is the only plan we have.
The Failsafe could finally save Etheria.
Shadow Weaver hurt us.
I haven't forgotten that.
But Prime is hurting so many more people.
I need to stop him, Catra.
I know, I know.
You have to go save the world.
Spare me the speech.
Hey, she can't do anything to us anymore.
Please, come. We--
I could really use your help.
Fine. But I'm only doing this to make sure
Shadow Weaver doesn't try anything.
Not because I like you.
[Melog purrs]
[Adora yelps]
-Bow! I need to talk to you!
-[yelps]
I was finally able to remove
Spinnerella's chip,
but it was a lot more difficult
than removing Catra's.
The chip had almost entirely fused
to her nervous system.
If we'd waited any longer,
I'm not sure we would've been able
to get it off at all.
The chip would've become a part of her.
That means we're running out of time
to save everyone else.
Yes. Luckily, I've got an idea.
This is the network that connects
all the chips to Prime's hivemind.
If I can just figure out how to crack
his signal pattern,
I could disrupt it,
severing his connection to the chips
and taking them all off-line at once!
That's amazing!
We could free everyone on Etheria!
You're a genius, Entrapta.
Just keep working on it until you get it.
We'll be back later tonight.
You got it!
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[gasps]
No sorcerers here. Looks like--
-Keep your voice down.
-Don't touch me!
[gasps]
For the Honor of Grayskull!
[gasps, then yelps]
We have to hurry!
Hmm.
Uh, hey there, where you going?
I'm so close to cracking
Prime's signal pattern!
But Spinnerella's chip's not enough.
I need to find a place
with a high concentration of clones
so I can analyze their connection
to the hivemind!
Whoa. Wait, wait, wait.
You're just gonna walk into a place
that's crawling with clones?
Yep!
Ugh, there's no way I'm going to stop you
from doing this, is there?
Nope!
Oh, this is a terrible idea.
Hop on. I can get you there faster,
and get you out if there's trouble.
Works for me!
Thanks, Bird Horse!
For the last time, I'm not--
Just get this over with.
[Shadow Weaver] We're here.
Follow my lead.
Would a "please" kill you?
[Glimmer] Whoa.
Hey, are you--?
I'm fine.
Catra, it'll be okay.
Trust me.
There's no time to waste.
News of our presence will have
reached the others by now after that...
disturbance.
Come on. We have to keep moving.
[Bow] What is all of this?
[Castaspella] We're on the right path.
The Crystal of Arxia
was rumored to be the key
to reaching deep magic within Etheria.
Many have tried, and failed, to find it.
But those who hungered for more power
have long sought other ways
to obtain the deep magic...
with disastrous results.
The Spell of Obtainment was a mistake,
one for which I've paid the price.
I don't see why you keep bringing it up.
You roped my brother into your twisted
dark magic when he was only a child.
You could've killed him.
It would've worked
had he not broken the connection.
Micah was an exceptional sorcerer,
even then.
It's a shame it didn't run in the family.
What is going on over there?
The pattern is incredibly complex.
I need more connections.
No way! Whatever's going on here,
it's not good.
No tech is worth you
getting captured by Prime!
This isn't about tech.
It's about our chipped friends.
If I can get this to work,
I can save them.
[groans]
Oh, okay, but be quick.
I'll cover you from behind.
Please be careful.
Yes! I've got it!
Ahh.
Uh-oh.
-[Shadow Weaver] Wait!
-[gasps]
Adora!
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Did you just jump into fire for me?
[Catra] What? No!
-[Adora laughing]
-Shut up!
[Adora] You did.
Oh, that's good.
It's an illusion!
[Shadow Weaver] Some of the fire
is illusory, and some is real.
Everyone, be careful.
[Shadow Weaver] I see you and Catra
are close again.
Do you really think that's wise?
It's none of your business.
But it is.
If your emotions are blocking you
from becoming She-Ra,
it's all of Etheria's business.
How long has it been
since you were able to transform?
It's been happening
ever since the Fright Zone.
What if...?
What if I'm losing her?
She-Ra is a being of pure magic.
To unleash her full strength,
you must be focused, clearheaded.
But you are letting your emotions
pull you in too many directions.
Catra, she distracts you, confuses you.
Haven't you hurt each other enough?
If you care about her,
focus on protecting her.
The world needs you as She-Ra right now,
not Adora.
And if She-Ra can't stop Prime,
then we are all doomed.
I will stop Prime.
No matter what.
[growls] Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Why do I know your face?
Hordak?
No, do not say that name to me.
I have no name.
What have you done to me?
You do remember me.
I knew you would.
[Swift Wind neighs]
Get away from her!
Entrapta, let's go!
Go.
Maybe then these memories,
these imperfections, will leave me.
Remember!
Your imperfections are beautiful!
-[Castaspella gasps]
-Whoa.
[Bow] Whoa.
[Glimmer] That is the Failsafe?
It's bigger than I thought it'd be.
How are we gonna get that to the Heart?
[Shadow Weaver] The Failsafe is a code.
It's stored inside the Crystal.
So, what do we--?
It needs a password.
I think you already know what it is.
We're friends of Mara.
What does it say?
"Someone needs to go inside
and accept the Failsafe"?
What does that mean?
It means the Failsafe must be bonded
to a willing soul
and carried to the Heart of Etheria
in their body in order to be deployed.
And we're sure that's safe?
We can't turn back now.
The Failsafe is within our grasp.
[Catra] Adora, don't go in there.
[Shadow Weaver]
Catra, this is not the time.
Someone must take the Failsafe.
So, you do it, then.
I've been watching you the whole way in.
You've been in here before, haven't you?
You could've taken the Failsafe yourself
and gotten all the power
you've ever wanted.
But you didn't. Why?
You're being paranoid.
This is the only way to stop Prime.
Adora understands that well enough.
Why does it have to be Adora?
What is going to happen to her?
What aren't you telling us?
Answer the question.
[growling]
Whoever uses the Failsafe must absorb
the full magic of the Heart
when it is destroyed.
That much raw magical power
would burn any mere mortal apart.
None of us are strong enough.
But She-Ra is.
Only She-Ra can hope to survive
the process.
No one else can do it.
And if I don't survive it?
Then the magic will be restored to Etheria
through your sacrifice.
You will give us the power
to bring us to victory.
Prime will be defeated.
Your friends will be free.
-You were planning this all along!
-Why are you surprised by this?
It's not going to work!
There is no way
we're risking Adora like that!
[Castaspella] You're using Adora
to get the magic for yourself.
[all shouting indistinctly]
[Adora] Stop it!
I'll do it.
No. What? What's wrong with you?
Shadow Weaver is sacrificing you.
Why can't you see that?
Because even if she is,
it's better than Prime getting the Heart
and destroying the universe!
We're out of options.
This is the only way.
[voices whispering indistinctly]
Well, look who it is.
[Catra] Adora!
Whoa!
Dad!
Hello, daughter.
I'm so pleased to see you.
[gasps]
And you, sister.
Her, not so much.
Glimmer!
For the Honor of Grayskull!
No.
We have to get out of here!
The Failsafe! We can't!
Adora, no!
Please. It doesn't always have to be you!
Adora! [yells]
[yelling]
Ahh.
What's happening?
[Micah laughs]
-[Glimmer] Is that--?
-Dark magic.
After all, I learned from the best.
[gasps] Micah, no!
[yelling]
-[gasps]
-[groans]
For the Honor of Grayskull!
[Micah yells]
I've got it. I've got the Failsafe.
Let's get out of here.
[Micah grunting]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[mewing]
Catra.
Catra?
Catra, stop!
You were just gonna leave?
I'm doing you a favor.
I'm a distraction, right?
Now you can go save the world without
having to worry about me confusing you.
No, that's not true.
Don't listen to Shadow Weaver.
This isn't about her.
Why?
Why are you like this?
Why do you always have to sacrifice
everything for everyone else?
When do you get to choose?
What do you want, Adora?
I...
I have to do this, Catra.
I'm the only one who can.
Then do it.
That's what you want.
That's what you'll always choose.
I don't have to stay and watch it happen.
Catra, please, stay.
I need you.
No, you don't.
You never have.
Catra!
Adora, you made the right choice.
Don't let Catra convince you otherwise.
She's never understood.
Stop!
I will never forgive you.
You ruin people.
You ruin any chance
they could ever be happy.
Haven't you done enough?
I did what I had to do.
Keep telling yourself that.
I'm going to take the Failsafe
to the Heart,
and I'm going to save Etheria.
But I am not doing it for you.
I'll do everything I can to make sure
you never get your hands on the magic.