[chattering]
You all right, darling?
Need something to drink?
Are you warm?
[chattering]
[winces]
[gasps]
These flowers really bring out
the color in your eyes.
Bow, could you stop playing that thing?
Hey, I'm still learning.
-Well, I like it.
-Hey...
Prime is getting closer every day
to figuring out how to access
the Heart of Etheria.
If he succeeds, he can use it
to destroy worlds, galaxies,
maybe even the entire universe.
The Failsafe is our only chance
at stopping him.
But Prime still has our friends.
His hold over them grows stronger
every day they're chipped.
If we don't free them now,
we might lose them forever.
Prime holds every advantage in this fight.
He'll be ready for us.
But we have a plan. Entrapta?
I finally succeeded
in cracking Prime's signal pattern.
If I get access to his Spire network,
I can broadcast a jamming frequency
that will disable all of the chips
on Etheria, freeing everyone at once!
I need you all
to get Entrapta to the Spire
and keep Prime's forces distracted
while she jams the signal.
I'm gonna take the Failsafe to the Heart
and destroy it, once and for all.
We're going to make sure that Prime
can never hurt anyone again.
We're ending this today. For good.
[all cheering]
[Entrapta] Yeah!
Ah. [chuckles] Oh, my goodness.
[Sea Hawk] Ha-cha! Friendship!
[chattering]
Oh.
You weren't trying to sneak out
without us, were you?
-Any sign of Catra?
-She's not coming back.
Are you sure you should come?
We don't know what to expect from the
Heart of Etheria. It could be dangerous.
There's no way
we're letting you do this on your own.
Whatever we find, we face it together.
For the honor of Grayskull!
♪ We're on the edge of greatness ♪
♪ Turning darkness to light ♪
♪ We're right beside you, ready to fight ♪
♪ We're gonna win in the end ♪
♪ We must be strong
And we must be brave ♪
♪ We must be brave ♪
♪ We gotta find every bit of strength
That we have ♪
-♪ And never let it go ♪
-♪ Oh ♪
♪ We must be strong ♪
[automated voice speaking disjointedly]
Warning. Planetary facilitator
Light Hope protocol offline.
Manual administrator access
not recommended at this time.
We're friends of Mara.
Now show us where the Heart of Etheria is.
Welcome, friends of Mara.
[grunts]
[yells]
Ow! What's wrong with you?!
-[mews]
-Stop it! Stop it!
I told you, I'm not going back.
[growling]
[grunting]
You saw what happened!
Adora chose Shadow Weaver, okay? Not me!
Adora doesn't want me!
Not like I want her.
[footsteps approaching]
[wind whooshing]
Hey, bot-faces! Come and get us!
[chuckles] Plenty for both of us.
[Wrong Hordak] Brothers.
It is I, a faithful acolyte
of Horde Prime, just like you.
[whinnies]
Nice work, Wrong Hordak.
[chuckling] Oh! This is so exciting!
[Sea Hawk] Perforation!
We have to keep their attention on us
until Entrapta can finish.
[yelps]
[gasps]
[Entrapta] Wow.
Okay, Entrapta, you got this.
You got this.
Are you scared?
No. I just really hope this works.
It's okay, Adora.
We'll be with you the whole way.
When we get back, it will be a new world.
[Catra laughs in distance]
-Did you guys hear that?
-What?
[Catra continues laughing]
Catra?
Hey, Adora.
-Catra, you came--
-[Bow] Adora!
You're going the wrong way.
The trail is back here. You okay?
[She-Ra] We need to be careful.
It looks like this place
can still project memories.
We can't let it distract us.
[gasps]
-[voices whispering indistinctly]
-[winces]
My brothers.
The time has come at last.
No longer shall She-Ra stand in my way.
The Heart shall be laid bare,
its power mine for the taking.
[clones] Cast out the shadows.
Bring the universe to Prime's light.
Cast out the shadows.
Begin the acquisition process.
[gasps]
Adora.
We have to warn Adora!
-[Glimmer] Adora?
-[Bow] Adora!
[gasps]
[Bow] Adora!
-Adora, are you okay?
-What's going on?
[She-Ra] I think I know.
This place is responding to my memories.
I think I'm doing this.
So, why here? And how do we get out?
When I broke the Sword, I thought...
I thought I could make my own destiny.
But I can't.
It was always going to end like this.
What do you mean, "end"?
Adora!
[She-Ra] I'm losing her.
I'm distracted and confused,
and I'm scared.
And I can't be any of those things
if this is going to work.
I need to go the rest of the way
by myself.
Adora, no! You don't have to do this!
I love you guys so much.
I never could have done
any of this without you.
Thank you for being the best friends
anyone could ask for.
Adora!
[rumbling]
[panting]
Adora! Adora!
[Shadow Weaver] She's not here.
What do you mean, she's not here?
Where is she?
She's gone to the Heart of Etheria
to free the magic
and become the hero she was born to be.
If you are still so selfish
as to try and stop--
Enough! This isn't about you
and your messed-up power trip anymore.
Prime is doing something to the planet.
He's infecting it.
He's going for the Heart.
[clone] The last of Etheria's security
protocols have been breached, Lord Prime.
Planetary acquisition is at 20 percent.
[laughing maniacally]
Oh...
Almost.
[yelps]
[screams]
[Horde Prime] Welcome, little rebel.
You're just in time
to witness the end of your world.
Why aren't they shooting?
Oh, no.
[all scream]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
Rejoice, Etheria,
for your day of reckoning has come.
I offered you mercy.
But you have spurned my good graces.
So be it.
[Entrapta screams]
Entrapta!
I'm sorry.
Your resistance has been for naught.
Your She-Ra has abandoned you.
All that is left for your world
is a terrible and eternal night.
Take us to Adora. Now!
She's too far away by now.
We'd never reach her in time.
No. Use your magic. I know you have
more power than you're letting on.
It doesn't work that way, Catra!
You've done it before!
When you abandoned me in the Fright Zone.
You've always been able to track us
our whole lives.
So, do something good with it and help me
save Adora before it's too late!
Come here.
Adora!
-[groans]
-Catra?
-Where's Adora?
-She... She left us.
She's headed to the Heart on her own.
Of course she's gone!
That's what she does, isn't it?
[rumbling]
Catra, what is going on?
Horde Prime is onto you.
He's hacking into the planet.
All of this is from him.
-He's gonna take the Heart.
-That's not all. He's got Entrapta.
If Prime has Entrapta, that means
the other princesses are still chipped.
-We have to get back up there.
-We can't just leave Adora!
[Catra] I'll stay. I'll find her.
-Catra...
-[Catra] I can't lose her again, okay?
I promised her a long time ago
that I'd look out for her.
It's time I made good on that.
Take care of her, Horde scum.
That's the plan, Sparkles.
And good luck.
The four of us don't need luck.
We're the Best Friend Squad.
[Melog meows]
Get them there safe, okay?
[meows]
Go help the princesses!
I'll handle the signal.
[grunts]
[Glimmer] Bow...
I love you.
I love you, too.
Be careful, okay?
Me?
I'm always careful.
[whistles]
I'm going to save Etheria,
no matter what it takes.
Your sacrifice won't be in vain,
I promise.
But at what cost?
I never wanted to die.
I sacrificed myself
so you would never have to.
Why are you doing this, Adora?
It's better this way.
My friends will be safe.
-They'll be happy.
-And you?
-What do you want when this is all over?
-I...
It doesn't matter. I'm She-Ra.
This is what I'm supposed to do.
You're worth more than what you can give
to other people. You deserve love, too.
You're so close, Adora. Don't give up yet.
Mara? What's--?
[Horde Prime] Ah.
Adora.
So, this is where you've run to hide.
-There's too many! We have to retreat!
-Retreat where? We're totally surrounded.
[yells]
-[scoffs]
-[Frosta laughing]
-Yeah!
-Miss me?
Yes, but also, behind you!
[Sea Hawk] Mermista.
Horde Prime thinks he controls you.
But I know you.
And I'm gonna prove it to you
with the power of shanty!
♪ Oh-- ♪
Whoa!
Downward!
[yelling]
You know, this is actually kind of nice.
Doesn't it remind you of the first time
we met? You also tried to kill me then.
[yelping]
[chuckles]
[groans, then gasps]
Couldn't wait to sweep me off my feet?
[growls]
Why are you like this?
Because I love you, dearest.
And also, it's a good distraction.
Please forgive me for that
when you're back to normal.
Uh, guys?
Did anyone see where Scorpia went?
I'm gonna help Bow with the signal.
Aunt Casta, can you--? [gasps]
Hello, baby girl.
You're not here.
You can't stop me.
How strange.
I must have fought her,
must have known her face.
But I have no memory of it.
[creature shrieking]
[Horde Prime]
I've seen so many like her over the years.
One by one, all their faces
have been lost to oblivion.
Just as yours will be.
[creature shrieking]
[yelps]
[screaming]
[Horde Prime] A parting gift
from the First Ones.
Their old security system.
Capable of taking out
even one as strong as She-Ra.
You will never make it
to the Heart, Adora.
Your own people made sure of that.
Goodbye, my oldest enemy.
[shrieking]