[wincing]
[shrieking]
[growls, then grunts]
[yells]
Hey, Adora.
Catra! You can't be here.
It's too dangerous.
Shadow Weaver?
Get Adora to the Heart.
I'll take care of this thing.
-Catra, no!
-I'll catch up, okay? Get to the Heart.
No, no. Catra!
Dad. No!
What's wrong, baby girl?
I've never felt better.
[screams]
[yells]
Scorpia, please! We're trying to save you.
Dad, please! It's me, it's Glimmer!
Oh, I know who you are. My daughter.
The weakling. The failure.
And so it ends.
Pathetic. Alone.
Weak.
Mom.
No. I'm not.
[yelling]
My mother raised me to be brave.
My friends taught me to be kind.
And I'm stubborn. I get that from you.
I will never stop fighting!
And I won't lose another parent!
[gasping]
I love you, Dad.
-[Glimmer grunts]
-[Micah screaming]
[keyboard clicking]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
I've got it! [gasps]
Scorpia, it's okay.
Prime may have made you do
a lot of things,
but he can't turn you
into something you're not.
So, right now,
all I need you to do is trust me.
[screams]
[Scorpia groaning]
-[grunts]
-Oh, my gosh, I am so sorry.
Did I hurt you? I did not mean to do that.
Welcome back.
[meows]
[Scorpia grunts]
[Entrapta laughs]
My device worked! I knew it would.
[growls]
Deploy all clone battalions.
Get this under control!
Hey, everyone. I'm Bow.
Prime is probably trying to get his
channel back. I have to make this quick.
Prime's controlled the universe
for a long time.
Right now, we're the only thing standing
in the way of him controlling it forever.
You might be feeling hopeless.
You might be thinking, "We don't stand
a chance." And maybe we don't.
Prime's too strong.
His army is too powerful.
But that's not gonna stop us.
We need to show Prime we're not afraid
of him, because we have each other.
And we have love.
We can't give up.
And if we go down, we go down together.
We need you. All of you.
It's time to take back our world.
It's time to fight. For She-Ra,
for our homes, and for each other!
Put an end to this mockery.
Destroy them all!
[yells]
[creature shrieking]
[Horde Prime chuckles]
Oh, little sister. What a shame.
I had such high hopes for you.
[screams]
No. No, wait.
Don't lose your focus. We're so close.
[pulsating]
[Adora groans]
[gasping]
[Catra screams in distance]
Catra!
Adora, wait!
So brave, risking yourself for Adora.
But it will make no difference.
The Heart is almost mine,
and when it is, your Adora will die.
So, tell me, little sister,
was it worth it?
[Catra yells]
-Shadow Weaver?
-Take Adora and run!
-What are you...?
-I told you to run! Now, run!
Shadow Weaver, no! What are you doing?
Please, Catra. You need to make sure
Adora reaches the Heart.
The magic must be set free.
[shrieking]
[Shadow Weaver groans]
Stop it! It's going to kill you!
[Shadow Weaver] It's too late for me.
But you,
this is only the beginning for you.
I am so proud of you, Catra.
No! No!
Catra?
You're welcome.
[Adora sobbing]
Come on. We have to go.
[screams]
-Yeah!
[clones yelling]
Impossible.
You can't control us.
You don't understand what makes us strong.
And that's why you'll never win.
[Adora grunting]
[both gasp]
[Adora] The Heart of Etheria.
We made it.
[screaming]
What is it? What's wrong?
I don't... I don't know.
I can't transform.
[rumbling]
[Adora] It's Prime's virus.
It's keeping me from becoming She-Ra.
What does that mean? Is the Failsafe
not going to work without her?
No. It'll work.
Get as far away from here as you can.
I have to do this next part on my own.
Adora, what is going to happen to you?
Without She-Ra, the magic will destroy me.
I'm sorry, Catra.
I'm so sorry.
But there's no more time.
It has to end here.
I can still save everybody.
It's okay.
I'm ready.
No.
-Catra...
-No.
I'm not leaving.
Whatever happens, I am staying with you.
[screaming]
Adora?
[groaning]
No, no, no. No! No!
[laughs]
Ah. I can feel it.
The Heart is mine!
You can't do this!
The Heart's power is too unstable.
It will take you and the whole universe
with it!
I have had enough
of this chatty little rebel.
Dispose of her now.
My dominion was perfect.
Everything was as it should be.
And so it shall be again.
Did you not hear me, little brother?
Do it now.
[grunts]
[yelling]
I am not your brother.
You made me in your image,
but I am more than that.
I gave myself a name,
I made a life of my own.
I made...
a friend.
I am Hordak, and I defy your will.
[Horde Prime screaming]
[laughs]
You did it! I knew you could-- [gasps]
[laughing]
[Horde Prime] Ah, little brother.
So, it's true.
You have been thoroughly corrupted.
-So be it!
-No!
[Horde Prime] You have forced my hand.
I will unleash the Heart,
and so we shall die
in cleansing flame together!
[snaps]
[Scorpia yelling]
[Scorpia] Whoo! [chuckles]
-Glimmer!
-Bow!
[crash]
Rejoice, Etheria,
for your end has finally come!
You have chosen darkness,
and so,
into darkness you shall be plunged.
The world will end in fire.
-Adora!
-The Failsafe.
It didn't work.
[Horde Prime] And when the ashes scatter,
at last
there will be peace!
Adora. Adora, stay awake!
I'm sorry.
Adora!
[gasps]
-[door opens]
-Just let me brush it!
-No!
-[Glimmer laughs]
Don't let her touch me.
She's gonna torture me.
Do you always have to be this dramatic?
[Bow] Come on, guys.
If we're late to Scorpia's first ball,
she's gonna kill us.
Fine! You're off the hook.
This time.
You coming?
A beautiful wish.
But there will be no future.
Not for you.
[screams]
Adora! Please! You have to wake up!
You can't give up.
You have never given up
on anything in your life.
Not even on me.
So, don't you dare start now!
It's too late.
I've failed.
No! No!
I've got you. I'm not letting go.
Don't you get it? I love you.
I always have.
So, please, just this once...
stay.
Stay.
You love me?
You're such an idiot.
I love you, too.
Cry, Etheria!
Cry for Prime's mercy!
There will be no comfort for you!
All the universe will be consumed
in undying flame!
[both gasp]
[grunts]
[growls]
[gasps]
[yells]
[grunting]
[growls]
Though all is reduced to rubble,
Prime shall rise again.
So it has been, and so it always shall be.
No.
You're wrong.
It's time for you to go.
[gasping]
[screaming]
[Hordak] I remember you.
Hordak!
I'm so glad you're back!
Oh, we have so much to talk about!
Glimmer?
Hi, Dad.
I... You...
Hello. I'm your dad!
Dad!
[Spinerella laughs]
[neighs]
[all laughing]
Perfuma! Hi. Wow, you look...
You look great.
Hey, Scorpia.
Look, I...
Ohh. There it is.
You know I'm a hugger.
Princess hug!
[all laughing]
[Entrapta] I'm so glad you're here! Oh...
So, are we all just, like, okay with this?
[Bow] Look at us now. From capturing you
to us now being buddies.
-[Catra] We did it!
-[Bow] This is so dope!
Ah. You would be proud, Mara dearie.
[Catra] Adora?
It's over.
He's gone.
Good riddance.
-[both yelling]
-Whoa!
So, what are we gonna do now?
[sighs]
[Adora] We can bring magic back
to the universe.
What do you guys say to one more
Best Friend Squad road trip?
-[Glimmer] I'm in!
-[Bow] Obviously!
[Catra] Of course I'm going with you,
dummy.
[Adora] Then let's do this. Together.