[snoring]
[squeals]
[humming]
[beatboxing]
Come to papa!
Whoa!
[hip-hop music plays]
♪ I wish I never saw the sunshine ♪
[grunting]
[vocalizing]
Nice!
[rumbling]
-♪ Hey, yo, this city heart can flutter ♪
-Hm?
♪ With stuttering sounds ♪
♪ Gutter music for silver lining class ♪
[music continues faintly]
[yelling]
[music playing loudly]
[music continues through speakers]
[grunts]
Whoa, that beat is fire!
[music continues]
We're drinking bubbly tonight!
[gasps]
[gulps] Ahh.
[crying in distance]
Hang on, Dave.
I'm coming, ya big baby.
Maybe they're in here!
[sighs] Not in this closet.
But maybe they're in here!
Man, what was in that poison?
Maybe they're in here!
Uh, Jamack, you've checked that closet,
like, six times.
I did? Huh.
[gasps] Ooh!
Maybe they're in here!
-[crying]
-Huh? Wait.
There was a baby?
-[crying]
-[blows raspberry]
[squealing]
Wolf, the lock!
[door knob rattles]
Dave, I'm home!
A hum--?
[gags]
A human?
Uh... [gasps]
I am so glad you frogs are here.
You've gotta help me.
I fell into this whole bush of,
uh, uh, explosion berries!
Hm. Explosion berries?
I guess that could be a thing.
I can't remember...
Oh, it is definitely a real thing.
And contagious!
If just one drop of their juice
gets on your skin, boom!
-OK, have you guys heard of this?
-Boom, boom!
Oh, I feel a warmth.
I don't have much... time.
[yelling]
It's happening!
Oh, the horror!
[all yelling]
-Explosion berries are real!
-Explosion berries!
Wait! Wait! Don't leave me...
[sobbing]
Oh, no! Are you OK?
[chuckling]
Yeah, I'm fine.
Explosion berry?
That was impressive!
I fully believed
explosion berries were a thing!
I know those frogs.
We need to keep moving
if we don't wanna die.
[chuckles]
Well, she seems like a lot of fun.
Hey, thanks for watching my buddy.
He just needed his formula.
So, he's your grub baby?
Dave? Oh, no.
We go way back.
-[exclaims]
-Kinda look out for each other.
Wow! Is that a deathstalker tail?
I have never actually seen one in person.
Can I touch it?
[Wolf] Be my guest.
On second thought,
I'm... I'm... I'm good.
Wait a minute. How can you
go way back when he's just a...
Huh?
-[babbles]
-[gasps]
I did not see that coming.
Sit tight. There's more.
[babbling]
What is that?
His body's going through some changes.
It's completely natural.
Hey! Quit talking about me
in front of strangers!
-Raging hormones.
-Why are you embarrassing me?
[groans]
[gasps]
Whoo-hoo!
I'm out of my awkward stage.
It doesn't do me any favors.
Mm...
Hey, my arm grew in short.
Did someone here mess with my cocoon?
Was it you?
You give off a vibe.
I can make your other arms
match the stub if you want.
Hey! We're all fellow
travelers here, all right?
I'm Benson.
You've already met Dave.
Charmed.
Travelers?
So, you're from the surface, too?
Second human I've met on top.
Mind blown.
Kipo, don't say anything more.
He's a mute.
And he's a friend of a mute.
Are you from one of those hole cities?
-Dave, what are they called?
-Burrows.
-You a burrow girl?
-I am from a burrow!
What did I just say?
Wild guess, top of my head, I don't know.
You're lost and need to get home.
How'd you know?
You're good.
Wolf's helping me.
We have to get over
a mountain of skyscrapers first.
Sure, just tell
complete strangers everything!
You mean Skyscraper Ridge?
Oh, it's a good thing you found us.
[growling]
[chuckles nervously]
Nice piggy.
You know, Dave's right.
Nobody gets over Skyscraper Ridge.
Not without experienced guides.
We've been over the ridge...
-What is it, Dave, ten times now?
-More like 12.
Tell you what, we'll take you
over the ridge in exchange for...
I don't know.
Dave, what should we do it for?
-The deathstalker tail.
-Yeah, the deathstalker tail.
Not a chance.
They're trying to hustle us.
[groans]
Oh, what do you think, Mandu?
[snorting]
OK, it's settled.
You both need to leave.
Why should we?
Because you're not the one
holding the deathstalker.
All right.
We can take a hint.
You coming?
[yawns]
[screams]
Stalkie!
[moaning]
Huh?
Didn't you say shouting was bad?
Ringing the dinner bell?
-They got our bike, too?! [groans]
-[snoring]
I just don't understand how these
two con artists got past my trap!
[grunting]
[moans] Five more minutes, Dad?
They seemed nice.
And they were so helpful.
[groans]
I can't believe I fell for it.
[laughing]
If you want, you can say,
"I told you so!"
[yelling]
[grunting]
♪ Day by day ♪
♪ We're reaching higher and higher ♪
[yelling]
[singing indistinctly]
-♪ Day by day ♪
-[grunts]
Look, it was nothing personal.
It's a deathstalker.
-You shoulda guarded it better!
-Here, have it back.
[grunting]
Look, we can really help you
get over Skyscraper Ridge.
We weren't lying.
And this time, we'll do it on the house!
-[screams]
-Wolf, are you seeing this?
I'm totally riding a bike.
[gasps, screams]
Hang on! I got you!
♪ Day by day ♪
[grunting]
I can't... Get it.
[yells]
-[yells]
-Benson!
Wolf, stab the tongue!
Yeah, get 'em!
[Wolf grunts]
Hey!
[tires screeching]
[panting] If you wanna find your home,
come with me.
Hey! We have to go back for them!
No, we don't.
[ribbiting]
You might wanna hang on to something.
-[grunts]
-[rumbling]
The hill is moving.
Wolf, the hill is moving!
[Wolf] It's not a hill!
[roaring]
[yells]
Sorry, Benson.
The frogs are never done.
They won't stop looking for us.
-Why do they want people so bad?
-I don't really know,
but that's why there's hardly
any of us left up here.
That's why we should stick together.
That's why we should be
helping Benson and Dave.
I mean, if we could get to them.
How could you do that?
How could you just leave them behind?
Kipo, do you know how valuable you are?
You could lead them
to a whole city full of humans.
Just be thankful we got away!
-Thank you.
-You haven't lived up here.
You don't know what it's like.
It's amazing.
In just a day, I've seen enough wonders
to fill a lifetime.
I've also seen people
being terrible to each other.
We need to eat.
[Mandu growls softly]
[grunts]
People being terrible?
I'm not being terrible.
[grunting]
She doesn't know me.
[yells]
[groans]
Huh?
Not today.
I don't get it.
They robbed us.
-[Wolf grunting]
-[Kipo sighs]
But they also tried to help us.
Something about this just feels wrong.
[screaming]
Get away!
[squeals]
[yelling, grunting]
[squealing]
Wolf, I've decided.
We're going back for Benson and Dave.
Up here you do what you have to,
and we have to do this.
[panting]
You're right.
And I won't take no...
Wait, what?
Those two aren't worth my spit...
[sighs]
But up here, we should stick together.
You do care, even if you can't admit it.
That's lesson one of people.
[Wolf] You're hugging me. Don't.
[Kipo sighs] Deal with it.
Look, we have one human.
That's pretty good.
Let's call it a day and go home.
Uh, I'm sorry. Pretty good?
You'd settle for pretty good,
when we could have the burrow girl
and make the biggest score of our lives?
And you call yourself a Mod Frog.
Also, your tie is uneven.
[gasps]
-[scoffs]
-[hums]
Man, that wolf girl.
It really burns me.
She could've helped us, and these ropes
are really cuttin' off my circulation.
To be fair, we did take her deathstalker.
So? Everyone steals.
That's just survival.
But turning her back on us like that
goes against the code.
We... We have a code?
The unwritten code
that we never speak about.
We both live by it.
I thought you knew!
Anything in that code
about untying knots?
Hang on.
Huh?
[grunting]
[tires screeching]
[groaning]
[sighs] Oh, yeah.
The boss is gonna be so happy
when we show her what we just found.
-The burrow girl!
-I hate to disappoint you.
You're gonna give us our two friends,
and then we'll be on our way.
You heard her.
Hand them over.
Harris, Kwat, they want us
to hand over their friends.
I think that's against company policy.
My coworker's a real stickler
for the rules.
Look, I totally get it.
You all want to be together.
So, I'll take all four of you.
[grunts]
[slow-motion growl]
-[grunts]
-[car door shuts]
Welp, there goes our last hope of rescue.
Next time, we pick smarter humans to rob.
[chuckles nervously]
I'm telling you, she smells awful.
[grunts]
Humans have no sense of hygiene.
[laughs] No.
That's just the smell
of how stinkin' rich
we're all about to be
because we have a burrow girl!
That's right.
If you ever wanted to see one...
-[all gasping]
-...in person, now's your chance.
We have a burrow girl!
-[chuckles nervously]
-[grunts]
Uh, whoever said I'm from a burrow...
[chuckles nervously]
I hunt mega bunnies.
Mm-hmm.
I've been on the surface my whole life...
[gruff voice] just surviving.
Just don't.
Huh.
Yeah, it's obvious she's a burrow girl.
But I'd rather have proof.
If you can confirm it, you both go free.
Who, Kipo?
My girl here is the baddest
mega-bunny hunter ever.
Yeah, she's a legend.
Apology accepted, girl.
Did it look like I apologized?
Boss!
-You're back. I have a--
-So, this is her?
A gift for you.
[groans]
Skin untouched by the sun.
[groaning]
Not a single tooth missing.
Well done, Jamack.
This girl is from a burrow.
Scarlemagne will pay handsomely for her.
Wait. What now?
Did she say who I think she said?
Scarlemagne?
Who's Scarlemagne?
Trust me.
You don't want to know.
[rumbling]
[sniffs]
Something smells funny.
Oh, that?
It's like we've been saying all along,
we're mega bunny hunters.
And right before Jamack grabbed us...
we found a nest of babies.
Their fur is so soft.
[gasps]
[roars]
[sniffs]
-Jamack!
-That was the signal!
-Where's our backup?
-Mandu, you're the backup!
[slow-motion yelling]
[shrieking]
[gasping]
[screaming]
We gotta move, or we'll be bunny chow!
Like, now!
[growling]
You enraged a 100-foot-tall
mom beast on purpose.
What was your plan for after that?
I never thought that far ahead.
I'm new at this.
Know what?
We'd have done the same.
-Look out!
-Human scum!
You played me!
Actually, I'm impressed.
[yells]
-[roars]
-[screaming]
Hang on!
I speak a little dragonfly.
[whistles]
[speaking Dragonfly]
-All right, hop on.
-My man!
[grunting]
-[speaking Dragonfly]
-What do you mean, "Not her"?
Uh, Dave!
[sniffs, growls]
[speaking Dragonfly]
[Dave] He says he'll do it.
[yelling]
Guys, what's faster,
a bunny or a frog?
Burrow girl!
There's only one way to shake him!
Time to put your money
where your mouth is, bug boy.
[both] Skyscraper Ridge.
-King of Pop?
-No. Old-school hip-hop.
Wait, I've got the perfect song.
[music playing]
See, this right here is why
you need experienced guides, OK?
-We'll take the Eastern Spur.
-We'll take the North Summit!
-Eastern Spur?
-North Summit?
Uh, guys...
[all screaming]
Burrow girl!
Go left!
Go right!
OK, go right again!
Go up! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go up, go up, go up!
Right! Left! Uh, up!
How is he still on our tail?!
[grunting]
[yells]
Incoming!
[all screaming]
We're close to it, aren't we?
Your home?
Ahh, I can already tell from your face.
So, let's make this easy.
Just point me in the direction.
OK, I'll sweeten the offer.
You go free, and your people
never learn it was you who betrayed them.
[laughs]
You need to do some soul searching.
Huh?
[stammers]
What?
[screaming]
[Kipo screaming]
Whoo-hoo!
That was cold, Kipo. Respect!
Don't wrinkle the suit!
[screams]
[grunts]
[grunting]
That probably would've been helpful,
like, five minutes ago.
Anyone need a jar opened?
I got you covered.
Just so you know,
no one in my burrow
has ever seen a mute before...
besides a giant worm.
[snorts]
But they'll get used to you pretty quick.
[chuckles] Wait a minute.
You're inviting us down there?
Yeah. Don't you wanna come?
You always have a warm meal.
You don't have to sleep
with one eye open.
-Sign us up!
-Bye-bye, surface! I won't miss you!
[Kipo] Everyone's probably still
cleaning up from the attack.
Wait till I tell my father
about the mutes we saw!
Where are you going?!
I promised to get you home.
I never said I'd be your roommate.
So, you're just gonna leave?
I'm a lone wolf!
Uh...
[groans]
Come on. We're almost home.
[panting]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[sighs]
Kipo, I'm really sorry.
[grunts]
[squeals]
Man, I knew this was too good to be true.
Uh, I see a lot of broken stuff,
but no signs of any people.
[gasps]
No signs of any people.
Are you sure you didn't live alone, Kipo?
I will not judge, OK?
[Kipo grunts]
I feel like we should follow her.
-[beeping]
-[door whirs]
Benson, you rule.
Oh, wh... what'd I do?
No people.
Not even in the bunker.
That's where we're supposed to hide
if things ever get really bad.
If no one's there, they got away.
My father, my friends...
they got away somewhere.
And if they're somewhere...
I can find them.
[Wolf] You're going to need help.
I thought you were a lone wolf.
I'm home now.
You did your job.
You're not home.
My job's not over yet.
We'll help you, too, Kipo.
We got your back.
Totally!
What should we do it for, Dave?
-[squealing]
-Ow, ow, ow! OK, we'll do it...
for, like, food.
-[snorting]
-OK, OK, for free, for free.
Pig, you need to be pet.
Come here. Let me give you some love.
[squealing]
[grunts]
[all laughing]
-Let go or lose the arm.
-Yes, ma'am.
You want me to pet you.
You want this love, admit it.
-[squealing]
-[all laughing]
-She likes you, Dave.
-[metal clanging]
Huh?
Uh, guys?