[squeals]
[yelling]
[squawking]
[grunts]
-[squawking]
-[grunting]
We're going after them.
[grunts]
Whoa!
Come on! Don't be such a meanie!
[panting] There you go.
Aren't you a little sweetie--
Oh!
-[growls]
-Nope. Just slightly less mean.
That thing's our only way to Scarlemagne.
If it comes down to it,
I'm willing to let it eat Dave.
What's that now?
Ew, Mandu!
You don't know where that Dave has been.
Climb on! The flamingo's fine!
[squawks]
Might want to hurry!
Come on!
[straining]
Gotcha!
Yes! Finally!
Everybody good?
-[both] Yeah.
-Ready to find Scarlemagne?
[both] Yeah!
Uh, what about them?
Uh...
[squawks]
-[woman] Where are we?
-[man] What do they want with us?
-Where are our children?
-Ask Lio!
His daughter led them right to us!
This is Kipo's fault!
No, this is my fault.
The mute who took us,
he has it out for me.
What?
[coughing]
[sighs]
-[gasps]
-[Scarlemagne] Uh-uh-uh...
Not him.
Hugo... I mean, Scarlemagne!
This is between you and me, let them go.
[laughs]
It is between you and me.
And that's precisely
why I won't let them go.
What are you going to do with them?
So much, dear Lio.
So much.
Kipo?
What happened to your arm?
Oh, long story.
I'm part mute.
Actually, that's all
I know about the story.
Were you about to go after the mute
who took everyone?
-I want in.
-It's too dangerous.
[both groaning]
Ha! This is normal for the surface.
You'll get used to it.
[squeals]
[grunting]
I got it! Wolf, you and Benson
can take them to the Timbercats.
I'll take Dave with me.
We'll leave a trail of Dave
for Mandu to follow.
That way you can find us!
You can't just charge into Scarlemagne's
and demand your people back!
Uh, hello, Superpaw!
Do you not see Superpaw?
[yelps, grunts]
You don't even have a plan!
Please, Wolf, I'm going with my gut here.
I need you to trust me.
-OK.
-Yes!
-I'm gonna get everyone back.
-[squawks]
I promise!
[squawks]
Wait! What makes you think
the Timbercats will take them?
[Kipo] Because they're my friends!
OK!
[laughs nervously]
There's no way the Timbercats
are gonna babysit some human kids, right?
[laughs nervously]
No way.
But Kipo asked us to do it.
Maybe we should give them
some Timbercat lessons first?
That is... actually kind of
what I was thinking, too.
[squawks]
I bet we're getting close.
-[squawks]
-Ready to kick Scarlemagne's butt?
Aw, yeah. I'mma kick his butt so hard
he's gonna be like, "Where'd my butt go?"
-And h-- [gasps]
[screaming]
[screams]
[grunts]
[beeping]
[roaring]
Whoa!
Isn't that Scarlemagne's pet Mega Monkey?
He's forcing it to guard his hideout!
-[panting]
-Hey! Over here, this way!
Look at me! It's me. Remember?
♪ We may not have sunshine
Or starlight or weather ♪
[screams]
Come on. Listen!
♪ We've got each other
And that's even better ♪
[roars]
[grunts]
♪ You don't need the sun to keep you warm
When you've got arms ♪
-[grunts]
-Kipo!
As soon as I tame this thing
I'm gonna come save you!
-[squawks]
-[screams] You're on your own!
♪ Wishes come from you
And not a random shooting star ♪
[panting, screaming]
[growling]
♪ We may not have storm clouds ♪
♪ But the sky's always blue ♪
[growling]
[calm breathing]
[laughs]
-[collar beeping]
-[gasps]
[groans]
Don't worry. I got you.
-[beeping continues]
-[grunts]
[groans]
[grunts]
Yes, you're free!
[grunting]
Aww.
[laughs]
I guess we're both a little furry.
[grunting]
You want me to go with you?
[grunts]
Aww, that's sweet.
[squawking]
But I can't.
We're on a mission.
[grunting]
You can't come with me.
I'm going to Scarlemagne's.
If you come, he'll be able
to use you as a weapon again.
-[sighs]
-Aww, don't be sad.
I have to go but...
Here, a little something
so you know we'll always be friends.
[Kipo chuckles]
That... was... touching.
Wow, I got chills.
If I could give my heart
a tissue right now, I would.
[Mega Monkey whimpering]
Dave, is it just me or is that
Mega Monkey, I don't know, special?
Definitely, most Mega's are big
and stupid. Dumb as a bag a rocks.
I'm coming for you, Scarlemagne.
Because of what you did to her
and because of all the other
bad stuff you've done.
[barking]
[snoring]
The only way the Timbercats will
protect you is if they respect you.
And they'll respect anyone
who can wrangle Pierre.
Wait, you want us to do it?
It'll be fine.
We just gotta lure him in
with his favorite dessert.
[both shuddering]
Maple syrup.
Phew, for a second there,
I thought you meant we were the dessert.
[grunting]
[squealing]
-[both screaming]
-Hey!
Whoa!
[whimpers]
Oh, oh, OK.
That's enough. That's enough.
You're doing great.
Now leash him.
Uh, sorry, but you do not wanna get
between Pierre and syrup, so...
Bold approach. Good call!
Thanks.
We're not a terrible team after all.
-[squawks]
-[Kipo] Whoa! Slow down.
[both] Ah! Tree, tree, tree!
[screams]
-[Kipo] Whoa!
-[Dave grunting]
All right, Scarlemagne!
Give me back my people or I'm going to
introduce your face to my fist!
[whispering] Where is everyone?
[squawking]
He's back.
OK, time for your next lesson.
[grunting]
[Benson] Wolf's right.
We can't send you to the Timbercats
without any wood-chopping skills.
Now chop!
-Decent.
-But your showmanship gets an A.
[grunts]
Not bad?
[grunting]
You... stupid... piece... of... wood.
[grunting continues]
Give her a minute.
It's been a day.
I... I think she needs this.
[grunting]
[gasps]
Dad?
[grunts]
-Kipo?
-[grunting]
No!
-No!
-[coughs]
[groans] That stinks.
Wha... Why isn't this working?
[grunting]
Uh, why is her hand a paw?
[grunts]
[growls]
[Kipo grunts]
Dad!
[sighs]
Aww...
-[Dave] Feels like it should.
-We totally took those guys out!
They never stood a chance!
Not against Captain Jaguar
and Mr. Gorgeous.
I'm working on our names still.
You got lucky.
You were very brave...
but very lucky.
[Mandu chewing]
Be honest. We don't stand a chance
with these Timbercats, do we?
What? No...
I mean, you do! It's just--
Outside of us, humans and mutes
usually do not go together.
[squealing]
[whispering] Stop.
[groans]
Well, how did you and Dave
become friends?
We bonded over food.
[gasps]
That's it! Flapjacks!
-Flapjacks?
-Yup. Timbercats love them.
Lucky for you,
I have the best recipe in the world.
Does your recipe
have flour, milk, and eggs?
Yes!
Do you mix it all together in a bowl?
-That's my favorite way to mix it!
-Me too! But the secret...
[both] Is in the flip!
[both chuckle]
Ah, we both like flapjacks.
[Wolf clears throat]
[both giggling]
They're ready for the Timbercats.
Let's hope it's enough.
-[crowd screaming]
-Attention Ratland patrons:
Please remain calm
and find the nearest exit.
[whispering]
Especially if you're a human.
Thank you!
Merci beaucoup.
[maniacal laughter]
[squawks]
Scarlemagne, you didn't pay
the entrance fee.
[Scarlemagne howling]
And I never will!
Because I don't pay to commingle
with human filth.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'll just take
whatever I please for my new empire.
-What empire?
-So glad you asked!
You see, I have a vision, to transform
the ruins of a failed society into this...
[vocalizing]
Lovely, isn't it?
I call it, Aurum.
♪ A golden city of dreams! ♪
Where mutes will unite and reign supreme.
♪ Reign supreme ♪
Under me, of course.
-Reign supreme over what?
-Humans.
The vermin you are so fond of
granting safe haven to.
A city like this will require
a lot of blood, sweat, and tears.
I'll do the sweat.
Humans will do the blood and tears.
[horn honks]
[clattering]
You're ruining our park!
[Scarlemagne] Unfortunately, in order
to create, one must first destroy.
[squawks]
[crowd meowing]
[shrieks]
[laughing]
-[meows]
-[hisses]
Pierre! You've returned!
[growls]
He's acting strange.
What have you done to him?
[grunts]
Nothing, Mr. Hammerpaw, sir.
He just made a new friend.
With this human?
[laughs nervously] Yumyan Hammerpaw,
meet Troy, Dahlia, and Asher.
We were actually wondering
if they could stay with you for a while.
They're not even useless.
Dahlia can use an axe.
Asher can help take care of Pierre.
And Troy makes amazing flapjacks.
-[all booing]
-[cat 1] Never again!
[cat 2] Dusty was never the same!
This time no hairballs.
We promise.
Look, we know this is a lot to ask
but they have a Timbercat's courage.
These kids lost everything.
They were from Kipo's burrow
and Scarlemagne destroyed their home
and took their parents.
They've never even
been to the surface before today.
But they didn't melt down
into a puddle of tears.
-They--
-[crying] They're so brave!
Whether they live like Timbercats or not,
we will happily take care of
Boy, Talia, and Dasher.
Uh, that's not their...
Wait, really?
Of course. We would have done it
just because they're friends of Kipo.
Thank you.
We'll come back for them
as soon as we rescue their parents.
We promise to keep them safe!
[sniffles]
Good luck.
Scarlemagne isn't an easy foe to defeat.
We know.
He has a mind controlled human army now.
You might want to have your axes on guard.
We always do.
[meowing]
But now we'll have our backup axes
on guard as well.
-Thanks... for everything.
-No prob.
And when we get back, you and I are gonna
talk flapjacks versus pancakes.
Different or the same?
-Uh...
-[both] The same?
Guess we'll have to find
something else to talk about.
It's a date.
Be careful out there.
Aw, come here, you guys!
[laughs]
Yumyan hugs you all!
[squeals]
[Kipo] What do we do next?
I'm basically invincible.
You're not.
And you need to be careful.
There's something I need to tell you.
I should've told you a long time ago.
Tell me what?
Your mother and I,
we infused your DNA with a mutagen
so you could become a Mega.
That's why Scarlemagne's pheromone
doesn't work on you.
It only works on primates
and you are more than human.
You'll become a Mega Jaguar.
What?
I... I'm going to be a Mega Jaguar?
Because you and mom infused my DNA?
That is... so cool!
[gasps] Tell me how to do it!
I mean, then I can get us out of here!
We could ride Kipo to safety!
You're not ready yet.
Before I lost your mom, we learned
that if it's not done properly,
you could get lost in the transformation
and never come back.
As soon as we get out of here,
I'm going to take you
to the Chevre Sisters.
They can help train you to control this.
[gasps] Hero training!
Wait, who are the Chevre Sisters?
[squawking]
There goes our ride.
Up there!
We can climb out!
Or, I can get our ride back.
Kipo, no!
Step away from the flamingo
and no one gets hurt!
[roaring]
This is not the training
I was talking about!
[straining]
I did it again!
[grunts]
[yells]
[roaring]
Dad! No!
[grunts]
We're not leaving you!
Get her out of here!
-[roars]
-Dave, don't listen to him!
-Dad!
-You know where to go!
Dad! No!
[gasping]
Your contributions to Aurum
are much appreciated.
Oh, and one more thing.
[squawks]
Humans had their chance.
They ran the world into the ground
when they were on top!
And they've been oppressing mutes
and animal kind for thousands of years!
[wheezing]
Boo yourselves.
-Boo, humans!
-They're the worst!
As for you two,
turning your backs on fellow mutes
to provide humans with a safe zone?
That, I cannot abide.
You will serve as an example
to any mute who disobeys me.
Is that explosive nectar?
I'd run if I were you.
Mandu, can you at least pretend like
you're not enjoying it so much?
[squeals]
Look out!
-[gasps]
-[grunts]
[buzzing]
What happened back there?
I just charged in there
with my stupid paw.
I was so sure I could get everybody out,
and I barely got out myself.
My dad wants me to become a Mega Jaguar
and save everyone.
How can I do that when it seems like
every instinct I have is wrong?
That's not true.
You were right about the Timbercats.
They took in Troy, Dahlia, and Asher.
No questions asked.
[Benson] Your friends are safe
because you made the right call there.
[Dave] And freeing the Mega Monkey?
You didn't have to do that.
But you did.
[Mega Monkey sighs]
[Dave] And it was the right thing to do.
-Thanks, guys.
-[Benson] No prob.
Now, what's this you were saying
about turning into a Mega Jaguar?
[rumbling]
[squawking]
[Benson] Ratland.
Those are my people.
We have to stop him.