[snoring]
[squeals]
Get back here, you little thief!
Do you have any idea how hard it is
to find chocolate around here?
[grunts, groans]
Stop!
[grunts]
That is Deathstalker territory.
[scoffs]
She's as good as gone.
And so is that chocolate.
[panting]
-[clattering]
-Huh? [gasps]
[gasps]
[heart beating]
[yelps, pants]
[grunts]
[hissing]
[heart beating fast]
-[breathes deeply]
-[heart beat slows]
[grunts]
[yells]
[squawking]
The fastest way to
your parents' old burrow is through there.
Deathstalker territory.
Death makes anything
instantly more scary.
"Death Dave."
Uh, having the word "Dave" in anything
makes it instantly less scary.
Deathstalkers don't hunt you
by sight or smell,
they track you through your heartbeats.
If your heart races,
you're as good as dinner.
-Got it?
-Got it.
-[squawking]
-[all yelp]
We're clear!
Go, go!
We could go through the mountains.
It'd be safer but it would
take a couple of days.
We don't have a couple of days!
You heard that Noble!
Scarlemagne is forcing
all the mutes in the city
to accept him as their emperor
at his coronation next week!
Who do you think he's going to use
to fight the ones that resist?
-Bears.
-No! My people.
We have to get to my parents' burrow
as fast as we can
so I can figure out who I am,
find an anchor, turn into a Mega Jaguar,
and save everyone before that coronation!
[panting]
[squawking]
-We have to lose those flamingos!
-She's right, we need a diversion.
I know what you're thinking.
Teacup Chop-Chop, or Scoot-n-Shoot?
No, we need something bigger.
-[gasps] The Flaming Phantom!
-Perfect!
Uh, what in the world
are you guys talking about?
We split up.
Dave and I create a diversion
to distract these flamingos.
-You get through Deathstalker territory.
-We'll catch up with you later.
-I'm not sure.
-[chuckles] We got this!
Benson and I have lived through
some bad things.
Kipo, they're right.
It will be impossible to calm down
while being chased
by scorpions and flamingos.
Splitting up is the fastest way
that doesn't definitely get us all killed.
OK, but be careful.
Ooh!
Do you still have that can of cheese?
-Indeed I do, my friend!
-We'll use Mandu for the mustache!
[squeals]
-When you see an explosion--
-Two! Flaming Phantoms is two!
Sorry! Two explosions,
that means you're good to go.
Hey, flamingos!
Over here!
-[squawking]
-[gasps]
I guess that's our cue.
[chuckles]
The nectar bomb is ready,
your imperial majesty.
Ah-ah-ah, not yet.
I am not officially your emperor
until the coronation.
Until then you may refer to me as:
future imperial majesty,
whom I am vastly inferior to
for I am nothing
but lowly human gutter sludge.
Go ahead, refer to me that way.
-I-I can't remember all that.
-Of course, you can't.
You're lowly human gutter sludge.
Step back.
All of you, step back!
We're about to make some beautiful music.
Now where is my soprano?
I need my soprano!
Give us a high C, would you?
[clears throat]
[vocalizing]
[rumbling]
[laughs]
There was a time you humans waged
countless wars to attain wealth like this.
But for two centuries
they've been sitting here
like a useless pile of bricks.
Waiting for someone like me to take them.
Why?
Because I like shiny things.
Rescuing that many people
is gonna be tricky.
[Wolf] Kipo, about these scorpions.
It only takes one sting
to knock you out cold.
Then they drag you back to their lair
and prepare you for dinner.
Nothing is immune to their venom.
Not even a mega.
And with that, I'm gonna try and be calm.
Somehow.
I'm gonna look at my hands.
My calm, calm hands.
-I am all serious.
-Well, your arm says otherwise.
[gasps]
Herbs in, herbs out.
OK, I got this, I just gotta be cool...
Inhale for four counts.
[inhales]
Exhale for eight.
[exhales]
That's how I keep my heart rate down.
In for four... [inhales]
Out for eight... [exhales],
-Keep your cool... now you're great.
-Everything OK?
[chuckles]
Oh, yeah. I'm rhyme timing.
In for four, out for eight,
keep your cool, now you're...
almost but not really,
hardly at all, great.
This is kinda intense, huh?
[gasps]
[heart beating fast]
[both breathe deeply]
[heart beat slows]
-[screeching]
-[gasps]
[screams]
[heart beating rapidly]
-Run!
-[grunts]
[whimpers]
I just have to say
it's taking everything I've got
to not mute out right now!
Herbs in, herbs out!
Phew.
[panting]
[screeching]
Uh...
Careful, there's a loose rung.
Whoa!
How did you know about that?
[strains]
Because this used to be my home.
-Wipe your feet before you come in.
-Wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You had a home before?
How come I never knew?
Don't get excited.
It's just a random place I found.
Not getting excited...
[gasps]
...by this magical place
we should totally make
into our forever hideout!
-Sorry.
-OK, I get that slowing down
your heartbeat to a normal person level
will be tough for you.
But you can't make it a game.
To get out of here alive,
you need to be serious.
Ah! This is where you slept!
Your bed is made up of inflatable guitars!
-You had a teddy bear?
-That's a head rest.
Oh, I can just imagine
little Wolf over here, all like,
"These aren't toys,
they're survival tools."
I've never said that.
But that is true.
I get it, this is a jump rope.
That's survival.
-Survival of the fitness!
-It's a hand-stopper.
-Why are you jumping in place with it?
-Hand-stopper?
[chuckles]
No way?!
What's a hand-stopper?
[grunting]
Awesome!
Ah!
I haven't seen these
since my fifth grade graduation party!
I was really scared to dance
so I played with these
the whole time instead.
But then I learned while I was playing,
really I was dancing.
-[laughs] What are you doing?
-I'm doing devil sticks, duh!
And dancing!
Oh, that's what the third
fighting stick was for.
Here, let me show you.
It's all in the wrists.
[grunting]
That is not what I was talking about!
You could do it with no problem
once you got the hang of it.
OK, so back to calming your heart rate--
-[gasps]
-[yelps]
[static rings]
This karaoke machine works!
Ooh. Sorry.
I'm sure you're about to tell me
your super-tough Wolfie name for this.
That is a Hoot-hoot.
-[giggles]
-Scorpions are afraid of owls.
I use the Hoot-hoot
to make owl sounds like this: Hoot! Hoot!
Aww.
Hoot-hoot?
I was five when I named it.
Now let's try to focus
so we can get out of this death trap.
Oh, come on.
Does it always have to be life or death?
Can't it be "have fun" for a minute?
No.
-Bah!
-[gasps]
-Try again.
-Come on!
-I was so close that time.
-Close doesn't cut it.
We've got to get you to be calm
in the eyes of danger
or else we're never gonna get out of--
Bah!
[screams]
OK, that time wasn't fair.
OK, OK.
Try again.
[breathes deeply]
Ah! Just "Bah!" me already!
-Kipo--
-I'm sorry!
We've been doing this
nonstop for over an hour
and I can't focus on focusing anymore!
-Kipo, it's important.
-I know it's important!
But what if I don't have it in me?
Everyone I care about is depending on me
to do something I've never done before,
and if I don't do it right even one time
I'm putting them all at risk,
including you guys.
And I can't stop thinking about it
long enough to focus on being calm!
So how am I ever going to control
the Mega Jaguar side of me?!
-OK, let's take a break.
-You mean it?
Thank you!
Ooh!
What song should we sing?
We?
No one said anything about we.
[exclaims]
They have one of my favorite songs!
-It's a duet so you have to sing.
-Pass.
OK, fine, if you'd rather sulk at the wall
on your break, that's on you.
Also, thank you for the break.
-[music plays]
-[grunts]
[exhales]
Here I go.
[clears throat]
♪ When the night is dark ♪
♪ And the outside's so cold ♪
Wolf!
♪ Heroes on fire ♪
Come on.
♪ I'm a child I knew
About a world so true ♪
♪ You should pull down the stars ♪
Wolf!
♪ I needed a hero
If I only knew that the hero was me ♪
♪ The hero was you, was you ♪
♪ Fear pulls me down
Reckless and hot ♪
♪ It tells me I'm nothing ♪
♪ When I know that I'm not! ♪
♪ Standing alone, in my fire! ♪
♪ You're not alone! ♪
♪ Future's hanging on a wire! ♪
Come on!
♪ Just take my hand! ♪
Take it!
Literally, come on! Take it!
♪ Standing alone, in my fire! ♪
♪ You're not alone! ♪
♪ Heroes on fire! ♪
♪ You and me, baby! ♪
Bah!
[whispers] In for four, out for eight,
keep your cool, now you're great.
I think we're ready.
Let's go to your parents' old burrow.
In for four... [inhale]
Out for eight... [exhale]
Keep your cool, now you're great.
Kipo, just, knock it off for a second.
I need to be able to focus.
It's OK, Wolf.
This is how I keep calm.
I'll do it silently.
[mumbling]
[Wolf gasps]
-[whispers] Kipo...
-I'm in a zone here.
[screeches]
Kipo!
Wolf?
[grunting]
[gasps]
What do I do?
What would Wolf do?
Hand-stoppers.
Fighting sticks.
Time to be serious.
Hoot-hoot!
[screeching]
[breathes deeply]
[upbeat music playing]
[grunting]
Wolf!
Uh-oh.
[grunting]
[panting]
I did it!
Really wish you were awake to see it.
-See what?
-Wolf!
Shh. What happened?
You got stung by a deathstalker
and I saved you! And--
[screeching]
Oh, no.
In for four... [inhales]
Out for eight... [exhales]
Keep your cool, now we're great.
[squawking]
[screeching]
[squawking
Lemieux, I see you're alone.
Why do you return to me empty-handed
when you know I'll feed you
to my flamingos for it?
I expected you to bring me
the one called Kipo.
We lost her trail.
But then we tried picking it up again,
and that's when we found that.
[squawking]
The Mega Monkey's collar.
It's gotten free!
I want the monkey!
We must find her immediately!
No.
He's going after the monkey.
We have to get to her first.
Kipo, you were amazing back there!
You learned all the stuff
I taught you so quickly!
Thanks.
I had a good teacher.
Sorry I wasn't focused before.
If I had been better at it,
maybe you wouldn't have been caught
in the first place.
Nope. I got myself caught,
I worried about you.
But you did it.
You were focused, calm, and cool.
[giggles]
I was, wasn't I?
And if you can
rescue me from deathstalkers,
then becoming a Mega Jaguar
and saving your people
should be easy as pie.
-You think so?
-No.
Me neither.
But at least I'm not alone.
OK, time to focus on
getting to my parents' burrow.
Nothing can stop us now.
[humming]
Wolfatha Christie the Fourth,
are you humming?
[groans]
It's that stupid song.
I can't get it out of my head.
You what?
How did it go?
I-I forget how it goes.
♪ When the night is dark
And the outside so cold ♪
♪ Heroes on fire ♪
-[Mandu squeals]
-Huh?
Whoa!
Did I hear Wolfie singing?
I know, right!
Wasn't it amazing?
Wait, what happened to you three?
[squeals]
Long story. Tell ya later.
But first...
♪ Fear pulls me down
Reckless and hot ♪
♪ It tells me I'm nothing
When I know that I'm not! ♪
Take it, Wolf!
♪ Standing alone in my fire ♪
♪ You're not alone! ♪
Whoo!
♪ Standing alone in my fire ♪
You guys, this is our song now.
♪ You're not alone ♪
[Dave] You're not alone, girl.
♪ Standing alone in my fire ♪
♪ You're not alone ♪
♪ Heroes on fire ♪