[snoring]
[squeals]
[grunts]
Hey, can you tell me what that says?
-[monkey chittering]
-[gasps]
[sighs]
[screeching]
[sighs] No response to formula 124.
Status report on the mandrill?
-[monkey screeching]
-No signs of mutation, yet.
We only have a few non-intelligent animals
from the old world left.
Increase the pace.
I want him on two, three formulas a day.
We will be the ones who learn
what made the animals mutate.
And then we will fix them.
Understood?
Guess I've gotta give you
some more formula, Hugo.
I'm sorry.
[monkey screeching]
It's OK.
Look, we got something for you.
[monkey screeching]
-Yeah, that's better.
-Formula 125.
-[slurps]
-One-hundred twenty-five.
Have a good feeling about this one.
Formula 3,853.
I've got a good feeling about this one.
Hoo-go.
-[gasps]
-Hu-go.
Hugo!
-[laughing]
-Hugo.
That's right.
That's your name!
You did it!
-Welcome to our world, Hugo.
-[laughing]
-I guess we should tell Emilia.
-Should we?
[Emilia] We'll reach Scarlemagne's palace
from the tunnels underneath.
This is where we'll lead the humans out
while Kipo fights off the Mega Monkey,
I'm pointing to no one.
Where's Kipo?
She's been asleep all day.
[chuckles]
Transforming into a giant jaguar
is pretty exhausting.
Fine, you can catch her up later.
Now, all we need
is someone to steal a nectar bomb
from under Scarlemagne's palace,
so we can blow the tunnels behind us.
We'll do it!
We're great at sneaking around.
Yeah.
We're small and fast!
And I'm very likeable.
Kipo said she would be back by now.
She definitely got captured.
Yeah, that's why
we're getting the nectar bomb.
-So we can find Kipo, and--
-Shh, shut up for a sec,
those nectar bombs are right under
Scarlemagne's palace!
[gasps]
We can break Kipo out,
then stop somewhere for dinner
on the way back!
-Emilia's none the wiser.
-Uh... Yeah, Dave.
Everything but the dinner part
was already the plan.
So, you're saying
I made the plan even better.
Hopefully, Mandu can keep Dr. Emilia
from getting suspicious.
[squeals]
Mmm...
Sorry, but this is really, really good!
Are you hurt?
Did you go to the goats?
I'm so glad you're here,
but what are you doing here?!
Don't worry, Dad.
I'm OK.
A lot has happened since I saw you.
Kipo Oak, I can't tell you
how long I've waited for this.
Just do what he asks.
It's gonna be all right.
Do you like your dress?
Tell me.
Wait, don't tell me!
OK, tell me.
So, uh, wait, you want me to tell you?
Desperately!
It's lovely.
And poofy.
To be honest, I thought I'd be locked
in a spooky dungeon eating dirt.
Don't give him any ideas.
[chuckles]
Please, you're no prisoner!
You're my guest of honor,
free to do as you please.
Eat, wander, relax,
but... no jaguar business.
Uh... OK.
Wonderful!
Now that we have all the nasties
out of the way, I must admit,
I had ulterior motives
for our little soiree.
Some mutes have been rather fixated
on the Burrow Girl.
The half-mute hero of Brunchington Beach,
who fought off the tyrant Scarlemagne.
[laughs] You can see
how that's bad for my image.
-[groans]
-So, tomorrow I want you
to stand by my side as I take the crown,
thus silencing any doubts
of the total authority of Scarlemagne.
But your name isn't Scarlemagne.
It's Hugo.
-What happened to you?
-Lio...
My own baby sister
and you never told her about us?
Well, tell her!
No, don't tell her.
I'll tell her.
"Which is why he would forever
be known as King Louis the Beloved."
Do kings still exist on the surface?
[chuckles]
No. Not... not for a long time.
Maybe I could be the king.
And I'll throw big parties
and wear beautiful habiliments.
That means clothes.
We could all live in my palace!
And go wherever we want,
with no walls to contain us!
[both] Shh.
Remember, buddy,
no one else can hear you talk.
It's too dangerous.
Things changed for us
the moment you spoke your name.
But we're afraid if she hears you,
she'll take you away from us.
[sighs]
Good night, King Hugo.
[slow tempo song plays]
♪ I'm not supposed to play the piano
When I'm all alone ♪
♪ Or sing along to melodies
All of my own ♪
♪ So, though I have perfect pitch
And a rather perfect ear ♪
♪ I'll never play a song
In case somebody else is near ♪
♪ Sure, yes, I'm rather bored
And could use some release ♪
♪ But it's hardly worth the risk ♪
♪ I think you'd easily agree ♪
♪ I could play a rocking solo ♪
♪ Yes, believe me I could shred ♪
♪ But I'm a careful lad ♪
♪ So, I'll just play it in my head ♪
[gasps]
[Scarlemagne] She'd seen me.
Dr. Emilia.
-Dr. Emilia?!
-Ah, ah, ah.
Don't interrupt, it's rude.
Didn't you teach her any manners?
As I was saying...
OK, OK. We... we were going to tell you
about our progress.
But... but...
but we had to confirm the results.
Yeah, I just watched a monkey
play a piano solo.
I think they're confirmed.
So, which formula held the mutagen?
-We don't know.
-Excuse me?!
You had us give him
three variations just today.
And who knows whether this was
a delayed effect or a reaction
-between two different formulas--
-Then I'll do it myself.
We're so close to turning these mutes
back into the animals they are.
Zane, take a sample.
Come here, monkey.
Stop, you're scaring him.
[grunts]
Oh...
[whimpering]
[Hugo] Stop it!
Um, let me go?
Please?
Zane?
What are you doing?
Mandrills have pheromones
that can influence other primates,
but the mutagen
must have heightened the effects.
Tell him something else.
Do it.
Do the waltz?
Incredible.
You two, stay here.
Don't let him out of your sight!
[door opens]
What you just did is remarkable!
-A little scary, but remarkable.
-Is it true?
You only gave me intelligence so you could
take it away from everyone else?
That's how it started.
But you showed us
we couldn't be a part of that anymore.
That's why we're going to
escape the burrow.
Let's leave right now.
-We... we can't.
-Yes, we can!
I can make them do
whatever I want with my pheromone.
I can make them pay
for being so mean to us...
I know you're angry, and I am too,
but forcing people to do things
against their will, that's wrong, Hugo.
As soon as the baby's born,
we're breaking you out of here.
We'll escape together.
I promise.
We only have a couple of minutes
before the guards are back.
Those nectar bombs are close.
I can feel it deep in my bug bones.
Dave, you better hold that thing tight.
One wrong move and this whole cave
-goes up like a firecrack--
-[footsteps approaching]
-[gasps]
-[whispering] Shh... Guard, hide!
Close one.
Now, let's rescue Kipo.
-Wait, where's the bomb?
-I panicked.
You guys were leaping behind crates
like majestic gazelles,
and I didn't want them to see that
I had the nectar bomb, so, I kinda ate it.
Oh, Dave.
Oh, no.
[belches]
[gasps]
[Emilia] I expected the mutation
to affect his size,
his intelligence, sure.
But, to manifest a power like this?
[panting, grunts]
It's an incredible discovery.
You can't lock him in a cage!
He's a person!
He's an animal, Lio.
The future of the human race
is on the line.
So, think like a scientist
and stop getting so attached.
I trust you won't need
any more convincing.
It's OK. It's just a little longer
until the baby comes.
I promise.
[hip-hop music playing]
-[rumbling]
-[gasps]
[alarm blaring]
Hello?
[animals growling]
What's happening?!
Hello?
-[yelling]
-[glass shattering]
[grunts]
[panting]
Oh.
[roaring]
It wasn't you?
Dr. Emilia was controlling my mom?!
Wait, that massive monkey is Song?
She's alive?
I knew there was something different
about that Mega Monkey.
Song's pregnancy had side effects.
And with your pheromone,
Dr. Emilia turned her into a weapon.
I spent months tracking them,
and I tried to get her back,
-but she's gone.
-No, Dad, she's not!
She knew who I was.
What? Uh... Are you sure?
[laughs]
You failed her, and now I have her.
-Oh, that is so us.
-My parents raised you.
They named you.
They... they loved you.
-How could you hate them so much?
-I was a child, on my own.
Thrown into a world a billion times larger
than anything I'd ever known.
Do you have any idea what that's like?
Actually, yes.
I know how scary it must have been alone.
You have no idea what it was like.
[groans]
[panting]
[rumbling]
[squawking]
[panting]
[screams]
[rumbling]
[squawking]
[growling]
Oh!
It's a palace!
[rock music playing]
They're just like me.
Well, kind of.
-[piano playing]
-[rock music stops]
Um, hello, chaps.
The name's Hugo,
and I have wonderful news.
You are my first friends on the surface!
What are you doing in our dark food court?
This is my domain.
[sniffs]
You smell like a human.
Oh, gross.
Humans are disgusting.
-They are not!
-You're a weirdo, aren't you?
-Seems a bit harsh.
-OK, tell you what,
I'll give you a chance
to prove your worth in battle.
Hm... Please, say it's a battle of wits.
[rock music playing]
-[grunts]
-[groans]
[both grunting]
Oh, you're very strong.
Good for you.
Should I finish him?
[chuckles]
Go for it.
[grunts]
[Hugo, voice echoing]
You're going to lose the fight.
[grunts]
[grunting]
-[groans]
-[laughs] Yeah!
C'mon, Porcelaine!
You can do it, just get him!
[grunts]
[groans]
[panting]
[laughs]
Not bad! All right, you're in.
OK, Dave. Easy does it.
One step at a time.
[stomach rumbling]
[gasps]
No!
Go without me.
I'll never make it.
-We would never.
-Yeah, you have the bomb.
But what if I explode?
Everyone but me would die!
And I'll be bummed out
for a really long time!
Scarlemagne's palace is guarded
by a thousand mind-controlled humans.
It's gonna take all of us
to break Kipo out.
I know you can do it.
I believe.
What about Wolf?
Do you believe in me
just as much as Benson?
-Uh... uh... yep.
-You paused!
Just please don't blow us up.
Whoa, everyone's counting on me.
Oh, almost there.
I did it!
[exhales]
[gasps]
No!
[laughing]
He's just, like, trying so hard.
-It's sad, it's, like, so weird.
-I know, right?
Hey, hey, quiet down.
We're here.
They're distracted.
Let's loot that observatory.
Oh, we're stealing?
Yeah, that's how it works up here.
You stick with your kind
and take what you need from everyone else.
[all growling]
[Lio]
Stay back! Stay away!
Everybody, cool it!
[sniffing]
Smells like fresh meat.
It's those goth apes!
C'mon, let's get 'em!
Oh snap, run!
[wolves howling]
Lio. Lio!
Hugo?
I thought you were...
Oh, Hugo.
I can't tell you
how good it is to see you.
Where's Song?
When the burrow fell...
we barely made it out.
[cooing]
Is that my blanket?
-Hugo, I--
-You promised we would all leave together.
Did you even try to save me?
Did you at least return,
to see if I'd survived the collapse?
-[crying]
-It all happened so fast.
Emilia came for the baby.
We had to run.
Hugo, we've been running ever since.
But you made it out,
and now we are together!
You, me... and this is Kipo.
You didn't even look.
May I... hold her?
I don't think...
-[crying]
-Let me hold her!
[both grunting]
[Kipo crying]
I'm sorry.
[laughing]
[grunts]
[panting]
Hugo, where'd you go?
You missed...
[grunts]
You're no longer the leader of this pack.
You're a subject.
My subject.
You know, I was once told
that forcing someone
to act against their will is wrong.
But, you know what I think is wrong?
Ignoring that which makes you superior.
The surface shall have kings once more.
-And the world will bow before--
-Hugo?
No...
Scarlemagne!
[laughing]
So, you see, Kipo?
All of this really began
with your father... with our father.
Dad, how could you leave him?
I had to make a choice.
And I chose you.
-I am so sorry, Hugo--
-Don't you dare call me that!
-Take him away!
-[gasps]
What?
What are you doing?
-I'm hugging you.
-Why?
Because you need it.
Man, that was tense.
[stomach rumbling]
Dave, what was that?
OK, it is possible that this
explosive nectar is upsetting my stomach.
[gasps]
Run!
Dave, no!
Stop following us!
Oh, oops!
My bad.
Take cover!
[explosion]
[sneezes]
Oh, I think I'm allergic to this stuff.
Bless you.
What are you nerds waiting for?
Scarlemagne's palace is this way.
[sneezes]
Dad?
He's right.
All of this is my fault.
-You must hate me.
-Of course not.
-No more secrets?
-No more secrets.
[explosion]
[all coughing]
Are you sure
that was only one drop of nectar?
Whoa, that stuff was inside me.
Let's find the secret prison
and blow the doors off the place.
Found her.
Hey.
[music playing]