[snoring]
[squeals]
[grunting]
Hi, Mom.
[snorts]
It's really you, isn't it?
[gasps]
[coos]
You look like you need this.
Let's get you out of here.
-[screams]
-[roaring]
[grunting]
[giggling]
[slurps]
[belches]
[screeching]
[groans]
[gasps]
Hi, there.
[screams]
I'm Mulholland.
I just freed you from mind control.
[stutters]
Wow.
You haven't talked in a while, huh?
I'm here to be your new brain roomie
and keep those pesky pheromones away.
How do you like your mindscape?
Kipo picked it out.
You... you know my daughter?
Yes.
Oh, Kipo sure is a special one,
and she needs your help.
Guess that means I'm a helper, too.
Cool.
Can you tell her...
tell her Mom loves her?
[sniffles]
[crowd chanting]
Scarlemagne! Scarlemagne! Scarlemagne!
[coughing]
[gasps]
Huh?
[both gasping and coughing]
-Did you stow away back there?
-Hi.
How did you not feel them?
And, I retract.
[all coughing]
[gasps]
Dad.
I really wish you hadn't done that.
Well, you're not in a position
to make demands, are you?
Let the games begin!
[crowd cheering]
Chip chop. Get along.
I command you to take up arms!
Why isn't it working?!
Song, attack her!
[grunting]
[groans]
What have you done?
Bum, bum, bum!
The night I snuck in to see my mom...
I called in a favor from a friend.
Da-da-da!
When no one was looking,
I poured Mulholland
into your vat of pheromone.
Boom!
You can't control the humans!
Or my mom!
Dah, should've boomed at the end.
[growls]
You think your parlor trick
will ruin my day?
This stops nothing!
[rumbling]
Huh?
[grunts]
[groans]
Now, time for
Operation Ave-say Umans-hay!
[whispers]
Save the humans.
[grunting]
[gasps]
Everyone, climb inside, now!
Does that thing really expect us
to trust it after it destroyed our home?!
Fine.
You can stay here.
But for everyone else that
wants their freedom, get in!
Snap him out of it, Mulholland!
Oh. Real quick, your mom wanted me
to tell you that she loves you.
Aww.
Wait, she actually talked to you?
Do you think we can get her out of there?
Oh...
she's been a Mega Monkey for a long time,
and it did a number on her.
I think she's stuck.
Are you sure you want to go Mega?
Oh, I have an anchor.
Don't worry about me.
Then back in mouth I go!
[giggles]
[grunts]
[grunting]
Everyone, sit down!
The coronation will proceed on schedule.
Gerard! Lemieux!
Stop her!
[squawking]
[roaring]
[grunting]
Everyone inside, let's go!
Just pretend like you're cereal.
Actually, that sounds like
the monkey's gonna eat you. Never mind.
Mandu, make sure
they get to the tunnels safely.
-They need you.
-[squeals]
[squawks]
Sorry, kids.
You're not on the list.
Oh, yeah?
Well, check it again.
Under the names Claw, The Hammer,
Slamson, and Little Poundcake.
Guess it's a fight.
Give it to 'em, Wolf!
-[squawks]
-[grunts]
[screams]
[grunts]
Hey, big eyes, over here!
[squawking]
[grunting]
This is usually the part
where I'd introduce you to Stalky.
[screams]
[squawks]
Ah!
[grunting]
Dave!
I need your ha-ha-help!
[grunting]
Why are you saying "help" weird?
Because I've never said it before.
-[squawks]
-[yelling]
Wha... hey!
Gerard, meet Lil' Poundcake.
[grunts]
[laughs]
[grunting]
[roars]
[grunts]
Time for one more gold statue.
[grunting]
Dad!
[yelling]
All right!
Whoo-hoo!
[gasps]
Uh, guys?
I'm gonna be a trophy in a few seconds.
[grunts]
[yelling]
No!
The anchor!
[all gasp]
It's gone.
The anchor's gone!
[Kipo grunting
[panting]
Get ready to meet the jaguar!
Don't do it, Kipo!
You'll be stuck!
I... [panting]
I lost your anchor!
Oh...
I'll assume that's something
you really, really need.
[growling]
[man] We've got to get out of here!
[roaring]
[squealing]
Is that Kipo's pig?
She says, this way.
[grunting]
What a predicament.
To save your precious humans,
you have to become a mute,
one of us, forever.
Why does it have to be a choice?
If humans and mutes worked together,
the surface would be a better place.
Sounds lovely.
Tick-tock, Kipo. What'll it be?
She won't need to be
the jaguar to fight you.
[grunting]
Get em', Little Poundcake!
Ha!
[grunts]
Wolf, come on!
[grunting]
I really miss Stalky right now!
Aw, what happened to Stalky?
[grunting]
[yells]
You know what. Tell me after!
[grunting]
Enough, Hugo!
[grunts]
[groaning]
[growls]
Careful, now.
No anchor...
[laughs]
[grunts]
[grunting]
Uh, should we...
should we do something?
Nah.
We have to help them.
Timbercats!
Yeah, I was just about to say that.
-Yumyan owns you!
-To Kipo!
[all yelling]
[battle cry]
Oh, must we go on
with this ridiculous game?
-Just give up.
-[Wolf] Give up?
You must not know us very well.
Put... down... my... crown.
No problem.
[gasps]
[Scarlemagne]
You've taken everything from me!
Is this what you were planning all along?
-Were you only pretending to care?
-What? No!
I only for real care!
That's why I was hoping
you'd do the right thing.
You still can.
I built a kingdom
from the ashes of humanity.
[grunting]
One way or another,
you all will be a part of it!
[all grunting]
[grunts]
Au revoir, Kipo!
[whistles]
[squawks]
We've got to get to higher ground.
Take my ax.
[explosion]
[yelling]
[gasps]
[slow-tempo music plays]
♪ Can it be true? ♪
♪ I think I'm falling in love with you ♪
Oh, hey, Troy!
Funny seeing... ha... you here.
I just grabbed this ax,
didn't expect you
to be on the other end of it.
[chuckles]
What a coincidence.
Um, you look... you... you look,
yeah... you really fit in!
[chuckles]
With these, uh, cats?
[gasps]
[all screaming]
I'm not leaving him!
I can't do that again.
[grunts]
[coos]
[groaning]
[screams]
How are we gonna
get everyone out of here?
We can't save everyone.
But the Mega Jaguar can.
What are you talking about?
Kipo--
If I turn Mega, I can knock that tree over
and stop the gold from rising any higher.
But we don't have your anchor.
You won't be able to come back.
Kipo, you'll be a jaguar
for the rest of your life.
Please.
I can't lose you, too.
[roaring]
I didn't think it would end this way.
Uh, yeah.
I don't think anyone did.
Timbercats, it's been an honor.
[grunting]
[all screaming]
[growling]
[shrieking]
Kipo!
[roars]
[gasps]
[growling]
[roars]
[all cheering]
[growling]
[roars]
She's trying to turn back.
She can't.
[roars]
Wait!
I'm a friend.
And I'm here to tell you,
it is time for us
to stop running like scared mice.
We've been led to believe
our only option is living underground,
but there is another way.
[moaning]
Isn't there another way to turn her back?
Mutes need to be saved from themselves.
Cured! Fixed!
And I know how to turn them back.
Mutes destroy everything.
And for what?
Today is just the latest example.
And if humans don't intervene,
it won't be the last.
Join me, and you'll never be afraid again.
[growling]
[Lio] Kipo, look at me.
It's gonna be OK.
You know why?
Because we're still a family.
We'll still look at the stars together.
We'll still sing.
Kipo, we're so sorry.
This is all our fault.
So, that's it?
[Wolf] No.
Kipo doesn't know the meaning of the word
"impossible..." and neither should we.
We might not have your anchor
to remind you who you are,
but I know who you are.
We've forgotten who we are...
what we are!
We're humans! And when we were on top,
the surface thrived.
[all cheering]
[Wolf] You're the friend
who fights for what's right,
who accepts everyone for who they are
and brings out the best in them.
Even me.
You taught me that change can be good.
I mean, you showed me how to have fun!
You even taught me how to sing.
♪ When the night is dark ♪
♪ And the outside's so cold ♪
-♪ Heroes on fire ♪
-[moans]
♪ I needed a hero ♪
♪ If I only knew that the hero was me ♪
[all]
♪ That the hero was you, was you ♪
♪ Fear pulls me down ♪
♪ Reckless and hot ♪
♪ It tells me I'm nothing ♪
♪ When I know that I'm not ♪
[growling]
[exhales]
[yells]
[growls]
[sighs]
[yells]
[voices echoing]
♪ Standing alone in the fire! ♪
♪ You're not alone! ♪
[no dialogue]
[growling]
♪ Standing alone in the fire ♪
♪ You're not alone ♪
[growls]
Miss me?
[all gasp]
[sighs]
OK, because that was super scary!
Am I right?
Wait, am I the only one who's confused?
What was that anchor stuff all about?
We spent a lot of time on that!
We're the anchor, Dave.
[gasps] We're the anchor!
Aw... I like that.
That's cute.
-We did it, Mom.
-[sighs]
Together.
And if I can turn back, so can you.
We'll figure this out.
[coos]
Are you sure you're OK with all of us
coming back to Timbercat Village?
Anything for you, Kipo,
Summoner of Mega Jaguar.
[chuckles]
Always knew you had cat in ya.
Thanks, Yumyan.
[Scarlemagne] You could've escaped.
But you were willing to get
stuck in the jaguar...
for a colosseum full of mutes?
You were right.
It doesn't mean it doesn't hurt.
[Troy gasps] Dad!
Uh-oh.
-Where's everyone else?
-Ho, boy.
Dr. Emilia intercepted us in the tunnels.
She convinced them all to follow her.
She has some research notebook,
and she says she can reverse the mutation.
If Emilia has that, she'll end all mutes.
We're gonna stop her.
And we're gonna do it, together.
[roars]