[snoring]
[squeals]
-[Mandu snorting, squeals]
-Huh!
[thuds]
[snorts, purrs]
[pop music playing]
[scream]
[cheers]
[crowd cheers wildly]
[in Korean]
♪ Wherever you go ♪
[in English]
♪ You know I'll always be there ♪
[in Korean]
♪ I can go to your dream harbor ♪
♪ Oh, I will ride your waves
To go to you ♪
♪ So with me our sea can breathe
Forever ♪
[in English]
♪ With me ♪
[in Korean]
♪ Together wherever we go ♪
♪ Surf the ocean waves just you and me ♪
[in English] ♪ And you and I
Can go to places never known ♪
[in Korean]
♪ Ride the wave with me ♪
[in English]
♪ Dive into my ocean of love ♪
[in Korean]
♪ To the sea forever ♪
[in English]
♪ Dive into my ocean of love ♪
♪ You and me equals love in the sea ♪
[screams, cheers]
[Hyun-Soo]
♪ Dive into my ocean ♪
♪ Dive into my ohh ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ Ohh ♪
-[crowd cheers wildly]
-[fireworks explode]
[cheering continues]
[in Korean]
Thank you! Thank you!
We love you all!
[cheers fade]
Ugh! Oh, uh... [sighs]
[bubbling]
[muffled]
Let's try Serum Sixty-Seven.
[squirts]
[thunks]
[in Korean]
What do you want?
Ugh!
Still just a stupid mute.
[clatters]
Aww, didn't work again.
Frustrating, huh?
Shut up, mute.
-[slams]
-Ugh!
I can't figure this out!
Song solved for X.
What am I missing?
I think we're missing the barbecue.
[exasperated sigh]
Let's go.
I need a break, anyway.
And remember, Greta,
just because it fits in your mouth,
doesn't mean it's food.
[door closes, locks]
All right, kid, don't cry.
[in Korean]
I'm not crying.
I just have a sad face.
Don't worry, we're gonna get out of here.
Someone's coming for us.
[sighs]
[theme music playing]
[tiny footsteps]
[loud splash]
I cannot believe
Emilia had the nerve to come here
and steal not one,
but two friends!
-What about Boom-Boom?
-Two friends
and Boom-Boom.
We have to get them back,
and soon!
Emilia has the journal.
She could create the cure any day, now.
We bravely volunteer!
[cheers]
Well, she has the sonic emitter.
We bravely un-volunteer!
-[clunks]
-[meows]
All right, time to plan.
Dahlia, do you have our schematics?
[chops, grinds]
As you can clearly see,
this is the ocean.
Our target, Emilia, is somewhere in here.
We're gonna need
to fly over it to find them.
This is gonna be a stealth mission.
We need to get the journal
before she can create the cure,
-and rescue our friends.
-And Boom-Boom.
You know, I'd feel a lot safer
if you came,
considering we're so good
at saving each other.
That seems fair.
Yeah, Troy's cool.
He can totally join us.
Aw, sorry, Dave,
but remember the last time
you were around a sonic emitter?
You were like-- Aah!
[wailing]
No!
Ow!
Yeah, buddy,
[sighs]
it would be pretty hard to be stealthy
with you screaming in pain.
-You gonna be okay?
-No, no, it's fine.
[chuckles]
Me and Mandu, we--
have already started
playing hide-and-seek.
[chuckles]
That sneaky pig.
I'm gonna have so much fun
without you guys. [chuckles]
[sniffs, crying]
So, what exactly are we up against?
Emilia? Oh, boy!
Let me tell ya.
It all started when she enslaved my mom
with mind control...
and after all that,
our people still went with her!
[buzzes]
[rustling]
Ugh, sorry. I keep scaring our ride away.
I get why you're upset.
But, to be fair,
our people don't know any of that.
Guys, shh.
You're right, they don't.
Because she didn't tell them,
because she's a lying liar!
Yeah, and I made pancakes,
and she didn't even touch 'em.
-[shouting] And she killed Stalky!
-[buzzes]
Aw, man, that's the third time
we've scared them away.
I can't help it, she makes me so angry!
-Argh!
-[buzzes]
Look, we're all angry,
but we need to calm down
if we're going to get the journal
and rescue our friends.
Yeah, they could be cured any second.
We need something to keep us on track,
on mission, on stealth!
Ooh! Like a code word.
A code word? Okay.
How about "destroy the doctor"?
It's more of a phrase
and not very calming,
but we're brainstorming here.
We're groovin', we're rollin'.
[inhales] Hmm...
How about "Mandu"?
That just makes me think about
how she tried to kill Mandu.
Good point. [gasps]
How about "milkshake"?
-Milkshake?
-[buzzes]
[whispering]
Guys, guys--
No one can get mad when they think about
a big frosty glass
of delicious deliciousness.
Milkshake...
[buzzing quietly]
[buzzes quietly]
See?
[buzzing]
[gasps]
[calypso music playing]
[Benson]
Oh.
You think maybe they're
on that giant cruise ship?
No wonder it was so hard to find her!
She's always moving!
Very smart. Ugh! I hate complimenting her.
-Hopefully our friends--
-And Boom-Boom.
And Boom-Boom are still okay.
Come on.
[Zane over loudspeaker]
Mute alert. Engaging sonic emitter.
Greta, hit the red button.
Zane's log, day thirty-eight at sea.
The water fills me with dread.
No, the red red button.
-[calypso music playing]
-[groans]
Turn on the emitter!
[high pitched pulse]
Ah!
[all]
Aah!
[calypso music playing]
[Kipo, Wolf, Benson, Troy]
Aah!
[splash]
[clangs]
[Kipo, Wolf, Benson, Troy grunting]
[humans laughing, playing]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Look how happy they are!
I can't believe it. They're thrilled to be
on this amazingly cool boat.
Is that a waterslide?!
Oh, that evil temptress
-knows what she is doing.
-[human yells delightedly]
[humans scream joyfully]
[screams]
[groans]
How dare she make it fun!
They'll never come with us.
Milkshake. We're not trying to get them
to come with us today.
Right. [soothingly]
Double scoops filling the glass...
Can't forget the frosty top...
Oh, look, there's a cherry. Plop.
Okay, I'm good.
[buzzing over loudspeaker]
[Emilia]
What a great day we had, friends.
And tomorrow is just a sleep away.
Have a dreamful night.
-Ugh.
-What does "dreamful" even mean?
Her voice is like cold soup down my back.
[Troy]
Um, guys...
Could we maybe hide in there
till everyone goes to sleep?
Uh, my arms are really tired.
[water sloshing]
Roberto! Lio!
I just noticed both your names
end in fun!
What is he talking about?
Talking about a boys' night.
No Kipo, Song's patrolling.
[to self]
No other friends who are definitely
not having fun without me.
[chuckles]
What are you two crazy guys up to?
Dishes.
Dishes! Starting big!
I'm ready to do some washin'!
Oh, we're done.
Great, I didn't want
to wash dishes anyway.
What a lame way to spend boys' night.
[scoffs]
Good thing Dave's here.
We ready to go?
Boy, that sounds real fun
but if I stay up any later,
my restless leg really starts acting up.
Have a good night, fellas!
So...?
Sure, Dave, we don't get to
spend a lot of time together.
All right, boys' night!
Lio and Dave-o.
See I put an "o" on mine, too?
Do you think everyone's asleep?
The coast is clear.
Then let's find Emilia's lab.
[door squeaks]
[gasps]
[chairs scrape]
[bangs]
Sing to me, Wall Siren.
[Hyun-Soo singing in Korean through vent]
♪ Whenever you swim ♪
♪ You make me smile ♪
-♪ You let my love breathe ♪
-[quietly] What is that?
[in English]
♪ Never stop swimming ♪
[Doag dancing]
[in Korean]
♪ Whenever I drown in loneliness ♪
-♪ You're always here and you ♪
-[twinkling]
-[in English] ♪ Rescue me ♪
-She is incredible!
That's Doag.
She was our friend in the burrow.
[Hyun-Soo continues singing in Korean]
Do you think she'll help us?
Probably not, she's Hoag's daughter.
Hoag and Doag? For real?
My dad said Hoag
was the first one to go with Emilia.
And I can't see Doag
going against her dad.
-[crashes]
-[all gasp]
[gasps] Kipo? Troy?
Kipo's friends that saved us
from the mean monkey dude?
Hi, Doag.
I hear the cats and snakes
are doing a community bonding thing.
Was it Kipo's idea?
It was Kipo's idea.
[crashing, loud voices]
Doesn't sound like it's going so well.
Let's go check it out.
[mutes all talking loudly]
Cucumber demon!
Fuzz nugget!
Ooh, that's a good one.
Those can both go in the song.
After the hiss?
I told you, I think the hiss
sounds better closer to the end,
but I'm dropping it.
I'm dropping it.
One more time!
♪ You might think they look
Like cucumber demons ♪
-[thuds]
-[cats yowl]
-♪ But that's just a facade ♪
-[hisses]
♪ They're mighty, they're cool
And full of such venom ♪
[hisses]
♪ That'll make ya feel real odd ♪
[heavy metal music playing]
♪ Fuzz nuggets! ♪
♪ Fuzz nuggets! Not so bad ♪
♪ Friendship Alliance ♪
♪ Led by a girl who loves science ♪
♪ Alliance! Science! ♪
[banjo solo]
[electric guitar solo]
[all singing]
♪ It's the Ultimate Friendship Alliance ♪
-♪ Taking down evil with defiance ♪
-[Dave] ♪ Come-- see-- clients ♪
♪ Friendship Alliance ♪
♪ Nothing rhymes well with-- ♪
♪ Singing! ♪
-♪ Alliance! ♪
-[hisses]
-[chuckles]
-Oh, right on!
The hiss does sound better there.
Whoo! That was fun!
The way those cats played--
man, it gets me every time!
Oh, well, it's getting pretty late.
Yeah! We need a pick-me-up!
I got a secret stash
of explosion berry cola.
It's still fizzy.
[yawns] Okay, yeah.
Sure, Dave, sounds great.
...and after all that,
you all still went with her.
I'm not judging.
I'm just saying she's tricky.
I hear you, and
I understand your feelings,
but also, I don't.
Emilia is so nice!
And she gave us a water slide.
She is not nice, Doag.
She's been looking for Kipo to kill her
since she was a baby!
And she didn't even eat Benson's pancakes!
[exhales]
That story is really infuriating.
Wow, you guys are, like,
really passionate about this.
We are.
But Emilia controlling a mega monkey?
Like, how, magic?
Magic? No!
She used Scarlemagne's pheromone.
Yeah, but like, who told you this?
Well, Scarlamagne, but--
You mean the super angry monkey
who destroyed our home twice
and brain-trapped us?
Yes?
Listen, Emilia has my friends
And Boom-Boom.
locked up on this boat.
Maybe I can't change your mind about mutes
but I can't let her hurt them.
I've danced my way all over this boat
and I can tell you,
there are no prisoners here.
But-- [sighs]
I just need a moment to think.
Okay, so I've really thought this through.
-[all gasp]
-I'm gonna get my dad.
-Doag, don't!
-No-no-no-no-no!
No, wait. What if you just
show us where Emilia's lab is?
Then you can prove she has no prisoners.
Mm, deal. Follow me.
I am not doing that.
Uh, it's here? That's it?
Not very hidden.
I told you she's got nothing to hide.
[handle rattles]
[grunting]
Then why is it locked?
I got this.
[scratching]
[clicks, unlocks]
How did you know how to do that?
Close-up magic.
[gasps] Whoa.
-Of course!
-[door bangs]
My boyfriend's so cool.
Our friends!
[Wolf]
And Boom-Boom.
Huh! Burrow girl.
[chuckles]
You really came.
-The frog's been talkin' about it
-[chuckles]
non-stop.
No prancing way!
She really does have prisoners.
But, like, maybe they
did something really bad first?
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom! [pants]
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-Boom-Boom's been through a lot.
-Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-Poked, prodded, Greta.
--Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
[shudders]
Greta talks to us so much.
[Doag gasps]
A dolphicorn!
Who are you?
♪ Hyun-Soo ♪
[gasps]
It's the Wall Siren.
[bubbles]
Your angelic voice finds me every night.
I dance to your music.
♪ You rescue me ♪
It isn't right!
She can't just lock people up like this.
[Hyun-Soo singing]
[banging]
♪ ...deep inside ♪
Huh?
Ah! Oh. Ugh.
You're right, I don't have to
dance-think a second longer.
Anyone that would cage up
a musical dolphin unicorn
can't be a good person.
I'm gonna help you get them out of here.
Just please don't tell my dad.
Aw, we changed someone's mind!
Bonus!
-[clinks]
-The journal!
Great! Now, let's get out of here.
We have all our friends.
Wait. Get Boom-Boom.
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
Boom-Boom-Boom!
[wings buzz]
-[clinking]
-Oh!
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-Run!
-Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-Ah!
-[thunks]
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
Boom Boom!
[glass breaking]
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-Well, so much for stealth.
-[alarm ringing]
The journal!
[rustling]
Whoo!
I'm so tired, I'm awake!
I haven't stayed up this late in years.
I'm gonna kick that leaf.
-[grunting]
-Man, you are so much fun!
Why haven't we been hanging out like this
the whole time?
Yah! Okay, I got the leaf.
What's next? What-do-we-do?
What-do-we-do next?
[giggles] I say we steal Molly's axes
and hide 'em in a bush.
And then she'll be like,
"Where are my axes?
What's with this ax-bush?"
And then we'll all laugh.
[laughs]
That's the best idea I've ever heard.
[snickers]
I'm laughing already,
thinking about laughing tomorrow.
Okay, shh. We have to be stealthy.
[Benson, Dave laughing while shushing]
[Yumyan laughs]
Shush! Shush!
[alarm ringing, buzzing]
[coughing]
I'm so sorry I dropped the journal.
At least it's destroyed.
Now Emilia can't use it to make the cure.
[grunts] Somebody help me
push my new best friend into a mini boat.
[in Korean]
Just push me into the water.
Shh, it's okay. I'll take care of you.
Ah! Ugh.
Kipo, come on!
-Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom! Boom-Boom!
-[grunts]
-[groans]
-[Kipo] She can't get away with this!
We finished the mission.
Let's go.
No.
Dude, milkshake!
I don't care about going off-mission.
There is no milkshake frosty enough
to cool my rage.
Hyuh!
Doag, get them out of here.
-[snaps]
-[splashes]
[gasps] Huh?
[Zane over loudspeaker]
Emitter engaging.
-[high pitched pulse]
-[groans, grunts]
-Hyuh!
-[metal crunches]
Ah!
[Emilia, Greta, Zane gasp]
[Zane, Greta yell war cry]
[whirring]
[clangs]
-Ah!
-[Zane, Greta grunt]
[gasps]
[sighs]
Feels good.
[whirring]
-[humans murmuring]
-Huh?
[whip whirring]
Kipo, why are you attacking us?
Because you kidnapped my friends!
What friends?
I mean, they were here,
but they're gone now.
-[crashes]
-[gasps]
Where's Doag?
What have you adolescent vandals
done with my sweet princess?
I know how this must look,
but I need you to listen to me.
Emilia is not who she says she is.
Yeah! She's evil!
She sent the mega monkey
to destroy our home.
And the monkey also
happens to be Kipo's mom!
-She mind controlled her...
-[gasps]
to find and kill her own daughter.
How messed up is that?
And she killed my best friend!
[crowd gasps, murmurs]
Stalky.
Lily? Earl? You believe me, don't you?
I'm sorry, Kipo,
but this sounds crazy.
Uh, Mr. Filburn, you know me.
I-- I wouldn't lie to you.
The Kipo I knew wouldn't.
What did they do to you?
Hmm. I think you're all confused.
You've spent too much time with mutes.
They've manipulated you.
Why don't you stay with us?
We can help you.
We can fix
whatever they did to your minds.
Ah!
[bangs]
[crowd gasps in horror]
-[man] Stop them!
-[woman] Stop her!
[man 2]
She's getting away!
You were right!
We've got what we came for.
It's time to get out of here.
Milkshake! Milkshake! Milkshake!
[splashes]
Sometimes my immortality is a curse.
But tonight, it really came in handy.
Yeah, Molly was mad.
[laugh]
Right, she killed me, like, five times.
[sighs]
Dave, I really needed this.
You knew I'd be up all night
worrying about Kipo.
You're a good friend.
Uh... Oh, yes, yes,
that's exactly what I was doing.
[chuckles]
Hey.
You think you can hit the litter box
down there with one of my arms?
Oh, definitely.
[laughs]
You only get four chances.
[bubbling]
Are you sure
you don't want to come with us?
I have to get back to the boat.
I can't just leave my dad.
We kinda made a mess back there.
I'm sorry.
Well, luckily for you,
you totally have a friend
on the inside, now.
I will be the voice
for the unicorn of the sea,
and for all other majestic creatures
that I haven't gotten to dance with yet.
Thank you for everything, Doag.
One more for the road?
[in Korean]
♪ Whenever you swim ♪
♪ You let my love breathe ♪
[Narhartz harmonizing]
♪ You make me smile ♪
[in English]
♪ Never stop swimming... ♪
I'm sorry we couldn't convince the people
to come with us,
but, hey, we did it.
Yeah, we destroyed the journal
so she can't "cure" anybody.
And rescued these two.
That was punk rock back there, Kipo.
For a hot minute,
I thought I'd never play guitar again.
[chuckles]
Couldn't let that happen.
[gasps]
She called me "punk rock."
I knew you'd come for me!
Dr. Emilia,
everything in the lab is ashes.
How are we gonna science away those mutes
if this is all that's left
of your science book?
Now we'll never know what X means.
[Emilia]
Hmm...
[gasps]
Wait.
Kipo is X.
I know what to do.
[laughs wickedly]
[Hyun-Soo singing in Korean]
♪ Ride the wave with me ♪
[in English]
♪ Dive into my ocean of love ♪
[in Korean]
♪ To the sea forever ♪
[in English]
♪ Dive into my ocean of love ♪
♪ You and me equals love in the sea ♪
♪ Dive into my ocean ♪
♪ Dive into my ohh ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ Ohh ♪