-[snoring]
-[crickets chirping]
[squeals]
-[grunts]
-[Mandu squeals]
[snorts, purrs]
-[gasps]
-[growls]
[roars]
It must be so tough for you,
knowing your daughter
is growing up without you.
She must be just about to turn 13, right?
Well, I've got good news.
I've found her.
-[growls]
-Turns out she's been living in a burrow
not too far from here this whole time.
And I'm gonna send you
to take care of her.
[gasps]
[growls]
[roars]
[beeping]
[yells]
Wow, such passion!
You must really care about her a lot.
But sadly, she's a monster.
Go and put her out of her misery.
[theme music playing]
[squeals]
[all laughing]
[yelling]
[giggles]
[Asher] Wolf! [grunts]
[screeching]
[sighs]
[chuckles]
You're back!
Yep.
Well, can you still, you know...
[growls]
Phew!
Then why are you so sad?
Wait.
Where's Yumyan?
[meows]
[gasps]
-[Yumyan meows, purrs]
-[hisses softly]
Let's take a moment to honor
Yumyan for his bravery.
The legend of Yumyan Hammerpaw
will live on for generations.
And though he's very much still here
and digging his claws into my shoulders...
-Ow-ow-ow!
-I'll take him.
-[yowls]
-Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
He has earned his place
in the Great Hall of Axe Lords.
[all cheering]
He fell asleep
while you were talking about him.
The old Yumyan would never fall asleep
while you were talking about him!
[Timbercat 1]
Aww... Look at that!
Everyone for themselves.
This whole "cure" thing
is totally not cool.
-I don't wanna be small!
-Oh, I'm sorry.
That's what you're worried about?
Losing your gains.
Look at him!
He can't talk!
On the bright side...
[meows]
Oh, no, I can't think of a bright side!
-Oh, no! All is lost!
-[all chattering]
-[mute] Who will protect us?
-[Label] What do we do?
During our fight with Dr. Emilia,
I stole this.
-[all gasping]
-It's the "cure."
I can make a vaccine,
but, I'll need Song's help.
[gasps]
Mom.
We're gonna get your mother back.
Wait, the Mega Monkey was a human?
[grunts]
Hey, Mom, Dad and I
have something to tell you.
[grunts]
You're coming home.
[grunting]
[roaring]
Mom?
[gasps]
K... Ki... Ki... Ki...
Mom!
[both laughing]
K... K... Kipo.
It's really you!
Oh, I-I can hug you!
[sighs]
I can't believe you're here.
I... I can't believe I'm here, either.
[whimpers]
[gasps]
[laughs]
[laughing]
I can't believe it!
Song, I missed you so much!
I... I... dr-- dreamed about this,
but I didn't think I'd ever...
[laughing]
Wolf, get in here!
Family hug!
-You forgot to say Benson and Dave!
-But we're coming, too.
[squeals]
-How do you feel?
-Short.
[laughing]
Oh, right, uh,
you can't hug my finger anymore
because it's not giant.
[laughs]
That's OK.
We-we'll come up with
a new Kipo and Mom thing.
It'll be so much... dah!
You have my nose.
Or-or, I guess I have yours.
This is so cool!
-I could stare at you all day!
-Right back at ya!
I don't know where to begin.
I've missed so much.
It's OK. We've got
the rest of our lives to catch up.
Wait.
This means Emilia has the cure.
Yes, and we're going to need your help
to make a vaccine.
But first, let's just enjoy this.
I know Emilia.
There's no time.
She'll be on her way.
We have to get started.
We won't let her turn them.
[growling]
[whimpers]
I told you I'd let you go
if you brought me that Wolf girl.
I always keep my promise.
[both panting]
Watch this.
I-I can't remember if the mutagen
was heterozygous or homozygous.
-Uh, heterozygous?
-Right, yes.
[exhales] Now I can't remember
the pattern of the dominant alleles!
Song, it's OK.
It's been a while since you've done this.
Lio, she's counting on me.
You're doing great, Mom!
Thanks, honey, except, I'm not.
It's just... it's just been so long.
It's OK!
You'll get it.
Mom! Mom!
[both chanting]
Mom! [clapping] Mom!
This is everything I imagined
having a mom would be!
Cheering for her while she does science?
-Yeah, that tracks.
-Whoo!
OK. OK.
I remember trying to prolong the process
of transient polymorphism, and then...
[grunts]
Nothing!
That's OK.
We'll get there.
Not in time to stop Dr. Emilia
from "curing" half the surface.
Kipo, I'm sorry.
It's not coming back to me fast enough.
-If Song can't make a vaccine...
-[all chattering]
What are we gonna do?
-All is lost!
-It's not!
My mom will figure out the vaccine.
But we basically asked her
to save the world in one afternoon.
-Which was nuts.
-It wouldn't have been for the old me.
But don't worry, I'm sure she'll
figure out the vaccine in a few days.
It's Emilia.
We saw her army by the old headquarters.
She's on her way.
Side note, we'll be joining HMUFA.
OK, so we only have one day.
We need to find another way
to defend ourselves from Dr. Emilia
in the meantime.
-We'll sharpen our axes.
-Our fangs are always sharp!
I will throw weights at them!
Love the enthusiasm, but--
None of that will work against cure darts.
Ooh! Ooh!
I know!
We can get the skunks
to put up a wall of stink.
Humans will be like,
"Ew, I'm not walking
through that, Johnny."
-And leave us alone.
-That's a great idea.
-[both] It is?
-Not the skunk part, but the wall!
A wall that big would take all
the timber in Timbercat Village.
Then, what are we even protecting?
OK, we'll build it with something else.
What would scare the humans?
-[Benson] Clowns?
-[mute 1] Other humans!
-[mute 2] Diversity!
-[mute 3] Public speaking!
-[mute 4] Great big cockroach!
-[mute 5] Their past!
[mute 6] A Mega Monkey!
Oh... Never mind.
-Death Ivy!
-Yes!
Thank you, Benson,
for having a usable idea.
I also said clowns, but I got there.
[chuckles]
Yeah, great plan... small problem.
No one can touch death ivy without,
you know, dying to death.
Dubstep Bees!
Fun fact: they're immune to it.
Fun follow-up: I don't know why.
Then I guess we're asking
the bees to join HMUFA!
They can build a wall of death ivy
to keep the humans out long enough
for my mom to make the vaccine.
Ahem.
Great idea, Kipo.
Yumyan would be proud.
-Hey, where is Yumyan?
-Oh, we put him in the kitchen.
The kitchen
with the giant hole in the wall?
[all gasping]
Oh, no.
He could be on top of something,
underneath something,
inside of something,
and that something could be anything!
Don't worry, Molly.
We're gonna find him
and whoever's responsible for losing him.
-Dave, it was us.
-So, we're halfway there.
All right, you guys go find Yumyan,
Wolf and I will convince the bees to help.
My mom seems so upset.
I wish there was something
I could do to make her feel better.
[groans] I wish I could make
the vaccine faster.
I feel like I'm failing her.
[sighs]
I feel like that all the time.
But I promise you,
she doesn't feel that way.
Maybe you just need a break,
recharge your batteries.
Hey, we could tag along with Kipo!
Then you can show her
who the coolest mom in the world is.
It's you.
Hey, why don't we invite her?
[gasps] Then we can save everyone together
and make special memories.
-[gasps] Wolf, you're a genius.
-Yeah...
-Hey, Mom...
-Kipo...
-Do you want to come with us?
-Can we come with you?
Song, do you want to help us find a cat?
Yes!
So, was that yes to me or to Kipo?
[snoring]
[whisper sounds]
[Benson] Yumyan!
-[whisper sounds]
-[snorts]
Mandu, have you seen Yumyan?
[snorts]
[sighs]
[clears throat, whisper noises]
-Ming ming ming.
-Ming ming ming?
Cats love this, trust me.
Ming ming ming!
[footsteps]
What is that enticing noise?
[all meowing]
Well, it worked on
every cat besides Yumyan.
[meows]
[Kipo] OK! OK! [gasps]
On the count of three,
what's your favorite cake.
One, two, three...
[both] Chocolate cake, peanut butter
frosting with chocolate chunks!
Our turn, Wolf.
One, two, three...
-Vanilla!
-I've never had cake, what is cake?
[motorbike approaching]
This highway belongs
to the Scooter Skunks, humans.
If you wanna cross, you gotta race.
We don't want any trouble.
We just need to get to the Dubstep Bees.
[whispering]
Lio, this is my chance.
I'll do it!
Get a good look at my face because from
now on, I'll be so far ahead of you,
you're only gonna see my back.
-Until we shake hands at the finish line.
-We'll see about that.
[engine revs]
Dah! My mom is so cool!
Ka-click.
Oh, that was me taking pictures
with my mind camera!
Memories being made!
[engines revving]
Ready, steady, go!
Oh-wha!
-[grunts]
-[gasps]
[laughs]
That's hilarious.
Guess you're not going anywhere.
-[roars]
-[screams]
-Wait, you're the jaguar girl?
-[growls]
We didn't recognize you
without the fur and giant teeth!
-You humans look the same!
-[roars]
[screaming]
Mom, are you OK?
I thought you knew how to ride.
Yeah, I thought it would be
like riding a bike.
-Which I also don't know how to do.
-You had me fooled.
I thought this was
gonna be one of those
"we learn something new
about each other every day" moments.
I think it's brave you tried.
I can't ride a motorcycle.
Ooh! Maybe we could learn together
and that could be our thing!
-[clears throat]
-Right, the mission!
We got places to be.
-[Benson] Yumyan!
-[Dave] Yumyan!
Do you really think Yumyan
could have gotten this far?
Absolutely, yes.
-[squeaks]
-Oh, no!
[gasps]
Did you just step on a bug?
Maybe it was a crunchy leaf?
[nervous chuckle]
Nope. That was a bug.
Dave, I-I-I'm so sorry,
I didn't mean to...
-How could you?
-It was an accident.
-I-I--
-Bup-bup!
There's only one way to make up for this.
We're gonna have to find a small,
tiny human to squish.
[gasps] Li... like a baby?
That... that's a baby, Dave!
Yes.
I-- I'm not gonna go step on a baby, now.
-That's... that makes it worse!
-How do you know that bug wasn't a baby?
Any luck finding Yumyan?
Oh, right, we were looking for a cat.
[laughs]
I was having so much fun
messing with Benson, I completely forgot.
Oh, look, another bug!
I'm gonna squish it!
-[laughing] Yeah!
-[squeaks]
-What?
-Squishing bugs!
[squeaking]
OK, dealing with the Dubstep Bees
can be tricky.
-I can talk to them.
-Are you sure?
I don't want you to get hurt again,
like with the bike.
Yes, I can definitely do this for you.
I learned a few things
from my time as a Mega Monkey.
I just need to warm up.
[clears throat]
-Whaa...
-[buzzing]
[dubstep music playing]
Back up!
That's my mom you're wubbing at.
Wuh-wuh-wuh-wuh-wha back at ya!
[buzzing]
Kipo!
You just insulted their queen.
Wait, you're actually talking to them?
[buzzing]
Du-du-du-du-doosh bom-bom!
Uh, hi, your majesty.
Sorry about whatever I said earlier,
but... Ow!
[whimpering]
[grunting]
Kipo, this is no time to dance.
What's happening to me?
I read in an ancient text
called Cat Sassy,
that cats can't resist
getting into boxes.
That's completely ridiculous.
Hmm?
[meows and gasps]
Oh!
[gasps]
[screeching]
Well, we tried everything.
Maybe we can find them a new cat
and they won't even notice.
Uh, why am I suddenly,
and uncontrollably, good at dancing?
The queen's sting
causes dance fever, honey.
You're gonna be OK.
She's not gonna be OK.
If we don't do something,
she'll dance until she dies.
On it!
[dubstep music plays]
[grunting]
Off it!
[whimpering]
Oh, I have an idea.
Sorry!
I thought that would work,
based on nothing.
There has to be a way
to get her out of this!
[buzzing]
Wah wub-wub-wub boom chk-chk.
Wah dush-dush wah dush-dush pew.
[buzzing]
Uh, what just happened?
She said she'll give Kipo back,
if we impress her with a dance.
It couldn't have been anything else?
Let's save Kipo.
["Sugar" by MYBADD & Sam Gray playing]
♪ I got sugar in my pocket
You can have some if you want it ♪
♪ If you wanna
Then I'll share it with you ♪
♪ I'll keep you going 'til the morning ♪
♪ We'll be writing all the stories ♪
♪ Tell me what else
Is there really to do? ♪
♪ Sugar
Wooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ When the sun goes down
I'll be coming up ♪
♪ Sugar, hey
Wooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ I wanna share it with
You you you you you ♪
♪ I wanna-- ♪
[door opens]
-Hey, look everyone, I found Yumyan.
-[gasping]
-Yumyan has returned!
-[all cheering]
Wait, what?
That ain't Yumyan.
-[meows]
-Yumyan!
[all gasping]
[meows]
[all cheering]
[groans]
We never checked the kitchen!
I knew that the whole time.
I just wanted to spend the day with you.
-Aw, really?
-Nah.
♪ I'll keep you going 'til the morning ♪
♪ We'll be writing all the stories ♪
♪ Tell me what else
Is there really to do? ♪
♪ Sugar
Wooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ When the sun goes down
I'll be coming up ♪
♪ Sugar, hey... ♪
[buzzing]
♪ I wanna share it with
You you you you you ♪
[music stops]
[panting]
Pose cool, pose cool!
[grunting]
[buzzing]
-What?
-No!
That seems right.
It's OK, guys. [chuckles]
It's not so bad.
I'm learning so many new moves!
Your majesty, please.
Kipo didn't mean to insult you.
She was just trying to protect me.
All I've wanted for the past 13 years
is to be there for my daughter.
But I haven't even been able
to hug her until today!
So, I am not leaving without her.
Please, as one mother to another,
give me back my girl.
Oh, right.
I have to say it in bee.
Doo ju-ju-ju wah-wah ge-ge-ge-ge bam.
Wee-wee.
Bam-wah-wah.
[buzzing]
Ow!
But, yay!
-[chuckles]
-[gasps]
Mom! You did it!
Thank you.
Um, now can you convince them
to help us build a wall of death ivy?
[buzzing]
Dush-dush pew.
Wow, you did it.
You got the bees
to build the wall of death ivy.
We found a cat...
[chuckles]
Which we lost in the first place.
-[meows]
-[gasps]
-[Label] Whoa.
How did he do that?
Yumyan owns the box!
-[all cheering]
-[meows]
Huh?
[all] Aww...
You did a cool thing, too.
Actually, it was all thanks to my mom.
[both]
Can I talk to you for a second? Great.
Hey, sorry.
I don't really need to talk.
Me neither. Blah-blah, something,
and then, eh, we laugh.
[both laughing]
Hey, Mom.
Sorry I didn't believe
that you could talk to bees.
Oh, honey, why would you?
I may have over-promised a lot today.
I guess...
I just really wanted to be there for you.
As the Mega Monkey I could protect you,
and as a scientist
I could help you, but now?
I just don't know what to do.
You're already doing it.
You're being my mom.
That's all I need.
That's what convinced the bees to help us.
A-- And that's what made
the special memories
I will cherish in my heart forever!
Ka-click!
I thought we should get one together.
This is our thing!
-[buzzing]
-[gasps]
Hopefully the death ivy
holds her off long enough.
[panting]
[whimpering]
[howling]
[music playing]
♪ I got sugar in my pocket
You can have some if you want it ♪
♪ If you wanna
Then I'll share it with you ♪
♪ I'll keep you going 'til the morning ♪
♪ We'll be writing all the stories ♪
♪ Tell me what else
Is there really to do? ♪
♪ Sugar
Wooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Sugar ♪