[snoring]
[squeals]
[humming]
[bleating]
-[grunting]
-[straining]
Why did we all try
to get in at the same time?
-[grunts]
-[chuckling]
Hi, ladies.
-Kipo!
-Thank goodness you're safe.
We have to leave now.
We're here to take you to--
Buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh,
they know why we're here.
They saw it in the cheese.
-Actually, we're washing dishes.
-I broke the sink!
It's not cheese, Dave.
Yet.
Quit eating, and start packing!
[Bev] And where exactly are we going?
-To Timbercat Village, because we--
-Because...
-We've built a death ivy wall to...
-Death ivy wall to...
...protect you from the horrible killer
that Doctor Emilia just finished making!
Do you guys even cheese anymore?
He's right.
Before we go anywhere,
we should look in the cheese.
Fine.
But please hurry.
I'm trying to save your life here.
[chanting] Feta, gouda, chèvre, fromage.
[Bev] Doctor Emilia will not waver
from ridding the surface of all mutekind.
[Ida] With her new army, she will succeed.
[Florabel] Unless you stop them.
You will need to fight the ones
you care about
in order to save us all.
[all gasp]
Dang, really?
I gotta fight you guys?
But to save the world...
I'll do it.
Not you.
We meant her.
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
[theme music playing]
[galloping]
[growling]
[whispering]
The password is "open the wall."
[speaking Bee]
Oh, I mean...
[imitates firefly speaking Bee]
Molly! Is the perimeter secure?
Any holes?
Any breaches?
Did I say the right words?
Yeah. Way to go.
The perimeter is set.
Our scouts have reported
no signs of Emilia.
-Did we leave the lanai?
-Right, the welcome speech.
Hurray!
Welcome to Timbercat Village.
It's the best place on the surface,
and you're totally gonna love it here.
Hurray.
Breach, breach, breach!
Relax.
It's just us.
Phew. I thought you were my people
and I was gonna have to fight you.
OK, everybody stand down.
Good practice!
Good practice.
Kipo, we can finish the welcome tour.
OK, so, over there is the place we eat.
And over there is where I sleep sometimes,
but I'm not supposed to. [chuckles]
And that bush right there
is where I hid all Molly's axes.
-You do know they can't see?
-And that's Zane in the cage.
He's our prisoner.
He used to work for Emilia.
Yeah. I tried to kill them,
but I'm reconsidering.
[Label] Here you go!
Huh?
An apple a day keeps the doctor away!
Thank you, Label!
Thank you for saying thanks!
We're working on him.
Anyway, let me show you all
my favorite yarn ball.
[Kipo] I'm so glad you decided to come.
Not only will you be so safe here,
but we're gonna become such great friends.
We're here until the danger passes,
then we're out.
-[meows]
-[gasps]
[Kipo] Yumyan!
That "doctor" gives science a bad name.
Monster.
Don't be afraid.
Today is the first step
in taking back what is rightfully ours.
Humans on top!
Humans on top! Humans on top!
[fireflies speaking Bee]
Ooh. My mom would know what you're saying,
but she's off getting supplies
to make the vaccine with my dad.
I'm fluent in Bee.
They've said... [clears throat]
"The dragonflies have agreed
to avoid any human contact,
so they can't fly over the wall,
my dudes."
Excellent. That means Emilia's
got no way over the wall.
And here, we have the great hall
where we have important meetings.
Like the one that we're interrupting.
Point is, we have enough food
and supplies to ride this out
until the humans turn around.
For how long?
Until my mom figures out the vaccine
or my people realize we're not a threat.
Or they get bored
and completely change their minds.
See?
Lots of options.
None of which end with us,
specifically me, fighting my people.
[laughs]
Take that, prophecy.
You're working very hard, dear.
But you can't fight destiny.
Sure I can.
-We've helped Kipo fight destiny before.
-We'll do it again.
[meowing alarm over loudspeaker]
All right, all right!
She's here.
What's going on?
The people from the burrow
actually did come with her?
Do you think
Mom and Dad are down there?
-What? They'd never.
-Troy's right.
Your mom stopped us
from running with scissors.
She would never run with a crossbow.
Regardless, all the humans...
How should I put this?
...despise me.
And here I am, all packaged up
in a see-through to-go box.
So, go ahead.
Pop the top.
Let me out so they don't kill me.
Thank you.
-Kipo, our parents did come!
-What?
[gasps] It is them!
And that's Mr. Filburn.
But he's a math teacher.
And they're heading
right for the death ivy!
They don't realize what it is.
I have to warn them!
Look out!
The wall is death ivy!
I think she said, "Dinner's ready."
No. She said, "It's death ivy."
Watch this.
Why is the enemy warning us?
That's Kipo.
Kipo! Are you OK?
Don't worry, kids.
We'll save you!
The wall goes all the way around.
There's no way in!
We don't wanna fight.
You should just go home!
Don't listen to her.
She has your children.
One way or another,
we are getting through this wall.
Shall I burn it?
No, Greta!
The fumes are poisonous.
We'll find another way.
[chuckles] We did it.
Thank you for leaving!
Have a great day!
It's OK, everybody.
The death ivy worked.
I knew they wouldn't
risk their lives to cure us.
Or... maybe they would.
We came here for the protection
of the death ivy wall.
But it seems
that hypothesis was erroneous.
Yeah, what he said!
I think.
He's saying we fight.
The egghead and stinky cats are right.
Yumyan would want us to fight
to protect our village!
Based on the density of the wall,
it looks like we have
approximately two hours,
give or take seven minutes,
before they get in.
-That wall was a terrible idea!
-Let's fight!
We don't have to fight.
We just have to get them in one spot.
Then we can talk to them.
-[Label] Lemme take that.
-Thanks, it was delicious.
-Did you add something?
-I added pepper.
-I thought you'd like a little kick.
-You're not wrong.
The pepper kicked me right in the teeth.
Right where I like it.
You know what else gives me a kick?
-No, what?
-A good ab workout!
Good to know. Thanks, Label.
What you doing, shaky head?
I've got it! Zane!
Zane talks to us
because he's in a small space
he can't leave.
We need to Zane my people.
Is that Kipo for "trap"?
That's not my word of choice, but yes.
Why would we waste our time on that,
when the Mega Jaguar
could just devour them?
First of all, ew.
Second, traps will work.
I knew Kipo would
come up with a smart plan.
That plan is foolish.
They came for a fight!
-We need to prepare.
-I dunno, traps are kind of fun.
Not wanting to fight
your people is admirable. But--
The cheese has spoken.
And it's always right.
I refuse to let that cheese
show me who's boss.
That's my girl!
These prophecies are not set in stone.
But they were pretty spot-on
about the Mega Jaguar prophecy.
Yeah, but we avoided
the scary parts last time,
and we'll do it again.
We're with you, Kipo.
And if you wanna do traps,
I've caught a lot of food.
[squeals]
Which I don't do anymore.
Yeah, I used to trap Dave all the time.
You were going to eat Dave?
What, what, what? No way!
Just to mess with him.
You know, like a prank?
Strange.
But interesting.
OK, team. Now, we just
have to convince all of... them.
-Walls don't work anyway!
-We have no choice.
No walls for timbercats!
Hey!
Kipo said we're doing traps!
We're doing traps!
-OK.
-Yes, we're doing traps!
I'm gonna dig a hole
and cover it with leaves,
somebody's gonna fall right into it.
Such a trap.
[Dave laughing]
Breaker, breaker, this is Mega Jag.
How's "Operation Rock You
Like a Hurricane?" Over.
[Jamack] Amps are in position.
Oh, man, you know, I was just thinking,
this is gonna be so good.
This is gonna be so good!
I mean, we even have a net. Come on!
It's, like, they'll be listening
to some music, and then boom!
-Net! And then--
-Over.
Right. Totally. Sorry.
Over.
But nets, right?
[sniffing]
[gasps] Oh, sweet, sweet cheese.
[grunting]
[cackling]
-Prank!
-Why'd you tell her what pranks are?
Now I look like a porcupine.
What?
Too much?
Yep.
Maybe a little.
First one through
gets to be the first one through.
Not if I'm the first one through.
[grunting]
I admire the enthusiasm, but be careful.
I just can't wait to get in there
and start curing every single one of them.
The surface will finally
be safe for my daughter.
[grunting]
[Kipo] Bad Dog. Come in, Bad Dog.
Is "Operation Balloon Pop and Fall"
in place?
Over.
[groans] Over.
[gasps, whines]
I'll take that as a yes.
Over.
So, you want me to paralyze them
with abject fear
while a trap encloses them?
[laughing]
Good plan.
Are you sure we can trust him?
Look at his hands.
Oh.
Yes. I know we can because he promises
he won't mind control anyone.
At all.
All right, no mind control, I promise.
Lead the way, mon capitaine.
Perfect.
Now help me with "Operation Leafy Leaf."
[cackles]
[Emilia] Don't forget
who we're fighting to protect.
Our sisters, our brothers,
our parents...
our children.
Earl, you know nothing matters more to me
than Asher and Dahlia, but...
Are we sure we're making
the right decision?
I don't know.
You saw what Emilia did to that wolf kid.
It was heartless.
How can we trust someone
who could hurt anyone that easily?
[Hoag] Everyone, keep going!
[Kipo] Everyone's in place?
[Billions] Balloon team, standing by.
[Jamack] Hurricane team, standing by.
Side note, love our code name.
[Scarlemagne] I'm not doing
a cutesy name... but I'm set.
I can't believe they're all
actually working together.
Even Scarlemagne.
You looked destiny in the eye and said,
"Not today, destiny."
Look who came around to realizing
the cheese can be wrong!
Or... maybe you did exactly
what destiny wanted,
and now you will
have to fight your own people.
Destiny is an unstoppable force.
You think you can stop it,
but you can't.
It stops when it wants to stop.
And it never wants to.
[rustling]
[wind whistling]
[screams]
[Emilia] This place is rigged.
Watch your step.
Phase two.
It's go time.
[hissing]
Remember, we're doing this
for Asher and Dahlia.
We can't risk them getting hurt.
Hey!
Finally.
My muscles are getting weak
sitting in this litter box.
Uh...
Hello to you, too, Doctor.
Greta!
Hi, Zane.
Do you mind?
No...?
Can you let me out?
Oh. OK.
[guitar music continues]
[grunts]
-[laughs] Net!
-Miss me?
[Kipo] Emilia!
We don't have to fight!
Of course, we do.
We'll only be safe when you
and the animals you've sided with
are cured of that virus.
What are you talking about?
The most dangerous part
of the surface is you.
[laughing]
[grunts, laughs]
[screaming]
You don't scare me, ball.
[Kipo] HMUFA!
Nice try, Kipo.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are!
You just got
"Operation Leafy Leafed."
That sounds ridiculous.
Says the lady in a box of leafy leaves.
Now for "Operation Talk To Humans So That
They Love HMUFA As Much As I Do."
You're really bad at code names.
I reject that criticism,
but you're entitled to your opinion.
[sighs]
[screams, grunts]
Emilia!
[laughing]
Where are you?
Right here, Greta.
Wait...
Are you a bush now?
Behind the leaves?
I knew I kept you around for a reason.
Let's get the others out.
Mom! Dad!
Kids!
We'll get you out,
but you have to hand over your crossbows.
[grunting]
-No!
-Leave our kids alone!
[Molly] Are you OK?
Be careful.
You saved them?
-We told you.
-They're our friends.
So, you see, you've got things all wrong.
Mutes like funny-face flapjacks
and live theatrical performances,
just like the rest of us.
Guys, no!
Do nice faces.
-[Hoag grunting] They're shooting at us!
-[gun shot sounds]
[humans grunting]
It's working!
Kipo, slight problem.
Greta is crazy strong.
She burst that yarn ball like a piñata!
It was insane!
Over.
Brother?
I can feel my mind fading...
like... a dying star.
No!
[howls]
No.
[mellow music playing]
Wheels?
Wheels!
Sorry, man.
My muscles really did get weak
in that litter box.
Ya know?
Fight it, Camille!
It's just like venom.
How could I let this happen?
I-I-I'm so sorry, Brad!
It's all my fault.
Stop... hurting... my friends!
Kipo!
Wha--
Why isn't this working?
Of course.
I used your DNA for the cure.
You're immune!
Retreat!
You did what you had to do, Kipo.
We won!
This... is no win.
He's right.
If I would've just
accepted my fate from the start...
none of this would've happened.
I'm sorry, dear.
The cheese tried to warn you.
I won't make the same mistake again.
[music continues]