-[snoring]
-[crickets chirping]
[squeals]
-[grunts]
-[squeals]
[snorts]
...which is why I, Kipo Oak,
am inviting you...
to Prahm.
Huh, prom? Like a dance?
No, Prahm, like, P-R-A-H-M.
A Party Reconciling All Humans and Mutes.
But also, yes. There will be dancing.
Yes!
If you could hear the Timbercats
shred on a banjo,
and if they could taste
one of Mrs. Graham's cakes,
there's no way you'd hate each other.
If you come to Prahm, you'll see that you
have more in common than you think.
[Emilia]
This is clearly a trap!
Who throws a party in the middle of a war?
[everyone]
Kipo.
[snorts]
So, what do you say?
Yes, yes, a thousand times yes!
We're not war people, we're burrow people.
We like fun museums
and giving each other compliments.
-You're doing great, Doag!
-[Doag] Thank you.
Great! Meet us tomorrow
at Skyscraper Ridge.
-I'll be going.
-[crowd gasping]
Really?
Cool.
[people laughing]
[laughing continues]
[gasps]
I accept your invitation.
[cooing]
[intro theme playing]
[grunting, panting]
Gah! Feel the Zane!
-All clear.
-Zane, you don't have to do that anymore.
Right, because I'm on the side
of the mutes, now.
So, who's the enemy?
There isn't one.
Right.
What if I like doing it?
Then follow your bliss, buddy.
Gah! I'm doing it!
-Yeah, baby, do it!
-[grunting]
-Hah!
-Uhh!
-Huh!
-Gah!
Ha!
Something's not right.
Is it the walking?
'Cause I hate walking, too.
Why don't we skate everywhere?
Think about that, hm?
It's not that. I-it's Emilia.
She agreed to Prahm, then smiled.
Something's up. I can feel it.
Even if you're right,
I don't think she can do anything.
She knows her cure won't work on me,
and she's lost her army.
It kinda feels like we won.
Well, half won.
We only have until tomorrow to convince
all of the mutes in Las Vistas
to come to a party with the people
who just attacked them.
I'll help. I'm charismatic
and people respect my strong jawline.
Um... that is true,
but I think you, Doag,
and everyone else from the boat
should just meet me after.
They might be a teeny bit upset that--
You didn't sink the boat?!
[angry mumbling and shouting]
Are you really gonna
just stand by and let this happen?
[clears throat] Doctor,
we can't just give up.
I don't give up.
[roaring]
[gasps] I'll turn on the emitter!
No, Greta. Let it come.
[Timbercat]
So, instead of sinking the boat,
you invited them to a dance?
-Who does that?
-Kipo.
Listen. Sinking the boat
wasn't the answer.
But Prahm won't bring our friends back
from what the humans did to them.
I tried to make BradLand, but in the end,
it was more like SadLand.
-[meows]
-Aah!
-[hissing]
-[Jamack] No, Yumyan!
No--Yumyan, no! Bad kitty!
I know we've lost friends.
I understand why you want revenge.
I'm asking a lot,
but if you can forgive today,
we can build a better tomorrow.
That's how we make sure
this never happens again.
You can't forgive someone
that's not sorry!
-I wanted a sunk boat!
-[angry crowd noise]
Yeah! I want them to apologize
for what they did to Camille.
-[voice 1] Yeah, and Jeff!
-[voice 2] Oh, wait, no the wolfs...
-[voice 3] And Carton!
-[voice 4] And Wheels!
And Yumyan.
Sorry, Kipo. We can't afford
to lose anyone else.
I hereby resign from HMUFA.
Wait, what?
Uh...
Me too, man.
They all left.
[footsteps approaching]
Not everyone.
You guys are staying?
Every Prahm needs a king.
Yeah, and, you know,
I already got my suit on, so.
And I, Dave,
also stay bravely by your side.
What a guy, ain't he amazing?
I met him once, he was cool.
-[coughs]
-[gasps]
I live here. You guys should go.
Huh!
[exhales] I needed that.
OK. Now we decorate.
Wait, Prahm's not off? But they said no.
They seemed pretty mad, remember?
We just didn't ask them right.
They need an apology.
-And it needs to come from us.
-Right.
And we need to live it.
We need to dance it.
-Yes!
-Dance it?
We need to Prahm-pose.
I have no idea what you guys
are talking about.
Right. Prahm-posing
is an ancient tradition
that goes all the way back
to the old world.
If you want someone to go with you to
Prahm, you've got to Prahm-pose to them.
It's the perfect way
to get the mutes to join us.
Plus, nobody can say no to a float.
What's a float?
Only the most exciting and visual way
to celebrate all of our differences.
Hoo! Hah!
Whoo! Hah!
[Scarlemagne] After this works and Prahm
is a raging success,
I'm guessing it'll take nine minutes
for Emilia to turn on us and attack.
I would've guessed five.
So, we're in agreement?
Um, did you pilfer the pail of flora?
-No.
-Then who did?
I made a you.
I'm--I'm sorry, why do I
only have one eye?
I got tired.
[groans]
[imitates airplane]
Whatchu thinkin' 'bout?
Troy. I wanna ask him to Prahm,
but it's gotta be really good.
You know, to make up
for how we can't just hang out
because we're always saving the world.
Whoa! I was thinking about
how french fries are the perfect food.
Well, Troy is the french fries
of boyfriends,
and he deserves the perfect Prahm-posal.
OK, if we're not
grabbing some french fries,
you need to stop bringing them up.
You brought them up!
Huh?
The ladder's missing, too?
T'would appear we have
a saboteur in our midst.
What?
[mega walrus growling]
[screaming]
[hisses] Bad walrus! Get out of here!
Looks like your Prahm date's here.
[cheering and applause]
[Kipo exhales] Amazing job, everyone!
Now, let's rehearse. Positions!
Hmm.
Kipo, can we talk to you?
Like, together? Both of you?
Oh, my gosh! You bonded!
-That's not what's happening.
-Not a big deal!
OK. When she says go,
we burst out the top.
For reasons most obvious,
we don't trust Emilia.
We've noticed that a paint bucket
and a ladder have gone missing.
OK. A-are you saying this is
the same thing or two different things?
We don't know, but we should
mount our defenses immediately.
OK. Possible that you're bringing out
the worst in each other.
Come on, isn't it obvious?
Emilia doesn't want Prahm to happen,
so, she's being a sabater.
[clears throat] Saboteur.
OK. Well, I didn't
invite Emilia to a battle.
Prahm only works if we all believe in it.
You can't seriously believe
Emilia is going to give up
her life's work to frolic with mutes.
I won't know unless I give her the chance.
-Uh, Kipo?
-I'm not changing my mind on this.
The float's gone.
Oh, come on!
Ugh! No more tracks.
And I still can't pick up
the sabater's scent.
[sighs] OK. Now you're just
doing it to annoy me.
[leaves rustling]
Ah! Come out, Emilia!
-Aah!
-Who's Emilia?
Are you looking for her?
'Cause you found us.
-But who are we?
-That's Kameko.
And that's Jeanine.
Ugh, of course. Treasure Squirrels.
Well, our friends mysteriously vanished
inside a giant float and--
[laughs] What a coincidence!
We just found a float at Skyscraper Ridge!
And then we hid it!
[whispering] We hide all our treasures
to keep them safe.
So, Emilia wasn't our saboteur.
-I suppose not.
-This time.
That float was filled with people.
So, if you could show us
where you hid it--
Yeah! Let's go save your treasures!
Eh... uh...
-What are we waiting for?
-For you to tell us where they are.
Oh, yeah! [laughs]
-That's Kameko, by the way.
-And that's Jeanine!
We're going on a treasure hunt!
-Oh, good. This is gonna be fun.
-We're going on a treasure hunt!
We're going on a treasure hunt!
Uh, Kipo?
Hey, Kipo! It's getting hot in here!
Yeah, why'd you move us?
Why do you think she's not answering us?
Are we dead?
[gasps]
Panic setting in. [chuckles]
Everyone stay calm!
We're going on a treasure hunt!
-We're going on a treasure hunt!
-Treasure hunt! Treasure hunt!
-On a treasure hunt!
-Here we go!
-Ah, ah, ah ,ah,!
-Ho, ho, ho, ho!
Where is the float? Tell us! Tell us, now!
-You're looking for a float?
-What a coincidence. We found one!
We know! You were
going to show us where you hid it.
We can never remember
where we put our treasures.
-Shocker.
-No, that's Kameko.
And that's Treasure Hill.
By chance, do you
bury your treasures there?
Oh-ho, ho! I just remembered that yes!
[laughing]
[growl]
Benson! Dave! Anyone!
[laughing]
Good suggestion to play a game, Lio.
It calmed everyone down.
Almost everyone.
[anxious chuckling]
Hah! Too fast.
I've got the reflexes of a tiger shark.
-Tiger sharks don't have good refl-- aah!
-Hah! Gotcha.
-[laughing]
-[loud thud]
I'm starting to think
we're trapped in here!
Hey guys, I'm sensing
some freaked-out vibes,
-but I know Kipo will find us.
-I'm gonna die!
I didn't even get to ask him to Prahm.
[laughing]
I get it. Asking someone to Prahm
is a lot of pressure.
I just want it to be perfect.
Don't worry about all of that.
You just have to be confident.
Check it out.
Hey, Song, you wanna go to Prahm with me?
No... duh!
Whoo! What a ride. [chuckles]
I was nervous when I heard no,
but I felt a lot better
when you got to the "duh."
Your turn.
[exhales]
Hey, Troy.
-You wanna go to-- huh?
-[roaring]
Kipo! Over here!
Please help us, there's not much air left!
What? I need air!
-[Lio in distance] Over here! Kipo!
-[gasps]
[growls]
Treasure!
[Wolf] That's our stuff!
The float's gotta be in there, too.
[growling]
[screaming]
[screaming, grunting]
Aah!
[panting, grunting]
Huh?
[growling]
Aah!
Uhh!
-Oh.
-[gasps]
No! Kipo!
[grunting]
Are you OK?
[with effort] I'm fine.
You could have been killed.
[chuckles]
[screaming and groaning]
[gasping for air] Oh, sweet!
Sweet air!
Phew! I knew everything
would work out in the end.
[Dave gagging] Tasted my lunch again.
I only wanted to eat it once.
-[loud thud]
-That was double the calories. [groans]
Thank you, sweet jaguar girl!
We will never lose our treasures again!
But what if somebody else finds them
and takes them from us?
Oh, yeah. We better start hiding them.
Not this one!
[roaring]
-[grunts]
-Huh!
[panting] Ha-- Ohh!
[gasps]
-[gasps]
-[growling]
Hah!
Huh!
Oh.
Ho!
[groaning]
The only way to defeat a mega jaguar
is with a mega of our own.
Ahh!
[grunting]
Where are you going?
To eliminate our Emilia problem.
[grunting]
I can't let you do that.
We both know Kipo.
She's always so focused on others,
she doesn't consider her own safety.
We just rescued her from one avalanche,
but there's another avalanche coming.
And someone has to stop it.
Emilia's the second avalanche.
Yeah, I got that.
But I won't go behind her back.
Ah, she's like a sister to you.
Believe it or not, I feel the same.
We'd both do anything to protect her.
And that's why you're going to let me go.
[Kipo]
Thanks for helping us.
-I'm Kameko!
-OK.
I'm just gonna write the details
for Prahm right here, so you don't forget.
[chuckling] Great! We'll be there.
Whoa! I found a treasure map on my hand!
Where do you think it leads?
-We're going on a treasure hunt!
-Going from my thumb to my pinkie...
-[sighs]
All right, everyone.
This is our one chance
to make Prahm happen
and peace on the surface forever and ever.
-[gasping]
-[Kipo] Are. You. Ready.
To. Prahm. Pose?
What is this, some kind of new toy?
[music starts playing]
♪ We messed up ♪
♪ We thought our way of life here
Was the only way to be ♪
♪ We messed up ♪
♪ We thought that mutes like you
Were the only enemy ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ We messed up ♪
♪ And now we're here
To give you our apology ♪
♪ We invite you ♪
♪ To come to Prahm ♪
♪ To say we're sorry ♪
♪ I don't like it when we fight ♪
♪ I don't need to be right ♪
♪ The only thing I need
Is to dance all night ♪
♪ I wanna dance on the surface with you ♪
♪ And there'll be nothing
That we couldn't do ♪
♪ Dream beyond the stars ♪
♪ So big they have to come true ♪
♪ Break the mold and make something new ♪
Hey, kid, I know you
can't really come to Prahm
because you're a spore-producing organism,
tethered to an abandoned
science place and all,
but if you could...
you know I'd save a dance for you.
[screaming]
♪ I wanna dance on the surface with you ♪
♪ And there'll be nothing
That we couldn't do ♪
♪ Dream beyond the stars ♪
♪ So big they'll have to come true ♪
♪ Break the mold and make something new ♪
[meows]
[Kipo]
Guys, that was amazing!
-Uh, nobody said yes.
-Hmm, technically, nobody said anything.
Silence is just possibility in disguise.
It's my fault. The high kicks
weren't high enough,
and I kept going mm--pah!
when I should have gone ka-ka--kah!
No, it was my timing.
It was too perfect and highlighted
that everyone else was off.
We did our best. Now,
we just have to see what they say.
Hold on. We have one Prahm-posal left.
[exhales]
Troy, I've been trying all day to think
of the perfect way to ask you to Prahm.
Because you're amazing and awesome
and that's what you deserve.
But what I've realized is...
I'm not perfect. Nothing is.
Not even french fries.
He's right. They should be
called potato noodles!
So, I'm not gonna try
to be perfect anymore.
I'm just gonna be me.
So, will you?
Will I go to Prahm with you?
Aah! I asked weird! I screwed it up!
No, no, that was really cute.
It's just, I was literally
about to ask you.
The answer's yes!
[applause]
I usually don't have these kinds
of emotions, but, uh, feels good.
[gasps]
You put a lot of love and effort
into your Prahm-posal.
It was an emotional workout!
So, we're in.
[gasps] All three of you?
No. We're here on behalf of everybody.
I'm going to Prahm!
[cheering]
-[laughing and cheering]
-[Kipo] Yes!
Now, all we have to do
is everything else...
by tomorrow!
Oh, I need all hands on deck.
-Doag, sparkly things!
-On it.
-Benson, music
-On it!
Dave, follow Benson.
Hey, I'm the leader.
-[Benson] Just follow me.
-OK.
[Kipo] Oh, and Scarlemagne,
do you think you can get your piano?
Ooh!
Where's Scarlemagne?
-It was the only way to protect you.
-[small gasp]
Prahm is a great idea,
but an idea won't keep you alive.
Scarlemagne went after Emilia.
To do what?
Wolf, no!
I thought you believed in Prahm.
It might be the most important thing
we've ever done.
We're just trying to help you.
Well, I don't want that kind of help!
Well, I hope one day you understand
why you need it.
[groans]
[music playing[