-[snoring]
-[crickets chirping]
[squeals]
-[grunts]
-[squeals]
[snorts]
♪ Heard you got a letter
From your teacher today ♪
♪ She said, Listen, girl
You'd better change your way ♪
♪ You've been failing in every class ♪
♪ And if you don't watch out
Then you may not pass ♪
♪ But baby... ♪
One last thing to pull it all together.
[intro theme playing]
The humans brought a cure bomb?
Hummingbombers, let's ghost this party!
Get out of the sky!
Don't let the embers touch you!
-Ahh!
-[Kipo] No!
Run for your life!
Huh!
[Emilia]
You did it, Kipo.
You brought every mute
in Las Vistas together.
Thanks for the help.
[screaming]
Everyone, get under me! [growls]
[roars]
[yelling]
-Ow! Ow!
-Come on, everyone!
[growling]
Where's my shield? Benson!
Benson, where are you? Aah!
-Right here!
-Aww.
[screaming in distance]
Mandu? Mandu?!
-[squealing]
-Mandu!
I got you, pig.
[growling]
[gasps] Is everyone else OK?
No! Sorry, I meant yes.
Kipo, look!
Prahm worked.
You were my safe zone!
Thank you for spotting me.
[purring]
-[gasps]
-[sighs]
-[Lio] Mmh!
-[Song chuckles]
-[happy squeals]
-You can stop now.
It's over, Emilia.
The mission is never over.
We don't want the world
to go back to the way it was.
We wanna move forward together.
This could be a new age,
an age of Wonderbeasts.
And you could join us.
No! If I can't restore the old world,
I'll just have to wipe
this one clean and start over.
[gasps]
[grunts]
Aah! [gasps]
[gasps]
[low growl]
[laughs]
[roaring]
Get everyone out of here! Now!
[screaming]
♪ But baby, I got an F... ♪
[grunts]
[crowd gasping]
[laughing and cheering]
[Emilia screaming]
I can get everyone to the bunker
at our old burrow. We'll be safe there.
Everyone through here!
♪ ...chemistry, but I got an A in love ♪
-[screams]
-Hang on.
♪ I got an F... ♪
I'm not letting you do this alone.
[growling]
[panting]
[screaming, roaring]
Aah!
♪ Come on, boy, and I'll show you how... ♪
[shrieking]
-[roaring]
-[grunting]
She's not used to being a mega.
Keep throwing her off balance.
[screaming]
Uhh! Huh!
Ohh!
[grunting]
Huh! Aah!
[Wolf yelling]
[growling]
[Wolf screaming]
-I think that's all of 'em.
-Benson, take a deep breath.
What? Wh--
[squealing]
Oh. [gasps]
[both grunting and growling]
I think she's used to being a mega now.
We're not leaving. We have to help Kipo.
Yeah, and fast. But how?
I have an idea.
Uhh!
[grunts]
-[roaring]
-[grunting]
[gasps]
-Huh!
-[groans]
[gasps]
Oh!
[coughing] I can't beat her, Wolf.
She's too strong!
Maybe you can. Look!
Emilia wouldn't turn herself into a mute
if she didn't have a way to turn back.
-Greta has the cure!
-That's how we beat her.
OK. You get the cure,
I'll hold her off as long as I can.
-Are you sure you can--
-[heavy thud]
-[Emilia growling]
-Go!
[growling]
[panting]
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
-You're the scariest of the kids!
-Hah!
Huh!
-[grunts]
-Aah!
-Uhh!
-[gasps]
[grunting]
[groaning]
Uhh.
[battle cries]
I hate this, I hate this, I hate this,
I hate this, I hate this!
[yelling]
Yeah!
Aah! Get her!
[cawing]
[yelling]
Yes! Double slappy-slap, yo!
-[barking]
-[roaring]
[Jamack laughing]
You need to do some soul-searching!
Come on, mama!
[roaring]
[yells]
Uhh!
[grunting] Ohh!
[cawing]
[Loretta]
Yeah!
Uhh.
[gasps]
[barking]
Uh, honey, maybe we should slow down?
She kept me from my daughter for 13 years.
I am not slowing down.
[Scarlemagne]
Get her, Song!
[shrieking]
[grunting]
-Aah!
-[groans]
[grunting]
[groaning]
Uhh, ehh!
[both grunting]
Give me the crossbow, Greta.
I can't!
[both grunting]
Emilia said, "Greta, for once, don't
be an idiot and lose this cure dart."
You're not an idiot, Greta. [grunts]
You were right about my cloak.
It was time for me to stop hiding.
You helped me see that.
Wait-- I helped?
Yeah, you can think for yourself.
Emilia just says you can't so you'll do
what she wants. What do you want?
Well, I don't know.
I kind of want to go to Prahm.
Do they have pancakes there?
Give me the cure, and we can make you
as many pancakes as you can eat.
Oh, aww, man, really?
OK.
[growling]
Uhh!
[grunting]
[groaning]
[roaring]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[growling]
-Kipo!
-[gasps]
[panting]
[growling]
-Honey, get up. You have to wake up!
-Come on, Kipo, please!
[gasps, whistles]
I'm glad we were able to be a family,
just one more time.
Hugo, what are you do--
[glass breaking]
[roaring]
Huh! Ha!
Hugo!
[laughing]
[Emilia gasps]
[grunting]
Remember me? [laughing]
[intense laughter]
[gasps]
Leave my sister alone!
[Scarlemagne yelling]
[muffled yelling]
[low groaning]
[Lio]
Hugo!
[groaning]
Kipo. Where's Emilia going?
I don't know. She just ran away.
Go after her. We'll find Hugo.
[groaning]
[muffled scream]
[screaming]
[groaning]
What's wrong with her?
She just looks... scared.
Emilia never had an anchor.
She lost herself in the mega!
She's just gone? No more evil,
mute-hating brain in there?
You know, we could just leave her
like this. She's harmless.
I mean, this way
it's way better for everyone.
No. She deserves to be punished
but not like this.
[groaning]
[groans, panting]
Ouf.
You brought me back. Why?
Nobody deserves to have their mind
taken away from them. Not even you.
That's not the world I wanna live in.
You've lived in darkness for so long,
but you have a choice, Emilia.
You can stay there
or you can fight through it.
[sighs]
-Aah!
-[squealing]
Arg! Stupid mute!
Uhh! Oh!
-[Kipo] No!
-[screaming, grunts]
Huh? [grunting]
[baby's laughter]
A forever friend! [laughing]
[Mandu snorts]
Any of us could be next.
I see you, Mandu, acting all cute,
licking your hooves, but you're ice cold.
-That's a good girl, Mandu.
-[squeals]
Trapped in her old burrow with a mute
that wants nothing more
than to be her best friend.
I guess that's as good
a punishment as any.
It's over.
[growling]
[gasps]
No, no. No!
Did we win the day?
Not to brag but... I totally saved you.
You did, but you shouldn't have.
You shouldn't have helped me.
But you did.
And because of that,
I got to have a family.
-[groans]
-Scarlemagne?
Call me Hugo.
[Mandu groans softly]
Goodbye, Hugo.
[pop music playing]
-[Kipo] Guess what?
-[barking]
Wolf's corgi had puppies!
Sit, sit! Stay!
And Benson's restaurant just got
six thumbs up from Cappuccino!
Here you go.
Oh, yeah.
[meowing]
[hissing]
Babe, did you pack
the sriracha peanut butter?
-Two bottles.
-How 'bout Dave's potato noodles?
It's all in there.
Say hi to everyone.
-Hey. You ready?
-Ready!
[Kipo]
And the city's really coming along great.
We even installed
a public transportation system.
-Hey, guys!
-[both] Hi, Jamack!
-[yawning]
-[yelling, grunts]
OK, folks. Looks like this is our stop
because our bus fell asleep.
[Kipo]
And Dave's giving his presentation today!
I think he's gonna nail it.
...and that brings me to my final thesis,
and this is gonna blow your little minds.
The Earth is not flat! It's round.
And the reason why we don't fall off?
Anyone? Anyone? Tad?
[chirping]
That's right! It's because
we are all made of magnets.
Nailed it.
We have to stop letting him guest lecture.
I mean, how do you know
we're not made of magnets, hmm?
So, that's what everyone's been up to.
Life is good. Las Vistas is amazing.
And I wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for you, so, thanks.
Happy birthday, Hugo.
[gasps, laughs] Hey, Mandu!
♪ I've got a good feeling, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, I'ma take out the crew
And ride around somewhere new, babe ♪
♪ Everywhere we go, we gon' light it up ♪
♪ Show up, show off
We gon' rise above ♪
♪ Hey, life's a party ♪
♪ Under the sun... ♪
♪ New age, let's go discover ♪
[laughing]
♪ This life is full of wonder ♪
♪ Hold on to me
We're celebrating ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, whoo! ♪
♪ New age, let's go discover ♪
♪ This life is full of wonder ♪
♪ Hold on to me
We're celebrating ♪
[everyone laughing]
[music playing]
♪ Every day is a new day ♪
♪ You and me, we OK ♪
♪ Pop a lemonade, go crazy, crazy ♪
♪ Nothing in this life gon' faze me ♪
♪ Everywhere we go, we gon' light it up ♪
♪ Show up, show off, we gon' rise above ♪
♪ Hey, life's a party ♪